(DOOR OPENS)
(LIGHT SWITCH CLICKING)
Ah!
Where is he? Where is he hiding?
I don't know. I've been looking
for him since yesterday.
I'm gonna ask you for the last time.
Where is he?
I don't know.
What are you gonna do to him?
(GROANS)
Stay here in case
that rat shows up.
Okay.
(GASPING)
BEEFY: Who you protecting,
you dumb asshole?
A stoolie who rats
on his own friends?
They were your friends too.
TRIGGER: I got it. You wanna end up
like that bitch, huh?
(MUMBLES)
At Chun Lao's. Chinese theater.
You stay here
with this barrel of shit.
(SPEAKING IN CHINESE)
Noodles. Noodles. Noodles.
(GROANS)
(PHONE RINGS)
MAN: Easy, easy...
(PHONE RINGING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(MAN SHOUTING)
(PHONE RINGING)
(MUSIC PLAYS)
(RINGING)
(SCREECHING)
This way. Hurry!
There down. Mott Street.
Go. Go. Go.
(ELEVATOR RATTLES)
(GROANS)
(GUNSHOT)
Noodles.
Untie me.
Stay that way. No, stay.
I want them to know I did it.
MOE: Where you going?
NOODLES: I'm gonna go get Eve.
MOE: Don't.
Why?
They... They already been there.
Do you need anything?
Money?
NOODLES: I got more than I need.
- Yeah, it's all yours now.
(TRAIN RATTLES)
(MUMBLING)
Where to?
Sir, where do you want to go?
Anywhere. First bus.
Buffalo?
One way.
That'll be $1.20.
(HORN HONKS)
I wanna rent a car.
Would you fill this out, please?
(HORN HOOTING)
(SHIP HOOTS)
(TRAIN HONKS)
MAN: Shoot the dice, man.
Shoot the dice.
(PHONE RINGING)
(VOICE NOT HEARD)
(DOORBELL RINGING)
Noodles.
I brought back
the key to your clock.
Lock the door.
When did you get back?
NOODLES: Today.
Why?
They got in touch with me.
Who?
I thought you might know.
Me?
I don't know nothing
about nobody no more.
(KEYS RATTLE)
You gonna offer me a drink?
Yeah, forgive me. Sure. Of course.
Please sit down.
Who's Robert Williams?
I am.
"We wish to inform you
that following the sale
of the Beth Israel Cemetery".
The synagogue sent these out if you
wanted to relocate your loved ones.
I got the same letter
on account of my father.
Only the synagogue didn't send that.
I got that last week.
The rabbi told me he sent those out
eight months ago.
Yeah, that's right.
That's about when I got mine.
So, what else did the rabbi say?
He said I was lucky.
The bodies of Philip Stein,
Maximilian Bercovicz, Patrick
Goldberg were already spoken for.
And they were up in a very fancy
cemetery in Riverdale.
What's this all mean?
It means...
"Noodles, though you've been hiding
in the asshole of the world,
we found you.
We know where you are."
It means...
"Get ready."
For what?
That's the one thing it didn't say.
What do you think?
I think the answer's here.
That's why I came back.
Hmm.
I moved everything in here.
I had to sell the house,
the backroom.
I always thought
you might have helped yourself
to that million bucks.
But now I know.
You're...
You're on your ass worse than ever.
But I thought it was you who...
No, you thought wrong.
The suitcase was empty.
Then who took it?
That's what I've been asking myself
for 35 years.
If it bothers you, I can sleep here.
- You can have my room.
NOODLES: No. It's okay.
(SIREN WAILS)
- How's your sister?
- I ain't seen her for years.
She's a big star now.
We should have known, huh?
You can always tell the winners
at the starting gate.
You can always tell the winners,
and you can tell the losers.
Who would've put a penny on you?
I'd have put everything
I ever had on you.
Yeah, and you would've lost.
Well, you're beat. Good night.
Good night, Moe. Thanks.
What have you been doing
all these years?
Been going to bed early.
(GRAMOPHONE PLAYS)
Deborah, Papa says you should help.
No.
We got customers all over.
We can't do everything.
Try. I've got my elocution lessons.
(MUSIC STOPS)
Fat, you better spray the toilet.
I saw a cockroach in there.
NOODLES: Sorry.
MAN: Meshuga!
DEBORAH: Sorry,
I can't make it today.
GIRL: Okay. Bye.
DEBORAH: Bye.
(YELL)
Sorry, Fats.
PATSY: Noodles!
- Bugsy's got a job for us.
PATSY: Hurry up.
He don't wait.
NOODLES: Who you calling
a cockroach?
So, what are you?
You're filthy, you make me sick.
You crawl up toilet walls
just like a roach. So, what are you?
Let go!
I make you sick, huh? Then how come
you showed me your tush?
To a roach.
Go look at yourself, David Aaronson.
She don't leave me alone, I'm gonna
give her what she's asking for.
- What's Bugsy want?
- We gotta wake up a deadbeat.
That schmuck at the newsstand
didn't pay.
NOODLES: Here's your money, sir.
(YELLING)
NOODLES: Beautiful.
Look at it, it looks great! Wow!
(MAN SOBBING)
NOODLES: Come on, guys.
Come on, come on.
Now make up your mind.
- Noodles, let's take the dollar.
- Yeah.
MAN: Skip, here you go.
NOODLES: That one.
Him.
MAN: Hey, Sam,
I'll see you next Thursday.
NOODLES: That one.
Are you nuts?
Bugsy said we could take the dollar
or we could roll the drunk.
Yeah, but he ain't even drunk yet.
We'll wait.
- Well, you roll that one over there.
- What's to roll? He drunk it all.
Bounce that little shikker.
(WOMAN YELLING IN YIDDISH)
(FLUTE PLAYS)
(WHISTLING)
Jacket.
It's Fartface.
Shit!
We should've took the dollar.
Could've had 10 corned beef
sandwiches on poppy-seed rolls.
Look, the wagon will hide us
from Fartface. Get ready!
Now! Throw your jacket over him.
MAX: Mister, you sick? Poor guy,
you'll be okay. I'll help ya.
Come on, up you go.
Now, you're worse
than my Uncle Nathan.
Why do you want to get soused?
I'll take you home.
Go, Mama.
WHITEY: Stop right there. Hey, you!
Yeah, I'm talking to you.
What are you kids doing here?
- What are we kids doing here?
- We're getting it up the ass.
Yeah, getting screwed.
Is there a law against it?
Can you spare a dime for pisherkehs
that just got it up the ass?
Get out of here.
Get off the street.
Go ahead. And don't come back.
I don't want to see you here again.
All right?
(FLUTE PLAYS)
Hey, stop by for you later.
Yeah, but knock here
on the john first.
My old man's praying,
and my old lady's crying.
And the light's turned off.
What the hell should I go home for?
At least in here I can read.
WOMAN: Where are you going?
GIRL: Mama, don't get worked up.
MOTHER: You got pots to clean.
Peggeleh?
PEGGY: I'll be right back, Ma.
I gotta go to the can.
Hi, Peggy.
At least you could lock the door.
Don't you like it?
I've seen better.
- You seen lots?
- How many you seen?
I'll tell you how many. None.
Let me see yours.
Looksies, no feelsies.
NOODLES: Peggy... Peggy, I...
- You like it, don't you?
- Not for free, I don't.
Bring me a charlotte russe, and
then you can do anything you like.
Tomorrow. I'll bring it
to you tomorrow.
- I'll bring it tomorrow.
- I don't give credit.
I promise. I promise.
You better stop squeezing me,
or I'm gonna poop in my pants.
Well, you getting out?
Come on, come on.
Give me six copies.
Drop your pants
and I'll stick it to you again.
- What do you mean, "again"?
- That's a long story.
And look what time it is.
It's already 6:34. And I gotta go.
Boy, I got a lot of work to do.
Hold it a minute.
Now it's 6:35.
And I ain't got a damn thing to do.
Just you wait, asshole.
I'll do something with your time.
Wait! Hey!
Since we're talking about time...
...it looks like you're gonna break
that lamp at 6:36.
- Where'd you pinch this?
- It's mine.
- Prove it.
- I gave it to him.
WHITEY: Yeah?
Who the hell are you?
- Where you from?
- The Bronx.
And you give away watches?
He's my uncle.
- And who gave it to you?
- My Uncle Nathan.
My little brother.
Tell your uncle
to stop by the precinct.
MAX: He's dead.
- Alcoholic.
MAX: In Kishnev, Poland.
Then he don't need it no more.
It's been requisitioned.
- What's that mean?
- Pinched, by him. At 6:37.
Just remember,
I got my eye on you two.
I got my eye on you too.
Take it! Take it!
Take the lamp off. I can't hold it.
Max.
Who's this?
MAX: My uncle.
- That one. With the cream.
- The 5-cent one?
PATSY: Yeah.
For the twopenny one she only gives
you a hand job.
I can do that myself.
Not that one!
That one.
You sure?
Wrap it up pretty.
Good morning. Peggy home?
MOTHER: She's taking a bath.
That's great.
Would you tell her I'm here?
Hey, Ma. Another bucket of water.
Wait.
(DOOR OPENS)
PEGGY: What do you want?
- Me?
- Mama said you were looking for me.
- No. The guys told me that...
- What?
- I'll come back some other time.
Noodles!
Noodles! Noodles! Noodles!
NOODLES: Did you get it?
His asshole blinked, but we got him.
Nice going, Fartface.
And on duty too.
You boys caught me
with my pants down that time.
No, we caught you
with your schmuck in a minor.
- Put this someplace safe.
- That's all right. Hey, hold it!
Where you going?
Hold it! Wait a minute!
Hey, you, stop! Hold it.
- What are you gonna do
with that plate? - Depends.
What time is it, Max?
I think it's time
we got our watch back.
- Okay, boys, we're even.
- The hell we are.
You'll be collecting
your pension before we're even.
PEGGY: Hiya, fellas.
What do you boys want?
MAX: First off...
...you're paying Peggy for us.
Okay. That's it?
MAX: Go ahead while I tell him.
I can't believe it. My first time,
and a lousy cop's paying for it.
WHITEY: Look, what else do you kids
want for that plate?
Noodles was telling me about Bugsy.
Seems he's boss, thanks to you.
- Meaning what?
- Meaning he pays you off.
PEGGY: Will you slow down?
What is your hurry? Take it easy.
If you keep this up,
you're gonna come too fast.
(NOODLES GROANS)
> Do you see what I mean? You're
so stupid. I can't believe it.
So why does Bugsy pay you?
What do you do for him?
- I close an eye once in a while.
- Well, now you close an eye for us.
Why? What are you kids up to?
He'll tell you.
Me, him, Cockeye and Patsy,
we're working together.
Bugsy'll flatten you.
Besides, I don't put up
with no trouble on my beat.
You'll put up, and you'll shut up.
You hear nothing,
and you see nothing.
Just like you did for Bugsy.
MAX: Shit!
Don't get upset. That makes it
worse. It can happen the first time.
It's them two talking out there.
Can't you see you're ruining
the mood?
We made our deal.
- So take a walk.
PEGGY: Come here, honey.
- Feel good, bubeleh?
- He'll never get it up.
PEGGY: Relax. Okay.
Calm down, calm down.
(PEGGY LAUGHING)
PEGGY: Okay. Okay, come here.
(PEGGY MOANING)
DEBORAH: I'm glad the baby's better.
WOMAN: Happy Pesach, Deborah.
DEBORAH: Happy Pesach, Becky.
Hurry. We're gonna be late.
- There's Deborah.
- Sorry. Mama needed help.
Good girl. I just locked up,
and I'm giving you the keys.
I thought I'd just practice
my dance routines. All right?
Make sure you don't let
the goyim in.
- Okay, bye.
- See you later, Debbie. Bye.
(GRAMOPHONE PLAYS)
DEBORAH: Get down off of there,
roach.
That record's just like Ex-Lax.
Every time I put it on,
you have to go to the bathroom.
What are you doing?
- Give me a drink.
- We're closed.
Nice people don't drink on Pesach.
They go to the synagogue.
So, what are you doing here?
Somebody's got to keep an eye
on the place.
There are a lot of thieves
out there.
One could get into your house.
Especially if you leave
the door open.
You can pray here too.
Here or in the synagogue,
to God it's the same difference.
Come over here and sit down.
"My beloved is white and ruddy.
His skin is as the most fine gold.
His cheeks are as a bed of spices."
Even though he hasn't washed
since last December.
"His eyes are as the eyes
of doves.
His body is as bright ivory.
His legs are as pillars of marble."
In pants so dirty
they stand by themselves.
"He is altogether lovable."
But he'll always be
a two-bit punk...
...so he'll never be my beloved.
What a shame.
(RATTLING)
DEBORAH: Somebody's there.
There ain't nobody.
(WHISTLING)
It's Max.
So that's who it was.
MAX: Noodles!
Go on, run.
Your mother's calling you.
MAX: Noodles!
Just gonna go see what he wants.
(WHISTLING)
NOODLES: Hey.
- Yo?
- You been here long?
- No.
Were you in there?
You're one lousy kisser.
I seen you go in there
after that ball-buster.
Here's the stuff from last night.
We got 4 for the silverware,
6 for the typewriter.
Lipschitz wouldn't cough up any
more. We gotta get somebody else.
I came to divvy up.
- Tomorrow, with the others.
- I also came to pick you up.
- I can't come right now. - The
houses, the stores are all empty.
We got our pick. You pick that.
Yeah.
Some partner I got. Have fun.
BUGSY: How's it going, boys?
Who's that?
Bugsy.
I hear you guys are in business
for yourselves now.
I hear youse are doing real good.
Ain't you gonna introduce me
to your friend here?
I'll introduce myself.
Excuse the glove.
BOY: Son of a bitch!
That's my cut.
You don't work for me,
you don't work for no one.
I don't like bosses.
You was better off
you stayed in the Bronx.
It would have been better
for you too.
(BUGSY SPITS)
(MAX COUGHS)
(NOODLES GROANS)
- I'm gonna kill him
one of these days. NOODLES: Yeah?
Meantime it looks like
he's killed us.
Deborah, open up the door.
Deborah.
AL: That stuff, is it ready?
- We're loading it.
(MEN LAUGHING)
(CHATTERING)
AL: Che cazzo succede down here?
Al, we got the big boys
with us today.
- They wanna work for us. - Doing what
Bugsy did. We want his job.
FRED: Do you get that?
We the best escorts
you ever gonna get.
A fangulo a ma, escort
your mother's ass out of here.
Okay. Let's go, Noodles.
We'll peddle your invention
somewhere else.
FRED: Hey, wait a minute.
What invention?
- You ship your stuff by the river,
right? - Sometimes.
And when you get caught,
you throw the cases overboard.
- You lose the whole shipment.
- So?
For 10 percent,
we'll save it all for you.
- What do you got, a submarine?
- We got salt.
You got what?
Me and the boys are rolling salts.
We need 3 tons of salt per shipment.
Get the fuck out of here.
Go back to school where you belong.
What is it with all this salt?
Hey, hey, we got salt
on our noodles. Show 'em.
NOODLES: This is full of salt.
All right, come here.
AL: So?
- Keep your shirt on.
NOODLES: We gotta wait for the salt
to dissolve.
(FOG HORN HONKING)
- Well?
- Hey, what's wrong?
Hey, look.
DOMINIC: Wow!
PATSY: Great!
- Look at that!
- It's great.
- Noodles.
- Look.
NOODLES: I see 'em! What did I say?
- Yeah.
Yeah!
(CHATTERING)
PATSY: Hey, Noodles.
NOODLES: Hooray. Hooray for us!
We did it.
Come here, Max.
MAX: We did it.
NOODLES: No, Max, no!
Max.
Max!
What would you do without me?
(LAUGHING)
MAX: There.
From here on, we establish
the shared funds of the gang.
They belong to all of us together
and to none of us alone.
And we solemnly swear to put in
50 percent of everything we make.
- Agreed?
- Agreed.
Agreed.
I wanna take another peek.
This goes to Fat Moe.
We don't tell him what it's for.
And he gives it back
only when we're all together.
Agreed?
ALL: Agreed.
Agreed.
(FLUTE PLAYS)
DOMINIC: Bugsy's coming! Run!
Noodles.
I slipped.
(NOODLES YELLING)
NOODLES: Schmuck.
(HORSES GALLOPING)
(NOODLES GROANING)
(BELL RINGING)
Wanna go in?
Yeah.
You a relative?
An uncle.
It's open.
(FLUTE PLAYING)
(FLUTE STOPS PLAYING)
(KEY CLANGING)
"Erected to their everlasting memory
by their friend and brother...
...David Aaronson, 1967."
Hello. May I help you?
- I was just looking.
- I'm the director of Riverdale.
I've never seen a tomb like this.
We like to call them "heavens",
we find it's more calming.
Erected to their everlasting memory
by their friend and brother...
David Aaronson, 1967.
Is it a new building?
Yes. Do you know Mr. Aaronson,
Mr? Sorry.
Mr. Williams.
Mr. Williams. An interest like yours
is a compliment to our architects.
After you.
I think the beauty of the interior
equals that of the exterior.
Don't you agree, Mr. Williams?
We wanted to do
the style of the 30s,
which is when our young friends
went away.
Was it Mr Aaronson's idea?
Actually he left the whole thing
up to us.
We had carte blanche.
All he suggested was
the inscription.
"Your youngest and strongest
will fall by the sword."
- What about the music?
- And the music.
- That was exactly his suggestion?
- Yes.
We received a tape.
You seem to know him so well.
I'd like to ask you to tell him
how much you like the "heaven",
- when you see him.
Could you do that? - Sure.
I've been away quite a long time
and I lost the address.
Maybe you...
You must have signed a bill
or something.
The bank handled it.
A foreign bank.
I wish I could be of more assistance
to you, Mr. Williams.
Have you ever thought to build
your own heaven?
Think about it.
Can I take that for you, sir?
Your limousine is waiting.
Maxie.
How are you, uncle?
You're looking good.
You're looking a little better.
Come on. Better get you
off the streets.
- Some limousine.
- What are you talking, huh?
We own the company now.
It's a good cover. It pays off too.
My mother wrote me you was
in the body-snatching business.
I appreciate everything you did
for my family.
Forget it. It's your dough.
It's all down in black and white
in the company books.
You're the company.
You and Patsy and Cockeye.
Gravediggers and partners.
Hey, enough of this.
Business before pleasure.
We got a rush job. Here.
Come here. Look at this. Come here.
Sudden death. Fucking tragedy, huh?
- 26 years old.
- 26?
- What a shame. - Great stiff.
She died of an overdose.
And I'm ready for another.
Pump the life into her. You didn't
turn pansy in there, did you?
MAX: There you go.
(GIRL LAUGHING)
Turning over in the grave.
They do it every time.
GIRL: Don't worry. A pansy he ain't.
(MAX CHUCKLING)
NOODLES: Thanks.
MAX: You're welcome, Noodles.
Whoops. Sorry.
GIRL: Thanks. Good night.
Hey, you want a little
pick-me-up?
GIRL: No, thanks. I've had mine.
(GIRL LAUGHING)
MAX: Did you give her your all?
NOODLES: What do you think? You bet.
(MUMBLING)
MAN: Wait till you see this place.
MAX: It's over here.
- Where we going?
- To a place that never closes.
Whoops. Watch yourself.
(WOMAN CHATTERING)
What's this?
Our place.
We got the hottest spot in town.
This is the real Fat Moe's.
Get rid of that rag, will you?
- What do you think?
- It's beautiful.
- You like it?
- Beautiful. Beautiful.
GIRL: Hey, give me that.
- Noodles.
MAX: Patsy, look.
Come here, son of a bitch.
Come here!
- You look fantastic.
- Wait a minute.
PATSY: How you doing?
- Look how big you got.
- Me?
Noodles. Oh, God.
- Noodles!
MAX: Number three coming through.
Let's have a toast, for chrissakes!
- You look like shit.
- I just got out of prison.
- Nice guy.
- Hey, Noodles, get a load of this.
Look.
Hey, scotch heating.
Yeah, a buck a cup.
- A buck a cup?
- Yeah.
- How much it cost us?
- Costing us?
- Yeah.
- A dime, including overhead.
- Hey, Noodles.
- Fat Moe.
NOODLES: You look terrific.
- Look like you lost an ounce or two.
- You think I'll lose hemorrhoids.
NOODLES: Can't recognize him
without an apron.
- L'Chaim.
ALL: L'Chaim.
Welcome home.
What kind of maître are you?
You don't even show a guy around.
PATSY: Yeah.
MAX: What's with you?
- I didn't know. I'm sorry.
NOODLES: You're some shtunks.
- You don't come up and get me.
COCKEYE: He's the shtunk.
He said you weren't out till
Monday.
You get him the next time
he gets out.
God forbid. God forbid.
ALL: Whoa! Whoa!
Come on, let's see
if you can guess who it is.
Charlotte russe. With a little
too much whipped cream.
Peggy.
Hey, you watch it, now.
And my prices, they've gone up.
I work in a high-class joint now.
And I get paid by the pound.
My Peggy, she's worth every penny
of it too, my red-hot mama.
Come on, come on.
COCKEYE: Timber!
You've seen your old pals, now
I want you to meet some new ones.
NOODLES: I'll see you later.
MAX: You gonna lay here all night?
Cockeye wanted to play
with the band. I'm serious.
Come on.
- Aren't you going to say hello?
- Hello.
(MUSIC STOPS)
(BAND PLAYING)
- Your brother's a real friend.
- He's a romantic.
- Max tell you I was getting out
today? - Max? No.
- You remembered yourself?
- No, Moe. It's always Moe.
Yeah.
You weren't counting the days?
DEBORAH: Of course I was.
4344, 4343.
I lost track at 3000.
- That wasn't my choice.
- Yes, it was. It still is.
Did you come here
to welcome me back at least?
I still live here. I was on my way
out. Moe said I should say hello.
I hope Moe didn't have
to bend your arm or anything.
No.
Welcome back, Noodles.
MAX: Hey, Noodles.
You dancing?
Every night at the Palace Theatre.
I've made some progress since
I danced here among the brooms
and the empties.
You can come spy on me if you like.
If you have time.
Every night.
Noodles.
Go on, Noodles,
your mother's calling you.
It's good to see you again, Noodles.
My pleasure.
- Did you get the wine?
- Dago Red. The best.
How you doing?
There they are.
The four horsemen of the apocalypse.
Did you see that movie, Joe?
It's a good movie.
- Max, how are you?
- Good to see you.
Nice to see you.
- This must be Noodles.
- Noodles, say hello to Mr. Monaldi.
- Hi, how are you?
- All right.
Nice to meet you. You don't have
to call me Mr. Monaldi.
I like my friends and people
I respect to call me Frankie.
Come on, sit down.
Get some chairs and some glasses.
Sit down, relax. You're home now.
This is my very dear friend Joe.
He came from Detroit to ask me
to do him a favor.
And I wanna do it for him.
I don't have to tell you who Joe is,
how far he got,
or how far he'll get.
He's not only my dear friend,
he's my brother.
I'll tell you the truth.
Even a Jew can't eat this shit.
I mean, the mustard
doesn't even help.
(FRANKIE CHUCKLING)
These guys with you?
I told you these fellas are with me.
You could trust them.
You're in good hands.
Just tell them
what you want them to do.
Move some diamonds from Detroit.
Kid stuff.
Why us then?
If it's kid stuff, why not have
the kids from Detroit do it?
Excuse me, Noodles. He means that
it's something that's very simple.
But he needs kids
from outside to handle it.
He just found out they're moving
these diamonds to Holland
in a few days. So it's something
came up right away.
You understand?
Hey, Joe.
Tell these guys the story about
the pussy being insured. What is it?
Insured?
FRANKIE: Tell these guys how you
stumbled on this whole thing.
- Tell them the story.
JOE: Come on.
Pussy insurance. The insurance
pussies. Tell them that story.
Life is stranger than shit, that's
all. It's a pisser. No big story.
I got this insurance agent,
this Jew kid named David.
He conned me into every policy
in the world. Every policy, name it.
Dogs, house, wife, life, anything.
I'm drinking with the boys one
night, he comes in with his wife...
...a brunette with a nice ass
who works for a jeweler.
And he's still on the hustle,
this guy.
So I wink at the guys,
I say, "Look...
...the most serious policy,
you don't have me covered for."
He goes, "What's that, Joe?"
"Cock insurance."
"You make me a policy that when
it don't work, I get a payment...
...I'll write out a check now."
He thinks, and he says,
"I don't know if the actuality
gauges govern this...
but we can make a policy.
But you gotta guarantee
you're in good health now."
I says, "Look, leave her with me.
Come back and see if it stands up.
If it stands up,
you know I'm in good health."
The jerk leaves her. I screw her.
Not only that, she likes it.
And she tells me when her boss,
the jeweler...
is shipping stones to Holland...
...where he keeps his stash
in a drawer in the safe. Everything.
Can't ask for more, right?
Except, one better.
I never paid the first premium
on the new cock policy.
MAX: Cock insurance.
Life is funnier than shit.
But...
...be easy with the girl.
I mean that. Be easy with the girl.
CAROL: Oh, my God!
MAX: Open it!
Who's gotten in?
COCKEYE:
Had to go and be a hero, huh?
MAX: Open it.
- No.
MAX: Open it!
CAROL: No, don't hurt him!
- Don't hurt him!
MAX: Get this bitch out of here.
You animal! You asshole!
- Come on, hit me.
NOODLES: What do you mean?
- Hit me.
NOODLES: What, are you crazy?
- Straighten up and fly right.
- I'm all right.
Let me make it look real.
Make it look real.
NOODLES: Knock it off.
- I'm all right. Let go.
- Come on, cut the act.
- Hit me!
COCKEYE: She said hit her.
Go ahead, rap her in the mouth.
CAROL: Hit me!
NOODLES: I'll hit you! You bitch!
CAROL: You animal!
MAX: Put a cork in her.
CAROL: No.
No. Don't.
Don't. No!
No! You dirty bastards!
Bastards!
Try the secret compartment.
Attaboy.
Thanks.
COCKEYE: Nice matzo balls.
COCKEYE: Beautiful. Look at that.
MAX: Okay, better wrap them up.
(CAROL GROANING)
MAX: We're going. You coming?
NOODLES: Coming.
- Morning.
- You get the stones?
Pay him.
- Any trouble?
- No trouble. Kid stuff.
- How come you didn't tell me?
- Being inside can change you.
I'd already made the deal
with Frankie to get rid of Joe.
With Frankie Monaldi
you don't say, "yes" and then, "no."
You're right.
I would have said, no.
Frankie is as big as they come.
He's got the combination
in his hand.
If we're not careful,
he'll have us in his hand.
You don't get nowhere alone.
I thought you didn't like bosses.
It sounded like a good idea then.
It still is.
MAX: Think about it.
They're gonna ask us to come in with
them. There's a lot in it for us.
Today they asked us to get rid
of Joe.
Tomorrow they ask me
to get rid of you.
Is that okay with you?
'Cause it's not okay with me.
All right.
Let's just forget about it.
Wanna go for a swim?
Yeah, let's go for a swim.
All right, what are you doing?
Hey, Noodles.
Don't fuck around, Noodles.
- Noodles, what are you doing?
PATSY: Hey!
COCKEYE: You crazy?
Shit.
PATSY: Asshole!
Can't believe you did this!
(VOICES NOT HEARD)
"District Attorney James Lister
was killed in an explosion of a car
belonging to Secretary of Commerce
Bailey
as he left the secretary's estate.
Mr. Lister, killed in the blast,
was scheduled to testify
in Washington on Thursday
before a Senate committee.
A committee investigating what has
been called "The Bailey Scandal."
A team of detectives
has been assigned to the case.
Secretary Bailey was not available
for any statement at this time."
Did you know them?
"...offices of his legal advisor,
Irving Gold...
...in hopes of getting some comment.
Mr. Gold, you're aware
that District Attorney Lister
is the second witness in the
Bailey Scandal to meet a sudden end.
The first was Thomas Finney,
undersecretary of commerce
who fell to his death from his
15th-floor office a month ago."
Is there a connection?
Take the money and run, Noodles.
What's keeping you here?
"The only remaining witness
is the man who
rightly or wrongly has given
his name to this affair,
Secretary Bailey."
Curious.
"The secretary has no worries.
If he has no worries,
why has he retreated to his place
on Long Island?
He's preparing his attack
on the questions
he will be asked
by the committee.
I'd call them accusations
more than questions.
- He has no worries.
BRENTLEY: The public does.
Particularly, in view of the rumors
about rigged contracts,
bribery, the international Mafia.
Especially those dealing
with the illegal use
of the Transport union
pension funds.
Could you tell us anything
about that?
Gentlemen,
I deny all of these rumors
and allegations
against my organization.
Our hands have always been
and will continue to remain clean.
In my entire life, I've fought to
keep the American labor movement..."
Him, I know.
"...forced speculation,
criminal elements
or corrupt politicians.
If any mistakes have..."
He's still giving out
the same old bullshit.
"If any guilt at all exists in this
situation, it lies elsewhere."
(CLICKING)
What's this I've been reading
about you in the newspapers?
Inflammatory words
from a union boss?
You still won't come and stop
the workers or the social movement.
Listen to me, you socialist asshole!
We don't give a good fart
about the socialist workers
and their movements.
We want you out of the factory so we
can get the furnaces working again.
This is the last offer
you're gonna get.
You want to sign it or what?
Tell your bosses they can wipe
their ass with it.
(JIMMY GROANS)
Fill her up.
(COUGHING)
This is my last...
(TIRES SCREECHING)
MAN: Hold it, boys. Don't shoot.
It's me, Crowning.
- Crowning.
- Yeah.
That'll do, boys.
What'll do?
We almost got the kid
where we want him.
And we got the boss
PATSY: Easy.
Easy.
Put 'em down.
Put your guns away, boys.
Just swapping prisoners.
COCKEYE: Fair trade,
huh, chickenhead?
Union boy over here
for Mr. Boss Man.
CHICKEN: Well, look who's here.
Fat Moe's boneyard boys.
Which reminds me.
How's that cancer in your gut
coming along, Chicken Joe?
- Untie him.
- I don't take orders from you.
We're not asking you to take orders.
We're telling you.
Now go ahead, untie him.
Untie him.
Who are you?
Who's paying you?
I think this is gonna piss you off,
Mac.
I think it's those dirty
politician friends of yours.
Yeah? Well, you crawl back and tell
'em we don't want you in with us.
Our fight's got nothing to do with
liquor and prostitution and dope.
MAX: Well, you'd better
get used to the idea, pal.
This country is still growing up.
Certain diseases it's better
to have when you're still young.
You boys ain't a mild case
of the measles. You're the plague.
Bastards like him are immune.
That's the difference
between us and them!
Take it easy.
The difference is,
they'll always win.
And you'll keep
getting it up the ass.
Sooner than you think.
Chief Aiello, moving policemen
into the factory came as a surprise.
The press, the unions,
especially the strikers.
What did you want,
a declaration of war?
Ours was a peaceable operation.
REPORTER: Wasn't that contrary
to new union laws?
I'm chief of police,
not chief of people.
Was there any violence to justify...
My motto is:
"Prevention, not repression."
You let scabs move in and work.
Young lady, you wanna talk to me,
call them "unemployed workers."
With your permission,
I'll take these flowers
to my missis before they wilt.
Or maybe you heard.
I'm the father of a baby boy.
(AIELLO LAUGHS)
REPORTER:
Chief, one more question.
We heard he's the youngest
stockholder
in that factory you occupied.
What'd you mean by that?
They say management expressed their
thanks with a present for the baby.
You know,
slander is a serious offense.
Especially from a hack reporter.
You wanna find out how serious?
But since this is my first boy
after four girls...
...I'll declare amnesty.
Behave yourself.
Go.
(BABIES CRYING)
Thank you.
- He's eating?
- Mmm.
- For five.
- For five? Well, why not.
You could feed an army
with these milk plants.
We could open up a dairy.
Oh, hey. Che bella.
Who loves you? Who loves you?
I love you.
And I love you.
Lucy!
- Don't you have to feed him at 6:00?
LUCY: Uh-huh.
(KNOCKING)
LUCY: Come in.
(DOOR OPENS)
LUCY: Oh, here he is now.
- That's my son.
That's my son.
That's my son! That's my son!
Jesus Christ, they change fast.
Yeah, but he looks like my old man.
Yeah, yeah, look, same eyes.
And look, the same devilish pride.
Hey. Hey, hey.
Did you see his dickey?
- Vincent.
AIELLO: What?
- The girls.
- The girls!
Sooner or later
you have to learn that after me,
the boss in the house is him.
He's got balls like his papa.
- Hey!
- Let me have him.
No, no, no.
I'll do this. I'll do this, huh.
Hey. No, no, no.
Look. Hey, hey.
Let Papa change you.
Come on,
everything will be swell.
Come on, come on, come on.
What the fuck is this?
- What is this? Huh? What's that?
LUCY: Oh, no!
- Look!
- It's the right number.
The right number?
I'll break your goddamn neck!
Find my son,
or I'll burn down this building.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello.
Would you shut up?
No, hey, no. Wait, wait.
I'm not talking to you.
Well, who's this?
Never mind.
To who am I talking?
AIELLO: Where the hell are you?
My son, where is he?
Where do you think? He's in the
maternity ward. He never left.
He got restless, so he wanted
to change his bed.
The other kids got the same idea,
so they wanted to change their beds.
You got 30, 40 screaming babies
jumping from one bed to another
switching tags,
so now we do have a real problem.
Piece of shit whoever you are!
What the fuck! I want my son!
Luckily, we were there to see
that everything was under control.
If you want,
we can put everything back.
- Except you gotta meet us halfway.
- Tell me!
NOODLES: Why do you give a fuck
who wins the strike?
AIELLO: That's got nothing to do
with me! What did I do?
First of all, you let the scabs in.
Second, you've got the cops in there
protecting them.
- I'm a cop!
- All right, shut the fuck up!
Now listen very carefully.
Call off your dogs
and let the strikers work it out
- with the bosses.
- I want my son!
NOODLES: Do that and
we'll give you the kid's number.
If you don't, look for your
kid yourself. And good luck.
- So, what is it gonna be?
- Okay.
- I'll call my men off today.
- Attaboy.
You know, for a rotten bastard
son of a bitch
you're not as stupid as I thought.
- We'll be in touch.
- When will you call?
Don't worry, don't worry.
We'll be in touch with you.
- Bye.
- I got to...
MAX: So?
NOODLES: We got a deal.
- To a very smooth talker.
PATSY: Yeah.
- Mazel.
COCKEYE: At least.
Peggeleh.
Where's that switch list?
PATSY: The switch list?
- Yeah.
- I can't find it.
MAX: What?
I can't find it.
- What'd you do with it?
- I think I dumped it.
What a yutz.
NOODLES: Oh, Pat.
PATSY: Wait a minute, listen.
Listen, Noodles,
Noodles, wait. I remember.
The boys' numbers was odd...
Even, and the girls' was odd.
- It's simple.
- You took good stock.
Hey, let's give him an even number.
Eight. Let's pick an eight.
Eight.
- Yeah, it's a good number. - Wait.
What about the other pischers?
We're better than fate.
We give some the good life,
give it to others up the ass.
All right, boys, let's settle up.
It's Saturday.
Settle-shmettle,
I'm gonna take mine out in trade.
PEGGY: You're such a nudge.
PATSY: You know what? I wish
I was switched when I was a kid.
MAX:
What makes you think you weren't?
I don't believe it.
Hey, you guys, come here.
Take a look at who's over here.
- That suit you, Peg?
PEGGY: Fine, Max.
- What've you got?
- Over there.
Well, what...
Holy shit! Noodles! Noodles!
Come here, come here.
Look.
The blond by the piano.
- Who's that?
- Who is that?
You and this broad were practically
engaged at one point.
Oh, beat me. Oh, I love it.
- Who was it?
The Detroit cock-squasher? - Yeah.
MAX: Peggy.
NOODLES: No, she looks different.
You know that platinum blond.
She's by the table.
See her? Call her in, will you?
- Carol.
- Carol, whatever.
Just tell her there's a bunch
of her old friends here.
PEGGY: Carol.
Carol!
MAX:
Noodles, come here.
- Somebody here wants to see you.
- Who?
You know these guys?
No.
I don't think so.
No. I'd remember a bunch
of good-lookers like these.
Oh, well,
how could I forget.
There was...
There was only one of you
I got to know personally, though.
MAX: Which one?
Let's see how good a memory
you've got for faces.
You.
MAX: No.
Him.
NOODLES: We've been hanging out so
long we're starting to look alike.
Charmed.
You can call me Carol.
We've already met.
Pleasure.
The pleasure...
...is all mine.
CAROL: Mmm.
So you left Detroit, huh?
Her and her husband
just come in on weekends.
Yeah, beats the seashore.
She takes on 10 guys while her hubby
watches through the peephole.
Beats the hell out of the movies.
I wonder what that jerk
is up to in his cubbyhole?
He must be wondering
where is his fucking wife.
(CAROL MOANS)
Why don't we make it a threesome,
huh?
Can't you see he's got
other plans for tonight?
CAROL: Well, bring her along.
We'll make it a foursome.
I'm not that kind of guy.
I'm afraid if I give you
a good crack in the mouth,
you'd probably like it.
Have a good night, fellas.
See you later.
They make you dress like those
lunatics who go around Germany
burning down all Jewish stores.
Those lunatics burned down also
our store and made us go to America.
- I'm Jewish too.
- I know, sir.
- Everybody knows.
- Knows what?
Everybody knows who you are, sir.
- And what do you think? - I don't
think, it's your business, sir.
No, you think.
You think it's a disgrace,
don't you?
We don't have to be
like the Italians,
who look up to the lawbreakers.
We have enough enemies
without becoming gangsters, sir.
How much money do you make a week?
Not everybody tips like you, sir.
I make enough to go to school
and learn for my degree.
Good for you. So maybe by the time
you are 60, you'll make enough,
but then you won't be able
to get it up anymore.
- Been waiting long?
- All my life.
You wanted a place by the ocean.
I had it opened.
It was closed for the season.
All these tables are for two people.
Pick whatever one you want.
I like this one.
NOODLES: Here, sit down.
Boeuf à la mode.
Blanquette de veau.
I'll have the asperges sauce
vinaigrette
and then a Châteaubriand.
- Pommes frites?
- Natures.
- Comme dessert?
- I'll decide later.
- Monsieur?
- I'll have the same.
For the wine?
DEBORAH: You decide.
I'll just have water.
- You decide.
- Thank you.
You've been around.
Where'd you learn them
parlez-vous français dishes?
Who's teaching you that stuff?
You mean a sugar daddy,
who tries to teach me how to act?
I read books.
I want to know everything.
Doesn't it make sense to have plans?
Yeah, it does.
What about me?
Am I in any of these plans?
Noodles...
You're the only person
that I have ever...
Ever what? Go ahead.
Ever what?
That I ever cared about.
But you'd lock me up and
throw away the key, wouldn't you?
Yeah.
Yeah, I guess so.
Yeah...
And the thing is,
I probably wouldn't even mind.
- So?
- So I got to get to where I'm going.
- And where's that?
- To the top.
Now you sound just like Maxie.
Youse both alike,
that's why you hate each other.
Do you want me to leave?
No, I don't want you to leave.
You dancing?
- You asking?
- I'm asking.
I'm dancing.
To keep from going crazy, you have
to cut yourself off from the world.
Just not think about it.
Yet there were years
that went by, it seemed like...
...no time at all,
because you're not doing anything.
There were two things I couldn't
get out of my mind. One was Dominic.
The way he said, "I slipped,"
just before he died.
The other was you.
How you used to read me
your Song of Songs, remember?
How beautiful are your feet
In sandals, O prince's daughter
I used to read the Bible
every night.
Every night
I used to think about you.
Your navel is a bowl
Well-rounded with no lack of wine
Your belly, a heap of wheat
Surrounded with lilies
Your breasts
Clusters of grapes
Your breath, sweet-scented as apples
Nobody's gonna love you
the way I loved you.
At times I couldn't stand it.
I used to think about you.
I'd think, "Deborah lives.
She's out there. She exists."
And that would get me
through it all.
You know how important
that was to me?
I'm leaving tomorrow
to go to Hollywood.
I wanted to see you tonight
to tell you.
DEBORAH: No.
No!
No! No.
No. Please, no. No, please. No!
No! No! No, please!
No, no! Please, no, no. No.
(SCREAMING)
No!
(SOBBING)
(SCREAMING)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(DEBORAH SOBBING)
NOODLES: Deborah.
DEBORAH: Get away! Get away!
CHAUFFEUR: I'll be right back.
Take her home.
Hi.
- Are you alone?
- No, I'm with you, I hope.
Wanna dance?
No, I'm not up to that.
You know what I want?
I want to fuck you.
That's what you're up to?
You drink like this every night
or this is just a bad night?
- Who are you, Mr. Rockefeller?
- No.
- Why, how much did I give you?
- 50.
50?
- What's your name?
- Eve.
I'll call you Deborah.
I did more complicated things
for less.
- Deborah... Do you love me?
- Yes.
You are so beautiful!
Thanks.
Your feet are so beautiful!
Sandals...
Prince's daughter...
Deborah...
Now I'll fuck you.
Take your time.
(ELEVATOR RATTLES)
(FLUTE PLAYS)
Well...
look who's back.
What's this?
It's a throne.
It was a gift to a pope.
- Cost me 800 bucks.
- It's from the 17th century.
NOODLES:
So, what are you doing with it?
I'm sitting on it.
(FLUTE STOPS)
- You got any coffee around?
MOE: Yes.
Thanks.
While you were on vacation,
we were working overtime.
The union paid off.
That's your share.
Yeah. Even that geek.
You know, Jimmy "Clean Hands."
He respects us.
I shed a little blood for the cause.
Here, it's all in the papers.
Morning Telegraph,
they didn't like it.
It says, "Underworld joins strikers
in brutal battle."
But The Post, they liked it.
"Ends justify means
in decisive gangland encounter."
And they kvetched
about the Atlantic City job.
Newspaper guys never know
what the fuck they want.
- Well, you could have looked for me.
MAX: We did.
Cockeye found you at the Chink's.
So doped up
you didn't even recognize him.
There you were.
You called me "Deborah."
(SPEAKS IN YIDDISH)
Go fuck yourself.
Mind your own business.
We do our business together,
and broads do not get in the way
- and you know it!
NOODLES: Yeah?
- Yeah.
- What's she doing here?
It ain't Saturday.
She should be screwing in Detroit.
Well, she's screwing here now.
And only with Max.
NOODLES: Oh, yeah?
- With her husband peeping through?
- No, I left him.
You live with her and you tell me
not to mess with broads.
- You forget one thing.
NOODLES: What?
- I don't give a fuck about her.
- Max...
- Shut up! Shut up!
NOODLES: Maxie, tell me something.
What'll you spend your honeymoon on?
- Maxie.
- Shut the fuck up! Shut up!
Just shut up!
You want me to dump her?
You want me to kick
her fucking ass out of here?
Want me to kick her ass out
or what?
You want me to kick... Get the fuck
out! Get the fuck out! Get out!
Gonna tell me I don't have
a way with women?
(PHONE RINGING)
- Hello. JIMMY: This is Jimmy.
Who's this, Max?
NOODLES: No, it's Noodles.
Okay, listen.
We're gonna need you guys today.
I'm gonna be making a tough speech,
and I think you...
Go, go!
(GROANING)
Start the engine.
I'll be right with you.
Mr. Gallagher wants you to know
he appreciates what you did.
To show his appreciation...
Here's an envelope
for the both of you.
If we gotta complete the job,
I'll let you know.
(CAR ROARING)
(GASPS)
Wiped out by a blast
of Cordon Rouge.
What would Crowning
and his bosses say after that?
Never be afraid of you, then.
They're still not afraid of me. It
was you boys that scared them off.
You didn't want these guys.
You're lucky you got party leaders
like me who care about the union.
The strike is settled. We won.
That's what counts. Am I right, Jim?
It was tough for Jimmy not to be
there to sign the contract.
No.
What's tough is,
you did more in a night
than I could in two years
of talking.
- Forget it.
SHARKEY: To the hottest newcomer
- in American unions.
MAX: There you go.
SHARKEY: Jimmy Conway.
MAX: Now you're talking.
Roll out the barrel.
PATSY: And God bless.
MAX: Drink up. Suck it right down.
NURSE: You must be crazy giving
him drinks. We're going to operate.
What's the rush?
They already told me I'd be a gimp
for the rest of my life.
Don't worry, with one leg a little
shy, you're gonna take giant steps.
Yeah. And always one step
right behind you, Sharkey?
MAX: Make sure they work on
the right leg, Jim.
It's only blood, huh?
You boys got yourself a real martyr
for a friend. Make it work for you.
Yeah, but what are we going to do
with a martyr?
Times change. Prohibition won't last
much longer. Take it from me,
a lot of you will be out
of work.
Go on, Mr. Sharkey.
We're interested.
You ever think of setting
yourselves up in business?
All those trucks
used to haul liquor,
soon be selling them for nothing.
SHARKEY: I'm talking about
hundreds controlled
by a national organization.
And supported by a powerful union
headed by Jimmy.
Whatever you ask,
there's no way he can turn you down.
COCKEYE:
You gotta be kidding, Sharkey.
Jimmy "Clean Hands"
in business with us?
They won't be clean for long,
with the hands he'll shake.
Everything in good time.
(SIREN WAILS)
- We're not interested. - What's
the matter, you got a problem?
We got plenty of money tucked away.
Why not invest it?
I'll put the party behind you.
And I got friends in high places.
I'm not interested,
and I don't trust politicians.
You still think
like some street schmuck.
If we'd listened to you,
we'd still be rolling drunks.
- You broke?
- Don't bust my balls.
I am talking about real money.
This is real money to me. It's a lot
of money. You want any of it?
- You carry that stink of the street.
- I like that. It makes me feel good.
I like the smell of it.
It opens up my lungs.
And it gives me a hard-on.
SHARKEY:
You're carrying dead weight, Maxie.
One of these days,
you're gonna have to dump it.
NOODLES: Let me know
when you're gonna dump me.
Meanwhile, I'll be in Florida.
I got a yen for the seashore.
MAX: Hey.
Listen, I was thinking it over
and...
I guess I kind of got a yen
for the seashore myself.
You wanna go swimming?
Yeah. Yeah, let's go for a swim.
MAN: Read all about it!
Read all about it!
Hey, Maxie.
- Max.
- Huh?
NOODLES:
How much money we got put away?
Why?
Because we're unemployed.
About a million bucks.
- Oh, yeah? Where'd you put it?
- In my underwear.
- I'd have found it there.
- Hey.
We gotta reorganize, Max.
And I got a couple of good ideas.
Me too.
If I had a million bucks,
I'd take it easy.
MAX:
We'll take it easy when we got 20.
- Fifty.
NOODLES: Where you gonna get that?
MAX: Right here.
What's that?
It's a dream.
A dream I've been dreaming
all my life.
I swear to God, you and me together,
we can make it come true.
What is it?
The Federal Reserve Bank.
It's the biggest step
we can take, Noodles.
You're really crazy.
Don't you ever say that to me.
Don't ever say that to me again!
What chance is there that a crazy
thing like this might succeed?
Don't ask me, ask Max.
You know as well as I do
that this is suicide,
pure and simple, for everyone.
Yeah, well, don't tell me, tell him.
You got your own methods.
I tried.
He doesn't want to screw anymore.
All he thinks about is this job.
Tear gas, hostages,
now he's gonna do this.
He's gonna do it
with or without you.
Noodles, we've never liked
each other.
We put up with each other for Max.
So why don't we get together once
and do something for him.
And after that...
we can go back to being enemies.
You know,
if you were all in jail first,
there wouldn't be any bank job.
I got the idea from your friend Max.
What do you mean?
He laughs at you.
He makes fun of you.
He says Eve has got you
by the balls.
Every time you walk past this place,
you shit in your pants.
You'd do anything for the cops
to pick you up
so you wouldn't have to do this.
Well, then do it.
Do it. Put him in jail.
Put him in jail. Not long.
Just long enough so he can get
the idea out of his mind.
If you can't stand being away
from him, put yourself there too.
Better off than being dead.
You know what to do.
And if you don't, I will.
Get out!
Take a cab. I'm busy.
I got things to do. Get out.
Noodles.
Make up your mind fast, huh?
(BAND PLAYS)
What's the matter?
Aren't you having a good time?
Why are you going out tonight?
Why bother now that prohibition
is almost over?
Everybody's selling. We got friends
who wanna get rid of booze.
Practically nothing.
So we figured, why not.
I'm gonna be gone for a while.
I'll be waiting at the hotel.
I like it when you come home
late and wake me up.
I'm not gonna be home tonight.
I'm not gonna be home tomorrow
either.
I thought these things
only take a couple of hours.
Ladies and gents, I drink to
the demise of Fat Moe's speakeasy.
Who the hell wants to drink
here legally anyway, am I right?
Okay. Come on, Moe, set them up.
Go on, get in there.
MAX:
Here's mud in your eye.
Boys.
Let's drink to our last shipment.
There's more onboard
tonight than just booze.
It's 10 years of our lives. Ten
years that were really worth living.
Yeah.
MAX: Noodles.
Noodles.
- L'Chaim.
How long will I have to wait?
A year and a half, more or less.
Six months off for good behavior.
- What are you gonna do?
NOODLES: Don't ask.
FEMALE OPERATOR: Operator.
Police, please.
(RINGS)
Fifth Precinct. Sergeant Halloran.
Hello.
Who's speaking? Can I help you?
- Hello.
- Yeah.
I got a good tip for you.
NOODLES: Yeah, who is it?
MAX: It's Max. Open the door.
- What's the matter with you?
You sick? - No, I'm fine.
MAX: You don't look it.
Maybe you'd better stay home
tonight, huh?
- Why?
- Huh.
You know, I've been watching you
all night.
And you've been drinking
like a fish.
Trying to get your courage up?
We're only bringing
in a shipment of booze.
It's got so you're even scared
to do that.
Maybe you just better
stay home tonight.
With Eve.
Hey, Maxie, everywhere you go,
I go too. Remember that.
Maybe Sharkey was right.
Maybe I ought to just dump you.
- You're really crazy.
- Never say that.
Don't say it!
CAROL: Max made fools of us,
Noodles. He wanted to die.
Did you know his old man died
in the nut house?
Max didn't want to end up
the same way.
So he put the idea
in our heads to tip off the cops.
And when they stopped the truck,
Max started shooting first
just to get himself killed.
What is this?
Opening night.
Fifteen years ago.
Who's this?
Patron saint of the place.
And some actress.
Do you know her?
No.
This proves me base:
If she first meet the curled Antony,
he'll make demand of her,
and spend that kiss
which is my heaven to have.
Come, thou mortal wretch,
with thy sharp teeth this knot
intrinsicate of life at once untie:
Poor venomous fool.
Be angry, and dispatch.
Oh, couldst thou speak,
that I might hear thee call
great Caesar ass unpolicied!
Oh eastern star! Peace, peace!
Dost thou not see my baby
at my breast,
that sucks the nurse asleep?
Oh, break! Oh, break!
As sweet as balm,
as soft as air, as gentle...
Oh, Antony!
Nay, I will take thee too.
What should I stay...
In this vile world?
So, fare thee well.
Now boast thee, death, in thy
possession lies a lass unparallel'd.
Downy windows, close,
and golden Phoebus never be beheld
of eyes again so royal!
Your crown's awry.
I'll mend it, and then play.
Hello, Deborah.
Aren't you gonna say anything?
What is someone
supposed to say after...
...more than 30 years.
Well, how about, "How you doing?
You're looking good." Or...
"I was hoping
I'd never see you again."
I never thought I would.
There's a difference.
At least you recognized me,
that's something.
Actresses have good memories.
You want a drink?
I'm having one.
Margo.
- Yes, miss?
DEBORAH: That's all. You can go.
All right, miss.
She called you "miss."
You never got married?
No.
You live alone?
Where were you?
I was out of town.
Have you been back long?
A couple of days.
Are you staying?
That depends.
Why do you want to see me?
Two reasons.
First, I wanted to see
if you did the right thing,
turning me down
to become an actress.
Well?
You did. You're terrific.
"Age cannot wither her."
It's like the play
was written for you.
What was the other reason?
The other reason...
...is to decide whether I should go
to a party tomorrow night.
Party?
Yeah, on Long Island.
A Secretary Bailey.
Do you know Secretary Bailey?
No.
But I was invited anyway.
If you don't know each other,
why were you invited?
I don't know.
I thought you might know why.
Me?
Why me?
Because you know him.
(KNOCKING)
DEBORAH: Who is it?
DAVID: David.
- No, David.
DAVID: Can I come in?
No. Just wait outside,
I'll call you.
Okay, I'll be right here.
- What does Bailey want from me?
- You came to ask me that?
- Why'd he send me an invitation?
- I don't know.
Why should I know about your
invitations? I don't know anything.
What do you want? Why did you come
here? I know nothing.
Now you're a lousy actress.
Who is Secretary Bailey?
Secretary Bailey
is a rich businessman.
He came to the United States as an
immigrant and made a lot of money...
...in San Francisco and L.A.,
where he's lived for 30 years.
NOODLES: I know all that. It's all
in the papers. What else is there?
He married a very wealthy woman.
They had a child.
She died when the child was born.
A few years ago, he went
into politics. Moved here.
That's history. I'm not talking
about that. I'm talking about now.
Right now he's in trouble.
Just tell me you've been living
with him all these years,
and you're his lover.
DEBORAH:
Age can wither me, Noodles.
We're both getting old.
All that we have left now
are our memories.
If you go to that party on Saturday
night, you won't have those anymore.
Tear up that invitation.
There's an exit back this way.
Noodles, go through it.
Keep walking.
Don't turn around.
Please, Noodles.
I'm begging you. Please.
Are you afraid that I'll turn
into a pillar of salt?
If you go out that door, yes.
DEBORAH:
This is Secretary Bailey's son.
His name's David, just like yours.
I must admit this party was
a wonderful idea, Mr. Secretary.
It's a bit like saying, "I'm going
up before the Commettee in 5 days,
like, my conscience is clear.
The most important people
in New York are my guests.
It's going to be a night
to remember."
Especially if the house blows up.
Where are you putting the next bomb?
In the freezer?
Or in the toilet?
You can't even think straight
anymore.
I'll tell you something.
A waiting list of people would like
to send flowers to your funeral.
- I can point out ten right now,
if you like me to. - Yes.
But none of them wants to read my
obituary in front of the Committee
as much as you do.
You and your union.
We just want to resolve
this situation clean.
I've heard that same song from you
for 35 fucking years!
Who do you think you are talking to?
I helped you to make a fortune,
you and the rest of those parasites!
It was a reasonable arrangement
between labour and management.
2% for them and 40% for you.
You defend them and you screw them.
Come on!
It's been the story of your life.
- Do you think anybody believe you
anymore? - Some.
But no one believes in you anymore,
because you have made mistakes
and I haven't.
But that's beside the point.
The important thing right now
is that
you and I straighten out
these transfers of authority.
Now it's all as we have agreed.
Have had our lawyers drawn it up.
All you have to do is sign.
My last will?
You are not in a position
to exercise your will.
I give up everything.
12% would be set aside for your boy.
In that way he can be assured
of living to a ripe old age.
Or not, if I don't sign?
Why don't you take care of this
by yourself?
I'd be very happy for you tonight,
if during all the noise of the party
- I heard a shot.
- Maybe you will.
(DOOR OPENS)
BUTLER: Please go in.
MAX: What are you waiting for?
I don't understand, Mr. Bailey.
Sit down, Noodles.
Make yourself comfortable.
I'm glad you accepted my invitation.
NOODLES: Well, I was curious.
So many important people
in one place.
MAX: Yes. Well, the rats usually
desert a sinking ship.
But in my case, they appear to be
flocking onboard.
Yeah, well, I read about
your troubles in the newspapers.
But a man in your position,
with all your power
and all your privileges...
...has to assume a certain amount
of responsibility...
...a certain amount of risk.
Why'd you ask me
to come here, Mr. Bailey?
That invitation doesn't mean
a goddamn thing, and you know it.
All that counts is what
was in that suitcase.
The money and the contract.
It didn't say who the contract
was on, though.
Haven't you figured that out yet?
You, Mr. Bailey?
I haven't had a gun in my hand
for many, many years.
My eyes aren't too good, even
with my glasses. My hands shake.
- And I wouldn't want to miss.
- Cut the bullshit, Noodles.
I'm already a dead man.
At least give me the chance to
settle the debt that I owe to you.
I'll never make it before
the investigating committee.
They're scared I'll implicate
the whole bunch of 'em.
They gotta get rid of me.
Today is as good a day as any.
You do it, Noodles.
You're the only person
I can accept it from.
You see, I found out where you were.
I brought you back here for this.
To even the score
between you and me.
You can get out through there.
It leads right down to the street.
Nobody will see you.
I don't know what you're talking
about. You don't owe me a thing.
Your eyes were too full of tears
to see it wasn't me burned up
on that street.
It was somebody else.
You were too shocked to realize
that the cops were in on it too.
That was a syndicate operation,
Noodles.
You're crazy.
You said that to me once before,
a long time ago.
My mind was never as clear
as it was at that moment.
I took away your whole life
from you.
I've been living in your place.
I took everything.
I took your money.
I took your girl.
All I left for you was 35 years
of grief over having killed me.
Now, why don't you shoot?
It's true,
I have killed people, Mr. Bailey.
Sometimes to defend myself.
Sometimes for money.
And many people used to come to us.
Business partners, rivals...
...lovers.
Some of the jobs we took,
and some we didn't.
Yours is one we would never touch.
Is this your way of getting revenge?
No.
It's just the way I see things.
It's 10:25...
...and I've got nothing left
to lose.
When you've been betrayed
by a friend, you hit back.
Do it.
You see, Mr. Secretary...
...I have a story also.
A little simpler than yours.
Many years ago I had a friend,
a dear friend.
I turned him in to save his life...
...but he was killed.
But he wanted it that way.
It was a great friendship.
It went bad for him,
and it went bad for me too.
Good night, Mr. Bailey.
I hope the investigation
turns out to be nothing.
It'd be a shame to see
a lifetime of work go to waste.
(TRUCK STARTS)
(KATE SMITH'S