City its lights.
The armada of this monument, we the people
of this city: "Peace and Prosperity"
the afternoon.
Did you receive sir?
Wait, your change!
Evening 900: 10: 35,200
-> 00: 10: 36,400 Grandma.
Night.
Tomorrow will sing birds.
Be brave, life stretched breasts!
No, I'd give everything to the last!
I came to myself. My buddy my life.
Ýsýnalým go home a little.
Is there any news?
Eþyalarýný just sent your wife, sir.
Beautiful!
I propose a toast to our friendship.
No, I will live!
James, Rolls-Royce, the maker!
The city's top gold getireceðiz!
Early morning hours. Time to go home.
Drive carefully!
Is the car I'm driving?
Andie approved, your car.
Then you get yours.
My friend where?
Gets in, he's my konuð I!
Let's buy some flowers.
That's $ 10.
Bozuð'm not a gentleman.
James!
Includes take them. I am coming soon.
You gentlemen thank you for your kindness.
You can visit you at home again, I wonder?
Whenever you sir.
Uyanmaktadý dawn time was a different man.
Whoever matter, I'm not here.
Whoever get rid of it immediately.
Then arabasýyl brought me home.
One must be rich.
Yes, other things have more money.
It afternoon.
Mate!
Let's go home, I'll give
a great party for you.
Parts.
Next morning.
Yola Öðlen çýkýyorum those et!
There is fire, I got a good look at him.
To help the girls find work.
Last Warning! Ladies, you have a $ 22 debt.
If you ödemedið until tomorrow morning...
çýkaracaðýz you home.
Grandma, he's coming today.
Grandma, what's wrong?
Grandma, I want tanýþmaný him.
He aradýðýn not be here at all.
Noon to lunch at a time.
Have you seen the soap?
Time is here!
It was difficult to play the role of
gentleman without a Millionaire Friend,
but he did his best.
Viennese doctor körlüð cures.
Free surgery for the poor.
Fantastic! Then I can see from my.
Is gelmiþ me? Read it please.
Do not be sad. Tomorrow, first
thing I'm going to pay it.
Late development.
This last time kalmandý now!
Get out of my sight!
Do you want to earn easy money?
That night.
Remember, half halfway We paylaþýy.
Promised to me bustin yakmayacaðýn.
Watch out, your boss might hear us.
LEAVE TOWN POLICE are PEÞÝN Jim
I gotta go, boss!
Do you want to fight for 50
dollars?, prize winner takes all.
You will fight with him!
This brings me luck rabbit ayaðým.
Þ The work of kolaylaþtýralým,
paylaþýrýz fifty-fifty percent.
Winner takes all!
Hoping to find money for the
girl, all þehr the ride begins.
Dönüþ from Europe.
Girl, do not worry, I ilgileneceð him.
$ 1000 is enough?
Police! Help!
Soyulmuþ, Call this guy!
Where did you get this money?
Tell me your verdiði him this money!
Who is this guy?
For rent.
And this is for your eyes.
I must go.
How can I thank you?
Do not you do not you go?
A while to ..
But you'll come back!
Autumn
I want to give a little flower orders.
What happened? My youngest got?
There's nothing, I thought
the only döndüð back.
I won!
Are you?
Can you see now?
Yes, I can see now.
Translation: Jaguar @ 2003