Our bosun's mate.
Been on quite a bender tonight.
The road's closed.
Whose pigs were they?
- The road's clear.
- Coming through!
They called that fireboat drill.
They're all from my boat.
Captain.
Merkel's crews. They moved out at dawn.
Okay, sailors! Let's go start a fire and
find ourselves a little French quill!
Just don't miss your mark!
Shall I tell you how to flush it out.
They're scared you know.
They comfort themselves in
women and schnapps.
What's going on here?
Ready and fire!
Sir!
My 2nd officer.
This is Lieutenant Werner,
war correspondent.
He'll ship out with us.
He'll report the true facts.
Life on a submarine.
Welcome aboard, lieutenant.
Good evening.
Hey lieutenant, come this way.
U-boat crews need relaxation.
- Good evening, Captain.
- Good evening.
Two beers please.
Of course captain, right away.
Where's our friend, Thomsen?
He should be toasting his Knight Cross.
You talk to your wife?
No calls to Germany before 10 o'clock.
Two beers.
My unit report back from U-96, sir.
All provisions onboard and fully
armed, sir. The boat is cleared for sea.
Thanks you lieutenant.
One more thing, Captain.
On the way here...
I had a very embarassing experience.
It was...
Quite outrageous!
They stopped me and...
You were initiated you mean.
Exactly!
Me too.
May I have your attention!
Now please a little silence to
be appreciated.
I'm very happy to call on our latest hero..
Captain Lietenant Thomsen!
Three big cheers!
That's Thomsen.
He's from the old guard.
Always drunk now.
My respects, Thomsen!
Quiet in this whorehouse, quiet!
To our wonderful
abstaining
and womanless führer...
who rose gloriously
from apprentice painter
to become the world's
greatest battle strategist.
What? Isn't it true?
He's the great naval expert
who took it upon himself
in his infinte wisdom--
How's it go again?
The English bedwetter
that cigar-chomping asshole Churchill
where exactly to go
and stick his stinking cigars!
Excuse me.
I see you in the morning.
I must phone home.
Philip the old bunch is gone.
Got these new heroes,
all wind and smoke.
Big mouths.
Cheeks together... balls in hands
and the belief in our führer in their eyes.
They'll know in time.
You're a pig's ass!
Combat! Conquer or die!
Come on, Phillip... come on!
Give me hand. Help me get him up!
You kow I wanted to
really
screw my brains out tonight but...
- Come on, Philip.
- I am not in the condition to fuck.
That will do!
- That's Thomsen's boat.
- Huh?
Are everything righted up?
Yes, starboard propeller blade was bend.
That's explained the running
noise in at low gears.
They've changed it. We have got a
brand-new propeller captain.
That's our boat.
Crew at attention!
At my point vector, attention!
All hands present and accounted
for captain. Watches at manuever station.
The boat is cleared for sea.
Thank you, number 1.
At ease!
Well, men...
All set?
All set, sir!
We have a guest on board.
Lieutenant Werner.
War correspondent.
He has even brought his camera.
He's writing a story on our war heroes.
See you remember your manners.
At your stations, man.
Heil und Sieg! Sink them all!
Moved all these crates out of here.
This isn't a vegetable garden.
Fish store.
Where we maintain and stored the torpedoes.
Head's up you slobs.
You're gonna to be in the papers.
- Thank you, men.
- Come on, follow me.
Here we have the can.
Just one for fifty men.
The other's full of provisions.
That's where we have to think
and eat and empty it, it's logical.
Chief petty officer's quarter.
- My home away from home.
- Here comes the newspaper.
- Here's the board room.
- Make sure you spell my name right.
What where you put that stuff!!
It's really cosy here.
Where are you, lieutenant?
Coming, excuse me please.
- Careful!
- He's got a picture of his mother.
The eyes and ears of the boat
Just what we need.
The control room.
The boat's command post.
Come on, through here lieutenant.
Let me through. We've got company.
- Morning, herr lieutenant.
- Morning, gentlemen.
Sir, this is where the petty officers bunk.
Sleep twelve men.
It means two guys have to share a bunk.
One sleep while the other's on duty.
And so one man comes off watch, he climbs
through the other's man stink. Right?
This bunk just for you.
One to yourself,
since you're a guest onboard.
Take here lieutenant. This is for you.
And here's your escape gear,
very important.
It's only for show.
Come in useful in the shower.
The mask comes out when the diesel stink.
Or when Frenssen pees.
Okay, come along.
Come along!
This is the galley.
And here is Johann, our phantom.
Hey Johann, everything in order?
- Could you come up?
- Yes lieutenant!
Better to take photos on our
return from the mission.
Not when we are going out.
What do you mean?
They'll have grown beards by then.
The British will be ashamed if they
see the shaven faces of their enemy.
Tight face kids.
Innocent stride from mama skirt.
Sailing with them makes you feel so old.
It's like a "Children's Crusade."
- Permission to pass, sir?
- Carry on.
You're from Mexico, ain't you?
Yes, south of Mexico City.
Good there?
Yes, very nice.
Good climate... high altitude.
Quite a way.
It was my duty as a German to come.
Did you work there or what?
Yes, on a plantation in fact.
Belongs to my step-parents.
You're boss' son?
You could say so.
Stand by, first watch and starboard watch.
Excuse me.
Can I get by?
- Permission to go on watch, Captain!
- Hmm!
A new breed, our Mexican recruit.
He's a machine.
Follows order without question.
He's so uptight,
he could crack nuts with his back cheek.
Careful... Eggs.
- Permission to come up?
- Yes lieutenant.
Alarm!
All hands forward!
Diving position!
Forward, come on!
Come on! Move it. Come on... move it.
Hop, hop....
Come on... Move! Move...
Faster... faster. Move...
Keep moving. I want to see steams
coming out of you guys!
In case you didn't know, it's an alarm!
It isn't the blasted cruise, damn it!
Blow negative tank.
Plow turn east to 10 degrees.
Not bad... not bad.
Practise makes perfect.
Keeps you from getting rusty.
A practice drill.
Level off chief.
Bow up 15. Stem up 10.
Planes on zero.
- Level off sir.
- Shut all main vents.
All main vents shut.
Take her down.
Let's see how the valves
and seals hold up...
Bow placed on 15, stern up 10.
The shipyard rates about to 90 metres.
We could go deeper.
There's a limit somewhere.
We can only take so much pressure
before the boat's be crushed.
Check all valves.
- It's pressure.
- Yeah... so?
Deeper!
140 metres.
She must takes this depth.
150.
160 metres.
That will do for now.
- Surface.
Bow up 10. Stem up 5.
Your girl?
French girl?
You know the shop that sells flowers
beside the Cafe Al'Ami Pierrot?
Beside where?
Al'Ami Pierrot.
Sure...
The two pretty salesgirls.
Jeannette and... The other one's call...
Francoise.
There's nobody who knows but we're engaged.
Unofficially.
Can I see?
Very pretty. Really...
What's wrong?
She's pregnant.
Go on...
Did you know what that means?
If the Resistance ever find out
German baby...
Told her about it.
She wants to have it.
You've got problems.
Our Master's in Berlin spend all their
time finding Churchill clever new nickname.
What's the latest creations?
"Drunken Pig"
"Fat Boar"
"Paralytic."
I must say for a drunken paralytic
he's putting up a damn good fight.
Just see...
We'll cut this man shreds.
That is my firm belief.
Listen to me, smart guy...
He's a long way from French, Mr Churchill.
I'd like to know how many of
their ships are getting through us.
Right now, while we sit on our
behind's waiting for orders.
Our patrol planes... where are they?
Answer that one Herr Göring!
The British have plenty of them.
Talking big is all he's good for,
that fat slob.
Big heroes, nothing but hot air.
All of them.
Go on.
Put that one down.
It will make exciting reading
in your "Epic".
The propaganda ministry will love it.
Music we need.
Think our Hitler Youth leader
might put a record on for us.
That "Tipperary" song,
if you've no objection!
Hey, now we're the Royal Navy.
A simple record won't make you do that.
Do you remember...
Shut the door, you lazy pig!
You stupid jerk.
They should use him as a door stopper.
His rear end big enough.
Yeah, it's so big, one of these days...
he'll stick it in the can and
he won't be able to pull it out again.
Morning... morning.
This stinks.
Yeah... sweaty feet and hair grease.
Pilgrim's specialty, huh.
Smell just like old socks.
These rotten eggs...
Poo babies...
Maybe Pilgrim could used the
control room to hatch chicken in...
That's right. Ducks in the bilge, why not.
Sweet little ducklings.
We could fat them up with
jam from your filthy feet.
- You dirty pig.
- Why, what's wrong?
They'd find it good fun.
In the morning they'd...
feed on fresh toe jams.
"We took cleanliness," four letters?
Bath.
Thank you.
A desert animal with two humps?
Camel.
Perfect!
Intellectual starvation... I would say.
It's completed sir.
One moment.
This could work.
A new course, sir?
One minute.
What's the signal position sir?
"Convoy squared at AK 2246,
main course 60 degrees, speed
8 knots." U-Boat 37.
U-Boat 37, that's Marten's boat.
Moving in to attack...
Too far away. Never make it.
Goddamn it!
When do we get some orders?
Hey, you lazy rat!
Put your back into it!
Pull them out. Slap some grease on it.
- For your journal, huh?
- Yeah, wonderful stuff.
Come on guys. Let's see you moving.
The press is here.
- You there. This way a moment.
- Sure, lieutenant!
So nicely grease with Vaseline now so...
Come on, we're ready to ram it in.
Don't let me disturb you. Carry on working.
- Can I just bring you round this way?
- Yes...
This is good.
You stayed here in the foreground.
I just want the picture like that.
Good, let;s have some more...
the camera's running.
Who did that?
Tell me now.
You got any hairs up your nose?
Why?
I've got some up mine.
Maybe we could knit them together
Francoise, my love
this is my 14th letter,
but you've yet to see one.
20th day at sea.
Feeling foggy and overfed.
It's all so crazy.
Alarm!
All ahead full!
Flood now!
Just a shadow off beyond the starboard.
Straight out of the rain.
Take her down 30 metres.
Stern planes up easy, bow planes 10.
Anything on the starboard beam?
Propeller sounds.
110 degrees.
Way aft of us.
Contact getting fainter.
Fading fast, sir.
We'd better stay down now.
Steer 120.
One ship travelling fast.
No chance of getting it in this light.
"It's more than merely
superficial to take the utmost
care in dress and personal apperances.
It denotes that the...
has a corresponding effect on other people.
An officer should be thoroughly
unpretentious
in character and wardrobe
always be the case. In the old days
young officers used to....
when superiors were more lenient
for the German lieutenant
always knew..."
Comfortably, huh?
No mail, no telephone.
A well-ventilated boat.
Solid wood paneling.
Free food too.
We're in clover here.
Like horse droppings.
They're rolling in clover smell.
No need to work to make a living.
We are even allow to smoke.
U-boat special cocktail.
Want some?
Stop that!
Our recent truimphs.
"Dived to evade enemy aircraft,
lost contact.“
"Dived to avoid destroyer
depth charges."
The British's have stopped making mistakes.
Next to supply fuel to the engines!
Okay.
Let's get to the diesel room!
Look out!
- Here we go again.
- What's happening?
U-32, he has spotted the British
convoy somewhere in our vicinity.
We should be there in 10 hours.
- Now hear this.
- Shut up... listen!
U-32 is operating against the convoy.
We're joining in the hunt.
Contact expected anytime after 1800 hours.
That's all!
Soon we'll flew this beauties out.
All ready for blast-off!
Over 30 freighters!
Berthold has to wait till we arrived.
Follow the convoy and
keep in contact with us.
For me it's the best getting draft
into the U-Boat
and sailing ships.
Skimmimg across the sea like
a bird on the wing.
I've sailed on a 3-masted schooner.
Wonderful ship.
Lots of room. Hull big as churches.
That's a fine way to waste fuel.
Lunatic.
Damn this weather, damn it!
We could passed the British completely
without seeing them.
We should be well within range.
Why doesn't Berthold signal us?
Why haven't we heard from HQ?
Visibility nil, sir. It's useless!
- Prepare to dive!
Cleared the bridge now!
Take her down 30 metres.
Bow planes up 10.
Stern down 5.
Bow planes zero.
Stern zero.
What's happening? Why are we diving?
- Hydrophone check.
- What?
In bad weather you're able to hear
more than see on the surface.
Can't you make a contact?
Nothing?
Contact, bearing 060. Quite faint.
Depth charges.
They're blasting someone.
What's the bearing from us now?
Moving right 045 degrees.
Moving away from us.
- Surface!
Steer 330.
Note this our log book.
In spite of bad weather decided
to commence operation. Moving in now.
Damn this stinking weather!
How's it look?
One minute captain.
We're here. The enemy should be here...
running zig-zagged!
Freight on starboard bow bearing 040.
They're over there. 040... and closing!
Damn it!
That's no freighter.
Oh no... a destroyer.
Coming straight at us.
- Clear the bridge.
- Aye, aye captain.
Take her down!
Come to periscope depth.
Stand by battle stations.
Make way!
Go! Go! Faster! Faster...
Keep her level, chief.
Flood tubes 1 to 4.
He wants to attack the destroyer.
Crazy in this weather.
Watch your depth, chief!
Bow planes up 2.
Stern planes down 2.
Come on...
Bow planes keep to zero.
13.5 metres.
Open bow caps now.
Enemy speed: 10.
Our left. Bow angle: 030.
Range: 6,000.
Depth: 2 metres.
Torpedo speed: 40.
Spread shots from tubes 1 and 3.
Angleof spread: 3 degrees.
Tubes 1 to 4 ready to fire.
Damn it.
Close bow caps! Takes her deeper, chief.
Takes her deeper!
Depth charges dropped!
Get some fuses, quick!
Check all high valves enclosures.
Control room secured.
All clear forward.
No serious damages.
They must have spotted our periscope.
Seems incredible in this sea.
Is it getting louder?
The same constant. Ahead of us.
It's pulling further ahead.
295 degrees.
- Left full rudder.
That's left full sir!
Steer due north.
Deeper chief!
Bow down planes 15. Stem up 10.
Pump 200 liters forward.
All ahead one-third.
Now it all turns psychological,
gentlemen.
Check torpedo tubes!
Stay calm, men.
That ain't nothing yet.
Kill the lights.
Silent run.
Both engines 50 r.p.m.
Contact closing.
Ahead, 52 degrees.
Approaching fast.
Midships.
All full ahead. Right full rudder.
Heading straight for us!
Those aren't amateurs
up there. Deeper!
Bow down 20.
Stern up 5.
Destroyer approaching.
Getting louder.
Deeper, quickly.
Don't be afraid.
It's only the pressure.
Deeper!
Stern up 15.
Tighten that flange!
Bring her up! Up 150 metres!
Chief... forward 20!
Come on Frentzen, quickly!
Come on... tighter Frentzen, hurry!
Depth gauge hull valves secured.
Both planes eased to zero.
Level at 150 metres.
Becoming louder.
She's turned around.
Go on, get it over.
They're above us.
Just above us.
Contact fading to starboard.
Twenty-two.
Twenty-three.
They're far away.
Contact receding aft.
Can barely hear it.
It has passed us by.
I think that will be all this time.
Hunt speed!
Both main engines silent speed, 50 r.p.m.
From my private collection.
How does it look in the engine room?
Smashed up quite badly.
- Be able to patch it up at sea?
- Already started.
Be sure to make it good, chief.
I've got a feeling we're going
to see some action.
Waited over an hour now.
I guess we've shaken them off, sir.
Don't be so sure.
It could have stopped,
they're still there waiting.
To surprise us when we try to surface.
Not dumb the British.
Stay on silent speed.
When it's dark we will surface.
- Okay. Show us...
- See better in the dark.
Coming up fast.
- Sound check at 30.
- Planes on zero.
Level at 30 metres.
Periscope depth.
Tower free.
Stern down 5.
Come up!
Stern up 3.
Zero.
Surface.
All set to blow.
What a cutie pie.
If only your Mama could see you now.
Cut it out! All this damn noise!
I've got bad news, men.
What's up now?
Our team is losing.
5-0.
Not a chance of making the final's now.
It can't be! I just don't believe it!
Drop them.
You dirty little boy.
Crabs.
A whole army of them.
A winky like yours,
they'll eat it down to the bones.
Yeah, give them a blow with the gun powder!
Excuse me, lieutenant.
Need a shave is what this meat does.
What's of those thing crawling
about in your eyebrows?
Pardon?
A case for the medical, I say.
Crabs by the look of them.
Are you joking?
When the creatures begin to surface,
it's the fifth stage.
Bosun!
Yes lieutenant?
Do you know where the medic is?
Yeah, in the bow compartment lieutenant.
This crabsgot you too!
Calm down...
What?
Take it easy... calm down!
You have gone crazy or something?
Hey... guess what? You heard the latest?
Our Dufte tying the knot.
Who the hell is this stupid bitch!
You're so mean...
I think half the fleet have tried her.
They should stick you in a zoo,
mate you and a chimpanzee like you.
Pictures of the beautiful fräulein!
Don't dirty them...
Don't tell me this 2nd hand matches that...
Did you sleep with her?
This boat are built to take it.
A real storm on a sailing ship,
you should try that sometime.
You don't feel a thing down here.
Compass.
The boat's heaving to starboard.
I can't keep her on course.
No cause for concern.
It's pointless sir.
We're burning up fuel for nothing.
Prepare to dive.
Diving stations!
Standby all main vents.
All main vents clear.
Nothing exciting out there, huh?
Just reports... very faint.
SOS calls from enemy frieghters.
If one of the rudder breaks
in one of those...
there's nothing to do but pray.
The sea can't sink us, you know.
No ship as safe as our U-Boat's.
Put the record on.
You know the one.
Watch out!
Man overboard!
Hold on!
Let's move! Hold onto him!
Hurry will you.
Lay him out flat!
First aid kits! Bring now...
First aid kit! Damn it!
Prepare to dive!
"A military leader leads
through self-discipline.
Without his example,
education is impossible."
Three ribs cracked and a gash on the head.
He was lucky.
What a rotten month.
Absolutely rotten.
Mildew is good for you.
It's the next best thing
to fresh grown lettuce.
Anything that grows on this boat,
we've got to be grateful for.
Must be snowing already back home.
Very funny.
It's been years since I have seen snow.
Can I look?
Sure!
Your wife?
There, in front... there!
Captain, U-boat, port ahead!
It's one of our, it's a German U-boat!
Sir, a German U-Boat over there.
You're right!
- Both engines stop.
- Bring out the lights.!
Look, it's Thomsen!
All back...
Good hunting, you rascal!
My god, Phillip.
So they pushed you out to sea again.
Goddamn it! How can this happen?
Dozen boats we've got in the Atlantic.
From Greenland to the Azores,
a mere dozen!
But still we... we almost collide
with one of our own.
Sixty metres. Boat is trimmed, sir.
Something's wrong here.
Check on our position's?
More or less, captain.
More or less... more or less,
that's not good enough!
We haven't had a sun shot in fourteen days.
And we've been drifting in this storm.
Hard to compute.
For certain!
We make a few errors in our own position,
the others do the same...
And we end playing collision games,
leaving the route wide open.
So we allowed the British to shove
the whole armada through.
It's another story in the middle
of the ocean, lieutenant.
I hope you're making notes of all these.
Maybe headquarters will listen to you.
You've more influence than I have sir.
You believe that?
What's up?
A convoy.
- Permission to come up?
- Affirmative.
Outward bound convoy. Five columns.
Very juicy.
Any escort in sight?
Destroyers?
Nope, nothing.
No protection. Nothing.
That's funny.
They could be off chasing one of our's.
That damn moon.
- How many of ours boat on contact?
- Five.
Do we risk it?
It's worth a try, captain.
Come left to 180.
Left to 5 degrees rudder.
New course 180.
Kriechbaum, what's your feeling?
It will work, captain. We've got them.
Prepared tubes 1 to 4, for surface firing.
Flood tubes 1 to 4.
I'm going in.
Mast to sight to bridge.
All ahead full,
left full rudder come to 107.
Standby to attack!
Watch the pressure of the lubricating oil!
Bow angle, bearing 050.
Lock on!
Range: 2200 metres.
Those two that are overlapping.
Double shot on the big one,
the other two a single each.
Target identified.
Right standard rudder. All ahead one-third.
Open bow hatches.
Lock on tubes 1 and 2. New bow angle 063.
Check... locked on!
Follow fore-bearing.
All set!
Tubes 1 and 2...
- fire when match.
- Tubes 1 and 2.
Tube 1, fire!
- Tube 2.
- Fire!
Tube 3, fire when match.
- Tube 3... fire.
Tube 4 ready.
Fire!
Destroyer ahead!
They're firing!
Alarm!
Bow head up 10, stern up 5.
Keep quiet you men!
Down 80 metres.
Easy...
Bow down 15, stern up 10.
What about the torpedoes?
Any minute now.
Not long to go now.
Hundred ten.
Hundred twenty.
Those lousy torpedoes. They don't run true.
What a crazy thing to do.
Charging in like that.
The destroyer won't let us off the hook.
Try to hunt us down, you'll see.
It hit the first.
We hit her! We hit her!
Psst... Quiet!
Time's up for third torpedo.
Number three.
Now they're going to the bottom.
It's the bulkheads. They've collasped!
This is it!
Now we have to pay off.
Destroyer bearing 044.
Our direction?
Moving left.
Fading, sir.
Right full rudder.
Both engines ahead two-thirds.
Astern of us.
Way astern of us.
They're spitting in the wrong direction.
We haven't thrown them off yet.
I reckon they won't be too happy.
Propeller noises.
Contact bearing 270... closing.
Both engines ahead one-third.
Now you'll see.
All ahead full!
Dump 150 liters!
Asdic.
Detector system - Ultrasonic.
Swine. Filthy rotten swine.
What's the damage?
Air shaft fractured.
Quiet boys. Keep it quiet.
Hold dead slow.
Fifty r.p.m. Kill the fans.
Left 15 degrees.
All ahead full!
Shut it off!
Shut the number two auxiliary!
Connect ventilation cartridges.
Switch on fans,
connect the emergency cartridges.
Yeah...
She doesn't want to let go of us.
What's going on?
Running away?
We've really smashed them.
These bulkheads, did you hear them burst?
What's the bearing?
065 sir. Bearing constant.
Deeper, chief. Silent speed.
Bearing?
Five 0.
Growing louder.
Yeah, sure!
Deeper still. Right thirty degrees.
They'll try doubling back.
Keep them guessing.
Bow steady. Stern up 10.
Contact bearing 270.
It's fading.
Right full rudder.
Rudder is full right.
Steer 090 degrees.
Ugh!
Second contact closing fast... bearing 076.
Damn them!
Another one!
Deeper...
Yes... deeper.
Bow planes down 10.
Stern planes up 7.
190 metres.
200 metres.
210 metres.
220 metres.
230 metres.
The bolts! They're bursting!
That's deep enough, chief. 10 metres rise.
All ahead standard!
Quiet, men, quiet.
Up to 150 metres! Both full ahead!
Left 20 degrees!
Steer 050!
He's near his mark.
Quiet, damn it!
Reports! I want actual damage report.
Captain... permission to
inspect engine room?
Number one... Take over!
- Bring the tank gaskets.
Bring me the gaskets.
Come on, move it!
Here... Torpedo hatch taking water!
Crow bar ! Hurry up!
They'll soon be out of fireworks.
Exhaust flaps secured.
150 metres, all ahead full.
What's wrong, Johann?
Back to your battle station.
Right now!
Don't disobey my orders. Do as you're told.
Back to your station!
I'm ordering you, Johann.
Take him aft, hurry!
He's under control.
Who would have thought it was Johann?
Degrading...
Shame.
Forget it... We can hear them.
That's it... come on.
Boat dropping!
190 metres!
220 metres!
We're sinking!
Make a note for the war diary.
Today submerged for 6 hours
at silent speed.
Satisfied, the destroyer has lost us.
Intense glowing sky, observed it...
210 degrees.
Probably flames from tanker we hit.
We'll surface in 10 minutes.
You see, lieutenant...
they didn't kill us.
Her back's already broken.
She's a tough one. She won't go down.
Alright number one. Let's finish her off.
Master sight to bridge.
Final shot. Prepare to fire.
Target speed zero.
Range: 650 metres.
4 metres... torpedo speed 30.
Aiming point. Forward of aft to mast.
Tube 1 ready.
- Fire!
Torpedo running!
There are still men on board!
Why didn't their own ship rescued them?
For the love of god!
They have had 6 hours!
They're swimming towards us.
Both engines back two-third.
May I clear the table sir?
Some more signals sir.
Go ahead.
"Three freighters sunk. Convoy's dispersed
into groups and stranglers.
Contact problem.
Cruising course 030."
U-112.
Wenzel.
Not bad.
Kupsch is in contact with the same convoy.
Stackmann has torpedo a 6000 tonner.
They're having a field day.
Any hope of joining them?
Difficult.
Minimum 5 hours away.
Our fuel--
- We can't make it.
- Yes, yes... it's no good!
So, when do we go back?
When it's time for us to go back.
And not before Klepton.
Fired at 950 metres.
Targeted aft mast.
Crew, assumed rescued,
was still on board.
Survivors swam toward U-96.
I wish to apologise.
Nothing to be said, Johann.
You deserted your post at the
critical moment in action.
You also disobeyed my order
to return to it.
You mean to say that there
has to be a court-martial?
How many patrols have you done?
Nine, sir.
You... why you... Johann.
Please it was a mistake.
I just somehow... all of a sudden...
as if...
It won't ever happen again.
You can depend on me.
I swear.
All right, Johann.
There isn't... no court martial, sir?
Get some sleep.
U-96 withdrew from survivors.
Decision...
Return to La Rochelle.
Cipher officer!
You found the problem?
- It's the bulkhead conduit, captain.
- Good.
Get it fix!
Morning there.
Get moving, there's a signal to be decoded.
Supposed it's top secrets.
Another wild goose chase.
Amateur task.
This rig is ready for a refit.
Not to mention our fuel shortage.
We won't even make La Rochelle.
- The last 100 miles--
- We'll hoist the sail.
Don't worry, chief.
Decoded it yet?
Well, what's it?
"For captain's only."
Very strange.
Triple cipher.
Well, what do you know...
Christmas in La Rochelle.
Real girls and Christmas stockings.
Delicious telephone operators,
cute sexy little nurses,
to comfort and kiss.
Hot damsels. We'll have a ball.
A valkyrie... in shinning armour,
really big and fat.
- Now hear this.
- Chief master's voice.
La Rochelle's out.
We've orders to a new port of destination.
La Spezia.
The Mediterranean. First...
we'll refuel and supplies at Vigo in Spain.
That's all.
They must be crazy.
Those dirty roaches.
There goes our Christmas stocking.
No sexy little nurses.
Not even decent a pig.
I'd like to kill those morons.
Well... Christmas and Macaronis.
That can't be such a bad thing.
We've got to get there first,
you stupid little jerk.
- And so?
Gibraltar!
Use your brain, you pathetic idiot.
It's like eye of a needle.
This camel will need more than a can of
Vaseline to get through there.
The Mediterranean.
It's madness.
It's swarming with English combat ships.
Venus... standby!
Zero...
25 degrees, 43.3 minutes.
Gibraltar.
It's the best chance to get ourselves kill.
When you reached Vigo you go ashore
Lieutenany Werner, you and the chief.
But sir...
I've already make the decision.
I'll have got to find new replacement
for the chief.
Our agents will smuggle you
out of Spain somehow.
Dress up as gypsies for instance.
- But captain I thought I would be going...
- No arguments.
It's all been settled.
It's easier to get two of you out.
I really believed the chief needs a break.
His wife is very ill.
He must get home.
I understand, sir.
Tough break?
When we reach Vigo it's goodbye.
Captain order me ashore.
The chief leaves too.
To deliver your mail for you?
That's quite a bunch of them.
Well... it's quite a romance, isn't it?
Equalize.
Pipe down.
White light.
Hurry up with that gear.
Quiet, man!
Now we just have to find this little bunch.
The "Weser"
a German merchant ship,
she's got herself interned here.
With a bellyful of torpedoes,
fuel and supplies.
And that's all for us.
Yeah... yeah, 1st class service.
Starboard engine stop.
We've arrived.
Port engine stop.
Officers to bridge.
Watch out on deck.
Gentlemen.
Three cheers for our gallant U-Boat men.
You're most welcome.
Captain lieutenant.
No, no please, not me.
This is the commandant.
My apologies, sir. I...
A pleasure to have you aboard the "Weser,“
captain lieutenant.
A hero, I am delighted to be so honored.
Gentlemen...
here they stand.
Our heroes of the deep.
The grey wolves...
our humble ship is honor on this occasion..
such as this is.
Captain, lead the way...
- Welcome onboard.
- Congratulations... well done!
Nice clean tugboat you've got here.
Here we are captain.
As you could see we've done
we can in our modesty way,
I hope it's to your taste.
Quite a table, just like home.
Fresh bread, cakes from the ship bakery.
With fruits,
fresh sausage our chef specialty.
We are waiting to hear your news.
You can't imagine what it means to us.
It isn't easy here despite what people say,
it's very frustrating.
Sure, there's plenty to eat.
Fuel supplies no problem.
Torpedoes are tricky though. Very tricky.
You're all set-up.
The Spaniards tolerate us,
but we couldn't called them enthusiastic.
Christmas cake.
Now tell us...
how many ships have you sunk?
Now let's see, I guess about...
Oh... champagne.
How forgetful of me.
Take a glass.
Gentlemen.
We drink to our heroes.
We are proud of you.
To the German U-boat's service...
and to our beloved Füh--
Aah yes, we're not exactly at home.
If you understand what I mean.
All the best!
Cheers!
And now... plenty for everyone, come on.
- And with me, let's get down to business.
- Yes, come...
Yes now, telll us all about it captain,
continue...
I'm bursting with curiosity.
Those are fresh figs.
Never had one.
Quiet, gentlemen.
This time we very nearly had it.
Phenomenal.
You see gentlemen,
that's the stuff heroes are made of.
There's no other word for it
but phenomenal.
Come on captain,
I want to hear more... here.
Give me your plate, herring sir.
Another specialty of our chef this.
His mother recipe.
Just taste it. There's lots more.
What's like to be underwater?
To be submerged...
while overhead the enemy lies in wait?
It's dark!
Yes and very quiet.
As long as no one belches.
Why is that?
- As long as no one...
- I'd explains what our number two means.
In the silent speed the men
must always execise discipline.
And that's why you're forbidden
to belches, yes...
Herr Seewald, we've been expecting you.
Captain...
Representatives of our naval attache here.
I brought some communications from Berlin.
Fisrt, the documents for the break-through.
This cable came.
Chief, Lieutenant Werner.
We're going for a little fresh air.
Well Seewald, what's happening?
Bad news.
Headquarters say no.
Our request has been denied, chief.
There's no replacement.
You'll stay too Werner.
I'm sorry.
I guess it's just as well.
Who knows what kind of idiot
they would have send you?
One of those new found warrior's.
Just all winds and smoke.
You could be right.
They should have stacked
the sub with a few horny little senorita.
Forget it lover boy. A case of
- Spanish crabs, that's all we need.
- Idiot!
Today he was a virgin.
Now he can't live without...
Hurry up and get this mess out of here.
Get that chart table clear.
I can't navigate on bananas.
What're you doing? Get that fruit out
of here, move it. I want....
Those depth control completely free.
Is that's a Christmas tree?
- What do you think it is?
- Camouflage...
We're staying on board.
They won't replace us.
I'm sorry, Ullman.
Seven miles from coast to coast.
A bit narrow.
Here are the British dockyards.
The only one the British have
in the western Mediterranean.
So they are very heavily defended.
The place will be crawling
with patrol boats.
Anything that floats will be on the water.
And this is where we have to go.
That's the situation.
We'll move in under darkness.
The surface.
We'll see if we can slip through
their cordon.
As near to Gibraltar as we can get.
Then dive down
and let ourselves drift through.
Dive...
And allow the surface current
to pull us through the strait.
As quiet as a shadow.
And we burnt less fuel.
Well, Kriechbaum?
Clever trick, captain.
Let's get going.
All ahead two-thirds.
Navigator and I stay up here,
now clear the bridge.
Half the British fleet are there.
- Left 20 degrees and change to main motor.
- Steering 05...
- Destroyer port...
- Range...
800...
Which way?
Is she closing?
No, she's heading away.
That's good.
- Full...
- Rudder left full.
Full.
All right, then.
Right full rudder! All ahead full.
Be quick.
Damn!
Gibraltar.
We'll dive in 10 minutes.
Alarm!
Flood valves!
Watch out, don't dive!
The captain's still on top! Don't dive!
We've got a wounded! Stopped flooding.
Safe off everything... everything!
Standby escape gear.
Ready to abandon ship!
- Power supply to escape gears...
- Medic to officers' mess immediately!
Bring the medic, hurry!
Both engines maximum power!
Hard starboard!
Easy...
To control room!
Prepare to abandon ship!
Faster, faster!
- Compresses!
Chief to captain. We've to stop
port engines. That's is loose.
Maintain full power chief.
All the power you've got!
Where's the hell is he going?
Due south!
Heading directly for the African coastline.
Damn it. Damn it.
Ready to dive!
All hands forward!
90 metres quick.
- Bow planes are inaction!
- Switch to manual!
The bow planes is jammed, we cannot dive!
All engines stop.
All men go aft!
Move, move... move!
Pump everything aft.
Auxiliary pump out of action!
Blow forward trim tanks.
Won't pull up!
She's still going down.
Got to shed some weight!
Pump 1000 liters!
... don't you know how to keep him quiet.
Ballast pump out of action.
Permission to blow?
Both engines hard astern full!
No effect!
- Alright blow.
- Blow I said.
Blow 4 ballasts.
Ooh... pull out. Pull out!
Damn you... pull out!
All that you've got, chief.
All you've got.
All that she's got... blow!
Come on up.
We can't hold her.
200.
210.
220 metres.
230.
240.
250 metres.
My God.
Do not turn away from me.
Oh dear lord. Take away...
A shovelful of sand.
The merciful God left a shovelful
of sand to keep us up.
280 metres.
She's still in one piece.
The torpedo hatch is taking water!
Control room... engine one and rising.
Taking water in motor bilge!
Tube 5 taking water!
What do you need?
- Timber for shoring.
- In the bow have it.
Exhaust valve okay?
Leakage plugs! Move!
Give me that flashlight!
I need a wrench, damn it!
Give me damage reports.
Water coming in around the aft area.
Where are the tools?
- Where is it?
- Bilge pump!
Both main motors switch put out of action!
Sir, engines room completely wrecked.
I want some proper damage reports.
Where's the most damage...?
Shafting valves sir. Below the...
Check damage to number two batteries.
Give us a hand.
That bolt, there.
Right underneath should do it.
Can't see! I can't see.
Push! Hard as you can.
It's stuck tight!
Can't get the wedge in!
Here... Give me that hammer!
Need any more men in the aft torpedo room?
I'll ask them again!
Argh.. this damn thing.
Here, hold my light!
- Father... forgive my sins.
- Hey...
Stupid son of a pig!
There's work to do.
- Floods going in the engine room
- Go back!
Hurry up!
Where's that damn wrench?
Bigger wrench!
Here hold the light.
- It's rising.
- Tighten the seals. Don't you...
There's a leak in the cooling system.
Tighten the .... up there. Hurry up!
Hoffman... give me that planks for shoring.
- Plugs down here... quick!
- Hurry up.
- Easy with him.
- Easy men easy.
We're taking water very fast.
The hull valves has burst. Cooling water
system blocked, in the tower vent.
Compressors are dislodged.
Shaft valves beginning to leak, sir.
What about fuel leaks?
Can't tell us yet.
- What else, chief?
The battery cells many of them are cracked.
How many I don't know.
It's red. Acid in the bilge.
- Sublimed of lime quickly.
- See how many cells have cracked.
- Battery straps over here. Move it you.
- Battery straps.
Over here!
I need plugs and a hammer!
- Here.
- Thanks, lieutenant.
Calm down.
Tell the chief.
Water is up to bilge torpedo hatch.
Rising faster.
Careful.
Twelve battery cells drained.
God almighty. What a hell of a mess.
Let's hope these are enough.
Packed the bridge with all of the life
cells. It's our only chance.
Without batteries we've had it.
It's no good. I can't see.
Lieutenant, more lights!
We got to close the leaks or
it's all over for us.
To the right, more to the right.
Wire.
- Get some wire to bridge them.
- Wire...
- Three cells.
- Move it, we need wire. Hurry up.
Wire. The chief needs wire. Get moving.
Look for wire. Did you hear me?
We've got plenty of
fancy torpedos, alright.
Each one is twenty-five thousand marks.
But no damn wire.
All they forget...
is 50 pennies worth of old wire.
The drainage pump jammed, sir.
- Won't even extend manually.
- That's great. Captain...
- Here!
- He's got some wire.
- Terrific... better than nothing.
- Got some wire.
Pliers!
All the leaks have been stopped.
Good, Johann.
That's good.
Now changed your wet things, men.
We must get rid of the water.
Just has to be a way.
Into the control room bilge
and then outside.
Come on. Move it.
Keep the rhythm going.
Step on it! .....
You lazy fat ass, quick.
Three more starboard side.
How does it look now?
Almost finish. Three cells to go, sir.
Make some room out there.
Chief coming through.
All of our compass are out of action.
And we may have lost sonar gear too.
And radio's contact seems bad.
First rate condition.
Can we get out again?
Do you think we have a chance, sir?
Good question.
Some air must be still in the ballast tanks
from the blowing.
Should help us.
If we used every ounce of high pressure,
we'll try.
The boat has to be light.
We've got to get the water out.
Must work. Must work.
Aft is almost bailed.
It could just work.
By hand into the trimming tanks,
then with ballast pump
and high pressure air,
we could forced the water's out.
Ballast pump?
We're fixing it.
Then we gamble on one pump.
One blast and--
Won't be a second chance.
When?
When all repaired are completed.
About 8 hours, sir.
- CO2 content?
- 1.8 percent.
Will the oxygen last?
No.
Emergency issue.
For all men who're working.
Crew off-watch. Turn in.
Will he pull through?
Difficult to say as it is, sir.
Doesn't look good, sir.
Ready to vent, Pilgrim.
Everything okay?
Everything under control sir.
Think we're ready.
How is it looking aft?
We've done what we can, sir.
I guess it's time I look things over.
You should be careful.
Can you make it?
- I'll make it.
- That's great.
Don't worry, captain.
We'll soon be arriving.
How's it going?
Two bearings. Stand to be changed and fix.
Do you want some glucose?
It's a little crazy.
Hauling us through the strait.
It was bound to go wrong.
He knew it.
The old man knew it.
From the moment that
radio signal comes through.
Realised the risk.
The reason he wanted us ashore...
at Vigo.
He knew there wasn't any hope.
He wanted us believe,
quite simple as that.
Easy trick.
"Dive drift with the current and" --
That's a clever trick.
But it has to work.
Will we ever get out of this?
I really don't know.
I'm sorry.
You think it's hopeless now?
It's been 15 hours.
He'll never do it.
I'm sorry.
That we wanted to stay.
"To be heading into the inexorable
where no mother will care for us
no woman crosses our path
where only reality reigns,
with cruelty and grandeur."
Just want someone to be with.
The only thing I feel is afraid.
Reporting sir.
Motors are all done.
The ballast tanks is cleared.
Accumulated water can all be pump
then blown out
with compressed air.
Compass is in order.
Echo sonar clear.
Good, Chief.
Go and take a rest.
Few small problems, sir.
Got to have good men.
An other thing.
Now listen men.
See if we can get our rear end
out of the sand.
At the surface
say your prayers men.
Traffics heavy up there.
And we pray the engines start.
So we can get out of this place.
If the condition about the same
we've got to head straight
to La Rochelle.
If we make it
it's half a bottle of beer for each.
There's one thing on our side...
They won't be expecting us.
Well, men...
- All set?
- Aye, aye!
Surface contact?
Nothing near, captain.
Get ready to surface, standby escape gear.
Switch on to red lights.
Man your stations.
Let it blow.
She's rising!
Easy men! Easy!
270 metres.
First watch, standby.
260 metres.
250 metres.
240 metres.
230 metres.
220.
Hatch is open.
Start up engines?
Both main engines.
Well, this is it boys.
Get going...
Yes chief.... it's going!
Never heard such sweet music
in all my life.
They won't catch us this time.
Not this time!
Just you keep on going and get us back.
It's an order!
Right full rudder. Turn to 320.
That's good!
They haven't spotted us.
They're all snoring in their bunks.
Oh, you know what?
They're drinking at the bar,
celebrating our sinking!
Drink up, boys! Here's to getting home!
Let's pray the engines hold out.
With a bit of luck it might.
We'll make it back home.
The 3rd Submarine Flotilla welcomes
our returning sailors with 3 cheers.
Both engines stop.
Stern line up.
We Build For Victory!
- Thanks you, Hinrich.
- It's okay.
Sun's shining out there.
Up with him.
All right? Already there.
Make a way. Wounded man coming ashore.