Random thoughts
for Valentine's Day, 2004.
Today is a holiday invented
by greeting-card companies
to make people feel like crap.
I ditched work today.
Took a train out to Montauk.
I don't know why.
I'm not an impulsive person.
I guess I just woke up
in a funk this morning.
I gotta get my car fixed.
Hi, Cindy. It's Joel.
Listen, I don't feel
very well today.
No, food poisoning, I think.
It's goddamn freezing
on this beach.
Montauk in February.
Brilliant, Joel.
Pages ripped out.
Don't remember doing that.
It appears this is
my first entry in two years.
Sand is overrated.
It's just tiny little rocks.
If only I could meet
someone new.
I guess my chances
of that happening
are somewhat diminished,
since I'm incapable of making eye contact
with a woman I don't know.
Maybe I should get back together
with Naomi. She was nice.
Nice is good.
She loved me.
Why do I fall in love
with every woman I see
who shows me
the least bit of attention?
Hi.
- I'm sorry?
- I just said hi.
Hi, hello.
Okay if I sit closer?
How far are you going?
Rockville Center.
Get out. Me, too.
Really?
What are the odds?
Listen, do I know you?
Do you ever shop
at Barnes and Noble?
Sure.
- That's it!
- Yeah?
I've seen you, man.
Book slave there
for five years now.
Jesus!
I would have thought
I would remember you.
It might be the hair.
What might?
It changes a lot, the color.
That's why you might
not recognize me.
- It's called Blue Ruin.
- Right.
The color.
Snappy name, huh?
I like it.
This company makes a whole line
of colors with equally snappy names.
You've got Red Menace,
Yellow Fever, Green Revolution.
That would be a job,
coming up with those names.
You think there could
possibly be a job like that?
I mean, how many hair colors
could there be? 15 maybe?
Someone's got that job.
Agent Orange.
I came up with that one.
I apply my personality
in a paste.
I doubt that very much.
Well, you don't know me,
so you don't know, do you?
I'm sorry.
I was just trying to be nice.
Yeah. I got it.
My name's Clementine,
by the way.
I'm Joel.
Hi, Joel.
No jokes about my name.
Oh, no.
You wouldn't do that.
You're trying to be nice.
I don't know any jokes
about your name.
Huckleberry Hound.
I don't know what that means.
Huckleberry Hound?
What are you, nuts?
It's been suggested.
Oh, my darling, oh, my darling,
oh, my darling Clementine
You are lost and gone forever,
dreadful sorry, Clementine
No?
I'm sorry.
It's a pretty name, though.
It really is nice.
It means merciful, right?
Clemency?
Although it hardly fits.
I'm a vindictive little bitch,
truth be told.
I wouldn't think that about you.
Why wouldn't you think that
about me?
I don't know.
You seem nice.
Now I'm nice?
Oh, God, don't you know
any other adjectives?
I don't need nice.
I don't need myself to be it
and I don't need anybody
to be it at me.
Okay.
It's Joel, right?
Yes.
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
I'm a little out of sorts today.
My embarrassing admission
is I really like that
you're nice right now.
I can't tell from one moment to
the next what I'm going to like,
but right now I'm glad you are.
I have some stuff
that I probably should...
- I'm writing...
- I'm sorry. Okay.
- No.
- Sure. That's okay.
Take care, then.
Jesus.
I could give you a ride
if you need.
It's cold.
Yeah! Okay. It is frosty.
You're not a stalker
or anything, right?
I'm not a stalker. You're the one
that talked to me, remember?
That is the oldest trick
in the stalker book.
Really?
There's a stalker book?
I've got to read that one.
Look, I'm sorry
if I came off sort of nutso.
I'm not really.
That's okay.
I didn't think you were.
Do you want to have a drink?
I have lots of drinks,
and I could...
Never mind. Sorry, that was stupid.
I'm embarrassed now.
Good night, Joel.
Two Blue Ruins.
Thank you.
Drink up, young man.
It'll make the whole seduction
part less repugnant.
I'm just kidding!
Come on.
You're kind of close-mouthed,
aren't you?
I'm sorry.
You know, my life isn't
that interesting.
I go to work, I come home.
I don't know what to say.
You should read my journal.
I mean, it's just blank.
Really? Does that
make you sad or anxious?
I'm always anxious, thinking
I'm not living my life to the fullest.
Taking advantage
of every possibility
and making sure I'm not wasting
one second of the little time I have.
- I think about that.
- Yeah?
You're really nice.
God, I have to stop saying that.
I'm gonna marry you.
I know it.
Okay.
Joel, you should come up
to the Charles with me sometime.
It gets frozen
this time of year.
- That sounds scary.
- Exactly.
I'll pack a picnic,
a night picnic.
Night picnics are different.
That sounds good.
But I should go now.
You should stay.
No, I really have...
I have to get up so early and...
I would like you to call me.
Would you do that?
I'd like it.
Yes.
Wish me a happy Valentine's Day
when you call.
That'd be nice.
What took you so long?
I just walked in.
You miss me?
Oddly enough, I do.
You said "I do".
I guess that means we're married.
I guess so.
Tomorrow night?
Honeymoon on ice?
It's really solid
this time of year.
- I don't know.
- Come on.
It's so beautiful.
Isn't it?
Don't go too far.
Are you okay?
Oh, my ass!
- I think I should go back.
- Come on!
But what if it breaks?
"What if?"
Do you really care right now?
Come here, please.
Slidey-slidey.
This looks good.
Let me show you this one thing.
What are you doing?
Come on.
Think I heard a crack.
It's not going to crack,
or break.
It's so thick.
Show me which constellations
you know.
I don't know any.
Show me which ones you know.
Okay.
There's Osidius.
Where?
Right there. See?
A sort of a swoop and a cross.
Osidius the Emphatic.
You're full of shit, right?
No. Osidius, right there.
Swoop and a cross.
Shut the fuck up!
Cock-a-doodle-doo.
Sorry to wake you,
but we're here.
Can I come over to your house,
to sleep? I'm so tired.
Okay. Yeah, sure.
Let me get my toothbrush.
Yes?
Can I help you?
What do you mean?
Can I help you with something?
No.
What are you doing here?
I'm not really sure
what you're asking me.
Thanks.
We're looking for 159.
What number is that?
I don't know
what number that is.
Jesus Christ. You'd think
they'd light the number
or at least put a number on...
- Is that him?
- I think so.
Yeah, that's him.
That's him.
- Hey, Joel.
- Frank.
Shit.
Jesus. The only Valentine's Day cards
I get are from my mother.
How pathetic is that?
You're lucky you have Clementine.
She is way cool.
You got any big Valentine's Day
plans with her?
No.
It's only a day away.
Better make some reservations or something.
Don't want to end up
at Mickey D's, right?
McRomance!
You want some fries
with that shake?
I have to go to sleep now,
Frank.
It's 8:30.
Patrick, stop it.
Okay.
Showtime at the Apollo.
Quiet.
Get it off your head.
Hey, Joel.
What's up?
Hi, Frank.
I only get Valentine's Day cards
from my mom. How pathetic is that?
You're lucky
you have Clementine, Joel.
You got any big Valentine's Day
plans with her?
No.
It's only a day away.
Better make a reservation somewhere.
Don't want to end up
at Mickey D's.
- Oh, no.
- Yes.
Valentine's Day is three days away.
I want it resolved.
I'm willing to be the one
to resolve it.
So I call her, and
she's changed her number.
So I walked over to Antic Attic
to get her something.
I thought I'd go over to work,
give her an early Valentine.
And you won't believe it.
She's there with this guy,
this really young guy.
And she looks at me like
she doesn't even know who I am.
Excuse me?
Can I help you
find something, sir?
Hey, Clem-ato.
Patrick! Baby boy!
What are you doing here, baby?
Just came to surprise you.
Let me know
if you need something, sir.
How are you?
Pretty good, pretty bored,
pretty tired.
- I so want what's in your suit.
- Good.
Why would she do that to me?
Does anybody want a joint?
God, Rob, give it a rest.
- God, she's punishing me.
- I know.
- For being honest.
- It's horrible.
- I should just go to her house.
- No.
You don't want to go there, man.
- Get off me. It's too...
- Right.
- Yeah.
- I don't want to seem desperate.
Joel, why don't you
just see this as a sign?
Make a clean break. Right?
All right, Joel.
Look, man, seriously,
here's the deal.
Don't do that.
Rob, what are you doing?
What's your fucking suggestion?
What's your brilliant,
reasoned solution?
You're making this
about our shit now?
- This isn't about us.
- I agree.
It's not about us.
It's about Joel, who's an adult, okay?
Not Mama Carrie's kid.
Why don't you go
do your laundry?
That's great.
That's good.
Okay.
- What is it?
- I don't know.
It's some place
that does a thing.
Good morning. Lacuna.
No, I'm sorry. That offer
expired after the New Year.
Yeah, sure.
We can fit you in...
How about on the 5th?
That's a Wednesday.
All right, great.
Could you spell that, please?
Okay, and we'll need
a daytime phone number.
Great. Have a nice day.
See you then.
May I help you?
- I'm Joel Barish.
- Excuse me?
I'm Joel Barish.
I have an appointment
with Doctor...
Mierzwiak.
Here, can you please fill this out?
I just want to talk to him.
You still need to
fill the form out, sir.
- All right.
- Thank you.
I don't have a pen.
There's a pen right there.
Good morning. Lacuna.
Yeah, that offer,
that's done now.
That expired after the New Year.
Mr. Barish?
How are we today?
Not too good, actually.
Oh, my God! Stan!
Sorry, I was just...
I'm working.
- Here, Doctor.
- Thank you.
You should not have seen this.
I apologize.
This is a hoax, right?
I mean, this is Clem's...
- I assure you, no.
- No.
There's no such thing as this.
Look, our files are
confidential, Mr. Barish,
so I can't show you evidence.
Suffice it to say
that Miss Kruczynski
was not happy
and she wanted to move on.
We provide that possibility.
"We provide that possibility."
What the hell is that?
I'm the nicest guy
she ever went out with.
Fuck!
Rob, give it a rest!
It's okay.
It's all right.
Carrie, I am making a birdhouse.
What can I say? You know,
Clementine's just like that.
She's impulsive.
She decided to erase you
almost as a lark.
A lark?
Why did you do that?
Don't. Wait.
I'm sorry, Doctor,
he just barged right in here.
Okay. I want it done.
I told him pre-Valentine's Day
is our busy time...
That's okay, Mary.
But there are people waiting.
Mr. Barish,
if you'd like to come inside.
- If you'd take care of Mrs. Woo.
- Yes, of course.
Goodbye, Mrs. Woo.
The first thing we need
you to do, Mr. Barish,
is to go home and collect
everything you own
that has some association
with Clementine.
Anything.
We'll use these items
to create a map of Clementine
in your brain, okay?
We'll need photos,
clothing, gifts, books
she may have bought you,
CDs you may have bought
together, journal entries.
We want to empty your home,
we want to empty your life
of Clementine.
And after the mapping is done,
our technicians will do the erasing
in your home tonight.
That way, when
you awake in the morning,
you'll find yourself
in your own bed
as if nothing had happened,
a new life awaiting you.
Wake up, buddy!
I'm sorry, Mrs. Sobel.
You can't have the procedure
done three times in one month.
It's just not our policy here.
How are you today,
Mr. Barish?
Hello, I'm right here.
I know it's an emergency.
We'll do everything we can.
We can fit you in on March 1.
Maybe you could talk
to the doctor and...
All right, so let's make
an appointment.
What day would you like
to come in this week?
- Mr. Barish.
- He's really busy this afternoon.
Maybe tomorrow would be better,
around 12:15.
Can you do that?
February is very busy for us
because of Valentine's Day.
This is Stan Fink, one of our most
experienced and skilled technicians.
He'll be handling
your case tonight.
Great to meet you, Mr. Barish.
My name is Joel Barish,
and I'm here to erase
Clementine Kruczynski.
Very good.
Now tell me about Clementine.
I was living with this woman,
Naomi,
a couple years ago.
And my friends, Rob and Carrie,
invited us to this party
at the beach.
I don't like parties.
Naomi couldn't go, but I went
and I met Clementine.
I'm sorry.
We'll start with your
most recent memories
and work backwards from there,
more or less.
There's an emotional core
to each of our memories,
and when you eradicate
that core,
it starts its
degradation process.
By the time you wake up
in the morning,
all the memories we've targeted
will have withered and disappeared.
As in a dream upon waking.
Is there any risk
of brain damage?
Technically speaking,
the procedure is brain damage.
But it's on a par with
a night of heavy drinking.
Nothing you'll miss.
Comfortable?
What we're doing here,
Mr. Barish,
is actually creating a map
of your brain.
Okay, let's get started.
If we want to get this procedure
underway tonight,
we have some work to do.
I want you to react to these
objects, Mr. Barish, if you will.
There's a good story
behind that...
Actually, Mr. Barish, I'll get
a much better emotional read-out
if you refrain from any sort of
verbal description of the items.
Just please try to focus
on the memories.
I'm sorry.
Healthy activity up there again.
Healthy read-outs.
Very good.
Here's another object.
Next item.
Potato head.
Just focus on the memories.
Patrick, do me a favor.
Patrick,
do me a favor, will you?
Can you check the voltage regulator?
What have we got there?
- Voltage looks fine.
- Really?
I'm not wiping
as clean as I like here.
Technically,
the procedure is brain damage.
But it's on a par with
a night of heavy drinking.
Check the connections, please.
There you are.
What am I...
I don't understand
what I'm looking at.
Why am I standing here...
Oh, my God, déjà vu.
- This is so...
- We should get started.
If we want to get the procedure
underway tonight,
we have some work to do.
I'm in my head already,
aren't I?
I suppose so.
This is about right.
This is what it would look like.
Very good.
We'll dispose of these mementos
when we're done here.
That way you won't
be confused later
by their unexplainable
presence in your home.
There we go. Patrick?
Patrick?
Why are there so many wires?
Because we have
a lot of equipment.
Does that help?
Are you sure you set
that thing up properly?
- How's that?
- How are you today, Mr. Barish?
- There we are, Mr. Barish.
- All right, that's better.
I don't know if I like this.
I think I might try this then.
We're almost done now.
Your journal.
That'll be invaluable.
I met someone tonight.
I don't know what to do.
Her name is Clementine
and she's amazing.
Jesus!
- What?
- Come on, careful! Step back!
Just take it easy.
It's fine.
Let's not roach the guy.
All right.
We got that one.
This place is sort of a dump,
don't you think?
It's an apartment, Patrick.
Well, not a dump then,
but sort of plain.
Uninspired.
And there's sort
of a stale smell.
Can we just please
get through this?
We've got a long night
ahead of us.
This is the last time I saw you.
It's 3:00.
I kind of,
sort of wrecked your car.
Driving drunk.
It's pathetic.
I was a little tipsy.
Don't call me pathetic!
It is pathetic.
It's fucking irresponsible.
You could have killed somebody.
Maybe you did kill somebody.
Should we turn on the news and see?
Should I check the grille to see
if there's children or small animals?
It's just a fucking dent.
You're like an old lady or something.
What are you like?
- A wino?
- A "wino"? Jesus.
Are you from the '50s
or something? A "wino"?
Face it, Joely.
You're freaked out because
I was out late without you.
And in your little, wormy brain,
you're trying to figure out,
"Did she fuck
someone tonight?"
Now, see, Clem, I assume
you fucked someone tonight.
Isn't that how you get
people to like you?
I'm sorry, okay?
Clem, I didn't mean it,
all right?
Your keys.
I won't need them anymore.
I was just angry or annoyed
or something. I don't know.
Got it.
Mary's coming over tonight.
Just thought you'd want to know.
I like Mary.
I like when she comes to visit.
I don't think she likes me.
She likes you okay.
So maybe I should invite
my girlfriend over.
I have a girlfriend now.
Do whatever you want.
Did I tell you...
Did I tell you
I have a new girlfriend?
We gotta focus here, Patrick.
The thing is,
my situation is a little weird.
My girlfriend situation.
I'm sure it is.
You've got to be...
Clem, let me drive you home.
Get out of my face, faggot!
Look at it out here!
It's all falling apart!
I'm erasing you, and I'm happy!
You did it to me first!
I can't believe you did this to me!
God damn it!
Did you hear me?
By morning you'll be gone!
The perfect ending
to this piece-of-shit story!
Is there something wrong with
a girl being attracted to me?
- Is that a problem?
- No, I think it's funny.
Who do you think's better-looking,
me or this guy?
Patrick, let's focus, buddy.
Remember that girl
we did last week?
The one with the potatoes?
That girl?
Yeah, that's this guy's girl.
Right, was.
We took care of that.
I kind of fell in love
with her that night.
What? You little fuck.
What?
She was unconscious, man.
She was beautiful.
I stole a pair of her panties,
as well.
Jesus!
What? It's not like...
I mean, they were clean and all.
Don't tell me this.
I don't want to hear this shit.
- They were clean.
- What? Don't. Stop.
- Okay, all right.
- We've got work to do.
Hold my papers.
There's more.
After we did her,
I kind of asked her out.
What?
Jesus.
...how unethical...
It's not really that bad.
Get that look off your face.
What's wrong?
Patrick, you stole
a girl's panties.
There's someone here.
He stole your underwear.
I don't see anyone.
Joel, where are my boots?
Now, why are you
showing me poisons?
Can't you understand English?
Potions, I said. Potions.
Love potion, please.
I'm fucking crawling
out of my skin!
I should have left you
at the flea market.
Want to go?
I want to have a baby.
Let's talk about it later.
No. I want to have a baby.
I don't think we're ready.
You're not ready.
Clem, do you really think
you could take care of a kid?
What?
I don't want to
talk about it here.
I can't hear you.
I can never the fuck understand
what you're saying.
I said I don't want to
talk about this!
We're fucking gonna
talk about it!
You can't just say that and say
you don't wanna talk about it.
- I'm sorry.
- I'd make a fucking good mother.
I love children.
I'm creative, I'm smart, and
I'd make a fucking great mother!
It's you, Joel.
It's you who can't
commit to anything.
It's going.
You've no idea how lucky you are
I'm interested in you.
I don't even know why I am.
Maybe I should end it right here!
Leave you at the flea market
with the stupid costume jewelry!
Maybe you can find a nice
antique rocking chair to die in!
- Hi, Patrick.
- Hi, Mary, how's it going?
- Hey, you.
- It's freezing outside.
Did you find us okay?
Yeah.
Hot.
Poor guy.
Don't you have
anything real to drink?
We haven't checked yet.
Let me do the honors.
Mary hates me.
Never really had
much luck with the ladies.
Maybe if you stopped
stealing their panties.
- There's more.
- No.
- Yes.
You didn't want any,
did you, Patrick?
No, I don't know.
That's okay.
Wait.
"Blessed are the forgetful,
for they get the better
even of their blunders."
That's Nietzsche.
Beyond Good and Evil.
I found it in my Bartlett's.
What's your Bartlett's?
It's a quote book, Patrick.
It's a book of quotations.
I think Howard will be
in Bartlett's one day.
Definitely.
Howard is pure Bartlett's.
Can you wake him up?
You can't wake him up.
You don't tell me things, Joel.
I'm an open book.
I tell you everything.
Every damn embarrassing thing.
You don't trust me.
Constantly talking isn't
necessarily communicating.
I don't do that.
I want to know you.
I don't constantly talk.
Jesus.
People have to share things,
Joel.
That's what intimacy is.
I'm really pissed
that you said that to me.
I'm sorry.
My life just isn't
that interesting.
I wanna read some of those journals
you're constantly scribbling in.
What do you write if you don't have
any thoughts or passions or love?
November 19, 2003.
Dinner at Kang's again.
Are we like those poor couples
you feel sorry for
in restaurants?
Are we the dining dead?
I can't stand the idea of us being
a couple people think that about.
I like that.
How's the chicken?
Good.
- More?
- No, thank you.
She's going to be
drunk and stupid now.
Would you do me a favor and clean
the goddamn hair off the soap
when you're done in the shower?
- It's really...
- Yeah.
- It's gross.
- Gross.
- I think it's just...
- Repulsive.
It's repulsive.
Patrick,
can we get through this?
Hey, Tangerine.
Patrick, it's you.
I'm so miserable right now.
Why? What's wrong?
I don't know. I'm just
confused about everything.
Confused?
What are you confused about?
Everything's fine.
Do you love me?
Of course I do.
Where's the self-help section?
Do you think I'm ugly?
No. You're beautiful.
- Maybe I should come over.
- No. I don't know.
I'm a mess, Patrick.
Just let me come over.
I'll cheer you up.
Okay.
Can I leave for a while?
My girlfriend's really upset.
We're right in the middle
of erasing this poor man's...
Let him go, Stan.
I'll help.
- See?
- How hard can it be?
She hates me.
She wants me to go.
Go.
All right.
I'll be right over, Tangerine.
You like?
I matched my sweatshirt exactly.
- I like it.
- You do?
You look like a tangerine.
Clementine the tangerine.
Juicy and seedless.
I like that.
I like tangerines.
Can you see me doing ducks?
Tangerine.
How does he know
to call you that?
How did who know?
- Oh, my God. Clem?
- This is pretty cool.
That's what
they called themselves.
The Clash,
the only band that mattered.
And they called themselves
that for a reason.
- It's amazing, isn't it?
- Like social justice.
Yeah, it's totally incredible.
What Howard gives to the world.
Yeah.
To let people begin again.
It's beautiful.
You look at a baby,
and it's so pure and so free
and so clean.
Adults are this mess of sadness
and phobias.
And Howard
just makes it all go away.
Baby, what's going on?
I don't know.
I'm lost, I'm scared,
I feel like I'm disappearing.
My skin's coming off!
I'm getting old!
Nothing makes any sense to me!
You're not getting old.
Nothing makes any sense.
Tangerine.
It's okay.
Let's go out dancing.
You want to go out
to Montauk with me?
Montauk?
No, come up to Boston with me.
Sure. We can go next weekend.
No, now. I have to go now.
I have to see
the frozen Charles now.
Hi, it's Joel.
Leave a message after the beep
and I'll get back to you.
Pick up.
Hello? What's up?
I got into a little situation
with the old lady.
Can you handle things tonight
alone? I'm really sorry.
Don't worry about it.
I've got it under control.
He's pretty much
on auto-pilot now, anyway.
Thanks.
I owe you big-time.
Dude, I got to go.
Look. You and me
on the Charles River.
I could die right now, Clem.
I'm just happy.
I've never felt that before.
I'm exactly where I want...
I'm so excited.
I'm excited, too.
Cool.
I got you this thing.
- Happy early Valentine's Day.
- Thank you.
What is it?
I don't know. Open it up.
It's gorgeous.
- You like it?
- It's just my taste, really.
God, I've never gone out with a guy
who bought me jewelry I liked.
Thank you.
- Let's go.
- Okay.
- Joely?
- Yeah, Tangerine?
Am I ugly?
When I was a kid,
I thought I was.
Can't believe
I'm crying already.
Sometimes I think
people don't understand
how lonely it is to be a kid.
Like you don't matter.
So, I'm eight,
and I have these toys,
these dolls.
My favorite is this ugly girl doll
who I call Clementine.
And I keep yelling at her,
"You can't be ugly.
Be pretty."
It's weird.
Like if I can transform her,
I would magically change, too.
You're pretty.
Don't ever leave me.
Mierzwiak, please
let me keep this memory.
Just this one.
I don't want to hold
your hand. Come on.
Stop it!
I could die right now.
I'm just so happy.
I've never felt that before.
I'm just exactly
where I want to be.
I want to call it off.
I'll give you a sign.
Can you hear me? I don't want
this anymore! I want to call it off!
Is anybody there?
- What?
- We've got to go.
- Where?
- I have an idea of how to stop this.
Stop what?
Don't tickle me. No.
Smell my pits!
Concentrate, Clem.
- We have to get back to the office.
- Halloween.
There was a tape recorder.
No, not the picture.
Back here. Come on.
Look at me.
I want to go there.
Our files are confidential,
so I can't show you evidence.
Suffice it to say
that Miss Kruczynski
was not happy and
she wanted to move on.
Tell me about...
Tell me everything you remember.
That's what he said.
What did we see that day?
- We're going to see my grandma.
- Shit!
- Joel, why...
- No. We're not going on a train.
Joel, please.
Don't make me run anymore.
Come on.
Mierzwiak!
Do we always have to run?
Please?
Why don't we begin by you telling me
everything you can remember...
Mierzwiak, wake me up!
I'm sorry, Mr. Barish, I thought
you understood what was going on.
You're erasing her from me.
You're erasing me from her.
You got this thing.
I'm in my bed. I know it.
I'm in my brain.
I'm part of
your imagination, too.
How can I help you from there?
I'm inside your head, too.
I'm you.
Sorry.
Look, who's that?
He works for us.
That's Patrick,
baby boy.
He's stealing my identity.
He stole my stuff.
He's seducing my girlfriend
with my words and my things.
He stole her underwear.
Jesus Christ.
I could die right now, Clem.
I'm just happy.
I've never felt that before.
I'm exactly where I want to be.
I want to go home.
What?
Wait, Clem.
Clem, they're erasing you.
Over here!
Clem, focus.
I hired them, okay?
I'm sorry. I'm so stupid.
Sweetie, calm down.
Enjoy the scenery.
I need it to stop before I wake up
and don't know you anymore.
Just tell them
to cancel it then.
What the hell are you
talking about?
I can't just cancel it.
I'm asleep.
Wake yourself up!
Okay, you want me
to wake up? All right.
Okay, here we go.
Will it make you happy if I try?
- Yeah.
- I'll try really hard.
Here we go.
That was a great idea.
That's working like gangbusters.
Don't!
That tickles me!
- What the hell is that?
- It's a birthmark!
It did work, for a second.
- But I couldn't...
- See?
I couldn't move.
Isn't that just another one
of Joel's self-fulfilling prophecies?
It's more important to prove me
wrong than to actually...
I don't want to discuss this
right now, okay?
Fine.
Then what? I'm listening.
I don't know.
You erased me.
That's why I'm here
and doing this.
I'm sorry.
You know me, I'm impulsive.
That's what I love about you.
I have another idea
for this problem.
This is a memory of me.
The way you wanted
to have sex on the couch
after you look down
at my crotch.
The eraser guys are coming,
so what if you take me
somewhere else,
somewhere where I don't belong,
and we hide there till morning?
I can't remember anything
without you.
- That's very sweet, but try, okay?
- Okay.
Row, row, row your boat,
gently down the stream
Merrily, merrily, merrily, merrily,
life is but a dream
It's working.
I'm a genius.
Where did you go?
I'm supposed to come, too!
I'm just gonna go
get a salad bowl.
Can you stir the soup
and keep an eye on Joel?
He likes to be near me.
Absolutely.
It worked.
My God, look at this.
It worked!
Look at this dress, man.
I wish I could take it with me.
- Who am I?
- Mrs. Hamlyn.
Right. Mrs. Hamlyn.
I must be about four.
Oh, my gosh.
Found the salad bowl.
I'm serving salad and string beans.
Is he okay under there?
Honey, are you all right?
I feel like I could
clean up all clay.
Would you hate me if I asked you
to clean some string beans?
No, not at all.
God, I love this kitchen.
Thank you so much.
She's not looking at me.
She's busy.
No one ever looks at me.
I want my mommy.
Oh, baby Joel.
Is every little peanut
under there okay?
He's fine.
Do you have something to drink?
How about a cocktail?
I know it's not 5:00...
I would die for a vodka.
Let me check if I have that.
Okay, I'm just going
to wait right here.
No, sweetie. Joely?
Your mother wants me to mind you.
Get back under the table.
Ice cream.
No, not until after
you've had your dinner.
Come on! Grow up.
Don't leave me, Clem.
Oh, my God.
No, I'm right here.
This is sort of warped.
I'm scared.
I want my mommy.
Don't cry, baby Joel.
It's okay.
Joel, stop it! I think it's working.
We're hidden, Joel. Look!
Honey, look.
Wait there.
My crotch is still here,
just as you remembered it.
Yuck.
- It stopped.
- What?
It stopped erasing.
Oh, shit!
This is terrible.
He's off the map.
- Where?
- I don't know where.
This is very bad news.
Where are my glasses?
Crap! What did we do?
What do I do?
- What shall we do?
- I don't know what to do.
- I just said, I don't know.
I'm sorry.
What shall we do?
I don't know. Mellow out.
You're freaking me out.
We have to do something.
He could wake up all half-baked.
- Quiet. You're freaking me out.
- All gooey and half-baked.
That sounds so good.
I'm hungry.
Oh, shit. What?
We should call Howard.
No way. No sir, man.
This is my... I can handle this.
You can't call Howard.
There's no time to fuck around.
I've got this under control.
What are you talking about?
Stop fucking around.
Okay. I'll call Howard.
Hello?
Howard, it's Stan. I'm working
on this guy down here.
We've lost him for a moment,
and I can't bring him back up.
Okay, tell me what happened
before he disappeared.
I wasn't sure because I was away
from the monitor for a minute,
and I had it on auto-pilot
because I had to pee.
Where was Patrick?
He had to go home sick.
What's the address?
I know, I'm so sorry.
That's okay. Come on.
We're at 159 South Village.
Apartment 1-E.
Rockville Center.
Mary, he's coming right now.
I'm staying.
Get your stuff, Mary.
I think you should go.
No.
I am so stoned.
Please, Mary, you have to go.
Stop being stoned.
I don't want him to see me stoned.
You have no idea how much trouble
I'll get into if Howard comes...
Joel, stop. Look.
I want her to pick me up.
Weird how strong that desire is.
Joel, look at me.
You'll remember me in the morning,
you'll come to me, you'll tell me
about us, and we'll start over.
Pat? I thought we could
have a little cocktail.
That Patrick guy,
he's copying me.
What Patrick guy?
- That guy.
- What?
He's here, in my apartment.
One of the eraser guys. He fell
for you when they were doing you,
and now he's introduced himself
like he doesn't even know you,
- and you guys are dating.
- Really?
Is he cute?
There's nothing wrong with you.
You're the most wonderful
person I've ever met.
You're kind, beautiful,
smart, funny, and nice.
What?
Okay, all right.
- Move. Come on, let's go.
- Careful.
I'm still stoned.
Those eye drops
you gave me didn't do shit.
Be cool.
Hello, Mary,
what are you doing here?
Hi, Howard. She was
just here to help out.
I wanted to understand as much
about the procedure as possible.
I think it's important for my job
to understand the inner workings
of the work that we do.
Not that I do,
but the work that is done
by people where I also work.
The work of my colleagues.
Let's see if we can get
to the bottom of this, shall we?
That's odd.
I already tried that.
You tried going
through the C-gate?
Of course.
I mean, yes.
All right.
- You want to get linked up?
- Yeah.
I ran the utility programs,
and I had nothing there,
so I checked all the memories
against the printed logs.
- Here, Howard, I got you a chair.
- Thank you.
There you go.
You're welcome.
All right.
I've got it.
I'll go through
the entire memory,
see if something comes up.
I love being bathed in the sink.
Such a feeling of security.
I've never seen you happier,
baby Joel.
There it is.
I don't understand why
it's off the map like that.
What the heck
was he doing there?
His eyes are open.
- Has this happened before with him?
- No.
This is not good.
I'm going to have
to give him this.
Can't you see
I love you, Antoine?
Okay, we're back in.
That was beautiful to watch, Howard,
like a surgeon or a concert pianist.
Thank you, Mary.
Howard, you should get some sleep.
I think I'll be fine now.
Can't you see I love you,
Antoine?
Lucky me. Lay one on me.
Don't call me Antoine.
My name is Wally.
Yes, I know, but how can a woman
love a man with a name like Wally?
What was that?
My God, there's people
coming out of your butt.
There is?
Got it.
Tangerine! Come on.
We've got to go.
Go on. Please go.
You can run, but you can't hide.
Clem, come on!
There I am.
That truck.
Doc? Please!
Let's begin by you telling me
everything you remember...
That's strange. He's in a memory
that we've already erased.
At least we know where he is.
He's back on track, right?
Come on, Clem.
He's developed some sort
of resistance to the procedure.
I don't want to run anymore.
Shit.
Come on.
Hide me somewhere deeper,
somewhere really buried.
- Where?
- Hide me in your humiliation.
Humiliation.
Come on, you big baby.
No!
- Bye, Howard.
- Wait.
He's disappeared again.
Oh, dear.
I'm so sorry, Howard.
Humiliation.
I don't like it, either. I'm trying
to find horrible secret places to...
Honey, I have a surprise.
You know what?
I'll just ask you in the morning.
Good night.
- I'm sorry.
- Shut up.
Look.
Joel, look where we are.
This isn't good.
Then hide me somewhere
really buried.
Hit it, Joel!
I can't, I've got to go home.
I'll do it later!
He has a girlfriend.
Wait, what am I doing?
Freddy, you don't scare me anymore.
Joely, get up.
Come on, it's not worth it.
They're not worth it, Joel.
He's not listening!
Come on.
Stupid!
I'm so ashamed.
It's okay. You were a little kid.
Come on.
That's where I live, lived.
I wish I knew you
when I was a kid.
Do you like my pink hat?
Here, look, feel better.
You can really kill me
this time. It's my turn. Go.
You're really going to die,
though, okay?
One, two, three.
You're dead.
My mom.
It's okay, we're playing.
It's not real.
He's killing me.
Are you dead yet?
You're dead!
I think I got the hang of this.
I still don't understand it,
but I'm finding him
quickly enough.
Are you okay?
Oh, my God, that was terrible.
Almost three seconds.
Let's do it one more time.
One more and then I get to go.
This is so cool!
Look out!
It's fluff.
Our house.
Wait, we've got to go.
Come on.
This is a really bad time
for this.
I don't even know
where we're going.
It's going to be fun.
It's the best place.
- No, this way.
- This way. Come on.
You're no help at all.
Come on.
Let go of me, Joel.
I like watching you work,
Howard.
I guess I'll go out
for some air,
if nobody minds.
It looks like you have
everything under control here.
Yeah, that's fine.
Do you like quotes, Howard?
What do you mean?
Like famous quotes.
I find reading them
inspirational,
and in my reading, I've come across
some I thought you might like, too.
I'd love to hear some.
There's one that goes,
"Blessed are the forgetful,
for they get the better
even of their blunders".
- That's Nietzsche, right?
- Yeah.
I thought I could tell you
something you didn't know.
No, it's a good quote.
I'm happy we both know it.
There's this other one I like.
It's by Pope Alexander
and it goes...
Alexander Pope?
Oh, yeah. Shit.
It's just that I told myself
not to say "Pope Alexander"
and sound like a dope,
and then I go ahead and say it.
- It's no big deal.
- You're such a sweetheart.
The quote goes, "How happy
is the blameless vestal's lot!"
"The world forgetting
by the world forgot"
"Eternal sunshine
of the spotless mind!"
"Each prayer accepted
and each wish resigned."
I want to be a great,
big, huge elephant.
With a huge trunk like that.
I haven't heard that one.
It's lovely.
I just thought it would
be appropriate, maybe.
I really admire the work you do.
I don't mean to be
so familiar...
It's fine.
I'm happy to hear...
I'm sorry.
I've loved you
for a very long time.
I shouldn't have said that.
Mary, you're a wonderful girl.
But, you know,
I have a wife and kids.
Mary, we can't do this.
Good morning,
Mrs. Mierzwiak.
- What? Who is it?
- Oh, my God.
Thank you, Stan.
Thanks a lot.
Hollis!
Wait.
I knew it, Howard.
It didn't start out like this.
I came here to work.
This is a one-time mistake.
I'm a stupid girl with a crush.
I basically forced him into it.
Don't be a monster.
Tell the girl.
Tell me what?
Oh, you poor kid.
You can have him.
You did.
What?
We have a history.
I'm sorry.
You wanted the procedure.
You wanted it done
so you could get past...
I have to finish the work in there.
It's almost morning.
We'll talk later, okay?
Let me give you a lift home.
Didn't figure you'd show
your face around me again.
I thought you were humiliated.
You did run away, after all.
I just needed to see you.
Yeah?
I'd like to
take you out or something.
You're married.
Not yet. Not married.
No, I'm not married.
Look, I'm telling you right off the bat,
I'm high maintenance,
so I'm not gonna tiptoe
around your marriage
or whatever it is
you've got going there.
If you want to be with me,
you're with me.
Okay.
Too many guys think
I'm a concept, or I complete them
or I'm gonna make them alive.
I'm just a fucked-up girl who's
looking for my own peace of mind.
Don't assign me yours.
I remember that speech
really well.
I had you pegged, didn't I?
Had the whole human race pegged.
Probably.
I still thought you were
going to save my life.
Even after that.
I know.
It would be different,
if we could just
give it another go-round.
Remember me.
Try your best.
Maybe we can.
Just tell me what you remember,
and we'll take it from there.
I liked you immediately.
You didn't come on to me at all.
I liked that.
I was so tongue-tied
around you at first,
but I wanted you to think
I was smart.
I couldn't wait to come to work.
I had these fantasies of us
being married and having kids...
Howie, I can't do this.
We agreed it's
for the best, Mary.
Yeah, I know.
Oh, God!
I'll take the bottom and you...
No, Joel, help me with that.
Will you get the cooler?
Honey, the cooler's pretty...
She can get it.
Let me get that.
No, no, no.
Don't take anything.
I can take the plane.
Put the gate back up.
This is the day we met.
You were by the surf. I could
just make you out in the distance.
I remember being drawn
to you, even then.
I thought,
"Wow, how odd!"
"I'm drawn to someone's back."
You were in that
orange sweatshirt
that I would come to know so well,
and even hate, eventually.
But at the time I thought,
"How cool, an orange sweatshirt."
Hi, there.
Hi.
I saw you sitting
over here by yourself,
and I thought, "Thank God",
"someone normal who doesn't know
how to interact at these things".
I don't ever know what to say.
I'm Clementine.
Can I borrow
a piece of your chicken?
And then you just took it,
without waiting for an answer.
It was so intimate,
like we were already lovers.
I'm Joel.
Hi, Joel.
So, no jokes about my name.
You mean, like
"Oh, my darlin, Clementine?"
Huckleberry Hound?
That sort of thing?
Yeah, like that.
No, no jokes.
One of my favorite things
when I was a kid
was my Huckleberry Hound doll.
I think your name is magical.
This is it, Joel.
It's gonna be gone soon.
I know.
What do we do?
Enjoy it.
- You married?
- No.
Let's move into
this neighborhood!
I do sort of live
with someone, though.
Male or female?
What? Female.
At least I'm not barking up
the wrong tree.
Do you know these people?
No, of course not.
Come on.
They might have a dog.
There's no dog.
What are you doing?
It's freezing out.
I don't believe this.
Come on, man.
The water's fine.
Nobody's coming here tonight,
believe me.
So, what's
your girlfriend's name?
Naomi, but we're not really...
Whatever.
So this is great.
Now I can look for candles,
matches, and the liquor cabinet.
Oh, God.
I think we should go.
There's no phone line.
- What?
- I think we should go.
Why? It's our house.
Just for tonight.
We are David and Ruth Laskin.
Which one do you want to be?
I prefer to be Ruth,
but I can be flexible.
What do you need?
Alcohol.
So, are you okay with wine?
I don't know.
Well, you choose the wine.
I'll go find the bedroom and
slip into something more Ruth.
- I'm Ruth-less at the moment.
- We really should go.
I've got to catch my ride.
So go.
I did. I thought
maybe you were a nut.
But you were exciting.
I wish you'd stayed.
I wish I'd stayed, too.
Now I wish I'd stayed.
I wish I'd done a lot of things.
I wish I'd stayed. I do.
I came back downstairs
and you were gone.
- I walked out the door.
- Why?
I don't know. I felt
like a scared little kid.
It was above my head.
- You were scared?
- Yeah.
I thought you knew
that about me.
I ran back to the bonfire,
trying to outrun my humiliation.
- Was it something I said?
- Yeah.
You said "so go"
with such disdain.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
What if you stayed this time?
I walked out the door.
There's no memory left.
Come back and make up a goodbye.
Let's pretend we had one.
Bye, Joel.
I love you.
Meet me in Montauk.
I didn't crash the plane.
The plane crashed.
You were operating the plane with
the remote control, and it crashed.
It was fucking windy.
Come on.
You're stoned
and you're driving.
The pot balances it out and brings you
back up. That's why I smoke it.
If I'm going to be drinking,
then I'll smoke it.
It does. A medical test was done.
It's proven on the Science Network.
Honey, just watch the road.
I can't see shit.
I saw you talking
to a pretty girl.
She was nice.
Yeah, man, who was it?
She was just a girl.
Okay.
So I've got to drop the van off.
Thanks, Stan. We'll talk.
You've got all your stuff,
I see.
That's right.
I take it you're not
coming back.
I wouldn't come back
if I was you.
- Do you swear you didn't know?
- I swear.
So you didn't do the erasing?
Of course not. God, no.
And you never even suspected
we were together?
Once, maybe.
I was coming back from a job,
and you were at his car,
and I saw you two talking.
So I waved to you,
and you giggled.
How did I look?
You looked happy.
Happy with a secret.
And after that?
I never saw you two together
again like that,
so I just figured
I was imagining things.
I really like you, Mary Svevo.
You know that?
Thanks.
Let me get my toothbrush.
Where are you, Clem?
I'm worried.
I feel like you're mad at me
and I don't know what I did.
What did I do?
I love you so much.
I'll do anything to make you happy.
Just tell me what you want me
to do, and I'll do it.
I'm going to stop by this morning,
just to make sure you're okay.
I had a really nice time
last night.
Nice?
I had the best fucking night of
my entire fucking life last night.
That's better.
This is weird.
"To all patients
of Dr. Howard Mierzwiak.
My name is Mary Svevo.
We've met, but
you don't remember me.
I worked for a company you hired
to have part of your memory erased.
I've since decided
that this is a horrible...
To correct this, I'm sending
everyone's file back to them."
My name is
Clementine Kruczynski.
I'm here to erase Joel Barish.
- What is this?
- I don't know.
He's boring.
Is that enough reason
to erase someone?
I've been thinking how I was before and
how I am now, and he changed me.
I feel like
I'm always pissy now.
I don't like myself when I'm with him.
I don't like myself anymore.
I can't stand
to even look at him.
That pathetic, wimpy,
apologetic smile.
That sort of wounded puppy shit.
- What are you doing?
- I'm not doing anything.
The bloom is certainly
off the rose at this point.
- Are you screwing with me?
- No!
- You are screwing with me.
- Joel, I'm not!
You clearly are!
Let's just take a minute and...
Patrick, get the fuck
away from me!
- Can we talk about it?
- No, get the fuck away!
Hey, Clementine.
Nice to see you.
I mean, she's smart, I think,
but not educated.
I couldn't talk to her
about books.
She's more of
a magazine-reading girl.
Her vocabulary leaves
something to be desired.
The truth is,
I was embarrassed in public,
Hi.
Because she would pronounce
library, "Li-berry".
Look what I found.
I think if there's a truly seductive
quality about Clementine,
it's that her personality promises
to take you out of the mundane.
Made me look skinny.
An amazing, burning meteorite
will carry you to another world
where things are exciting.
But what you quickly learn is
that it's really an elaborate ruse.
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
It's okay.
I really like you. I hate that
I said mean things about you.
Let me turn this off, okay?
That's only fair.
The whole thing with the hair,
it's all bullshit.
I really like your hair.
Thank you.
I do.
You want a drink or something?
Do you have any whiskey?
I didn't think her sex
was motivated.
I saw it clearly the last night
we were together. It wasn't sexy.
It was just sad.
Sorry, I thought there was more.
The only way Clem thinks
she can get people to like her
is to fuck them.
Or at least dangle the possibility
of getting fucked in front of them.
I think she's so
desperate and insecure
that she'll sooner or later
go around fucking everybody.
I don't do that.
I wouldn't think that about you.
- Because I don't.
- I know.
It hurts me that you said that,
because I don't do that.
- I'm so sorry.
- I'm sorry about all this.
I'm going to go.
I'm a little confused.
I don't really think
I can be here.
Bye.
I really thought
I knew her so well.
It was nice meeting you and all.
What a loss to spend
that much time with someone,
only to find out
that she's a stranger.
Wait.
- What?
- I don't know. Just wait.
- What do you want, Joel?
- I want you to wait for a while.
- Okay.
- Really?
I'm not a concept, just a fucked-up girl
looking for my peace of mind.
I'm not perfect.
I can't see anything
that I don't like about you.
- But you will.
- Right now I can't.
You will think of things.
And I'll get bored with you
and feel trapped,
because that's
what happens with me.
Okay.