[SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE]
The Hovitos are near.
The poison is still
fresh, three days.
They're following us.
If they knew we were here, they
would've killed us already.
This is it.
This is where Forrestal cashed in.
A friend of yours?
A competitor.
He was good.
He was very, very good.
Señor... nobody's come
out of there alive.
Please...
Señor.
Stop.
Stay out of the light.
Forrestal.
Let us hurry. There is
nothing to fear here.
That's what scares me.
Stay here.
If you insist, señor.
Give me the whip.
Throw me the idol.
No time to argue.
Throw me the idol, I
throw you the whip.
Give me the whip.
Adios, señor.
Adios, Satipo.
Dr Jones.
Again we see there is
nothing you can possess
which I cannot take away.
And you thought I had given up.
You chose the wrong friends.
This time, it will cost you.
Too bad the Hovitos...
don't know you the
way I do, Belloq.
Yes, too bad.
You could warn them, if
only you spoke Hovitos.
[SPEAKING HOVITOS]
Jock. Start the engines.
Get it up.
Jock, the engines.
Start the engines, Jock.
There's a big snake
in the plane, Jock.
Oh, that's just my
pet snake Reggie.
I hate snakes, Jock.
I hate them.
Come on. Show a little
backbone, will ya?
"Neo," meaning "new"
and "lithic"... I-T-H...
I-C, meaning "stone."
All right, let's get
back to this site:
Turkdean Barrow, near Hazelton.
Contains a central passage and
three chambers, or cysts...
don't confuse that with robbing,
in which case we mean...
the removal of the
contents of the barrow.
This site also demonstrates...
one of the great dangers
of archaeology...
Not to life and limb, although
that does sometimes take place...
No, I'm talking about folklore.
In this case, local tradition held
that there was golden
coffin buried at the site,
and this accounts for the
holes dug all over the barrow
and the generally poor
condition of the find.
However, chamber three
was undisturbed,
and the undisturbed chamber
and the grave goods
that were found in another...
In the area, give us a r...
reason to da... To, to date this,
find as we have.
Any questions, then?
No? Okay, that's it
for the day, then.
Don't forget...
Michaelson, chapters four
and five for next time.
And I will be in my office on
Thursday, but not Wednesday.
I had it, Marcus.
I had it in my hand.
What happened?
Guess.
Belloq?
You want to hear about it?
Not at all.
I'm sure everything
you do for the museum
conforms to the
International Treaty
for the Protection of Antiquities.
It's beautiful, Marcus.
I can get it.
I got it all figured out.
There's only one place he
can sell it: Marrakech.
I need $2,000. Look...
Listen to me, old boy.
I brought some people to see you.
Look.
I got these pieces.
They're good pieces, Marcus.
- Look.
- Indiana...
Yes, the museum will buy them,
as usual, no questions asked.
- Yes, they are nice.
- They're worth at least
the price of a
ticket to Marrakech.
But the people I brought are
important, and they're waiting.
What people?
Army Intelligence.
They knew you were
coming before I did.
Seem to know everything.
They wouldn't tell
me what they want.
Well, what do I want
to see them for?
What am I, in trouble?
Yes, Dr Jones, we've heard
a great deal about you.
Have you?
Professor of archaeology,
expert on the occult,
and, how does one say it?
Obtainer of rare antiquities.
That's one way of saying it.
Why don't you sit down?
You'll be more comfortable.
- Oh, thank you.
- Thank you.
Yes, you're a man of many talents.
Now, you studied under
Professor Ravenwood
at the University of Chicago.
Yes, I did.
You have no idea of his
present whereabouts?
Well, just rumours, really.
Somewhere in Asia, I think.
I haven't really spoken
to him for ten years.
We were friends, but...
had a bit of a falling
out, I'm afraid.
Dr Jones, now, you must understand
that this is all
strictly confidential?
I understand.
Yesterday afternoon,
our European sections
intercepted a... a
German communiqué
that was sent from
Cairo to Berlin.
- Now, to Cairo...
- See, over the last two years,
the Nazis have had teams
of archaeologists running
around the world looking for all
kinds of religious artefacts.
Hitler's a nut on the subject.
He's crazy.
He's obsessed with the occult.
And, right now, apparently,
there's some kind of
German archaeological dig
going on in the desert
outside of Cairo.
Now, we've got some
information here,
but we can't make anything out
of it, and maybe you can.
"Tanis development proceeding.
"Acquire headpiece, Staff of Ra.
"Abner Ravenwood, US"
The Nazis have discovered Tanis.
Just what does that
mean to you, Tanis?
Well, it...
The city of Tanis is
one of the possible
resting places of the Lost Ark.
The Lost Ark?
Yeah, the Ark of the Covenant.
The chest the Hebrews
used to carry
around the Ten Commandments.
What do you mean, "commandments"?
You talking about the
Ten Commandments?
Yes, the actual Ten Commandments.
The original stone tablets
that Moses brought down out
of Mount Horeb and smashed,
if you believe in
that sort of thing.
Any of you guys ever
go to Sunday school?
Well, I...
Oh, look.
The Hebrews took the broken
pieces and put them in the Ark.
When they settled in Canaan, they
put the Ark in a place called
the Temple of Solomon.
In Jerusalem.
Where it stayed for many years.
Until, all of a sudden,
whoosh, it's gone.
Where?
Well, nobody knows where or when.
However, an Egyptian pharaoh...
- Shishak.
- Yes.
Invaded the city of Jerusalem
right about 980 BC,
and he may have taken the Ark
back to the city of Tanis
and hidden it in a secret chamber
called the Well of Souls.
Secret chamber?
However, about a year after the
pharaoh would return to Egypt,
the city of Tanis was
consumed by the desert
in a sandstorm which
lasted a whole year.
Wiped clean by the wrath of God.
Huh.
Obviously, we've come
to the right men.
Now you seem to know, all
about this Tanis, then.
No, no, not really.
Ravenwood is the real expert.
Abner did the first
serious work on Tanis.
Collected some of its relics.
It was his obsession, really.
But he never found the city.
Frankly, we're somewhat
suspicious of Mr Ravenwood.
An American being mentioned so
prominently in a
secret Nazi cable.
Oh, rubbish.
Ravenwood's no Nazi.
Well, what do the Nazis
want him for, then?
Well, obviously, the
Nazis are looking
for the headpiece to the Staff of
Ra and they think Abner's got it.
What exactly is a headpiece
to the Staff of Ra?
Well, the staff is just a stick...
I don't know, about this big,
nobody really knows
for sure how high...
And it's... it's... it's capped
with an elaborate headpiece...
in the shape of the sun, with
a crystal in the centre.
And what you did was
you take the staff to a
special room in Tanis...
A map room with a miniature
of the city all laid
out on the floor...
and if you put the staff
in a certain place,
at a certain time of day,
the sun shone through here
and made a beam that came
down on the floor here...
and gave you the exact location
of the Well of the Souls.
Where the Ark of the
Covenant was kept, right?
Which is exactly what the
Nazis are looking for.
What does this Ark look like?
There's a picture
of it right here.
That's it.
Good God.
Yes, that's just what
the Hebrews thought.
Now, what's that supposed
to be coming out of there?
Lightning...
fire...
power of God or something.
I'm beginning to understand
Hitler's interest in this.
Oh, yes.
The Bible speaks of the
Ark levelling mountains,
and laying waste
to entire regions.
An army which carries
the Ark before it...
is invincible.
You did it, didn't you?
They want you to go for it.
Oh, Marcus.
They want you to get a hold of
the Ark before the Nazis do
and they're prepared to
pay handsomely for it.
And the museum?
The museum gets the Ark
when we're finished?
Oh, yes.
Oh...
The Ark of the Covenant.
Nothing else has come close.
That thing represents everything
we got into archaeology
for in the first place.
You know, five years ago, I
would've gone after it myself.
I'm really rather envious.
I've got to locate Abner.
I think I know where to start.
Suppose she'll still be with him?
Possibly, but...
Marion's the least of
your worries right now,
believe me, Indy.
What do you mean?
Well, I mean that for
nearly 3,000 years,
man has been searching
for the Lost Ark.
Not something to be taken lightly.
No one knows its secrets.
It's like nothing you've
ever gone after before.
Oh, Marcus.
What are you trying
to do, scare me?
You sound like my mother.
We've known each other
for a long time.
I don't believe in magic, a lot
of superstitious hocus-pocus.
I'm going after a find of
incredible historical
significance.
You're talking about the bogeyman.
Besides, you know what a
cautious fellow I am.
Nice to see you again, Dr Jones.
Thank you.
Give him space. Give him space.
Go on, Regan.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE]
Hello, Marion.
Indiana Jones.
Always knew, someday, you'd come
walking back through my door.
I never doubted that.
Something made it inevitable.
So, what are you
doing here in Nepal?
I need one of the pieces
your father collected.
I learnt to hate you
in the last ten years.
I never meant to hurt you.
I was a child.
I was in love.
It was wrong and you knew it.
You knew what you were doing.
Now I do.
This is my place.
Get out.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE]
I did what I did.
You don't have to
be happy about it,
but maybe we could help
each other out now.
I need one of the pieces
your father collected.
Bronze piece, about this size,
with a hole in it,
off-centre, with a crystal.
You know the one I mean?
Yeah.
I know it.
Where's Abner?
Abner's dead.
Marion, I'm sorry.
Do you know what you
did to me, to my life?
I can only say I'm
sorry so many times.
Well, say it again, anyway.
Sorry.
Yeah, everybody's sorry.
Abner was sorry for dragging
me all over this earth
looking for his
little bits of junk.
I'm sorry to still be
stuck in this dive.
Everybody's sorry for something.
It's a worthless bronze
medallion, Marion.
You going to give it to me?
Maybe.
I don't know where it is.
Well, maybe you could find it.
3,000 bucks.
Well, that will get me
back, but not in style.
I can get you another two
when we get to the States.
It's important, Marion.
Trust me.
You know the piece I mean?
Do you know where it is?
Come back tomorrow.
Why?
Because I said so, that's why.
Ha.
See you tomorrow, Indiana Jones.
Good evening, Fraulein.
The bar's closed.
We... We are...
not thirsty.
What do you want?
The same thing your
friend Dr Jones wanted.
Surely he told you there would
be other interested parties.
Must've slipped his mind.
The man is... nefarious.
I hope, for your sake, he
has not yet acquired it.
Why, are you willing
to offer more?
Oh, almost certainly.
Do you still have it?
No.
But I know where it is.
Hey, how about a drink
for you and your men?
Your fire is dying here.
Why don't you tell me where
the piece is right now?
Listen, Herr Mac...
I don't know what kind of people
you're used to dealing with,
but nobody tells me
what to do in my place.
Fraulein Ravenwood, let me
show you what I am used to.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
Take your hands off me.
Take your lousy hands off.
Wait a minute.
Wait, I can be reasonable.
That time is passed.
You don't need that.
Wait...
I'll tell you everything.
Yes, I know you will.
Let her go.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
Whiskey.
Shoot them.
Shoot them both.
My medallion.
Well, Jones, at least
you haven't forgotten
how to show a lady a good time.
Boy, you're something.
Yeah, I'll tell you what.
Until I get back my $5,000,
you're going to get more
than you bargained for.
I'm your goddamn partner.
Cairo, city of the living.
A paradise on earth.
Silence.
Why do you forget yourselves?
What is this?
Where did this animal come from?
Oh... oh, no.
Cute.
What an adorable creature.
Then it shall be
welcome in our house.
Oh, well, no, you don't have to
keep it here just because of me.
I knew the Germans would
hire you, Sallah.
You're the best digger in Egypt.
My services are entirely
inconsequential to them.
They've hired or shanghaied
every digger in Cairo.
The excavation is enormous.
They hire only strong backs and
they pay pennies for them.
It's as if the
pharaohs had returned.
When did they find the map room?
Three days ago.
They have not one
brain among them.
Except one.
He is very clever. He's
a French archaeologist.
What's his name?
They call him "Bellosh."
Belloq. Belloq.
The Germans have a great
advantage over us.
They are near to discovering
the Well of Souls.
Well, they're not going
to find it without this.
Who can tell us about
these markings?
Perhaps a man I know can help us.
Indy...
there is something
that troubles me.
What is it?
The Ark.
If it is there, at Tanis,
then it is something that man
was not meant to disturb.
Death has always surrounded it.
It is not of this earth.
Do we need the monkey, huh?
I'm surprised at you, Jones...
talking that way about our baby.
He's got your looks, too.
And your brains.
Oops.
I noticed that.
She's a smart little
thing... smart.
Hey.
Hey, where you going?
She'll be all right. Have a date.
Come on. Come on.
Okay...
Marion.
What's this?
It's a date.
You eat them.
Sieg heil.
Ja.
Heil Hitler. Sieg heil.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
How come you haven't found some
nice girl to settle down with,
raise eight or nine kids,
like your friend Sallah?
Who says I haven't?
I do.
Dad had you figured
a long time ago.
He said you were a bum.
Oh, he's being generous.
The most gifted bum
he ever trained.
You know, he loved you like a son.
Took a hell of a lot for
you to alienate him.
Not much, just you.
Marion, get out of here.
Duck.
Right.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
Marion.
Help. Over here, Indy.
Get out of the way.
Move. Move it.
Help me.
You can't do this to me.
I'm an American.
Indy.
Indiana Jones.
Help me, Jones.
Jones.
Marion.
Indy.
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
Marion...
Dr Jones.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
You looking for me?
Belloq.
Good afternoon, Dr Jones.
I ought to kill you right now.
Not a very private
place for a murder.
Well, these Arabs don't
care if we kill each other.
They're not going to
interfere in our business.
It was not I who brought the
girl into this business.
Please, sit down
before you fall down.
We can at least behave
like civilised people.
I see your taste in friends
remains consistent.
How odd that it should
end this way for us,
after so many
stimulating encounters.
I almost regret it.
Where shall I find a new adversary
so close to my own level?
Try the local sewer.
You and I are very much alike.
Archaeology is our religion,
yet we have both fallen
from the purer faith.
Our methods have not differed
as much as you pretend.
I am a shadowy reflection of you.
It would take only a nudge
to make you like me,
to push you out of the light.
Now you're getting nasty.
You know it's true.
How nice.
Look at this.
It's worthless.
Ten dollars from a
vendor in the street.
But I take it, I bury it in the
sand for a thousand years,
it becomes priceless...
like the Ark.
Men will kill for it.
Men like you and me.
What about your boss, der Fuhrer?
I thought he was waiting
to take possession.
All in good time.
When I am finished with it.
Jones, do you realise
what the Ark is?
It's a transmitter.
It's a radio for speaking to God.
And it's within my reach.
You want to talk to God?
Let's go see Him together.
I've got nothing better to do.
Uncle Indy, come back home now.
Uncle Indy.
Next time, Indiana Jones,
it'll take more than
children to save you.
Uncle Indy.
I thought I would find you there.
Better than the United
States Marines?
Marion's dead.
Yes, I know.
And me. And me.
I'm sorry.
Life goes on, Indy.
There is the proof.
Oh.
I have much to tell you.
First we will take them home,
and then I will take
you to the old man.
I can't figure out
how Belloq did it.
Where'd he get a copy
of the headpiece?
There are no pictures, no
duplicates of it anywhere.
I tell you only what I
saw with my own eyes:
A headpiece like that one,
except round the edges,
which were rougher.
In the centre, the Frenchman
had embedded a crystal,
and... and surrounding the
crystal, on one side,
there were raised markings,
just like that one.
They made their calculations
in the map room?
This morning.
Belloq and the boss
German, Dietrich.
When they came out
of the map room,
they gave us a new spot in which
to dig, out away from the camp.
The Well of the Souls, huh?
Come, come, look.
Look here... look.
Sit down.
Come, sit down.
What is it?
This is a warning not to disturb
the Ark of the Covenant.
What about the height
of the staff, though?
Did Belloq get it off here?
Yes.
It is here.
This were the old way,
this mean six kadam high.
- About 72 inches.
- Wait.
"And take back one kadam
to honour the Hebrew God
whose Ark this is."
You said their headpiece only
had markings on one side.
Are you absolutely sure?
Belloq's staff is too long.
They're digging in
the wrong place.
♪ I am the monarch of the sea ♪
♪ I am the ruler of the...
Bad dates.
I told you not to be premature
in your communiqué to Berlin.
Archaeology is not
an exact science.
It does not deal
in time schedules.
The Fuhrer is not a patient man.
He demands constant reports,
and he expects progress.
You led me to believe...
Nothing. I made no promises.
I only said it looked
very favourable.
Besides, with the information
in our possession,
my calculations were correct.
Boy, they're not
kidding, are they?
What time does the sun
hit the map room?
At about 9:00 in the morning.
Not much time, then.
Where are they digging for
the Well of the Souls?
On that ridge... but the
map room's over there.
Let's go, come on.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
Sallah.
They're here.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
Please, my friend,
what is the matter?
I fetch the water. I
shall get it for you.
If you want water, I
will get you water.
No problem, no problem.
I thought you were dead.
You must have switched baskets.
Are you hurt?
No. You have to get me
out of here, quick.
They're gonna be
back at any minute.
Cut me loose.
Quick.
They keep asking about
you. What you know.
What's wrong?
Cut me loose.
I know where the Ark is, Marion.
The Ark's here?
I'm coming with you,
Jones. Get me out of here.
Cut me loose. You
can't leave me here.
If I take you out of here now,
they'll start combing
the place for us.
Jones, you've got to
get me out of here.
Come on, Jones, are you crazy?
Marion, I hate to do this,
but if you don't sit
still and keep quiet,
this whole thing is
going to be shot.
I'll be back to get you.
Jones, what's the matter?
That's it.
Who knows?
Perhaps the Ark is still waiting
in some antechamber
for us to discover.
Perhaps there's some vital bit
of evidence which eludes us.
Perhaps...
Perhaps the girl can help us.
My feeling exactly.
She was in possession of the
original piece for years.
She may know much, if
properly motivated.
I tell you, the
girl knows nothing.
I'm surprised to
find you squeamish.
That is not your reputation.
But it needn't concern you.
I have the perfect man
for this kind of work.
Heil Hitler.
Indy. Here.
We've hit stone.
Clear it off.
Come on, find the edges.
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
Good, good, good.
You see, Indy? You see?
Okay, bring the pry bars in.
As a team, boys. As a team.
[SPEAKING ARABIC]
Push.
Get them in there.
Get them under.
Good, good, that's it.
Watch your toes.
Carefully, carefully.
Sorry, Indy.
Indy...
why does the floor move?
Give me your torch.
Snakes.
Why did it have to be snakes?
Asps.
Very dangerous.
You go first.
If you're trying
to escape on foot,
the desert is three weeks
in every direction,
so please, eat something.
I must apologise for
their treatment of you.
Yeah. Whose idea was it?
No food, no water.
What kind of people are
these friends of yours?
At this particular time
and place, to do my work,
they are necessary evils.
They're not my friends.
However, with the
right connections,
even in this part of the world,
we are not entirely uncivilised.
It's beautiful.
I would very much like
to see you in it.
I'll bet you would.
All right.
What do you got to
drink around here?
We don't have much time.
Soon they will come to harm you,
and I will not be
able to stop them,
unless you are able to give
me something to placate them.
Some, piece of information...
which I can use to
protect you from them.
I've already told you
everything I know.
I have no loyalty to Jones.
He's brought me
nothing but trouble.
Marion, you are beautiful.
I don't think we need a chaperone.
Steadily.
Steadily. Whoa.
Down...
Down... Whoa.
Carefully, carefully.
You all right, Indy?
Now gently, boys. Gently, gently.
Whoa...
I told you it will be all right.
Huh...
Sallah, get down here.
You pour.
Oh, that's good.
Whoops.
What is this stuff, Rene?
I grew up with this.
It's my family label.
Well... I have to
be going now, Rene.
I like you, Rene, very much.
Perhaps we'll meet someday
under better circumstances.
We meet again, Fraulein.
You Americans,
you're all the same.
Always overdressing for
the wrong occasions.
Now...
what shall we talk about?
All right... take it up.
Easy.
You're as stubborn as that girl.
You like her too much, I think.
Your methods of archaeology
are too primitive for me.
You would use a bulldozer
to find a... China cup.
Shliemann. Wake your men.
Indy, the torches are burning out.
Go on, get out of here.
Hyah.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
Sallah.
Hello.
Why, Dr Jones, whatever are you
doing in such a nasty place?
Why don't you come on
down here. I'll show you.
Thank you, my friend,
but I think we are all
very comfortable up here.
That's right, isn't it?
Yes, we are very
comfortable up here.
So, once again, Jones, what was
briefly yours is now mine.
What a fitting end to
your life's pursuits.
You're about to become
a permanent addition
to this archaeological find.
Who knows?
In a thousand years, even
you may be worth something.
Son of a bitch.
I'm afraid we must be
going now, Dr Jones.
Our prize is awaited in Berlin.
But I do not wish
to leave you down
in that awful place all alone.
Slimy pig, you let me go.
Stop it.
Marion.
Hang on.
Don't...
- Indy.
- Don't fall.
Marion, I got you. I
got you. I got you.
You traitor. You get
your hands off me.
Snakes.
Oh, oh, at your feet.
The girl was mine.
She's of no use to us.
Only our mission for
the Fuhrer matters.
I wonder sometimes, Monsieur, if
you have that clearly in mind.
It was not to be, chérie.
You bastards. I'll
get you for this.
Indiana Jones...
adieu.
No.
Take this.
Wave it at anything that slithers.
Thank you.
Oh, my God, this whole
place is slithering.
Indy.
Ow. Jesus.
Where did you get this? From him?
I was trying to escape.
No thanks to you.
How hard were you trying?
Well, where the hell were you?
Watch it, watch it.
What are you doing?
For the fire.
How the hell are we going
to get out of here?
I'm working on it.
Well, whatever you're
doing, do it faster.
Ah...
Where are you going?
Through that wall.
Just get ready to run,
whatever happens to me.
What do you mean by that?
Indy.
Damn it. Don't you leave
me down here by myself.
Indy.
Here we go.
Get ready.
Indy, the torch is going out.
Indy?
Marion.
Look. Look.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
They're going to fly
it out of here.
When that Ark gets loaded, we're
already going to be on the plane.
Ah, monsieur, let us toast
our success in the desert.
To the Ark.
When we are very far from here.
That will do.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
Hey, you now... come here.
Come here.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
Indy.
Stay with the Ark.
Look out.
Oh, my God.
Marion.
In here. Up here.
Indy, come on.
Hold on.
Move up. It's gonna blow up.
It's stuck. Indy.
I can't push it off.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
It's stuck.
- Turn it. Turn it.
- It's stuck.
Turn it there.
Never mind. Get back. Get back.
Get the Ark away from
this place immediately.
Have it put on the truck.
We'll fly it out of Cairo.
And Gobler, I want
plenty of protection.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
Jones.
Holy smoke, my friends, I'm
so pleased you're not dead.
Indy, Indy, we have no time.
If you still want the Ark,
it is being loaded onto
a truck for Cairo.
Truck?
What truck?
Let's go.
Get back to Cairo.
Get us some transport
to England...
Boat, plane, anything.
Meet me at Omar's.
Be ready for me.
I'm going after that truck.
How?
I don't know.
I'm making this up as I go.
Hyah. Hyah. Hyah. Hyah.
Hyah. Hyah.
Hyah.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
He's there.
Idiot. Idiot.
Everything at last
has been arranged.
The Ark?
Is on board.
Nothing is lacking,
now that you're here.
Or what is left of you.
You trust these guys?
Yes.
Mr Katanga.
Mr Katanga, these are my friends.
They are my family.
I will hear of it if they
are not treated well.
My cabin is theirs.
Mr Jones...
I've heard a lot about you, sir.
Your appearance is exactly
the way I imagined.
Goodbye.
Look out for each other.
I am already missing you.
You're my good friend.
Sallah.
That is for Fayah...
that is for your children...
and this is for you.
Thank you.
♪ A British tar is
a soaring soul ♪
♪ As free as a mountain bird ♪
♪ His energetic fist
should be ready to ♪
♪ A dictator ♪
Where did you go?
I'm cleaning up.
Where'd you get that?
From him.
Who him?
Katanga.
I got a feeling I'm
not the first woman
ever to travel with these pirates.
It's lovely.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Really?
What'd you say?
Wait... I don't need any help.
You know you do.
You're not the man I
knew ten years ago.
It's not the years,
honey, it's the mileage.
You are...
Please, I don't need a nurse.
- I just want to sleep.
- Don't be such a baby.
Marion, leave me alone.
- What is this here?
- Go away.
Yes, it hurts.
Ow.
Well, goddamn it, Indy,
where doesn't it hurt?
Here.
This isn't too bad.
Jones...
Jones?
We never seem to get
a break, do we?
What is it?
Engines have stopped.
I'm going to go check.
What's happening?
We have most important friends.
Holy shit.
I sent my man for you.
You and the girl must disappear.
We have a place in the hold.
Come on, go, go, go.
Come on, go, my friend, go.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
Where is Dr Jones?
What's the big idea?
Let go.
Don't you touch me.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
What about Jones?
There's no trace yet, sir.
Jones is dead.
I killed him.
He was of no use to us.
This girl, however, has certain
value where we're headed.
She'll bring a very good price.
Herr Colonel, that
cargo you've taken...
If it's your goal, go in peace
with it, but leave us the girl.
It would reduce our
loss on this trip.
Savage.
You are not in the position
to ask for anything.
We will take what we wish.
And then decide whether or not to
blow your ship from the water.
The girl goes with me.
She'll be part of my compensation.
I'm sure your Fuhrer
would approve.
If she fails to please me, you
may do with her as you wish.
I will waste no more
time with her now.
Excuse me.
I can't find Mr Jones, Captain.
I've looked everywhere.
He's got to be here somewhere.
Look again.
- I found him.
- Where?
There.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
The altar has been
prepared in accordance
with your radio instructions, sir.
Good.
Take the Ark there immediately.
Monsieur...
I am uncomfortable
with the thought
of this... Jewish ritual.
Are you sure it's necessary?
Let me ask you this:
Would you be more comfortable
opening the Ark in Berlin,
for your Fuhrer?
Finding out, only then,
if the sacred pieces of
the Covenant are inside?
Knowing, only then, whether you
have accomplished your mission,
and obtained the one true Ark?
Hello.
Jones.
I'm going to blow
up the Ark, Rene.
Your persistence
surprises even me.
You're going to give
mercenaries a bad name.
Dr Jones...
surely you don't think you
can escape from this island.
That depends on how reasonable
we're all willing to be.
All I want is the girl.
If we refuse?
Then your Fuhrer has no prize.
Okay, stand back.
All of you, stand back.
Stand back.
Okay, Jones.
You win.
Blow it up.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
Yes, blow it up.
Blow it back to God.
All your life has been spent in
pursuit of archaeological relics.
Inside the Ark are treasures
beyond your wildest aspirations.
You want to see it
open as well as I.
Indiana...
we are simply passing
through history.
This...
This is history.
Do as you will.
[SPEAKING HEBREW]
Marion, don't look at it.
Shut your eyes, Marion.
Don't look at it, no
matter what happens.
Ah...
It's beautiful.
Indy?
Don't look, Marion.
Keep your eyes shut.
Marion.
You've done your country a great
service, and we thank you
and we trust you found the
settlement satisfactory.
Oh, the money's fine.
The situation's
totally unacceptable.
Well, gentlemen, I guess
that just about wraps it up.
Where is the Ark?
I thought we'd settled that.
The Ark is somewhere very safe.
From whom?
The Ark is a source
of unspeakable power
and it has to be researched.
And it will be, I assure
you, Dr Brody, Dr Jones.
We have top men working
on it right now.
Who?
Top men.
Hey, what happened?
You don't look very happy.
Fools. Bureaucratic fools.
What'd they say?
They don't know what
they've got there.
Well, I know what I've got here.
Come on.
I'll buy you a drink.
You know... a drink?