Chapter One
Once upon a time...
in Nazi-occupied France
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Go back inside and shut the door.
Julie, get me some water
for my wash up...
then get inside with your sisters.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Ready, Papa.
Thank you, my darling...
now you go inside
with your sisters.
Don't run.
(MEN SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Is this the property
of Perrier LaPadite?
I am Perrier LaPadite.
It is a pleasure to meet
you, Monsieur LaPadite...
I am Colonel Hans Landa of the SS.
What can I do for you?
I was hoping you could invite
me inside your home...
and we may have a discussion.
Certainly. After you.
Colonel Landa, this is my family.
Colonel Hans Landa of the SS...
Mademoiselle...
at your service.
The rumours I have
heard in the village
about your family are all true.
Each one of your daughters is
more lovely than the last.
Thank you.
Please...
have a seat.
Suzanne, would you be so good as
to get the Colonel some wine?
But no.
Merci beaucoup, Monsieur
LaPadite, but no wine.
This being a dairy farm, one would
be safe in assuming you have milk?
Yes.
Then milk is what I prefer.
Very well.
Julie, would you mind
closing the window?
Thank you.
Monsieur, to both your
family and your cows...
I say, "Bravo."
Thank you.
Please join me at your table.
Very well.
Monsieur LaPadite...
what we have to discuss would
be better discussed in private.
You'll notice I left
my men outdoors.
If it wouldn't offend
them, could you
ask your lovely ladies
to step outside?
You are right.
Charlotte, would you
take the girls outside?
The Colonel and I need
to have a few words.
Monsieur LaPadite...
I regret to inform you I've
exhausted the extent of my French.
To continue to speak
it so inadequately
would only serve to embarrass me.
However, I've been led to believe
you speak English quite well.
Yes.
Well, it just so happens, I do as
well. This being your house...
I ask your permission
to switch to English...
for the remainder of
the conversation.
By all means.
While I'm very familiar
with you and your family,
I have no way of knowing if you
are familiar with who I am.
Are you aware of my existence?
- Yes.
- This is good.
Now, are you aware of the job I've
been ordered to carry
out in France?
Yes.
Please tell me what you've heard.
I've heard
that the Führer has
put you in charge
of rounding up the
Jews left in France
who are either hiding
or passing for Gentile.
The Führer couldn't have
said it better himself.
But the meaning of your visit,
pleasant though it is,
is mysterious to me.
The Germans looked
through my house
nine months ago for hiding Jews
and found nothing.
I'm aware of that.
I've read the reports
of this area.
But like any enterprise,
when under new management,
there is always a slight
duplication of efforts,
most of it being a
complete waste of
time, but needs to be
done nevertheless.
I just have a few questions,
Monsieur LaPadite.
If you can assist me with answers,
my department can close
the file on your family.
Now,
before the occupation, there were
four Jewish families in this area,
all dairy farmers like yourself.
Doleracs, Rollins, the Loveitts
and the Dreyfuses.
Is that correct?
To my knowledge,
those were the Jewish families
among the dairy farmers.
Herr Colonel, would it disturb
you if I smoked my pipe?
Please, Monsieur LaPadite,
this is your house, make
yourself comfortable.
Now, according to these papers,
all the Jewish families in this
area have been accounted for
except the Dreyfuses.
Somewhere in the last year it
would appear they've vanished.
Which leads me to
the conclusion that
they've either made
good their escape
or someone is very
successfully hiding them.
What have you heard about the
Dreyfuses, Monsieur LaPadite?
- Only rumours.
- I love rumours.
Facts could be so misleading,
where rumours, true or
false, are often revealing.
So, Monsieur LaPadite,
what rumours have you heard
regarding the Dreyfuses?
Again, this is just a rumour,
but we heard the Dreyfuses had
made their way into Spain.
So, the rumours you've
heard have been of escape?
(AGREES IN FRENCH)
Yes.
Having never met the Dreyfuses,
would you confirm for me
the exact members of the
household and their names?
There were five of them.
The father, Jacob.
Wife, Miram.
And her brother, Bob.
How old is Bob?
Thirty, 31.
Continue.
And the children,
Amos
and Shosanna.
Ages of the children?
Amos was nine or 10.
- And Shosanna?
- And Shosanna was
18 or 19. I'm not really sure.
Well, I guess that should do it.
However, before I go, could I have
another glass of
your delicious milk?
But of course.
Monsieur LaPadite,
are you aware of the nickname the
people of France have given me?
I have no interest in such things.
But you are aware of
what they call me.
I'm aware.
What are you aware of?
(THANKING IN FRENCH)
That they call you
"The Jew Hunter."
Precisely.
I understand your trepidation
in repeating it.
Heydrich apparently
hates the moniker
the good people of Prague
have bestowed on him.
Actually, why he
would hate the name
"the Hangman" is baffling to me.
It would appear he has done
everything in his
power to earn it.
Now I, on the other hand,
love my unofficial title
precisely because I've earned it.
The feature that makes me such an
effective hunter of the Jews is,
as opposed to most
German soldiers,
I can think like a Jew
where they can only
think like a German.
More precisely, a German soldier.
Now, if one were to
determine what attribute
the German people
share with a beast,
it would be the cunning and the
predatory instinct of a hawk.
But if one were to determine what
attributes the Jews
share with a beast,
it would be that of the rat.
The Führer and
Goebbels' propaganda
have said pretty
much the same thing.
But where our conclusions differ,
is I don't consider the
comparison an insult.
Consider for a moment the
world a rat lives in.
It's a hostile world, indeed.
If a rat were to scamper through
your front door, right now,
would you greet it with hostility?
I suppose I would.
Has a rat ever done
anything to you to
create this animosity
you feel toward them?
Rats spread disease.
They bite people.
Rats were the cause of the bubonic
plague, but that's some time ago.
I propose to you any disease
a rat could spread,
a squirrel could equally carry.
Would you agree?
(AGREES IN FRENCH)
Yet, I assume you don't share the
same animosity with squirrels
- that you do with rats, do you?
- No.
Yet, they're both
rodents, are they not?
And except for the tail, they even
rather look alike, don't they?
It's an interesting
thought, Herr Colonel.
However interesting as
the thought may be,
it makes not one bit of
difference to how you feel.
If a rat were to walk in here,
right now, as I'm talking
would you greet it with a
saucer of your delicious milk?
Probably not.
I didn't think so.
You don't like them.
You don't really know why
you don't like them.
All you know is you
find them repulsive.
Consequently, a German
soldier conducts a search
of a house suspected
of hiding Jews.
Where does the hawk look?
He looks in the barn, he looks in
the attic, he looks in the cellar,
he looks everywhere he would hide.
But there are so
many places it would
never occur to a hawk to hide.
However, the reason the Führer has
brought me off my Alps in Austria
and placed me in
French cow country
today is because it
does occur to me.
Because I'm aware what tremendous
feats human beings are capable of
once they abandon dignity.
May I smoke my pipe as well?
Please, Herr Colonel,
make yourself at home.
Now, my job dictates
that I must have my
men enter your home
and conduct a thorough search
before I can officially cross
your family's name off my list.
And if there are any
irregularities to
be found, rest assured
they will be.
That is unless you have
something to tell me
that makes the conducting
of a search unnecessary.
I might add, also,
that any information
that makes the
performance of my duty
easier will not be
met with punishment.
Actually, quite the contrary.
It will be met with reward.
And that reward will be,
your family will cease to
be harassed in any way
by the German military
during the rest
of our occupation of your country.
You're sheltering enemies
of the state, are you not?
Yes.
You're sheltering them underneath
your floorboards, aren't you?
Yes.
Point out to me the areas
where they're hiding.
Since I haven't heard
any disturbance,
I assume, while they're listening,
they don't speak English.
Yes.
I'm going to switch
back to French now,
and I want you to
follow my masquerade.
Is that clear?
Yes.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Monsieur LaPadite...
I thank you for the milk...
and your hospitality.
I do believe our
business here is done.
Ah, ladies.
I thank you for your time.
We shan't be bothering
your family any longer.
So, Monsieur...
Mademoiselle.
I bid farewell to you and say...
adieu.
It's the girl.
Goodbye, Shosanna.
Chapter Two
INGLOURIOUS BASTERDS
Ten-hut.
My name is Lieutenant Aldo Raine.
And I'm putting together a special
team, and I need
me eight soldiers.
Eight Jewish American soldiers.
Now, you all might've
heard rumours
about the armada happening soon.
Well, we'll be leaving
a little earlier.
We're going to be dropped into
France dressed as civilians.
Once we're in enemy territory,
as a bushwhacking guerrilla army,
we're going to be doing one
thing and one thing only.
Killing Nazis.
I don't know about you all,
but I sure as hell
didn't come down
from the goddamn Smoky Mountains,
cross 5,000 miles of water, fight
my way through half of Sicily
and jump out of a
fucking aeroplane to
teach the Nazis
lessons in humanity.
Nazi ain't got no humanity.
They're the foot soldiers of a
Jew-hating, mass-murdering maniac
and they need to be destroyed.
That's why any and every son of a
bitch we find wearing
a Nazi uniform,
they're going to die.
Now, I'm the direct descendent
of the mountain man Jim Bridger.
That means I got a
little Indian in me.
And our battle plan will be
that of an Apache resistance.
We will be cruel to the Germans.
And through our cruelty,
they will know who we are.
And they will find the
evidence of our cruelty
in the disembowelled, dismembered
and disfigured bodies of their
brothers we leave behind us.
And the German won't be
able to help themselves
but imagine the cruelty their
brothers endured at our hands,
and our boot heels and
the edge of our knives.
And the German will
be sickened by us.
And the German will talk about us.
And the German will fear us.
And when the German closes
their eyes at night
and they're tortured by their
subconscious for the
evil they have done,
it will be with thoughts of us
that they are tortured with.
Sound good?
- Yes, sir.
That's what I like to hear.
But I got a word of warning for
all you would-be warriors.
When you join my command,
you take on debit.
A debit you owe me, personally.
Each and every man under my
command owes me 100 Nazi scalps.
And I want my scalps.
And all you all will
get me 100 Nazi scalps
taken from the heads
of 100 dead Nazis.
Or you will die trying.
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
How much more of these
Jew swine must I endure?
They butcher my men
like they were flies.
Do you know the latest
rumour they've conjured up
in their fear-induced delirium?
The one...
that beats my boys with a bat.
The one they call
"The Bear Jew"...
is a Golem.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
My Führer, this is
just soldiers' gossip.
No one really believes
"The Bear Jew" is a Golem.
Why not?
They seem to be able to elude
capture like an apparition.
They seem to be able to
appear and disappear at will.
You want to prove they're
flesh and blood?
Then bring them to me.
I will hang them naked, by their
heels, from the Eiffel Tower.
And then throw their
bodies in the sewers...
for the rats of Paris to feast.
Kliest.
(KLIEST SPEAKING
GERMAN ON INTERCOM)
Yes, my Führer.
I have an order I
want relayed to all
German soldiers
stationed in France.
The Jew degenerate known
as "The Bear Jew,"
henceforth, is never to be
referred to as The Bear Jew again.
(KLIEST SPEAKING GERMAN)
Yes, my Führer.
Do you still wish to
see Private Butz?
Who and what is a Private Butz?
He's the soldier you
wanted to see personally.
His squad was ambushed by
Lieutenant Raine's Jews.
He was its only survivor.
Indeed, I do want to see him.
Thank you for reminding me.
Send him in.
(BUTZ SPEAKING GERMAN)
Sergeant Rachtmann, Ludwig and I
were the only ones left
alive after the ambush.
While one man guarded us,
the rest removed the hair.
Hey, Hirschberg.
Send that Kraut sarge over.
You. Go.
Sergeant Werner Rachtman.
Lieutenant Aldo Raine.
Pleased to meet you.
You know what "sit
down" means, Werner?
- Yes.
- Then sit down.
How is your English, Werner?
Because if need be,
we got a couple
of fellows who can translate.
Wicki here,
an Austrian-Jew, got
the fuck out of
Munich while the getting was good.
Became American, got drafted, come
back to give you all what for.
Another one up there you
might be familiar with.
Sergeant Hugo Stiglitz.
Heard of him?
Everybody in the German Army
has heard of Hugo Stiglitz.
The reason for Hugo
Stiglitz's celebrity
among German soldiers is simple.
As a German-enlisted man, he
killed 13 Gestapo officers.
Instead of putting him
up against a wall,
the High Command decided
to send him back to Berlin
to be made an example of.
Needless to say, once the
Basterds heard about him,
he never got there.
Sergeant Hugo Stiglitz?
Lieutenant Aldo Raine.
These are the Basterds.
Ever heard of us?
We just want to say we're
a big fan of your work.
When it comes to killing Nazis,
I think you show great talent.
And I pride myself for having
an eye for that kind of talent.
But your status as a Nazi
killer is still amateur.
We all come here to see
if you want to go pro.
Can I assume you know who we are?
You're Aldo the Apache.
Werner, if you heard of us,
you probably heard we ain't in
the prisoner-taking business.
We in the killing Nazi business,
and, cousin, business
is a-booming.
Oh, yeah.
Now, that leaves two ways
we can play this out.
Either kill you or let you go.
Whether or not you're going
to leave this ditch alive
depends entirely on you.
Up the road a piece,
there's an orchard.
Besides you, we know
there's another Kraut
patrol fucking around
here somewhere.
If that patrol were to
have any crack shots,
that orchard would be a
goddamn sniper's delight.
So if you ever want to eat a
sauerkraut sandwich again,
you got to show me on this
here map where they are.
You got to tell me how many they
are, and you got to tell me
what kind of artillery
they're carrying with them.
You can't expect me to
divulge information
that would put German
lives in danger.
Well, now, Werner,
that's where you're
wrong, because that's
exactly what I expect.
I need to know about
Germans hiding in trees.
And you need to tell me. And
you need to tell me right now.
Now, just take that
finger of yours
and point out on this here map
where this party is being held,
how many is coming and what
they brought to play with.
I respectfully refuse, sir.
Hear that?
Yes.
That's Sergeant Donny Donowitz.
You might know him
better by his nickname.
The Bear Jew.
Now, if you heard of
Aldo the Apache, you
got to have heard
about The Bear Jew.
- I heard of The Bear Jew.
- What did you hear?
Beats German soldiers with a club.
He bashes their brains in with
a baseball bat, what he does.
And, Werner, I'm going to ask
you one last goddamn time,
and if you still
respectfully refuse,
I'm calling The Bear Jew over.
He's going to take
that big bat of his,
and he's going to beat
your ass to death with it.
Now, take your
Wiener-schnitzel-licking finger,
and point out on this map
what I want to know.
Fuck you.
And your Jew dogs.
Actually, Werner, we're all
tickled to hear you say that.
Quite frankly, watching
Donny beat Nazis to death
is the closest we ever get to
going to the movies. Donny.
Yeah?
Got us a German here who
wants to die for country.
Oblige him.
Did you get that for killing Jews?
Bravery.
Yeah.
Oh, no.
Donny.
Yeah, Donny.
About now I'd be shitting
my pants if I was you.
Teddy Fucking Williams
knocks it out of the park.
Fenway Park is on its feet
for Teddy Fucking Ballgame.
He went yard on that one, on
to fucking Lansdowne Street.
You.
Damn it, Hirschberg.
Donny, bring that other
one over here. Alive.
Get the fuck up. Batter
up. You're on deck.
Two hits. I hit you,
you hit the ground.
English?
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Wicki.
Ask him if he wants to live.
(BOTH SPEAKING GERMAN)
Tell him to point out on this
map the German position.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Ask him how many Germans.
(BOTH SPEAKING GERMAN)
Around about 12.
What kind of artillery?
(BOTH SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
How did you survive this ordeal?
They let me go.
Now, when you report
what happened here,
you can't tell them
you told us what
you told us. They'll shoot you.
They're going to want to know why
you so special, we let you live.
So tell them, we let
you live so you
could spread the word
through the ranks
what's going to happen
to every Nazi we find.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
You are not to tell anybody
anything. Not one word of detail.
Your outfit was ambushed,
and you got away.
Not one word more.
Yes, my Führer.
Did they mark you like they
did the other survivors?
Yes, my Führer.
Now that you've
survived the war, when
you get home, what
you going to do?
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
I will hug my mother like
I've never hugged her before.
He's going to hug his mother.
Well, ain't that nice?
Ask if he's going to
take off his uniform.
(WICKI SPEAKING GERMAN)
(BUTZ SPEAKING GERMAN)
Not only shall I remove it,
but I intend to burn it.
He's going to burn it.
Yeah, that's what we
thought. We don't like that.
See, we like our
Nazis in uniforms.
That way you can spot them.
Just like that.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
But you take off
that uniform, ain't
nobody going to know you's a Nazi.
And that don't sit well with us.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
So I'm going to give you a little
something you can't take off.
You know, Lieutenant, you're
getting pretty good at that.
You know how you get to
Carnegie Hall, don't you?
Practise.
Chapter Three
GERMAN NIGHT IN PARIS
JUNE
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
What starts tomorrow?
A Max Linder festival.
I always preferred
Linder to Chaplin.
Except Linder never made a
film as good as "The Kid."
The chase climax of
"The Kid," superb.
I adore your cinema very much.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Merci.
Is it yours?
Do I own it?
Yes.
How is it a girl as young
as you owns a cinema?
My aunt left it to me.
Merci for hosting a German night.
I don't have a choice...
but you're welcome.
I love the Riefenstahl
mountain films...
especially Piz Palü.
It's nice to see a French girl
who's an admirer of Riefenstahl.
"Admire" would not really
be the word I would use...
to describe my feelings
towards Fräulein Riefenstahl.
But you do admire the
director Pabst, don't you?
That's why you include his
name on the marquee...
when you didn't have to.
I'm French. We respect
directors in our country.
Even Germans.
Even Germans, yes.
Merci for your assistance,
soldier. Adieu.
You're not finished.
I'll finish in the morning.
May I ask your name?
You wish to see my papers?
Emmanuelle Mimieux.
That's a very pretty name.
Merci.
Are you finished with my papers?
Mademoiselle, may I
introduce myself...
Fredrick Zoller.
Well...
it's been a pleasure chatting
with a fellow cinema lover.
Sweet dreams, mademoiselle.
Adieu.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Hello, mademoiselle.
May I join you?
Look, Fredrick...
You remember my name?
Yes.
Look, you seem a pleasant
enough fellow...
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Regardless, I want you
to stop pestering me.
I apologise, mademoiselle...
I wasn't trying to be a pest.
I was simply trying
to be friendly.
I don't wish to be your friend.
Why not?
Don't act like an
infant. You know why.
I'm more than just a uniform.
Not to me.
If you are so desperate for
a French girlfriend...
I suggest you try Vichy.
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Who are you?
I thought I was just a uniform.
You're not just a German soldier.
Are you somebody's son?
Most German soldiers
are somebody's son.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
You're a very lucky girl,
catching a brave war hero.
No, no, no, no, the mademoiselle
is not my girlfriend.
Can you write "Amour Babette"?
(BOTH SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
So you're a war hero.
What did you do?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
I was alone in a bell tower
in a walled off city.
It was myself and
a thousand rounds
of ammo, in a bird's nest...
against three hundred
enemy soldiers.
What's a bird's nest?
A bird's nest is what a sniper
would call a bell tower.
It's a high structure, offering a
three hundred and
sixty degree view.
Very advantageous for marksmen.
How many did you kill?
Sixty-eight.
The first day.
A hundred and fifty...
the second day.
Thirty-two the third day.
On the fourth day
they exited the city.
Naturally, my war story received
a lot of attention in Germany...
that's why they all recognise me.
They call me the
German Sergeant York.
Maybe they'll make a film
about your exploits.
Well, that's just what
Joseph Goebbels thought.
So he did and called
it "Nation's Pride."
And they wanted me
to play myself...
so I did.
Joseph thinks this movie will be
proven to be his masterpiece.
And I will be the
German Van Johnson.
"Nation's Pride" is about you?
"Nation's Pride" is starring you?
I know.
Comical?
Well, good luck with
your movie, Private. I
hope all goes well for
Joseph and yourself.
(SAYING GOODBYE IN FRENCH)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Goodbye.
- Do you need help?
- No, it's okay.
If you need me, I'll be
in the storage room.
Okay, my love.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Mademoiselle Mimieux?
Yes?
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Is this your cinema?
Yes.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Come down.
Please.
I don't understand.
What have I done?
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
She wants to know what she's done.
Get your ass in that car.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
It's only the offspring
of slaves that allows
America to be competitive
athletically.
American Olympic gold can
be measured in Negro sweat.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Good, you came.
I wasn't sure whether or not
you'd accept my invitation.
Invitation?
(GOEBBELS SPEAKING GERMAN)
Is that the young lady
in question, Fredrick?
Yes, it is, Dr Goebbels.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Emmanuelle, there is
somebody I want you to meet.
Emmanuelle Mimieux,
I'd like to introduce
you to the minister
of propaganda...
the leader of the entire
German film industry...
and now that I'm an actor,
my boss, Dr Joseph Goebbels.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Your reputation precedes
you, Fräulein Mimieux.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
And normally, this is Herr
Goebbels' French interpreter...
Mademoiselle Francesca Mondino.
Hello.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
And you've met the Major.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Actually, I didn't
introduce myself.
Major Dieter Hellstrom
of the Gestapo.
At your service, mademoiselle.
Please allow me...
have a seat, please.
Try the champagne,
mademoiselle, it's quite good.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
I must say, Fräulein, I should
be rather annoyed with you.
(TRANSLATING IN FRENCH)
I arrive in France...
and I wish to have
lunch with my star.
(TRANSLATING IN FRENCH)
Little do I know...
he's become the toast of Paris.
And now he must find time for me.
(TRANSLATING IN FRENCH)
People wait in line
hours, days to see me.
For the Führer...
and Private Zoller, I wait.
So finally, I'm granted an
audience with the young Private.
(TRANSLATOR SPEAKING FRENCH)
And he spends the entire lunch
speaking of you and your cinema.
So Fräulein Mimieux, let's
get down to business.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Herr Minister Doctor Goebbels...
I haven't informed her yet.
Unless the girl's a simpleton, I'm
sure she's figured it out by now.
After all, she does
operate a cinema.
Francesca, tell her.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
What they are trying to tell you,
Emmanuelle, is Private Zoller...
has spent the last
hour at lunch trying
to convince Monsieur Goebbels...
to abandon previous plans for
Private Zoller's film premiere...
and change the venue
to your cinema.
What?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
I wanted to inform her.
Shit. I apologise, Private,
of course you did.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
What's the issue?
The Private wanted to inform
the mademoiselle himself.
Nonsense.
Until I ask my questions,
he has nothing to inform.
Let the record state,
I have not agreed
to switch cinemas for my premiere.
Duly noted.
You have opera boxes?
(TRANSLATOR SPEAKING FRENCH)
Yes.
How many?
Two.
(TRANSLATES IN GERMAN)
More would be better.
(GOEBBELS SPEAKING GERMAN)
How many seats in your auditorium?
Three hundred and fifty.
(TRANSLATING IN GERMAN)
That's almost four hundred
less than The Ritz.
But Dr Goebbels...
that's not such a terrible thing.
You said yourself you
didn't want to indulge
every two-faced
French bourgeois...
taking up space, currying favour.
With less seats, it makes
the event more exclusive.
You're not trying to fill the
house, they're fighting for seats.
Besides, to hell with the French.
This is a German night, a German
event, a German celebration.
This night is for you, me...
for the German military,
the high command...
their family and friends.
The only people who should
be allowed in the room...
are people who will be moved
by the exploits on the screen.
I see your public
speaking has improved.
It appears I've created a monster.
A strangely persuasive monster.
When the war is over,
politics await.
Well, Private...
though it is true, I'm inclined
to indulge you anything...
I must watch a film
in this young lady's
cinema before I can
say, yes or no.
So young lady, you
are to close your
cinema for a private
screening tonight.
(TRANSLATING IN FRENCH)
What German films do you have?
Ah, Landa, you are here.
(FREDRICK SPEAKING FRENCH)
Emmanuelle, this is Colonel
Hans Landa of the SS.
He'll be running the
security for the premiere.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Charmed, mademoiselle.
Au revoir, Shosanna.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
And now I must get the Reich
Minister to his next appointment.
Slave driver.
French slave driver.
(HANS SPEAKING GERMAN)
Actually, in my role as
security chief of this joyous
German occasion, I'm
afraid I must...
have a word with
Mademoiselle Mimieux.
(FREDRICK SPEAKING GERMAN)
What sort of discussion?
(HANS SPEAKING GERMAN)
That sounded suspiciously
like a Private
questioning the
order of a Colonel.
Or am I just being sensitive?
(FREDRICK SPEAKING GERMAN)
Nothing could be further
from the truth, Colonel.
Your authority is beyond question.
But your reputation
does precede you.
Should Mademoiselle Mimieux
or myself be concerned?
(GOEBBELS SPEAKING GERMAN)
Hans, the boy means no harm...
he's simply smitten.
And he's correct. Your
reputation does precede you.
(HANS SPEAKING GERMAN)
No need for concern,
you two. As security
chief, I simply need
to have a chat...
with the possible new
venue's property owner.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Have you tried the strudel here?
No, no.
It's not so terrible.
So how is it the young Private and
yourself came to be acquainted?
Yes, two strudels. One for myself
and one for the mademoiselle.
For me a cup of espresso and
for the mademoiselle...
a glass of milk.
So, mademoiselle, you were
beginning to explain?
Up until a couple
of days ago, I had
no knowledge of Private Zoller...
or his exploits.
To me...
the Private was simply
just a patron of
my cinema. We spoke
a few times but...
Mademoiselle, let
me interrupt you.
This is a simple formality.
No reason for you to feel anxious.
I apologise, I forgot
to order the cream.
One moment.
Wait for the cream.
So, Emmanuelle. May I
call you Emmanuelle?
Yes.
So, Emmanuelle...
explain to me...
how does it happen,
that a young lady
such as yourself, comes
to own a cinema?
After you.
Verdict?
Like I said, not so terrible.
You were explaining the origin
of your cinema ownership.
The cinema originally belonged
to my aunt and uncle.
What are their names?
Jean-Pierre and Ada Mimieux.
Where are they now?
My uncle was killed
during Blitzkrieg.
Pity.
Continue.
Aunt Ada passed away
from fever last spring.
Regrettable.
It's come to my
attention you have a
Negro in your employ.
Is that true?
Yes.
He is a Frenchman.
His name is Marcel.
He worked with my aunt and uncle
since they opened the cinema.
He's the only other one
who works with me.
Doing what?
Projectionist.
Is he any good?
The best.
Actually, one could see where that
might be a good trade for them.
Can you operate the projectors?
Of course I can.
Knowing the Reich
Minister as I do...
I'm quite positive...
he wouldn't want the success or
failure of his
illustrious evening...
dependant on the
prowess of a Negro.
So...
if it comes to pass...
we hold this event
at your venue...
talented no doubt, as
your Negro may be...
you will...
operate the projectors.
Is that acceptable?
Yes.
Cigarette?
They are not French.
They are German.
I did have something else
I wanted to ask you.
But right now, for the life of
me, I can't remember what it is.
Oh, well, must not
have been important.
'Til tonight.
(GOEBBELS SPEAKING GERMAN)
I must say, I appreciate the
modesty of this cinema.
Your cinema has real
respect, almost church like.
Not to say we couldn't
spruce the place up a bit.
Maybe I'll go to the Louvre,
pick up a few Greek nudes,
and scatter them about the lobby.
So, Emmanuelle, how did
you like "Lucky Kids"?
(TRANSLATOR SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SHOSANNA SPEAKING FRENCH)
I quite like Lilian Harvey.
(GOEBBELS SPEAKING GERMAN)
Lilian Harvey.
Never mention that name
again in my presence.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Hey...
what the fuck are
we supposed to do?
It looks like we're supposed
to have a Nazi premiere.
Like I said, what the fuck
are we supposed to do?
Well, I need to talk
with you about that.
I'm confused, what are
we talking about?
Filling the cinema with Nazis and
burning it down to the ground.
I'm not talking about that.
You are talking about that.
No, we're talking about
that, right now.
If we can keep this place from
burning down by ourselves...
we can burn it down by ourselves?
Yes, Shosanna, we could do that.
And with Madame Mimieux's 350
nitrate film print collection...
we wouldn't even
need explosives...
would we?
You mean we wouldn't need
any more explosives?
At that time, 35 millimetre
nitrate film was so flammable
that you couldn't even bring
a reel onto a streetcar.
Hey, you can't bring those
here on a public vehicle.
- They're films, ain't they?
- Yes.
Then they're flammable.
Go on, hop off.
Because nitrate film burns
three times faster than paper.
Shosanna has a collection
of over 350 nitrate film prints.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
I am going to burn down
the cinema on Nazi night.
And if I'm going to
burn down the cinema...
which I am...
we both know, you're not going
to let me do it by myself.
Because you love me.
And I love you.
And you're the only person
on this earth I can trust.
But that's not all
we're going to do.
Does the film-making equipment
in the attic still work?
I know the film camera does.
How about the sound recorder?
Quite well, actually.
I recorded a new
guitarist I met in
a cafe last week. It works superb.
Why do we need
film-making equipment?
Because Marcel, my sweet...
we're going to make a film.
Just for the Nazis.
Chapter Four
OPERATION KINO
Right this way, Lieutenant.
Lieutenant Archie
Hicox reporting, sir.
General Ed Fenech. At ease, Hicox.
Drink?
If you offer me a
scotch and plain water,
I could drink a scotch
and plain water.
That-a-boy, Lieutenant. Make it
yourself like a good
chap, will you?
The bar is in the globe.
Something for yourself, sir?
Whiskey. Straight. No junk in it.
It says here that you
speak German fluently.
Like a Katzenjammer Kid.
And your occupation
before the war?
I'm a film critic.
- List your accomplishments.
- Well, sir, such as they are,
I write reviews and articles for a
publication called
Films and Film-makers,
and I've had two books published.
Impressive. Don't be modest,
Lieutenant. What are their titles?
The first book was called
Art of the Eyes, the
Heart and the Mind:
A Study of German
Cinema in the '20s.
And the second one was called
Twenty-Four Frame Da Vinci.
It's a sub textual film
criticism study of
the work of German
director G.W. Pabst.
- What should we drink to, sir?
- Well...
- Down with Hitler.
- All the way down, sir.
Yes.
Are you familiar with German
cinema under the Third Reich?
Yes. Obviously, I
haven't seen any of
the films made in the
last three years,
- but I'm familiar with it.
- Explain it to me.
Pardon, sir?
Well, this little
escapade of ours requires
a knowledge of the
German film industry
under the Third Reich. Explain
to me UFA under Goebbels.
Goebbels considers the
films he's making
to be the beginning of a
new era in German cinema.
An alternative to
what he considers
the Jewish-German intellectual
cinema of the '20s,
and the Jewish-controlled
dogma of Hollywood.
How's he doing?
Frightfully sorry,
sir. Once again?
You say he wants to take on
the Jews at their own game.
Well, compared to,
say, Louis B. Mayer,
- how's he doing?
- Quite well, actually.
Since Goebbels has taken over,
film attendance has
steadily risen in
Germany over the last eight years.
But Louis B. Mayer wouldn't be
Goebbels' proper opposite number.
I believe Goebbels sees himself
closer to David O. Selznick.
Brief him.
Lieutenant Hicox, at
this point and time
I'd like to brief you
on Operation Kino.
Three days from now
Joseph Goebbels is
throwing a gala premiere
of one of his new movies in Paris.
What film, sir?
The motion picture is
called Nation's Pride.
In attendance at this
joyous Germatic occasion
will be Goebbels, Göring, Bormann,
and most of the
German High Command
including all high
ranking officers
of both the SS and the Gestapo,
as well as luminaries of the
Nazi propaganda film industry.
The master race at play?
Basically, we have all our
rotten eggs in one basket.
The objective of Operation Kino,
blow up the basket.
And like the snows of yesteryear,
gone from this earth.
Jolly good, sir.
An American Secret Service outfit
that lives deep behind enemy lines
will be your assist.
The Germans call
them the Basterds.
The Basterds. Never heard of them.
Whole point of the Secret Service,
old boy, you not hearing of them.
But the Jerries have
heard of them, because
these Yanks have
been them the devil.
You'll be dropped
into France, about
24 kilometres outside of Paris.
The Basterds will
be waiting for you.
First thing, you'll go to a
little village called Nadine.
In Nadine, there's a tavern
called La Louisiane.
There you'll rendezvous
with our double
agent. She'll take it from there.
She's the one who is going to
get you into the premiere.
It'll be you, her, and two
German-born members
of the Basterds.
She's also made all the other
arrangements you're going to need.
How will I know her?
I suspect that won't be
too much trouble for you.
Your contact is Bridget
von Hammersmark.
Bridget von Hammersmark?
The German movie star
is working for England?
Yes, for the last two years now.
One could even say that Operation
Kino was her brainchild.
- Indeed.
- Got the gist?
I think so, sir. Paris
when it sizzles.
The village of Nadine
You didn't say the goddamn
rendezvous is in a
fucking basement.
- I didn't know.
- You said it was in a tavern.
- It is a tavern.
- Yeah, in a basement.
You know, fighting in a basement
offers a lot of difficulties.
Number one being, you're
fighting in a basement.
What if we go in there and
she's not even there?
We wait.
Don't worry. She's a British
spy. She'll make the rendezvous.
- Stiglitz, right?
- That's right, sir.
I hear you're pretty
good with that.
You know, we're not looking
for trouble right now.
Simply making contact with our
agent. Should be uneventful.
However, the off chance I'm
wrong, things prove eventful,
I need to know we can
all remain calm.
I don't look calm to you?
Well, now that you put it
like that, I guess you do.
This Jerry of yours, Stiglitz, not
exactly the loquacious
type, is he?
Is that the kind of man you
need? Loquacious type?
Fair point, Lieutenant.
So you all get in trouble in
there, what are we supposed to do?
Make bets on how it all comes out?
If we get into trouble,
we can handle it.
But if trouble does happen,
we need you to make damn sure
no Germans, or French, for that
matter, escape from that basement.
If Frau von Hammersmark's cover is
compromised, the mission is kaput.
Speaking of Frau von
Hammersmark, whose
idea was it for the
death-trap rendezvous?
- She chose the spot.
- Isn't that just dandy?
Look, she's not a military
strategist. She's just an actress.
You don't got to be
Stonewall Jackson to
know you don't want to
fight in a basement.
She wasn't picking
a place to fight.
She was picking a place
isolated and without Germans.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
So, I'm male...
I'm a fictional, literary
character from the past...
I'm American, and
that's controversial.
No, it's not controversial at all.
The nationality of the
author has nothing to
do with the nationality
of the character.
The character is the character.
Hamlet is not British.
He is Danish.
So yes, this character
was born in America.
Well then.
Mathilda.
Schnapps? Schnapps?
Schnapps... Schnapps... Schnapps.
(ORDERING IN GERMAN AND FRENCH)
Five schnapps, please.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
If I had a wife...
would she be called a squaw?
Yes.
He's got it.
Three more questions.
Is my blood brother
Old Shatterhand?
Yes.
Did Karl May write me?
So who are you?
I am "Winnetou," chief
of the Apaches.
Yes.
That was good. That was
good. That was good.
Now down with the glasses.
Cheers.
(FEMALE SERGEANT SPEAKING GERMAN)
Attention.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Hello, my lovelies.
Take a seat.
I will join you in
moments. I'm just saying
goodbye to my five
new friends here.
No hurry, Frau von
Hammersmark. Take your time.
Enjoy yourself. We'll be
just over here waiting.
(SPEAKING FRENCH AND GERMAN)
Eric, my love. Those are the
friends I've been waiting for.
Please treat them to
anything they like.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Frau von Hammersmark.
Your wish is my command.
Officers...
it would appear the drinks
are on the Fräulein.
- What would you like?
- Whiskey.
Two whiskeys.
- Three whiskeys.
- Three whiskeys, very well.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
I wish you a wonderful evening.
- Same to you.
- I thank you.
Your card.
Yes, you're right.
Let's see.
Genghis Khan. I would
never have gotten that.
But of course you would have.
Hello, darling.
How are you?
So good to see you.
(SPEAKING GERMAN SOFTLY)
I thought this place was supposed
to have more French than Germans?
Yes, normally that's true.
The Sergeant over there's
wife just had a baby.
And his commanding
officer gave him and
his mates the night
off to celebrate.
We should leave.
No.
We should stay.
For one drink at least.
I've been waiting
for you in a bar.
It would look strange if we
left before we had a drink.
She's right. Just be calm
and enjoy your whiskey.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Mathilda...
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
come join us in the game. Take
Frau Hammersmark's place.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
She would love to play the game.
I will translate... and protect.
Don't worry, pretty little thing.
If any of these wolves gets out
of line, I'll kick their ass in.
Watch.
Rip off his nose.
Stop it.
Schnapps, schnapps, take your
schnapps in hand, comrades.
Before we go on playing...
we will drink.
We drink to our friend Wilhelm.
And his little boy...
Maximilian.
(ALL TOASTING IN GERMAN)
- To Max.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
There's some new development.
The cinema venue has changed.
Why?
No one knows but that should
not be a real problem.
The cinema it's been changed to is
considerably smaller
than The Ritz.
So whatever explosives
you brought for The
Ritz should be doubly
effective here.
Now the next piece
of information...
is colossal.
Try not to overreact.
The Führer...
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
I was just thinking...
could you sign an autograph
to my son on his birthday?
Of course. I'd love to, Wilhelm.
This handsome Staff Sergeant
just became a father today.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Do you know the name
of this progeny yet?
I most certainly do, Fräulein.
His name is Maximilian.
Maximilian, wonderful name.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
Nothing but the best
for little Maximilian.
(THANKING IN GERMAN)
Max may not know who
you are now but...
he will. I will show him
all of your movies.
Good.
He will grow up with
your films and...
this napkin on his wall.
I propose a toast to the
greatest actress in Germany.
There is no Dietrich. There is no
Riefenstahl. Only Von Hammersmark.
- Cheers.
Cheers.
Once again...
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Frau Hammersmark, what
brings you to France?
None of your business.
Staff Sergeant.
You might not have worn
out your welcome with
the Fräulein with your
drunken boorish behaviour...
but you have worn out
your welcome with me.
Might I remind you,
Staff Sergeant,
you are an enlisted man.
This is an officer's table.
I suggest you stop
pestering the Fräulein...
and rejoin your table.
Excuse me, Captain, but your
accent is very unusual.
Where are you from?
You must be either completely
drunk or mad to dare...
to speak to a superior officer
with such impertinentness.
Staff Sergeant.
I'm making you and you
responsible for him.
I suggest you take
hold of your friend...
or he'll spend Max's
first birthday
in jail for public drunkenness.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Might I inquire?
Like our young newly
christened father here...
I, too, have an acute
ear for accents.
And like him...
I, too, find yours odd.
From where do you hail, Captain?
Major, this is highly...
I wasn't speaking to
you, Lieutenant Munich.
Or you either,
Lieutenant Frankfurt.
I was speaking to Captain
I-don't-know-what.
I was born in a village that rests
in the shadow of the Piz Palü.
- The mountain?
- Yes.
In that village, we
all speak like this.
Have you seen the
Riefenstahl film?
- Yes.
- Then you saw me.
You remember the
skiing torch scene?
Yes.
In that scene was
myself, my father,
my sister and my two brothers.
My brother is so handsome...
the director Pabst,
gave him a Close-Up.
Herr Major, if my word
means anything...
I can vouch for everything the
young Captain has just said.
He does hail from the
bottom of the Piz Palü.
He was in the film and his brother
is far more handsome than he.
You should rejoin your friends.
May I join you?
By all means.
Wunderbar.
So that's the source of
your bizarre accent.
That's extraordinary.
What are you doing here?
Aside from having a drink
with the lovely Fräulein?
Well, that pleasure
requires no explanation.
I mean in country.
You're obviously not stationed in
France or I'd know who you are.
You know every German in France?
Worth knowing.
Well, there lies the problem.
We never claimed to
be worth knowing.
All levity aside, what
are you doing in France?
Attending Minister Goebbels' film
premiere as the Fräulein's escort.
You are the Fräulein
Hammersmark's escort.
Someone has to carry her lighter.
The Captain is my date, but
all three are my guests.
We are old friends...
who go back a long time.
Actually, longer than an
actress would care to admit.
Well, in that case...
let me raise my glass to the
three luckiest men in the room.
I'll drink to that.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Queen Christina.
Mata Hari.
I must say...
that game they're playing
looks like a good bit of fun.
I didn't join them because
you're quite right, Captain.
An officer should not
fraternise with enlisted men.
But...
seeing as we are all officers...
and sophisticated lady
friends of officers.
What say we play the game?
Yes, great, one game.
Wunderbar.
Soldiers...
the cards.
Thank you.
So gentlemen...
the object of the game is to...
write the name of a famous
person on your card.
Real or fictitious,
doesn't matter.
For instance, you could write,
Confucius or Doctor Fu Manchu.
Eric. More pens.
And they must be famous,
not aunt Frida.
When you finish writing, put the
card face down on the table.
And move it to the
person on your right...
Thanks.
The person to your left
moves his card to you.
You pick up the card
without looking at it...
lick the back...
and stick it on your forehead.
Write.
I'll start, give you the idea.
Am I German?
- No.
Am I American?
Wait a minute, he goes to...
Obviously, he wasn't
born in America.
So... I visited America, aye?
Yes.
Was this visit fortuitous?
Not for you.
My native land, is it what
one would call, exotic?
(VON HAMMERSMARK AND
HICOX SPEAKING GERMAN)
- Yes.
That could be either a reference
to the jungle or the Orient.
I'm going to let my
first instinct take
over and ask. Am I
from the jungle?
- Yes.
Now gentlemen, around
this time you could
ask whether you're
real or fictitious.
I, however, think that's too
easy, so I won't ask that yet.
Okay...
my native land is the jungle...
I visited America...
but my visit was not
fortuitous to me...
but the implication is that
it was to somebody else.
When I went...
from the jungle to America...
did I go by boat?
- Yes.
Did I go against my will?
On this boat ride,
was I in chains?
Yes.
When I arrived in America,
was I displayed in chains?
- Yes.
Am I the story of the
Negro in America?
(HICOX SPEAKING GERMAN)
No.
Well then I must be King Kong.
Bravo.
Impressive.
Now, since I answered
correctly, you
all need to finish your drinks.
Cheers.
Now, who is next?
Well, Major...
I don't mean to be rude. But the
four of us are very good friends.
And we haven't seen each
other in quite a while.
So, Major...
I am afraid...
you are intruding.
I beg to differ, Captain.
It's only if the
Fräulein considers
my presence an intrusion...
that I become an intruder.
How about it, Fräulein von
Hammersmark? Am I intruding?
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
I didn't think so.
It's simply the Captain
is immune to my charms.
I am just joking.
Just joking. Of
course I'm intruding.
Allow me to refill your
glasses, gentlemen,
and I will bid you and
the Fräulein adieu.
Eric has a bottle of
thirty-three-year-old whiskey.
From the Scottish Highlands.
What do you say, gentlemen?
You're most gracious, Major.
Eric. The thirty-three.
And new glasses.
You don't want to contaminate
the thirty-three
with the swill you were drinking.
How many glasses?
- Five.
- Not for me.
I like scotch, scotch
doesn't like me.
Nor I. I'll stay with bubbly.
Three glasses.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(ERIC SPEAKING GERMAN)
Frau von Hammersmark.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Thank you.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
A thousand year German Reich.
- A thousand year Reich.
I must say I grow weary
of these monkeyshines.
Did you hear that?
That was the sound of my Walther.
Pointed right at your testicles.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Why do you have your Walther
pointed at my testicles?
Because you've just given
yourself away, Captain.
You're no more German
than that scotch.
(BOTH SPEAKING GERMAN)
- Well, Major.
- Shut up slut.
You were saying?
I was saying that makes two of us.
I've had a gun pointed at your
balls since you sat down.
That makes three of us.
And at this range, I'm a
real Fredrick Zoller.
Looks like we have a bit of
a sticky situation here.
What's going to happen, Major...
you're going to stand up and
walk out that door with us.
No, no, no, no, no,
no. I don't think so.
I'm afraid you and I...
we both know, Captain...
no matter what happens to
anybody else in this room...
the two of us aren't
going anywhere.
Too bad about Sergeant Wilhelm
and his famous friends.
If any of you expect to live,
you'll have to shoot them too.
Looks like little Max
will grow up an orphan.
How sad.
Well, if this is it, old boy,
I hope you don't mind if I
go out speaking the King's.
By all means, Captain.
There's a special
rung in hell reserved
for people who waste good Scotch.
Seeing as I may be rapping
on the door momentarily,
I must say, damn good stuff, sir.
Now, about this pickle
we find ourselves in.
It would appear there's only
one thing left for you to do.
And what would that be?
Stiglitz.
Say auf Wiedersehen
to your Nazi balls.
You outside. Who are you?
British? American?
What?
We're American.
What are you?
I'm a German, you idiot.
Speak English pretty
good for a German.
I agree.
So let's talk.
Okay, talk.
I'm a father.
My baby was born
today. In Frankfurt.
Five hours ago.
His name is Max. We were in
here drinking, celebrating.
They're the ones that
came in shooting
and killing. It's not my fault.
Okay. It wasn't your fault.
What's your name, soldier?
Wilhelm.
Now, is there anybody
alive on our side?
- No.
- I'm alive.
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
Who's that?
Is the girl on your side?
Which girl?
Who do you think? Von Hammersmark.
Yeah, she's ours.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Is she okay?
Wilhelm.
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
She's been shot.
But she's alive.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Okay, Wilhelm.
What do you say we make us a deal?
What's your name?
Aldo.
Okay, Wilhelm, here's my deal.
You let me and one of my men come
down there and take the girl away.
No guns. No guns me, no guns you.
And we take the girl and leave.
It's that simple, Willi.
You go your way, we go ours.
And little Max gets to grow up
playing catch with his daddy.
So what do you say,
Willi? We got us a deal?
Aldo.
I'm here, Willi.
I want to trust you.
But...
But how can I?
What choice you got, son?
Okay, okay.
Aldo,
I'm going to trust you.
Come down.
Hey, Willi, what's
with the machine
gun? I thought we had us a deal?
We still have a deal.
Now, get the girl and go.
Not so fast.
We only got a deal,
we trust each other.
And a Mexican stand-off
ain't trust.
You need guns on me for it
to be a Mexican stand-off.
You got guns on us. You
decide to shoot, we're dead.
Up top, they got grenades. They
drop them down here, you're dead.
That's a Mexican stand-off,
and that was not the deal.
No trust, no deal.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
All right, Aldo.
Fine.
Just take that fucking traitor,
and get her out of my sight.
(VON HAMMERSMARK GROANING)
Not so goddamn fast, Doc. Tell
him to go play with his dogs.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Before we yank that slug out you,
you need to answer
a few questions.
Few questions about what?
About I got three men
dead back there.
Why don't you try telling
us what the fuck happened?
The British officer
blew his German
act and the Gestapo Major saw it.
Before we get into who shot John,
why'd you invite my
men to a rendezvous
in a basement with
a bunch of Nazis?
I can see since you didn't
see what happened inside,
that the Nazis being
there must look odd.
Yeah, we got a word for that
kind of odd in English.
It's called suspicious.
Everybody needs to calm down.
You're letting your imagination
get the better of you.
You met the Sergeant
yourself. Willi.
You remember him, don't you?
Yeah, I remember him.
His wife had a baby tonight.
He had just become a...
He had just become a father.
His commanding
officer gave him and
his mates the night
off to celebrate.
The Germans being
there was either a
trap set by me or a
tragic coincidence.
It couldn't be both.
How'd the shooting start?
The Englishman gave himself away.
How'd he do that?
He ordered three glasses.
We order three glasses.
That's the German three.
The other looks odd.
Germans would and did notice it.
Okay, let's pretend
there were no Germans
and everything went exactly
the way it was supposed to.
What was the next step?
Tuxedos.
To get them into the premiere
wearing military uniforms
with all the military there
would've been suicide.
But going as members of
the German film industry,
they wear tuxedos and fit
in with everybody else.
I arranged for the tailor to
fit three tuxedos tonight.
How'd you intend to get
them in that premiere?
Hand me my purse.
Lieutenant Hicox was
going as my escort.
The other two were going as a
German cameraman
and his assistant.
You still get us in that premiere?
You speak German better
than your friends? No.
Have I been shot? Yes.
I don't see me tripping the light
fantastique up a red
carpet anytime soon.
Least of all, by tomorrow night.
However, there's something
you don't know.
There've been two
recent developments
regarding Operation Kino.
One, the venue has
been changed from
The Ritz to a much smaller venue.
Enormous change at the last
minute? That's not very Germatic.
Why the hell is Goebbels doing
stuff so damn peculiar?
It probably has something to do
with the second development.
Which is?
Der Führer is attending
the premiere.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
I've been rethinking
my position...
in regards to your Paris
premiere of "Nation's Pride."
As the weeks have gone on...
and the Americans
are on the beach...
I do find myself thinking
more and more...
about this Private Zoller.
This boy has done something
tremendous for us.
And I'm beginning to think...
my participation in this
event could be meaningful.
Fuck a duck.
What are you thinking?
I'm thinking getting a whack
at planting old Uncle Adolf
makes this horse a
different colour.
What is that supposed to mean?
It means you getting
us in that premiere.
I'm probably going to
end up losing this leg.
Bye-bye, acting career.
Fun while it lasted.
How do you expect me to
walk the red carpet?
Doggy Doc's going to dig
that slug out your gam.
He's going to wrap
it up in a cast,
and you got a good "how I broke
my leg mountain climbing" story.
That's German, ain't it? You all
like climbing
mountains, don't you?
I don't. I like smoking, drinking
and ordering in restaurants.
But I see your point.
We fill you up with morphine
till it's coming out your ears
and just limp your little
ass up that rouge carpet.
I know this is a silly
question before I ask it,
but can you Americans speak any
other language than English?
We both speak a little Italian.
With an atrocious
accent, no doubt.
But that doesn't exactly
kill us in the crib.
Germans don't have a
good ear for Italian.
So you mumble Italian and brazen
through it. Is that the plan?
That's about it.
That sounds good.
It sounds like shit. What else
are we going to do? Go home?
No, that sounds good.
If you don't blow it, with that,
I can get you in the building.
Who does what?
Well, I speak the most Italian,
so I'll be your escort.
Donowitz speaks second most, so
he'll be your Italian cameraman.
Omar, third most. He'll
be Donny's assistant.
I don't speak Italian.
Like I said, third best. Just
keep your fucking mouth shut.
In fact, why don't you start
practising right now?
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
You've moved up in the world.
Look at you, Lieutenant
First Class.
And with your record of
insubordination. Truly remarkable.
And that one's name is...
Wilhelm Wicki.
He's an Austrian-born Jew, who
immigrated to the United States...
when things began turning
sour for the Israelites.
They are the two German-born
members of the Basterds.
They've been known to don German
uniforms, to ambush squads.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
What brings you all
the way out here?
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
But that doesn't look like this.
This is odd.
It would appear
somebody's missing.
Somebody fashionable.
Everybody out.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
"To Max, with love."
Bridget von Hammersmark.
Chapter Five
REVENGE OF THE GIANT FACE
Night of "NATION'S PRIDE" premiere
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Remember... in English.
Yes.
Action.
But how do we get it developed?
Only a suicidal idiot like us
would develop that footage.
And suppose someone would
develop the footage...
how do we get a 35mm
print with a soundtrack?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
We find somebody who
can develop and
process a 35mm print
with a soundtrack.
And we make them do it...
or we kill them.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Bring that fucker over here. Put
his head down on that table.
You either do what the
fuck we tell you...
or I'll bury this axe in
your collaborating skull.
(MAN SPEAKING FRENCH)
I'm not a collaborator.
Marcel, do his wife and
children know you?
Yes.
Then after we kill this
dog for the Germans...
we'll go and silence them.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Jannings, come on, show the ring.
Come on, come on. There you go.
Fredrick, have a look
at it. This is the
highest artistic
honour that I give.
Herr Doctor, I'm also
feeling very honoured.
You deserve it, my dear Jannings.
But I believe after the premiere
today, we have a new candidate.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Ah, Emmanuelle...
I'd like you to meet the
greatest actor in the world...
Emil Jannings.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Mademoiselle, I'm
pleased to meet you.
You have a beautiful cinema.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Thank you, Hermann.
Fräulein von Hammersmark.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Colonel Landa, it's been years.
Dashing as ever, I see.
So what's happened
to your lovely leg?
A by-product of kicking ass in
the German cinema, no doubt.
Save your flattery, you old dog.
I know too many of your former
conquests to fall
into that honey pot.
Seriously, what happened?
Well, I tried my hand,
foolishly I might add...
at mountain climbing.
And this is the result.
Mountain climbing?
That's how you injured your
leg, mountain climbing?
Believe it or not, yes it is.
Forgive me, Fräulein. I don't
mean to laugh at your misfortune.
It's just... mountain climbing?
I'm curious, Fräulein, what
could have ever compelled
you to undertake such a
foolhardy endeavour?
Well, I shan't be doing it
again, I can tell you that.
That cast looks as fresh
as my old Uncle Gustav.
When were you climbing
this mountain, last night?
Very good eye, Colonel.
It happened yesterday morning.
And where in Paris
is this mountain?
No, I'm just teasing
you, Fräulein.
You know me, I tease rough.
So, who are your three
handsome escorts?
I'm afraid neither three
speak a word of German.
They're friends of
mine from Italy.
This is a wonderful Italian
stuntman, Enzo Gorlomi.
A very talented cameraman,
Antonio Margheriti.
And Antonio's camera
assistant Dominick Decocco.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Gentlemen, this is an old friend,
Colonel Hans Landa of the SS.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Hello.
Gentlemen, it's a pleasure...
the friends of our cherished
star, admired by all of us,
this outright jewel
of our culture...
are naturally going to
be under my personal
protection for the
duration of their stay.
Thank you.
Gorlomi?
Am I saying it correctly?
Yes, correct.
Gorlomi?
Say it for me once please?
Gorlomi.
I'm sorry, again?
Once more?
Gorlomi.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
What's your name again?
Antonio Margheriti.
Again?
Margheriti.
One more time, but let me
really hear the music in it.
Margheriti.
And you?
Dominick Decocco.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Well, my two cameraman friends
need to find their seats.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Let me see your tickets.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
I suppose you getting
premiere tickets
for your friends wouldn't be
the most difficult thing...
for a star of your status.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
0023 and 0024.
That shouldn't be too
difficult to find, goodbye.
(ALL SAYING GOODBYE IN ITALIAN)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Ooh la la, Danielle Darrieux.
I have to go down and socialise
with these Hun pigs.
Let's go over it again.
Reel one is on the
first projector.
Reel two...
is on the second.
The third one is on the spool.
And the fourth one is ready to go.
Okay, the big sniper
battle in the film...
begins around the middle
of the third reel.
Our film comes in
on the fourth reel.
Somewhere towards the end
of the third reel...
go down and lock the
doors of the auditorium.
Then take your place behind the
screen and wait for my cue.
Then burn it down.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Take your seats.
The show is about to begin.
Everybody, please take your seats.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
We'll see you later.
(HANS SPEAKING GERMAN)
Not so fast.
A glass of champagne...
to toast "Nation's Pride."
My Fräulein, may I have a
word with you in private?
Certainly.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Excuse us.
(USHER CONTINUES
ANNOUNCING IN GERMAN)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Have a seat, my Fräulein.
May I?
Mademoiselle Mimieux allowed me...
to set up camp in her
office for the time being.
Let me see your foot.
I beg your pardon?
Put your foot in my lap.
Hans, you embarrass me.
Could you please reach into the
right pocket of my coat...
and give me what
you find in there.
May I?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
What's that American
expression? "If
the shoe fits, you must wear it."
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
What now, Colonel?
The guy in the white
smoking jacket.
Fucking shithead.
Faggot fuck. Fuck you.
Bunch of shithead fuck.
Fuck you, too.
Goddamn Nazi farts, sons of
bitches. Get your hands off me.
You fucking bratwurst-smelling...
God damn you. Get off.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Clever.
I informed the Führer that the
audience has taken their seats.
He should arrive any minute.
Thank you, Hans.
You Jerry-banging,
Limburg-smelling...
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Let go.
As Stanley said to Livingstone,
Lieutenant Aldo Raine, I presume?
Hans Landa.
You've had a nice long run, Aldo.
Alas, you're now in
the hands of the SS.
My hands to be exact.
And they've been waiting a
long time to touch you.
Caught you flinching.
Touch me again, Kraut-burger.
- Utivich?
- Is that you, Lieutenant?
Yeah.
Do you know what
happened to Donny?
Omar?
- The woman?
- No, I do not.
Tell me, Aldo, if I were
sitting where you're sitting,
would you show me mercy?
Nope.
What is that English expression
about shoes and feet?
"Looks like the shoe
is on the other
foot." Yeah, I was
just thinking that.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
You may leave us.
But stay alert outside.
So you're Aldo the Apache.
- So you're The Jew Hunter.
- I'm a detective.
A damn good detective.
Finding people is my speciality,
so naturally, I worked for
the Nazis finding people.
And, yes, some of them
were Jews. But Jew Hunter?
Just a name that stuck.
Well, you do have to
admit, it is catchy.
Do you control the nicknames
your enemies bestow on you?
Aldo the Apache and
the Little Man?
What do you mean the Little Man?
Germans' nickname for you.
The Germans' nickname for
me is the Little Man?
And as if to make my
point, I'm a little
surprised how tall you
were in real life.
I mean, you're a little fellow,
but not circus-midget little,
as your reputation would suggest.
Where's my men?
Where's Bridget von Hammersmark?
Well, let's just say, she
got what she deserved.
And when you purchase friends
like Bridget von Hammersmark,
you get what you pay for.
Now as far as your
paesanos, Sergeant
Donowitz and Private Omar...
How you know our names?
Lieutenant Aldo,
if you don't think I
wouldn't interrogate
every single one of your
swastika-marked survivors,
we simply aren't operating on the
level of mutual respect I assumed.
No, I guess not.
Well, back to the whereabouts
of your two Italian saboteurs.
As of this moment,
both Omar and Donowitz
should be sitting
in the very seats we left them in.
Double-zero 23 and double-zero
24, if my memory serves.
Explosives still around their
ankles, still ready to explode.
And your mission, some would
call a terrorist plot,
as of this moment, is still a go.
That's a pretty exciting story.
What's next? Eliza on Ice?
However,
all I have to do is pick
up this phone right here,
inform the cinema, and
your plan is kaput.
If they're still
here, and if they're
still alive, and
that's one big if,
there ain't no way
you're going to take
them boys without
setting off them bombs.
I have no doubt.
And, yes, some Germans will die.
Yes, it will ruin the evening.
And, yes, Goebbels will be
very, very, very mad at you
for what you've done
to his big night.
But you won't get Hitler,
you won't get Goebbels,
you won't get Göring, and
you won't get Bormann.
And you need all
four to end the war.
But if I don't pick up
this phone right here,
you may very well get all four.
And if you get all
four, you end the war
tonight.
So, gentlemen,
let's discuss the prospect
of ending the war tonight.
So, the way I see it,
since Hitler's death or possible
rescue rests solely
on my reaction,
if I do nothing,
it's as if I'm causing
his death even
more than yourselves.
Wouldn't you agree?
I guess so.
How about you, Utivich?
I guess so, too.
Gentlemen, I have no intention
of killing Hitler and
killing Goebbels
and killing Göring
and killing Bormann,
not to mention winning the war
single-handedly for the Allies,
only later to find myself standing
before a Jewish tribunal.
If you want to win
the war tonight,
we have to make a deal.
What kind of deal?
The kind you wouldn't have
the authority to make.
However, I'm sure this mission of
yours has a commanding officer.
A General.
I'm betting for...
OSS would be my guess.
That's a bingo.
Is that the way you say
it? "That's a bingo."
You just say, "Bingo."
Bingo. How fun.
But I digress. Where were
we? Yeah. Make a deal.
Over there is a very
capable two-way
radio and sitting behind it
is a more than capable radio
operator named Hermann.
Get me someone on the
other end of that radio
with the power of the
pen to authorise my,
let's call it, the terms of
my conditional surrender.
If that tastes better going down.
You know, where I'm from...
Yeah? Where is that exactly?
Maynardville, Tennessee.
I've done my share of bootlegging.
Up there, if you engage
in what the federal
government calls illegal activity,
but what we call just a man trying
to make a living for his family
selling moonshine liquor, it
behoves oneself to keep his wits.
Long story short, we hear a
story too good to be true,
it ain't.
Sitting in your chair, I would
probably say the same thing,
and 999,999 times out of a
million, you would be correct.
But in the pages of history,
every once in a while,
fate reaches out and
extends its hand.
What shall the history books read?
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
I implore you. We must
destroy that tower.
Sarge, that tower...
The tower stands.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Gum?
Psst. Psst.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
It's time.
I should go lock
the auditorium and
take my place behind the screen.
So when the military history
of this night is written,
it will be recorded that I
was part of Operation Kino
from the very beginning
as a double agent.
Anything I've done in my
guise as an SS Colonel
was sanctioned by the
OSS as a necessary evil
to establish my cover
with the Germans.
And it was my placement of
Lieutenant Raine's dynamite
in Hitler and Goebbels' opera
box that assured their demise.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
I informed the Führer that the
audience has taken their seats.
He should arrive any minute.
Thank you, Hans.
By the way, that last
part is actually true.
I want my full
military pension and
benefits under my proper rank.
I want to receive the
Congressional Medal of Honour
for my invaluable assistance in
the toppling of the Third Reich.
In fact, I want all the
members of Operation Kino
to receive the Congressional
Medal of Honour.
Full citizenship for myself.
Well, that goes without saying.
And I would like the
United States of America
to purchase property for
me on Nantucket Island
as a reward for all the
countless lives I've saved
by bringing the tyranny of
the National Socialist Party
to a swifter-than-imagined end.
Do you have all that, sir?
I look forward to seeing you
face to face as well, sir.
Lieutenant Raine? Right here.
Yes, sir.
Colonel Landa will
put you and Private
Utivich in a truck as prisoners.
Then he and his radio
operator will get
in the truck and
drive to our lines.
Upon crossing our
lines, Colonel Landa
and his man will surrender to you.
You will then take over
driving of the truck
and bring them straight to me for
debriefing. Is that
clear, Lieutenant?
Yes, sir.
Over and out.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Herr Dr Goebbels, excuse me.
Could I go out for a moment?
Perfectly understandable, my boy.
You go now, and we'll
see you after the show.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Who is it?
Fredrick.
Shit.
Are you the manager of this
cinema? I want my money back.
That actor in the movie stinks.
What are you doing here?
I came to visit you.
Can't you see how busy I am?
Then allow me to lend an assist.
Fredrick, it's not funny,
you can't be here.
This is your premiere, you need
to be out there with them.
Normally, you would be right.
And for all the
other films I do...
I intend to endure evenings like
tonight, in the proper spirit.
However, the fact remains...
this film is based on
my military exploits.
And in this case, my exploits
consisted of killing many men.
Consequently, the part of the
film that's playing now...
I don't like watching this part.
- I am sorry, Fredrick, but...
- So, I thought...
I'd come up here and
do what I do best...
annoy you.
And from the look on your face, it
would appear I haven't
lost my touch.
Are you so used to the
Nazis kissing your ass...
you've forgotten what
the word "no" means?
No... you can't be here.
Now go away.
Fredrick, you hurt me.
Well, it's nice to know
you can feel something.
Even if it's just physical pain.
I'm not a man you
say, "go away" to.
There's over three hundred
dead bodies in Italy,
that if they could,
would testify to that.
After what I've done for you...
you disrespect me at your peril.
Lock the door.
What?
We don't have much time.
Time for what?
Forget it.
No, no, no... wait.
You want me to... lock the door?
For the fifty-seventh time, yes.
When I kill that guy, you got
30 feet to get to that guard.
- Can you do it?
- I have to.
Champagne?
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Extraordinary my dear,
simply extraordinary.
This is your finest film yet.
Thank you, my Führer.
Thank you.
Who wants to send a
message to Germany?
I have a message for Germany.
That you are all going to die.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Enough. Stop it.
Turn off the projector.
And I want you to
look deep into the
face of the Jew who's
going to do it.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
I don't know what's going on.
That does not belong in my movie.
Marcel, burn it down.
Yes, Shosanna.
My name is Shosanna Dreyfus,
and this is the face
of Jewish vengeance.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
These are the American
lines, Colonel sir.
Excellent, Hermann.
Hermann, uncuff them.
I'm officially surrendering myself
over to you, Lieutenant Raine.
We're your prisoners.
How about my knife?
Thank you very much, Colonel.
Utivich, cuff the Colonel's
hands behind his back.
Is that really necessary?
I'm a slave to appearances.
Scalp Hermann.
Are you mad?
What have you done?
I made a deal with your
General for that man's life.
Yeah, they made that
deal. But they don't
give a fuck about
him. They need you.
You'll be shot for this.
Nah, I don't think
so. More like chewed
out. I've been chewed out before.
You know, Utivich and myself heard
that deal you made with the brass.
End the war tonight?
I'd make that deal.
How about you, Utivich?
You make that deal?
I'd make that deal.
I don't blame you. Damn good deal.
And that pretty little nest
you feathered for yourself.
Well, if you're willing to
barbecue the whole High Command,
I suppose that's worth
certain considerations.
But I do have one question.
When you get to your little
place on Nantucket Island,
I imagine you are going
to take off that
handsome-looking SS
uniform of yours.
Ain't you?
That's what I thought.
Now, that I can't abide.
How about you, Utivich,
can you abide it?
Not one damn bit, sir.
I mean, if I had my way,
you'd wear that
goddamn uniform for
the rest of your
pecker-sucking life.
But I'm aware that
ain't practical.
I mean, at some point, you're
going to have to take it off.
So,
I'm going to give you a little
something you can't take off.
You know something, Utivich?
I think this just might
be my masterpiece.