War began between Germany
and France on August 3rd 1914.
Five weeks later
the German army had smashed its way
to within 18 miles of Paris.
There, the battered French rallied
their forces at the Marne river
and, in a series of
unexpected counterattacks,
drove the Germans back.
The front was stabilised,
then shortly afterwards
developed into a continuous
line of heavily fortified trenches,
zigzagging their way 500 miles
from the English Channel
to the Swiss frontier.
By 1916, after two grisly years
of trench warfare,
the battle lines had changed very little.
Successful attacks were
measured in hundreds of yards,
and paid for in lives
by hundreds of thousands.
General Bollard, sir.
- Hello, George. How are you?
- Paul. Wonderful seeing you again.
Well, this is splendid.
Superb!
I try to create a pleasant atmosphere
in which to work.
You've succeeded marvellously. I wish
I had your taste in carpets and pictures.
You're much too kind, George.
Sit down, George.
I haven't done very much.
The place is much the same
as it was when I moved in.
Paul, I've come to see you
about something big.
It's top-secret. It must go no further
than your Chief of Staff, and not to him,
- unless you can trust his discretion.
- Of course.
A group of armies is forming
on this front for an offensive very soon.
Headquarters is determined to make
a breakthrough. Why are you smiling?
I'm sorry. I thought for a moment
I knew what you were going to say.
Please go on.
I never knew you were a mind-reader.
What did you think I was about to say?
- Something about the Ant Hill.
- You are a mind-reader.
Well, it is a key position.
It's in my sector.
To be perfectly honest,
I've heard some talk.
You know there's nothing really
secret around headquarters.
Well, what do you think?
It's the key to the German position
in this sector.
They've held onto it for a year now.
And it looks as if
they'll hold onto it for another year.
Paul, I have formal orders to take
the Ant Hill no later than the 10th,
that's the day after tomorrow.
That comes pretty close to being
ridiculous, don't you think?
I don't imagine I would be here
if I really thought that.
Paul, if there's one man in this army
who can do this for me, it's you.
It's out of the question, George.
Absolutely out of the question.
My division was cut to pieces.
What's left of it is in no position
to hold the Ant Hill, let alone take it.
I'm sorry, but that's the truth.
Well, Paul, there was something else
I wanted to tell you.
But you may misunderstand
my motives in mentioning it.
What was it?
You'd be bound to misunderstand.
However, as your friend,
maybe I should tell you.
- What are you trying to say, George?
- Paul...
the talk around headquarters is that you
are being considered for the 12th Corps.
- The 12th Corps?
- Yes, and with that, another star.
I've pushed it all I can.
The 12th Corps needs a fighting
general and you're overdue another star.
We both know that your record is good
enough for you to refuse this assignment
on the grounds you've stated.
No one would question your opinion.
They'd simply get
someone else to do the job.
So you shouldn't let this
influence your opinion, Paul.
- Oh, I'm sorry. Have a cognac?
- No, thanks. Not before dinner.
George, I'm responsible
for the lives of 8,000 men.
What is my ambition against that?
What is my reputation
in comparison to that?
My men come first of all, George,
- and those men know it, too.
- I know that they do.
You see, George. Those men
know I would never let them down.
That goes without saying.
The life of one soldier means more to me
than all the stars and declarations
and honours in France.
So...
you think this attack is absolutely beyond
the ability of your men at this time?
I didn't say that, George.
Nothing is beyond those men
once their fighting spirit is aroused.
Paul, I don't want to push you
into it if you think it's ill-advised.
Don't worry, George.
You couldn't do that if you tried.
Of course, artillery would
make an enormous difference.
- What artillery support can you give me?
- I'll see.
- What about replacements?
- We'll see what we can do,
but I feel sure you can get along
with what you have.
We might just do it.
Paul, I knew that I was right
to come to you.
You are the man to take the Ant Hill.
Now, as for that star is concerned...
That had nothing
to do with my decision.
- If anything, it'd sway me the other way.
- I realise that perfectly.
- Now, when do you see this coming on?
- No later than the day after tomorrow.
We just might do it.
Hello there, soldier.
Ready to kill more Germans?
Yes, sir.
- What's your name, soldier?
- Sir, Private Ferol, Company A.
- Are you married?
- No, sir.
- Well, I'll bet your mother's proud of you.
- Yes, sir.
Well, carry on, Private.
And good luck to you.
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
Hello there, soldier.
Ready to kill more Germans?
Yes, sir.
Working over your rifle, I see. That's
the way. It's a soldier's best friend.
You be good to it,
and it'll always be good to you.
- Well, good luck to you, soldier.
- Carry on.
- Thank you, sir.
Hello there, soldier.
Ready to kill more Germans?
Is everything all right, soldier?
- All right? Yes, sir. I'm all right.
- Ah-ha. Good fella.
- Are you married, soldier?
- Married? Me married?
Yes. Have you got a wife?
- A wife? Have I got a wife?
- Sir, he's a bit shell-shocked.
I beg your pardon, Sergeant.
There is no such thing as shell shock.
Have you got a wife, soldier?
My wife? My wife.
Yes, I have a wife. I'm never going to
see her again. I'm going to be killed.
Get a grip on yourself.
You're acting like a coward!
- I am a coward.
- Snap out of it, soldier!
Sergeant, arrange for the immediate
transfer of this baby out of my regiment!
I won't have other brave men
contaminated by him!
- Yes, sir.
- Carry on, Sergeant.
You were right, sir. This sort of thing
can spread if it isn't checked.
You know General, I'm convinced
that these tours of yours
have an incalculable effect
upon the morale of these men.
In think the fighting spirit
of the 701st derives from it.
No, Major, that spirit
was just born in them.
The general is coming, sir.
- Always a pleasure to see you, Colonel.
- I'm honoured, General.
Well, quite a neat little
spot you have here.
I'll reserve comment on
the neatness, sir, but it is little.
- Pretty shy on seating accommodation.
- More than enough for me.
Never got the habit of sitting.
Like to be on my feet.
- Keep on the move.
- I can vouch for that, Colonel.
I can hardly get the general behind a desk
long enough to sign an order.
That's the way I am, Dax.
I can't understand these armchair officers.
Fellas trying to fight a war from behind
a desk. Waving papers at the enemy!
Worrying whether a mouse is
going to run up their pants leg.
If I had the choice between mice and
Mausers, I'd take the mice every time.
You'll never make me believe that, Colonel.
Seriously, though,
if a man's a ninny, let him put on
a dress and hide under the bed.
But if he wants to be a soldier,
then by heavens, he's got to be one.
He's got to fight, and he can't do that
unless he's where the fighting is.
- That's my credo.
- I think I have to agree with you,
- presenting your case so convincingly, sir.
- You never fail to live up to it, sir.
I imagine you'd like a look around,
would you.
Yes, Colonel.
Here's something to see - the Ant Hill.
It's as good a view as you can get
without actually being there.
That won't be long now, will it?
Hm. Yeah.
Well, I've seen much more formidable
objectives. Much, much worse.
Not something we can grab and run
away with, but certainly pregnable.
- Sounds kind of odd, though, doesn't it?
- Why?
- Like something to do with giving birth.
- Oh, yes. Quite.
You're right on your toes this morning.
Even sharper than usual.
We mustn't forget the colonel was perhaps
the foremost criminal lawyer
in all France.
Gentlemen, you're both much too kind.
Tell me, Colonel, how did your relief
come off last night?
We drew some artillery. 29 casualties, sir.
Yes, noticed it on the road in.
Utterly inexcusable. Stupid.
All swarmed together like flies,
waiting for someone to swat them.
They never learn. They get in a tight spot
under heavy fire, gang up every time.
Herd instinct, I suppose.
Kind of a lower animal sort of thing.
A human sort of thing, it seems to me.
Don't you make a distinction, Major?
Yes, very regrettable, of course.
Very. Yes, indeed.
Major, would you be kind enough
to excuse us for a few minutes?
Yes, sir. Of course.
Colonel.
Well, Colonel, what do you think of it?
- What do I think of what, sir?
- The Ant Hill.
Colonel, your regiment is going
to take the Ant Hill tomorrow.
- You know the condition of my men, sir.
- Men will have to be killed.
Possibly a lot of them.
They absorb bullets and shrapnel,
making it possible
for others to get through.
- What support will we have?
- I have none to give you.
What sort of casualties
do you anticipate, sir?
Say 5% killed by our own barrage.
That's a very generous allowance.
10% more in getting
through no-man's-land,
and 20% more getting through the wire.
That leaves 65%
with the worst part of the job over.
Let's say another 25%
in actually taking the Ant Hill.
We're still left with a force
more than adequate to hold it.
You're saying that more than
half my men will be killed.
Yes, it's a terrible price to pay, Colonel,
but we will have the Ant Hill.
- But will we, sir?
- I'm depending on you, Colonel.
All France is depending on you.
Am I amusing you, Colonel?
I'm not a bull, General. I don't need a flag
waving in front of me to get me to charge.
I don't like a comparison of the flag of
France to a bullfighter's cape.
I meant no disrespect to our flag.
Patriotism may be old-fashioned,
but show me a patriot
and I'll show you an honest man.
Everyone always thought so.
Samuel Johnson had something else
to say about patriotism.
And what was that, may I ask?
- Nothing, really.
- What do you mean, "nothing, really"?
Sir, nothing really important.
Colonel, when I ask a question,
it's always important.
- Now who was this man?
- Samuel Johnson, sir.
What did he have to say about patriotism?
That it was the last refuge of a scoundrel,
sir. I'm sorry, I meant nothing personal.
You're tired, Dax. You're very tired.
It's you who are exhausted, not your men.
And it's my fault. I've given you
one impossible task after another.
- You need rest.
- I haven't said...
You never would, so you aren't
going to have any say-so about it, Colonel.
As from now, I'm ordering you
on indefinite furlough.
General, you can't take me away
from my men. You can't do that to me, Sir.
Not to you, Dax. For you.
- For your good and the good of your men.
- The good of my men, sir?
If a commanding officer lacks confidence,
what can we expect of his men?
Naturally, I don't want to relieve you,
but I must have your enthusiastic support.
Not once have you said
that your men can take the Ant Hill.
We'll take the Ant Hill.
If any soldiers in the world can take it,
we'll take the Ant Hill.
And when you do, your men will
be relieved and get a long rest.
Corporal Paris and Private Lejeune
reporting, sir.
- You took your time about it.
- We prepared as quick as we could, sir.
- We had to alert the sentries.
- All right. You men at ease.
This is a reconnaissance patrol.
German wire,
machine-gun posts,
identification of bodies.
There will only be the three of us.
We're to avoid a fight if we can.
We go out to the left and we come
back through post six on the right.
- Is everything all clear at post six?
- All the sentries have been warned.
Number six will send up flares
at 10-minute intervals starting at 04:00.
- I wanted them every five minutes.
- I told them that, sir.
The sergeant says
every five minutes is too much.
- He says it's certain to draw artillery.
- Quite a strategist, this sergeant.
- What's his name?
- I don't know, sir.
All right. You men wait outside.
I'll join you in a minute.
Would you mind telling us the password,
sir?
- Calais.
- Yes, sir.
- He's fortifying himself.
- It smelled like heaven.
I can always tell when he's had a few.
He gets sarcastic.
At least he could have
passed it around, the pig.
What's he got against you, anyway?
We went to school together
before the war.
He thinks I don't have enough
respect for him. He's right.
If you gentlemen are ready.
Colonel.
- Everything clear and understood?
- Yes, sir.
The lane through our Wire's in front here.
Machine gun's pointing at the opening.
- Good luck, men.
- Thank you, sir.
All right, men. Let's go.
- What's that?
- I don't know.
Lejeune, move out and look
that over. We'll cover you.
Split up a night patrol?
Move out, Lejeune.
- I don't like this. Let's get outta here.
- We haven't given him enough time.
- If we wait any longer, they'll get us too.
- We've gotta wait for him.
He must be dead! Where is he?
- Well!
- Surprised, Lieutenant?
Yes, I am. Happily surprised.
I thought you'd been killed.
- You didn't wait to find out, did you?
- Look here, what do you mean?
I mean you ran like a rabbit
after you killed Lejeune.
Killed Lejeune?
What are you talking about?
I don't think I like your tone.
You're speaking to an officer.
Remember that.
Well, I must be mistaken, then, sir.
An officer wouldn't do that.
A man wouldn't do it. Only a thing would.
A sneaky, booze-guzzling,
yellow-bellied rat
with a bottle for a brain
and a streak of spit...
- That's enough, Corporal.
- You've got yourself into a mess.
I have, have I?
You've got yourself in a worse one.
First, general insubordination.
Second, threatening your superior officer.
Third, refusing to obey an order
and inciting others to do the same.
How do you think those charges
will look on paper?
Not half as bad as these:
endangering the lives of your men
through recklessness, drunk on duty,
wanton murder of one of your own men,
and cowardice in the face of the enemy.
Phillip, have you ever tried to bring
charges against an officer?
It's my word against yours, you know.
Whose word do you think
they're gonna believe?
Let me put it another way. Whose word
do you think they're going to accept?
Now, I'll tell you what I'm willing to do.
S0 far, all I have written in this report
is that you and Lejeune
were killed while out on patrol.
I'll fix this to read
that you made your way back
after becoming separated
during the skirmish.
That'll end the matter...
You killed Lejeune.
You know that, don't you?
I'm sorry. It was an accident.
I'd give anything in the world if it
hadn't happened and that's the truth.
Honestly, I know you don't like me, but
what kind of a man do you think I am?
- Oh, good morning, Colonel.
- At ease, men.
I've been waiting for your report,
Lieutenant.
Well, I think we found out a thing or two.
- Everything go well?
- No, sir. Private Lejeune was killed.
- How did it happen?
- It's all right here in the report, sir.
- Let's have it.
- It isn't quite finished yet, sir.
That's all, Corporal.
You did a good night's work.
Should feel very proud of yourself.
- Go get some sleep.
- Yes, sir.
- How did you lose Lejeune?
- Machine-gun fire, sir.
He coughed. Almost got us all killed.
Finish that report
and get it to me immediately.
Yes, sir.
The artillery starts at 05:15.
The 1st Battalion will move out at 05:30.
When the leading elements
have cleared the German wires,
the second wave consisting of-
the 2nd and 3rd Battalions minus
two companies in reserve - will move out,
in no case later than 05:40.
That's it, gentlemen.
Are there any questions?
Sir, is 15 minutes of artillery
preparation all that we can expect?
The feeling is that any more than that will
give them too much time to get organised.
What's weather supposed
to be like tomorrow, sir?
- Too good.
- No chance of rain or fog?
The forecast is for sun all day.
If... Perhaps I should say
when we take the Ant Hill
how long do we have to hold it
before we can expect any support?
General Mireau, who will be
personally observing the attack,
has promised support from
the 72nd by sundown tomorrow,
which means, of course,
that we'll have to hold all day.
Are there any more questions?
Well, gentlemen, good luck. I'm sure
you'll come through as you always do.
Let's get some sleep.
I'm not afraid of dying tomorrow,
only of getting killed.
- That's as clear as mud.
- Which would you rather be done in by?
- A bayonet or a machine gun?
- A machine gun.
That's just my point. They're both
pieces of steel ripping into you,
only the machine gun is quicker,
cleaner and less painful.
- What does that prove?
- It proves that most of us are more afraid
of getting hurt than of getting killed.
Look at Bernard. He panics when it comes
to gas. Gas doesn't bother me a bit.
He's seen photos of gas cases -
doesn't mean anything to me.
But I'll tell you something. I'd hate
like the devil to be without my tin hat.
But I don't mind
not having a tin hat for my tail.
Why? Because I know a wound in the
head would hurt more than one in the tail.
The tail is just meat.
But the head is all bone.
- Speak for yourself.
- Tell me this.
Aside from the bayonet,
what are you most afraid of?
- High explosives.
- Exactly! It's the same with me,
because I know that it can chew
you up worse than anything else.
Look, it's what I'm trying to tell you.
If you're really afraid of dying,
you'd be living in a funk
all the rest of your life
because you know
you've got to go someday, anyday.
And if it's death you're afraid of, why
should you care about what kills you?
You're too smart for me, professor.
All I know is, nobody wants to die.
Through to Division, sir.
Through to Polygon.
Everything quiet.
All units report themselves ready.
Zero minus two.
- May I offer you gentlemen some cognac?
- Thank you, sir.
After you, sir.
To France.
Minus 15... 14... 13...
10, 9, 8, 7,
6, 5, 4, 3,
2, 1... zero!
- Sergeant, where's B Company?
- I don't know, sir.
- Where in heaven's name are they?
- On the left...
Where are the rest? Zero plus one,
and they're still in the trenches.
Now they're advancing.
Miserable cowards.
They're not advancing!
The barrage is getting away from them!
They're still in the trenches!
Yes, sir.
- Captain Nichols.
- Yes, sir?
Order the 75s to commence
firing on our own positions.
Captain, do you fail to comprehend
the meaning of my order?
No, sir, but... I respectfully ask to...
Captain, do you fail to comprehend
the meaning of my order?
No, sir.
- Then carry it out, Captain.
- Yes, sir.
Hello, Polygon? This is Division.
Batteries 1 and 2 commence firing...
on coordinates 32-58-78.
Batteries 1 and 2 to commence
firing on coordinates 32-58-78. Over.
General, the battery commander reports
those are our own positions.
- He says it must be a mistake.
- Confirm the order, Captain.
The order is confirmed.
Battery commander respectfully reports
he cannot execute such an order
unless it is in writing
and signed by the general. Over.
Battery commander respectfully reports
he cannot execute
such an order unless it is in writing,
- and signed by the general.
- Give me that phone!
- General Mireau speaking!
- Battery commander speaking.
The troops are mutinying,
refusing to advance.
Fire as ordered until further notice!
With all respect, you have no right
to order me to shoot down my own men
unless you are willing to take
full and undivided responsibility for it.
Captain Rousseau,
will you obey my order?
I must have a written order before
I can execute such a command, sir.
Supposing you're killed. Where will I be?
In front of a firing squad
tomorrow morning, that's where you'll be!
Hand over your command and report
yourself under arrest to my headquarters.
Roget! Lieutenant Roget,
why are your men still in here?
- It's impossible, sir. Major Vignon is dead.
- Get these men out of the trenches!
Come on! Let's get ready for another try.
- Get these men outta here!
- I tried three times.
All right! Let's give it another try!
Come on! Let's give it another try!
It's impossible, sir.
All the men are falling back.
Sir, I respectfully
submit to the colonel...
Pardon me. Your remarks to me
were very unfair, sir.
It's just impossible.
According to reports,
the attack has failed all along the line.
The men are falling back
to our own trenches.
Major Saint-Auban, arrange for the
immediate relief of the 701st Regiment.
Have them sent to the Château de I'Aigle.
Have Colonel Dax report to me.
Major Couderc, assemble
a general court martial.
Have it ready to meet at 3 o'clock
tomorrow afternoon.
If those little sweethearts won't face
German bullets, they'll face French ones!
I ordered an attack.
Your troops refused to attack.
The troops did attack, sir,
but they could make no headway.
Because they didn't try. I saw it myself.
Half of your men never left the trenches.
A third of my men were pinned down
because the fire was so intense.
Don't quibble over fractions, Colonel.
The fact remains that a good part of
your men never left their own trenches.
Colonel Dax, I'm going to have 10 men
from each company in your regiment
tried under penalty of death
for cowardice.
- Penalty of death...?
- For cowardice!
They have skimmed milk in their veins
instead of blood.
It's the reddest milk I've ever seen.
My trenches...
- That's enough...
- I'm not gonna mince words...
Colonel Dax,
if you continue in this manner,
I shall have to place you under arrest.
I believe the colonel has a point,
even though he makes it bluntly.
This is not a trial,
but it does bear certain aspects of one.
Colonel Dax technically is cast in the role
of the defence.
In view of the gravity of the charges,
a court of law would grant him all
possible latitude in presenting his case.
Latitude is one thing,
insubordination another.
I am merely offering an opinion. Please
do not feel constrained to accept it.
I'm perfectly willing to accept it,
General Broulard.
I'm sorry, sir. I certainly
didn't intend to be insubordinate.
My only aim is
to remind you of the heroism
these men have shown
on every occasion in the past.
We're not talking about the past,
we're talking about the present.
Don't you see, sir, they're not cowards.
If some didn't leave the trenches,
it must have been
because it was impossible.
They were ordered to attack.
It was their duty to obey that order.
We can't leave it up to the men to decide
when an order is possible or not.
If it was impossible, the only proof would
be their dead bodies lying in the trenches.
They're scum, Colonel.
The whole rotten regiment.
A pack of sneaking,
whining, tail-dragging curs.
- Do you really believe that, sir?
- Yes, I do. That's exactly what I believe.
And what's more,
it's an incontestable fact.
Then why not shoot the entire regiment?
I'm perfectly serious.
Now, Colonel,
you're missing the point entirely.
We don't want to slaughter the French
army. All we want to do is set an example.
- If it's an example you want, take me.
- Take you?
Yes, sir. If it's an example you want,
one man will do as well as a 100.
The logical choice is the officer
most responsible for the attack.
Now, Colonel, I think you're overwrought.
This is not a question of officers.
Paul, we don't want to overdo this thing.
Suppose we just make it a dozen?
I was talking of 100 men.
Now we're down to 12.
Let's not haggle over this thing anymore.
Let's get it settled once and for all
so that we can all live with it.
Well, perhaps I was a bit too anxious
to see properjustice meted out.
I've spent my entire life in the army.
I've always tried
to be true to my principles.
That's the only mistake
I can ever be accused of.
I'll settle for this: have the company
commanders select one man
from each company
in the first wave - three in all.
That's very reasonable of you, Paul.
The court martial will meet at the chateau
at three o'clock this afternoon.
- Will that be convenient for you?
- I won't be there, Paul.
- You won't be there?
- I think it best that you handle this matter.
Probably so.
General Mireau, if possible, I'd like to
be appointed counsellor for the accused.
- I'll take the matter under consideration.
- We can permit that, Paul.
- Consider it settled, Colonel.
- Thank you, sir.
Noon straight up. I hope
you can stay for lunch, Colonel.
George, I'm afraid
the colonel won't have time.
Don't deny it, Paul.
You've been hiding this man.
Keeping him for your own.
I think that was very selfish of you.
Thank you for your courtesy,
General
but I'm afraid there isn't much time
between now and three o'clock.
Of course, Colonel. I shall look forward
to the pleasure of seeing you again.
Yes, Captain?
They ordered me to report
to you here. Captain Rousseau.
Yes, of course.
I wanted to speak to you
about some of your shells falling short.
I haven't time to go into it now.
Report back to your command
until further orders.
- Bad stuff. Demoralises the men.
- I quite agree with you.
The best solution is to shelve him
to another outfit.
A court of inquiry
ought to roast him a bit first.
In cases like this, shells falling short,
I always try to avoid an inquiry.
It gets around among the men
and makes a bad impression.
Shelving would be the best discipline
in my opinion.
Well, perhaps you're right.
Would you excuse me for a moment?
A regimental matter
I want to mention to the colonel.
- I'll join you in the dining room.
- Splendid. In a moment.
That'll be Captain Sancy,
Captain Renoir and Lieutenant Roget...
Yes, sir.
...to meet me at regimental
headquarters in half an hour.
- Yes, sir!
- Colonel Dax!
Yes, General?
- I'd like a word with you.
- Certainly, sir.
Best be sensible about this.
Sensible, sir?
Listen to me, Dax. Give up
this fancy talk with me, you understand?
Colonel Broulard seems
to think you're funny. I don't.
- I want you to drop this affair.
- I beg your pardon, sir, is that an order?
Colonel Dax, when this mess
is cleaned up, I'll break you.
I'll find an excuse and
break through the ranks. I'll ruin you!
It'll be just what you deserve, showing so
little loyalty to your commanding officer.
That's all, Colonel.
General Mireau feels that the attack
on the Ant Hill yesterday morning
failed because of an inadequate effort
on the part of the 1st Battalion.
Each of you is to select one man from
your company, place him under arrest,
and have him ready to appear
before a general court martial
no later than 15:00 hours this afternoon.
The charge is cowardice
in the face of the enemy.
You have your orders, gentlemen.
Let's carry them out.
Lieutenant Roget killed Lejeune
on that patrol
and then blackmailed me into
keeping quiet about the whole thing!
That's why he picked me.
I understand your feelings,
but that has nothing to do
with these charges you're being tried for.
- Don't you believe me, sir?
- Yes, I do.
But who else will?
You've got no witnesses.
Besides, such charges against an officer
would only antagonise the court.
When this is over, I'm going
into the story of that patrol again.
Sir, in my case, Captain Renoir
had the sergeant draw lots.
I was picked purely by chance.
You're lucky. Look at me.
I was just picked because Captain Sancy
said I was a social undesirable.
Me, a social undesirable.
- I didn't act like a coward!
- Neither did I!
Gentlemen, you must understand that
the reason you were picked is immaterial.
Whatever the reason,
you're on trial for your lives.
Stick to the stories you've told me. Don't
let the prosecutor shake you out of it.
You'll be soldiers in
the presence of superior officers,
so act like what you are - soldiers.
And brave ones at that.
I've been in the room you'll be sitting in.
The afternoon sun will be in your faces,
so don't let it seem as if you're dropping
your eyes in a hangdog manner.
When you answer questions,
look the judges in the eye.
Don't whine, plead or
make speeches - that's my job.
Simple statements - short, but make them
so they can be heard all over the room.
Try not to repeat yourselves.
I'll do that for you when I sum up.
We haven't much time.
The court martial begins in an hour
and I've got notes to look at.
Good luck.
Thank you, sir.
The court martial is open.
The prisoners may be seated.
This is a general court martial, so we shall
dispense with unnecessary formalities.
These men are charged with
cowardice in the face of the enemy,
and will be tried for that offence.
- Mr. Prosecutor?
- Call the accused. Private Ferol.
Mr. President, will the prosecutor
question the witnesses
without even reading the indictment?
Please don't take up
the court's time with technicalities.
The indictment is lengthy,
and there's no point in reading it.
The defence has a right
to know the exact...
the indictment is that the accused
showed cowardice
in the face of the enemy
during the attack on the Ant Hill.
Proceed, Mr. Prosecutor.
Call the accused, Private Ferol.
- Private Ferol.
- Yes, sir.
Were you in the first wave
during the attack on the Ant Hill?
Yes, sir.
- Did you refuse to advance?
- No, sir.
- Did you advance?
- Yes, sir.
- How far did you advance?
- To about the middle of no-man's-land, sir.
Then what did you do?
- There were machine-gun bullets...
- Answer the question. What did you do?
Well... I saw that me and Meyer...
I didn't ask you what you saw.
The court has no concern
with your visual experiences.
My what, sir?
- The prisoner will reply to the question.
- Yes, sir. What question was it?
You advanced to the middle of
no-man's-land. What did you do then?
- Then, sir?
- Did you go back or forward?
I went back, sir.
In other words, Private Ferol,
you retreated.
Yes, sir.
That's all.
The accused may return to his seat.
Just a minute.
Mr. President, I'd like
to question the witness, if I may.
- Proceed, Colonel.
- Thank you.
Private, when you reached no-man's-land,
were you alone with Private Meyer?
Yes, sir.
What happened to
the rest of your company?
I don't know, sir.
I guess they had been killed or wounded.
You found yourself in the middle of
no-man's-land alone with Private Meyer.
Yes, sir.
Why didn't you attack
the Ant Hill single-handed?
Why didn't you storm the Ant Hill alone?
Just me and Meyer? You're kidding, sir.
Yes, I'm kidding, Private Ferol.
Thank you. That's all.
I don't see the point
of this line of questioning?
I'm attempting to indicate, sir,
the utter absurdity
of the line of questioning
used by the prosecutor.
Mr. Prosecutor.
So you freely admit, Private Ferol,
that you retreated.
Yes, sir. Me and Meyer both.
I knew we should have took Ant Hill
but we came on back.
That's all.
The accused may return to his seat.
Private Arnaud.
- Did you advance?
- Yes, sir.
Until I was ordered back
to the trenches by Captain Renoir.
- How far did you advance?
- Into the wire, sir.
The... enemy wire, I suppose?
No, sir. It was our wire.
You mean to tell me that you didn't
advance any further than our wire?
No, sir, I didn't.
How far would you say that was?
How many metres?
I advanced as far as I could.
- How many metres?
- Not many.
Not many.
Now, Private Arnaud.
Before you were ordered back, did you
urge your fellow soldiers forward?
Most of them were dead or wounded
before they got three steps
beyond the trenches.
- Reply to the question.
- I didn't urge them on. No, sir.
Thank you.
Private Arnaud.
At ease, please.
Aside from your sad failure
to give throat to spirited battle cries,
did your behaviour differ from
that of other men in your company?
Objection.
That's a matter of conjecture.
Sustained.
Did any men in your company
get beyond our wire?
No, sir.
Is it true that you've
been designated a coward
simply and purely because you drew
a slip of paper marked "X"?
- Yes, sir.
- I don't see that that's significant.
It's accepted practice in the French army
to pick examples by lot.
And since this entire company
advanced only a few metres,
picking by lot
was eminently fair in this case.
I'd like to point out that this soldier
has distinguished himself
in some of the bloodiest battles
of the war.
With court permission,
I'll read citations for bravery
that he's already earned
on two occasions.
First, citations in the orders in the army
for bravery...
That's immaterial, Colonel.
The accused is not being tried for former
bravery, but for his recent cowardice.
Medals are no defence.
- May I call witnesses to his character?
- You may not.
But you may call witnesses to the effect
that he reached the German wire.
Mr. President, no one
in the entire regiment
got anywhere near the German wire,
including myself.
Call the next accused...
if you're through, Colonel.
Thank you.
The prisoner may return to his seat.
S0 you never even left the trenches?
- No, sir.
- That's all.
Corporal Paris, why didn't
you leave the trenches?
Major Vignon was shot and he fell back
on top of me, sir, and knocked me cold.
Were you lying unconscious in
the trenches during the entire attack?
Yes, sir.
That's all.
Have you any witnesses to that?
No, sir. I guess everybody
was too busy to notice me,
and there were so many others
lying dead anyway.
- But you have no witnesses?
- No, sir.
I only have a rather large cut
on my head, sir.
That could have been self-inflicted later.
Thank you. You may stand down.
Mr. Prosecutor,
you can make your plea now.
Gentlemen of the court,
this case speaks for itself.
All of us witnessed
the regrettable attack yesterday morning.
And I submit that that attack
was a stain on the flag of France,
a blot on the honour of every man,
woman and child in the French nation.
It is to us that the sad,
distressing, repellent duty falls.
Gentlemen, I ask this court
to find the accused guilty,
and impose the penalties prescribed
by the code of military justice.
Thank you, Mr. Prosecutor.
Colonel, would you like
to make your plea?
Gentlemen of the court,
there are times when I'm ashamed
to be a member of the human race,
and this is one such occasion.
It's impossible for me to summarise
the case for the defence,
since the court never allowed me
a reasonable opportunity
to present my case.
Are you protesting
the authenticity of this court?
Yes, sir. I protest against being
prevented from introducing evidence
that I consider vital to the defence.
The prosecution presented no witnesses.
There has never been a written indictment
of charges made against the defendants.
And lastly, I protest against the fact
that no stenographic records
of this trial have been kept.
The attack yesterday morning
is no stain on the honour of France,
and certainly no disgrace
to the fighting men of this nation.
But this court martial
is such a stain, and such a disgrace.
The case made against these men
is a mockery of all human justice.
Gentlemen of the court,
to find these men guilty
will be a crime to haunt each of you
till the day you die.
I can't believe that
the noblest impulse of man,
his compassion for another,
can be completely dead here.
Therefore, I humbly beg you,
show mercy to these men.
The accused will be escorted back to
the guardroom. The hearing is closed.
The court will now retire to deliberate.
There will be a guard of six men
under arms. Rifles loaded, bayonets fixed.
Two men to each prisoner.
Any sign of trouble,
the prisoners will be instantly covered.
If the trouble doesn't subside at once,
the prisoner will be shot on the spot.
Everything must all go off without a hitch
and with the least possible delay.
It shouldn't be hurried,
but there must be no fumbling around.
I've been put in charge
and made personally responsible
for any lack of order, or for any mistakes.
But you can take it from me that I shall
pass on any blame, and with interest,
to any one of you who fails in his duties.
Execution will take place at seven o'clock,
according to the verdict
of the court martial.
Detail, attention! Dismissed!
This is compliments of General Mireau.
- Duck.
- Well, tell him thanks!
Don't blame me, soldier.
Are we supposed to eat
this with our fingers?
The guard says you can't
have any knives or forks.
Is this supposed to be our last meal
or something?
It isn't supposed to be our last meal.
It is our last meal.
This duck is terrific.
Do you suppose they put
anything in the food?
First they poison us, then they shoot us?
- I think they put something in it.
- Like what?
Like, uh... something
to make us groggy or something.
What would be wrong
with that if they did?
Maybe nothing for you,
but I'm gonna get out of this somehow,
and I don't wanna be drugged.
How are you gonna get out?
Chew your way through that stone wall?
I don't know. Colonel Dax.
He'll see us through.
Listen, we gotta get outta here.
They're gonna kill us in a few hours
if we don't.
- Have you got an idea?
- No, but there's gotta be a way.
How many guards
do you think they've got out there?
They may have a couple of squads.
That's what it sounded like this morning.
- Maybe they're some of our friends.
- That's the 3rd Battalion.
Anyway, right now we have no friends.
Why kid yourself?
We're not gonna get out of this.
Maybe you're not, but I am.
I'll guarantee you of that.
See that cockroach?
Tomorrow morning,
we'll be dead and it'll be alive.
It'll have more contact
with my wife and child than I will.
I'll be nothing and it'll be alive.
Now you've got the edge on him.
Good evening, my sons. I'm Father Dupré.
Is there any news?
I'm afraid I bring you very bad news.
You must prepare yourselves
for the worst.
- Colonel Dax asked me to tell you.
- Oh, mercy, no!
He's been in telephone contact
with army headquarters,
but unable to speak to General Broulard
or for that matter to anyone in authority.
The same way at Division.
No one wants to be found.
- How much time do we have?
- You have plenty of time yet.
Certainly more than enough
to prepare yourselves.
In nomine Patris et Filii
et Spiritus Sancti.
Amen.
Father, will you take this letter
for me, please?
Of course, my son.
It's to my wife. She won't understand
this, and I tried to explain it to her.
I'll see that she gets it.
Do you want me to hear your confession?
Well, Father, to tell you the truth,
I'm not very religious.
I know you're trying to help
and I appreciate it,
but if I started praying now
I'd feel like a hypocrite.
That's an error, my son. God is
always ready to listen to your prayers.
All right, Father.
Will you please hear my confession now?
Yes.
Have faith in your Creator, my son.
Death comes to us all.
The Father, the Son and the Holy Ghost.
That's really deep,
"Death comes to us all".
That really is deep.
Say Ferol, what's the matter?
Afraid your luck isn't going to hold out?
Well, look. This is my religion.
O great bottle, forgive me my sins,
for now I lay me down to sleep.
May I drink you first? Thank you. Amen.
I understand your anguish, my son,
but you must not let it harden your heart.
May I tell you something, Father?
Back in my home town,
there was a certain little café
with an amusing sign over the bar.
It read "Do not be afraid to ask for credit
for our way of refusing is very polite."
- Come on, Arnaud. Sit down, you're drunk.
- Oh, Paris, leave me alone.
Get out of here with
your sanctimonious pat answers!
What are you hanging around here for,
to torture us?
No, to help you with all my power.
Your power, you have no power!
- God has power.
- Does he? What a laugh!
- You can be saved.
- Saved? I'll be saved?
Cut it out, Arnaud!
Arnaud!
Arnaud.
Father, get a doctor. Quick.
That should keep him quiet long enough.
That's a nasty skull fracture, though.
He may not live out the night.
- What are we supposed to do with him?
- My advice is to tie him to a stretcher
so he won't slip
when you tilt him vertically.
Surely they won't execute
a man in that condition?
I'm sorry, Father.
The sentence will be carried out.
I've already checked with the general.
If he's still alive in the morning,
pinch his cheeks a couple of times
before you take him out on the field.
It may make him open his eyes.
The general wants him to be conscious.
Yes?
- Lieutenant Roget reporting, sir.
- Come in.
Sergeant Boulanger
said you wanted to see me, sir.
Yes, Lieutenant.
Looks as if we have a pretty unpleasant
thing on our hands in a few hours.
- You mean the execution, sir.
- Yes, I mean the execution.
- Yes, sir. It's very unfortunate.
- "Very unfortunate."
- That's just how I feel about it.
- None of us are happy about it, sir.
How did you happen
to pick Corporal Paris?
Well, I had to pick somebody, sir.
That's right, you did.
Of course you had no personal motive
in picking Paris, did you?
Oh, no, sir.
You picked him because
he was a coward, didn't you?
Did you or didn't you?
Oh, yes, sir, I did.
Like you say, somebody had to be picked.
It was quite a problem, sir.
Yes, I had the same kind of problem.
I have to pick someone
to be in charge of
the firing squad tomorrow.
Do you have any objections
to taking the job?
- Me, sir?
- Yes, you.
What's the matter? Don't you feel well?
No... Yeah, I feel all right, sir.
It's just that I...
- Would you like me to open a window?
- No, sir.
Well, it's... just that I've never been
in charge of a firing squad before, sir.
Oh, there's nothing to it. First, you help
the sergeant tie the men to the posts.
Of course, you offer the men blindfolds
and... if they want them, you tie them on.
You take your position with the firing
squad, raise your sword - ready, aim, fire.
Then you draw your revolver out,
you walk forward,
and put a bullet through each man's head.
Sir, I request that I be
excused from this duty.
- Request denied.
- Colonel...
You've got the job. It's all yours.
That's all, Lieutenant.
- Colonel, if you could...
- That's all, lieutenant!
- Yes?
- Excuse me, sir. Colonel Dax?
My name is Rousseau, sir.
Captain of artillery.
What is it, Captain?
I have something to tell you, sir, that may
have a great bearing on the court martial.
Come in, Captain.
- Colonel, good evening!
- Good evening, sir.
- Good evening. Come and sit down.
- Thank you, sir.
I'm really sorry to intrude
on you in this way.
Not at all. I'm always delighted
to see you, colonel Dax.
- Will you have a cigar?
- No, thank you, sir.
- Well, I...
- I think you'll find it delicious.
I apologise for not inviting you
to join the party downstairs tonight,
but I'm afraid that it's a dress affair.
Thank you, sir, but I must confess
that this is not entirely a social visit.
Oh, come, Dax, let's not go
over all that ground again.
I must admit that judging
from the casualties,
the efforts of your regiment
must have been considerable.
How can you understand that
and allow these men to be shot tomorrow?
Colonel, you're choosing to take
a rather simple view of this.
The attack was impossible from the start.
The general staff
must have known that.
Colonel Dax, we think we're doing
a good job running the war.
You must be aware of the fact
that the general staff is subject
to all kinds of unfair pressures
from newspapers and politicians.
Maybe the attack against
the Ant Hill was impossible.
Perhaps it was an error of judgement
on our part. On the other hand,
if your men had been a little more daring,
they might have taken it. Who knows?
In any case,
why should we have to bear any more
criticism for the failure than we have to?
Aside from the inescapable fact
that a good many of your men
never left the trenches,
there's the question of the troops' morale,
don't forget that.
- The troops' morale?
- Certainly.
These executions will be
a tonic for the division.
There are few things more fundamentally
encouraging and stimulating
than seeing someone else die.
I never thought of that, sir.
You see, colonel, troops are like children.
Just as a child wants his father to
be firm, troops crave discipline.
One way to maintain discipline
is to shoot a man now and then.
May I ask... do you sincerely believe
all the things you've just said?
It's been a pleasure discussing this with
you, but I'd better get back to my guests.
Forgive me for having
kept you from your party.
By the way, sir,
have you heard that General Mireau
ordered his own battery
commander, Captain Rousseau,
to open fire on his own positions
during the attack?
Of course, the captain refused
without a written order.
But General Mireau demanded that
he commence firing on our own trenches.
Rousseau refused
without an order in writing,
but again he was ordered, and again
he refused... all in front of witnesses.
Do you actually believe
this fantastic story?
Here are copies of the sworn statements
from all the principals involved.
Battery Commander Rousseau,
Captain Nichols, the artillery spotter,
the telephone clerk, and, uh...
my own deposition.
What has all this got to do with the charge
against the condemned prisoners?
A general in a tantrum
over the failure of an impossible attack
orders his artillery to
fire on his own men.
Now, the same officer on the same day
orders a court martial in which
three of his men are sentenced to be shot.
General, what would your newspapers
and your politicians do with that?
Colonel Dax,
are you trying to blackmail me?
Sir, that's an ugly word,
but you are in a difficult position.
Too much has happened. Someone's
got to be hurt. The only question is who.
General Mireau's assault
on the Ant Hill failed.
His order to fire on
his own troops was refused,
but his attempt to murder three innocent
men to protect his own reputation
will be prevented by the general staff.
Will you pardon me, Colonel Dax?
I've been rude to my guests too long.
Detail, halt!
Order arms!
Fall out.
Courage, my sons. The worst is over.
Morning, Paris.
Morning, Sergeant.
- How are you today?
- Not too bad.
How are you?
You missed some good chow
in here last night.
What'd you have?
Have you got a drink for us?
Take a swig of this.
It just occurred to me... a funny thing.
I haven't had one sexual thought since the
court martial. It's extraordinary, isn't it?
Pull yourself together. Act like a man.
Listen, Paris, are you listening to me?
There'll be a lot of dignitaries
and newspaper men out there.
You've got a wife and family.
How do you wanna be remembered?
I don't wanna die.
Many of us'll be joining you
before this war's over.
I don't care. I don't wanna die.
- Please save me, Sergeant.
- I can't save you. No one can now.
This is the last decision
you'll have a chance to make on earth.
You can pull yourself together
and act like a man,
or we'll have to drag you out of here.
In the end, it'll all be the same.
It's up to you.
Let's get busy. You and Ferol, take your
coats off. It's no use hanging around here.
With the help of thy grace, to do penance,
and to amend my life.
Why do I have to die, Father?
I didn't do anything.
We do not question
the will of God, my son.
But I fought, I fought!
I fought on the battlefield.
Why don't they die?
Why don't you put them to death?
You showed courage in the face of the
enemy. Show it before your own troops.
But I'm scared, I'm scared.
Oh, Father, I'm scared.
Courage. Brace yourself, man.
He said "This day thou shalt
be with me in paradise."
- Really, Father?
- Yes.
Really, Father?
I'll never see my wife again.
I'll never see nobody again, Father.
Courage, man. Brace yourself.
- I can't help it!
- Brace yourself.
I can't help it, Father.
Oh, Christ, Christ.
Strengthen me, God.
Please strengthen me.
Secure prisoners!
Detail, attention!
Forward... march!
Detail...
halt!
Left... face!
In the name of the French people,
Corporal Phillip Paris, Private Maurice
Ferol, and Private Pierre Arnaud
of the 701st Regiment,
having been found guilty of cowardice
in the face of the enemy,
are to be executed
by rifle fire immediately,
in accordance with the judgement
of the military court martial.
Right face!
Forward march!
Do you want a blindfold?
Yes, Lieutenant, please.
I don't wanna die.
Do... do you want a blindfold?
No.
I'm sorry.
Ready!
Aim!
Fire!
I'm awfully glad you could be there,
George.
This sort of thing is always rather grim,
but this one had a kind of splendour to it.
I have never seen an affair
of this sort handled any better.
The men died wonderfully.
There's always that chance
that one of them will do something
that would leave a bad taste.
This time you couldn't ask for better.
Yes?
- Yes, Colonel?
- You wanted to see me, sir.
Oh, yes, yes!
Come in, Colonel, and sit down.
Colonel Dax. Your men died very well.
- Would you like some coffee, Colonel?
- No, thank you, sir.
By the way, I've been told
that you ordered your artillery
to fire on your own men
during the attack on the Ant Hill.
I did what? Who told you that?
Colonel Dax came to me
last night with the story.
Colonel Dax, I've always known
that you were a disloyal officer,
but I never dreamed that you
would stoop to anything so low as this.
General, I have sworn statements from
Captain Nichols, your artillery spotter,
Captain Rousseau, the battery commander
who refused your order.
I think it's infamous. Absolutely infamous.
Then there's no truth at all in the charge
made by colonel Dax?
I don't see how you can even ask me that.
You cannot imagine
how glad I am to hear that, Paul.
I'm certain that
you'll come through it all right.
- I'll come through what?
- There'll have to be an inquiry.
An inquiry?
It won't amount to much,
those things never do.
- The public forgets.
- Public?
You have the right to clear your name.
You cannot allow such violent insinuations
against your character to go undenied.
So that's it.
You're making me the goat -
the only completely innocent man
in this whole affair.
I have only one last thing
to say to you, George.
The man you stabbed in the back
is a soldier.
Well... It had to be done.
France cannot afford to have
fools guiding her military destiny.
I'm grateful to you for bringing
the matter to my attention.
Colonel Dax, how would you like
General Mireau's job?
- His what, sir?
- His job.
Let me get this straight, sir.
You're offering me
General Mireau's command?
Come, Colonel Dax,
don't overdo the surprise.
You've been after the job from the start.
We all know that, my boy.
I may be many things, sir,
but I'm not your boy.
Well, I certainly didn't mean to imply
any biological relationship.
- I'm not your boy in any sense.
- Are you trying to provoke me, Colonel?
Why should I want to do that?
Exactly. It would be a pity to lose
your promotion before you get it.
A promotion you have
so very carefully planned for.
Sir, would you like me to suggest
what you can do with that promotion?
Colonel Dax!
You will apologise at once, or else
you'll be placed under arrest!
I apologise for not being
entirely honest with you.
I apologise for not
revealing my true feelings.
I apologise for not telling you sooner that
you are a degenerate, sadistic old man.
And you can go to hell before
I apologise to you now or ever again!
Colonel Dax,
you're a disappointment to me.
You have spoiled the keenness of
your mind by wallowing in sentimentality.
You really did want to save those men,
and you were not angling
for Mireau's command.
You're an idealist, and I pity you,
as I would the village idiot.
We're fighting a war,
a war we've got to win.
Those men didn't fight, so they were shot.
You bring charges against General
Mireau, so I insist that he answer them.
Wherein have I done wrong?
Because you don't know
the answer to that question...
I pity you.
Thank you.
Gentlemen, we have a little
special entertainment for you.
Sort of a little
diversion, as it were.
As my wife always says, what
is life without a little diversion?
Now, gentlemen, I give you
our latest acquisition from the enemy.
From Germany, the land of the Hun.
Gentlemen, a little pearl, washed
ashore by the tide of the war.
Sag den Herrschaften guten Tag.
Guten Tag.
Hey, talk in a civilised language!
It's true, the little lady
has her limitations.
As a matter of fact,
she has absolutely no talent at all.
Except, that is...
Well, maybe a little natural talent.
The little lady can't dance,
she can't tell any jokes,
and she can't balance
rubber balls on her little nose.
Ah!
But she can sing like a bird.
She has a throat of gold.
Come on, honey!
Sing us a song! Come on!
Louder! Louder!
♪ Ein ganzes Jahr und noch viel mehr ♪
♪ Die Liebe nahm kein Ende mehr ♪
♪ Und als man ihm die Botschaft bracht' ♪
♪ Dass sein Herzliebchen im Sterben lag ♪
♪ Da liess er all sein Hab und Gut ♪
♪ Und eilte seinem Herzliebchen zu ♪
- ♪ Da liess er all sein Hab und Gut ♪
♪ Ach bitte, Mutter, bring ein Licht ♪
♪ Mein Liebchen stirbt, ich seh es nicht ♪
♪ Das war fürwahr ein treuer Husar ♪
♪ Der liebt' sein Mädchen ein ganzes Jahr ♪
- Sir.
- Yes, Sergeant?
We have orders to move back
to the front immediately.
- Well, give the men a few minutes more.
- Yes, sir.