♪ Singing in the rain just
singing in the rain ♪
♪ What a glorious feeling
we're happy again ♪
♪ We'll walk down the lane ♪
♪ With a happy refrain ♪
♪ And singing just
singing in the rain ♪
This is Dora Bailey,
ladies and gentlemen...
talking to you from the front of
the Chinese Theatre in Hollywood.
What a night, ladies and
gentlemen. What a night.
Every star in Hollywood is here to
make Monumental
Pictures' premiere...
of The Royal Rascal, the
outstanding event of 1927.
Everyone breathlessly awaits...
the arrival of Lina
Lamont and Don Lockwood.
Look who's arriving now.
It's that famous "zip"
girl of the screen...
the darling of the flapper set...
Zelda Zanders.
Zelda. Zelda.
Her new red-hot pash, J.
Cumberland Spendrill III...
that well-known eligible bachelor.
Zelda's had so much unhappiness, I
hope this time it's really love.
And here comes that
exotic star, Olga Mara.
Ooh.
And her new husband, the Baron
de la Bonnet de la Toulon.
They've been married
two months already,
but still as happy as newlyweds.
Well, well, well.
It's Cosmo Brown.
Cosmo is Don's best friend.
He plays the piano on the
set for Don and Lina...
to get them into those
romantic moods.
Oh, folks, this is it. This is it.
The stars of tonight's
picture, those
romantic lovers of the screen...
Don Lockwood and Lina Lamont.
Ladies and gentlemen, when you
look at this gorgeous couple...
it's no wonder they're a household
name all over the world.
Like "bacon and eggs."
"Lockwood and Lamont."
Don, tell me confidentially,
are these rumours true...
that wedding bells are soon
to ring for you and Lina?
Lina and I have no statement
to make at the present time.
We're just good friends.
You've come a long way together.
Won't you tell us how it happened?
Lina and I have made a number
of pictures together...
Oh, no, no, Don. I want your
story from the beginning.
Dora, not in front
of all these people.
The story of your success
is an inspiration...
to young people all
over the world.
Please.
Well, to begin with, any
story of my career...
would have to include my
lifelong friend, Cosmo Brown.
We were kids together, grew
up together, worked together.
Yes?
Well, Dora, I've had one motto
which I've always lived by:
"Dignity. Always dignity."
This was instilled in me by Mum
and Dad from the very beginning.
They sent me to the finest
schools, including dancing school.
That's where I first met Cosmo.
And with him, I used to perform
for Mum and Dad's society friends.
They used to make
such a fuss over me.
If I was very good,
I was allowed to
accompany Mum and
Dad to the theatre.
They brought me up on Shaw...
Molière, the finest
of the classics.
To this was added rigorous
musical training...
at the Conservatory of Fine Arts.
We rounded out our apprenticeship
at an exclusive dramatics academy.
And at all times...
the motto remained...
"Dignity.
Always dignity."
In a few years, we were ready to
embark on a dance concert tour.
We played the finest symphonic
halls in the country.
♪ Fit as a fiddle and
ready for love ♪
♪ I can jump over
the moon up above ♪
♪ Fit as a fiddle and
ready for love ♪
♪ Haven't a worry haven't a care ♪
♪ Feeling like a feather
that's floating on air ♪
♪ Fit as a fiddle and
ready for love ♪
♪ Soon the church bells
will be ringing ♪
♪ And a march with Ma and Pa ♪
♪ How the church bells
will be ringing ♪
♪ With a hey-nonny-nonny
and a hot-cha-cha ♪
♪ Hi diddle diddle
my baby's okay ♪
♪ Ask me a riddle
I'm happy to say ♪
♪ Fit as a fiddle and
ready for love ♪
Audiences everywhere adored us.
Get out of here.
Finally we decided to
come to sunny California.
We were stranded... We were
staying here, resting up...
when offers from the movie
studios started pouring in.
We sorted them out and decided
to favour Monumental Pictures.
Lina, you hate him. Resist him.
Keep that mood music going.
Now, Phil, you come
in. Keep on grinding.
Now you see her. Now
here's the bit,
Bert, where you get it on the jaw.
Cut.
No, no. That wasn't right.
You were supposed to
go over the bar and
crash into the
glasses. Try it again.
Okay, Bert? Bert.
Oh, that's swell, just swell.
Take him away, fellas.
You'll be all right. We've lost
more stuntmen on these pictures...
It'll take hours to get a new
one from Central Casting.
Mr Dexter, I can do that.
- You? You're a musician.
- That's a moot point.
No kidding. What's your name?
Don Lockwood, but the
fellas call me "Donald."
Wise guy, huh? Okay, I'll try you.
Get this guy into Bert's suit.
And remember, Lockwood,
you might be
trading that fiddle in for a harp.
Camera.
Phil, come in. Now you
see him. That's it.
Now, here's where you get
it right on the jaw.
Cut.
That was wonderful.
Got any more little
chores you want done?
Plenty.
Okay.
My roles in these
films were urbane...
sophisticated...
suave.
And of course, all through
those pictures...
Lina was, as always,
an inspiration to me.
Warm and helpful.
A real lady.
Hello, Miss Lamont. I'm Don
Lockwood, the stuntman.
It was a thrill working
with you, Miss Lamont.
Hey, Don.
Meet the producer of the
picture, R.F. Simpson.
I just saw some rushes and asked
Dexter who the stuntmen were.
He said they were all
you. I'm putting
you and Lina together
in a picture.
Come to my office. We'll
discuss a contract.
Thanks, Mr Simpson.
Are you doing anything
tonight, Miss Lamont?
That's funny.
I'm busy.
Lina and I have had the same
wonderful relationship ever since.
But most important of all, I
continue living up to my motto:
"Dignity.
Always dignity."
Thank you, Don.
And I'm sure you and
Lina will continue
making movie history tonight...
in your greatest picture,
The Royal Rascal.
Get enough, boys?
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
She's so refined...
I think I'll kill myself.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
We're thrilled at your
response to The Royal Rascal.
We had fun making it, and we hope
you had fun seeing it tonight.
We screen actors aren't much
good at speaking in public.
So we'll just act out our thanks.
- Hot diggity. It's a smash.
- Don, Lina, you were gorgeous.
Lina, you looked pretty
good for a girl.
What's the big idea?
Can't a girl get a word in
edgewise? They're my public too.
The publicity department...
thought it'd be better if Don made
all the speeches for the team.
Why?
You're beautiful. Audiences
think you got a voice to match.
We got to keep our stars from
looking ridiculous at any cost.
No one's got that much money.
What's wrong with the way I talk?
Am I dumb or something?
No, it's just that Don's had
so much more experience...
Next time, write me out a
speech. I could memorise it.
Sure. Why don't you recite
the Gettysburg Address?
What do you know about it, you
piano player? Are you anybody?
Donnie, how can you let him talk
to me like that, your fiancée?
My fia...
Lina, you've been reading
those fan magazines again.
Look, you shouldn't believe
all that banana oil...
that Dora Bailey dishes out.
Now, try to get this straight:
There is nothing between us.
There has never been
anything between us.
- Just air.
- Oh, Donnie, you don't mean that.
We'll be late for R.F.'s party.
Better go in separate cars to
break up the mobs. Come on, honey.
Ta-ta, Donnie. See you there.
"Donnie."
Can't that girl
take a gentle hint?
Haven't you heard? She's
irresistible. She told me so.
I can't get her out of my hair.
This romance for publicity...
The price of fame.
You've got the glory.
The little heartaches go with it.
Look at me. I got no glory. I
got no fame. I got no mansions.
I got no money. But I've got...
- What have I got?
- I don't know.
I got to get out of here.
Don't tell me. It's a flat tire.
This car hasn't given me
trouble in nearly six hours.
Hey, there's Don Lockwood.
Hey, give me an autograph.
- Give me your autograph.
- I want a souvenir.
I want a souvenir too.
Hey. You're playing rough
here. You're tearing my...
Hey, Cos, do something.
Call me a cab.
You're a cab.
Thanks a lot.
- Lady, keep driving.
- Get out.
- Everything's all right.
- I'll call a policeman.
- Just a few blocks.
- Don't hurt me.
- I'm not a criminal.
- I don't care...
You are a criminal. I've seen
that face. You're a gangster.
I've seen your picture in the
paper or in the post office.
Officer.
- This man jumped in my car and...
- Why, it's Don Lockwood.
- Don Lockwood?
- How are you? Out for a joy ride?
Just a lift. My car broke
down. I got surrounded by...
You're a lucky lady.
Anything wrong?
Why, no.
No, I should think
not. Good night.
Good night, officer.
Well, thanks for saving my
life. I'll get out now.
I'm driving to Beverly Hills.
Can I drop you some place?
I'd like to get out
of this suit if
you're going by Camden and Sunset.
Yes, I am.
I'd like to know whose
hospitality I'm enjoying.
Selden. Kathy Selden.
Enchanted, Miss Selden.
I'm sorry I frightened you.
I was getting a little too
much love from my fans.
Oh, that's what you
were running away from.
They did that to you?
That's terrible.
Yes. Yes, it is, isn't it?
It is terrible.
Well, we movie stars
get the glory...
I guess we have to take the little
heartaches that go with it.
People think we lead lives
of glamour and romance...
but we're really lonely.
Terribly lonely.
I really can't tell
you how sorry I
am about taking you
for a criminal.
But it was understandable,
under the
circumstances. I
knew I'd seen you.
Which of my pictures
have you seen?
I don't remember.
I saw one once.
- You saw one once?
- I think you were duelling.
And there was a girl. Lina Lamont.
I don't go to the movies much.
If you've seen one,
you've seen them all.
Thank you.
No offence.
Movies are entertaining
for the masses...
but the personalities on the
screen don't impress me.
They don't talk or act. They
just make a lot of dumb show.
Well, you know.
Like that.
You mean, like what I do.
Well, yes.
Here we are, Sunset and Camden.
Wait, you mean I'm not an actor?
- Pantomime isn't acting?
- Of course not.
Acting means great parts,
wonderful lines, glorious words.
Shakespeare. Ibsen.
What's your lofty
mission in life...
that lets you sneer at
my humble profession?
I'm an actress. On the stage.
Oh, on the stage.
I'd like to see you.
What're you in now?
I could brush up on my English
or bring an interpreter.
That's if they'd let
in a movie actor.
I'm not in a play now. But
I'm going to New York...
You're going to New
York, and someday
we'll all hear of you, won't we?
Kathy Selden as Juliet, as
Lady Macbeth, as King Lear.
You'll have to wear a beard.
Laugh if you want, but the stage
is a dignified profession.
Why are you so conceited?
You're nothing but a shadow on
film. You're not flesh and blood.
Stop.
What can I do? I'm only a shadow.
Keep away from me. Just because
you're a big movie star...
you expect every girl to faint
at your feet. Don't touch me.
Fear not, sweet lady. I
will not molest you.
I am but a humble jester. And
you? You are too far above me.
Farewell, Ethel Barrymore.
I must tear myself from your side.
Is this R.F. Simpson's house? I'm
one of the Coconut Grove girls.
Yes, the floor show.
Around the back.
Oh, I see. Thank you.
- Nice little party, R.F.
- Thanks, Roscoe.
Do you really think you
can get me in the movies?
- I should think so.
- Really?
The picture's great.
There's Don. I loved the picture.
Did you come by way of Australia?
Hello, Cos. Excuse me.
Cos, tell me the truth.
Am I a good actor?
As long as I work for Monumental,
you're the greatest.
No kidding. You're my
pal. You can tell me.
What's the matter? Of
course, you're good.
Keep telling me from time to
time. I feel a little shaken.
- The new Don Lockwood.
- Don.
Hi, R.F.
It's colossal. Where
have you been?
There you are. Where
were you? I was lonely.
Hello, Lina.
Okay, fellas. Hold it.
Together again, my two
little stars, Don and Lina.
No kidding, folks,
aren't they great?
All right, open that screen.
A movie? We just saw one.
Gotta show one at a
party. It's a law.
Everybody, I've got a
few surprises for you.
All right, sit down, sit down.
This'll make you laugh.
There's a madman coming into
my office for months, and...
- You got that gadget working?
- All set.
Okay, let her go.
Hello.
This is a demonstration
of a talking picture.
Notice, it is a picture
of me and I am talking.
Note how my lips and the
sound issuing from them...
are synchronised together...
in perfect unison.
Who's that?
Somebody's talking
behind that screen.
Come out from behind
that screen, Mr Simpson.
Oh, no. I'm right here.
My voice has been
recorded on a record.
A talking picture.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Well?
- It's just a toy.
- It's a scream.
- It's vulgar.
- You think they'll ever use it?
I doubt it. Warners is making a
picture with it, The Jazz Singer.
- They'll lose their shirts.
- It'll never amount to a thing.
They said that about the
horseless carriage.
Let's get on with the
show. Okay, boys.
Come on, my little starlets.
I have a surprise. A
very special cake.
I want you kiddies to
have the first piece.
Well. If it isn't Ethel Barrymore.
I do hope you'll favour
us with something
special. Say,
Hamlet's soliloquy...
or a scene from Romeo and
Juliet? Don't be shy.
You make about the prettiest
Juliet I've ever seen. Really.
♪ All I do is dream of you
the whole night through ♪
♪ With the dawn I still
go on dreaming of you ♪
♪ You're every thought
you're everything ♪
♪ You're every song I ever sing ♪
♪ Summer, winter,
autumn and spring ♪
♪ And were there more than
twenty-four hours a day ♪
♪ They'd be spent in sweet
content dreaming away ♪
♪ When skies are grey
when skies are blue ♪
♪ Morning, noon and
nighttime too ♪
♪ All I do the whole day
through is dream of you ♪
It's the cat's meow.
♪ All I do the whole day
through is dream of you ♪
I had to tell you
how good you were.
Excuse me.
Now that I know where you live,
I'd like to see you home.
- Listen, Mr Lockwood...
- Say, who is this dame anyway?
Someone lofty and
far above us all.
She couldn't learn anything from
the movies. She's a stage actress.
Here's one thing I've
learnt from the movies.
- I'll kill her.
- Lina, she was aiming at me.
- You never looked lovelier.
- It was an accident.
It happens to me five
or six times a day.
Where is she?
Donnie?
Excuse me. Where'd Miss Selden go?
She grabbed her things and
bolted. Anything I can do?
Sorry. I don't have
time to find out.
Kathy.
Hey, Kathy.
Hey.
Keep that action going.
More steam in the kettle.
More action, boys. A
little more rhythm.
More steam and more water.
- Hi, Maxie.
- Hi, Don.
- Good morning, fellas.
- Hiya, Don.
Did you read Variety today?
"First talking picture,
The Jazz Singer.
All-time smash end of first week."
- All-time flop end of the second.
- We start today.
- Good luck.
- Thanks.
I'm now Count Pierre de Bataille,
known as the Duelling Cavalier.
- What's it about?
- It's a French Revolution story.
You're a French aristocrat.
She's a simple girl of the people
and won't even give you a tumble.
Well, it's a living.
Good morning.
Keep the background
moving. Hit him.
Come on. Knock him down.
Get up there and hit
him again. Hurry up.
Why bother to shoot this? Release
the old one under a new title.
You've seen one,
you've seen them all.
- Why'd you say that?
- What's the matter?
That's what that Kathy Selden
said to me that night.
That's three weeks ago. You
still thinking about that?
- I can't get her out of my mind.
- How could you?
She's the first dame who hasn't
fallen for you since you were 4.
She's on my conscience.
It's not your fault
she lost her job.
- I've got to find her.
- You've been trying to.
Short of sending out
bloodhounds and a posse.
Come on, now. Snap out of it.
You can't let this get you down.
You're Donald Lockwood. Donald
Lockwood's an actor, isn't he?
What's the first thing
an actor learns?
"The show must go on, come rain,
come shine, come
snow, come sleet."
Yeah.
♪ The world's so full
of a number of things ♪
♪ I'm sure we should
all be as happy as ♪
♪ But are we? No ♪
♪ Definitely, no ♪
♪ Positively, no decidedly, no ♪
♪ Short people have long faces ♪
♪ Long people have short faces ♪
♪ Big people have little humour
little people have
no humour at all ♪
♪ In the words of that immortal
bard Samuel J. Snodgrass ♪
♪ As he was being led
to the guillotine ♪
♪ Make them laugh
make them laugh ♪
♪ Don't you know everyone
wants to laugh ha, ha ♪
♪ My dad said, "be
an actor, my son ♪
♪ But be a comical one" ♪
♪ They'll be standing in lines ♪
♪ For those old
honky-tonk monkeyshines ♪
♪ Now you could study Shakespeare
and be quite elite ♪
♪ And you could charm the critics
and have nothing to eat ♪
♪ Just slip on a banana peel
the world's at your feet ♪
♪ Make them laugh
make them laugh ♪
♪ Make them laugh ♪
♪ Make...? ♪
♪ Don't you know everyone
wants to laugh? ♪
♪ My grandpa said, "go out
and tell them a joke ♪
♪ But give it plenty of Hoke" ♪
♪ Make them roar
make them scream ♪
♪ Take a fall, butt a
wall split a seam ♪
♪ You start off by pretending
you're a dancer with grace ♪
♪ You wiggle till they're
giggling all over the place ♪
♪ And then you get a great big
custard pie in the face ♪
♪ Make them laugh
make them laugh ♪
♪ Make them laugh ♪
♪ Don't ya... all the ♪
♪ What...? ♪
♪ My dad ♪
♪ They'll be standing in lines ♪
♪ For those old
honky-tonk monkeyshines ♪
♪ Make them laugh
make them laugh ♪
♪ Don't you know everyone ♪
♪ Make them laugh ♪
♪ Make them laugh
make them laugh ♪
♪ Make them laugh ♪
Ready, Don?
- All set.
- Here we go again.
We have another
smash on our hands.
I hope so.
You're darn tooting we have.
- Where's Lina?
- Here she is, Mr Dexter.
Well. Here comes our
lovely leading lady now.
This wig weighs a tonne. What
dope'd wear a thing like this?
Everybody wore them.
Then everybody was a dope.
- You look beautiful.
- You look great.
Let's get into the set.
Thanks, Joe.
I looked for you at Wally
Ray's party. Where were you?
I've been busy.
And I know what you've been
busy at. Looking for that girl.
- As a matter of fact, yes.
- Why?
I've been worried about her.
You should've been
worried about me.
I'm the one who got the
whipped cream in the kisser.
Yes, but you didn't lose
your job, and she did.
Darn tooting she
did. I arranged it.
What?
They weren't gonna fire her,
so I told them they better.
- Why...
- Don, now remember.
You're madly in love with her and
you have to overcome her shyness.
Cosmo, mood music.
Roll them.
Okay, Don.
Now enter.
You see her.
Run to her.
Why, you rattlesnake, you.
You got that poor kid fired.
That's not all I'm gonna do if
I ever get my hands on her.
I never heard of anything so low.
Fine. Fine. Looks great.
What did you do it for?
Because you liked
her. I could tell.
So that's it.
Believe me, I don't like her
half as much as I hate you.
You reptile.
Sticks and stones
may break my bones.
I'd like to break every
bone in your body.
You and who else, you big lummox?
Now kiss her, Don.
That's it. More.
Great. Cut.
You couldn't kiss me
like that and not
mean it just a teensy-weensy bit.
Meet the world's greatest actor.
I'd rather kiss a tarantula.
- You don't mean that.
- I don't...?
Joe, bring me a
tarantula. Now listen...
Stop that chitchat, you lovebirds.
Let's get another take.
Hold it.
- Hold it, Dexter.
- Hello, Mr Simpson.
We're really rolling.
Well, you can stop
rolling at once.
All right, everybody. Save it.
Save it? Tell them to go
home. We're shutting down.
Don't stand there. Tell them.
Go home until further
notice. What is this?
What's the matter?
The Jazz Singer, that's
what's the matter.
♪ Oh, my darling little
mammy down in Alabamy ♪
This is no joke. It's a sensation.
The public's screaming for more.
- More what?
- Talking pictures.
- It's just a freak.
- We should have such a freak.
I said talking pictures were a
menace, but no one would listen.
We're going to make The Duelling
Cavalier into a talking picture.
That means I'm out of a job.
I can start suffering and
write that symphony.
We'll put you in as head
of the music department.
Thanks. I can stop suffering
and write that symphony.
Wait a second. Talking
pictures. You should wait...
Every studio's jumping
on the bandwagon.
All the theatres are putting
in sound equipment.
We know nothing about it.
What do you have to know?
You do what you always did.
You just add talking to it.
Believe me, it'll be a sensation.
"Lamont and Lockwood. They talk."
Well, of course we
talk. Don't everybody?
♪ I got a feeling you're fooling ♪
♪ I got a feeling
you're having fun ♪
♪ I get the go-by when you
are done fooling with me ♪
♪ It's a holiday today's The
Wedding of the Painted Doll ♪
♪ It's a jolly day the
news is spreading ♪
♪ Should I reveal
exactly how I feel ♪
♪ Should I confess ♪
♪ I got a feeling you're fooling
I got a feeling you're ♪
♪ It's a holiday
today's the wedding ♪
♪ Should I reveal ♪
♪ Exactly how I feel ♪
♪ Beautiful girl you're
a lovely picture ♪
a gorgeous mixture ♪
♪ Of all that lies under
the big blue sky ♪
♪ My heart cries ♪
Who's that? She looks familiar.
♪ You're a dazzling eyeful ♪
I featured her before, in
lots of nightclub shows.
I've seen her there.
She'd be good as Zelda's sister.
- That's a good idea.
- Excuse me.
♪ There may be blondes
and brunettes
that are hard to resist ♪
♪ You surpass them like a queen ♪
♪ You've got those lips that
were meant to be kissed ♪
♪ And you're over sweet 16 ♪
♪ Beautiful girl what
a gorgeous creature ♪
♪ Beautiful girl let
me call a preacher ♪
♪ What can I do ♪
♪ But give my heart to you? ♪
♪ A beautiful girl is like
a great work of art ♪
♪ She's stylish she's chic ♪
♪ And she also is smart ♪
♪ For lounging in her boudoir ♪
♪ This simple plain pyjama ♪
♪ Her cloak is trimmed
with monkey fur ♪
♪ To lend a dash of drama ♪
♪ Anyone for tennis? ♪
♪ Well, this will
make them cringe ♪
♪ And you'll knock
them dead at dinner ♪
♪ If your gown just
drips with fringe ♪
♪ You simply can't be too modest
at the beach or by the pool ♪
♪ And in summertime,
it's organdy ♪
♪ That'll keep you
fresh and cool ♪
♪ You'd never guess
what loud applause ♪
♪ This cunning hat receives ♪
♪ And you'd never dream the
things that you could hide ♪
♪ Within these sleeves ♪
♪ A string of pearls
with a suit of tweed ♪
♪ It's started quite a riot ♪
♪ And if you must wear
fox to the opera ♪
♪ Dame fashion says, "dye it" ♪
♪ Black is best when
you're in court ♪
♪ The judge will be impressed ♪
♪ But white is right
when you're a bride ♪
♪ And you want to
be well-dressed ♪
♪ Beautiful girl ♪
♪ For you I've got a passion ♪
♪ You're my queen of fashion ♪
♪ I'm in a whirl ♪
♪ Over ♪
♪ My beautiful girl ♪
- That's stupendous.
- Thanks.
Kathy, come here.
This will start a trend
in musical pictures.
Mr Simpson's thinking about
casting you as Zelda's sister.
That's wonderful.
Hey, Kathy.
That's Kathy Selden.
Thanks anyway. It was nice of you.
- Wait a minute.
- That's all right.
Before Mr Lockwood refreshes your
memory, you may as well know...
I'm the girl who hit
Miss Lamont with
a cake. It was meant
for Mr Lockwood.
Goodbye. I'm sorry. I
should've told you.
Wait a minute. What's
this all about?
We were gonna use her, but if
it'd make you and Lina unhappy...
Unhappy? It's wonderful.
He's been looking for her.
Are you speaking for Lina also?
The owner of the Coconut Grove
may do what Lina tells him...
but you're the head
of this studio.
Yes, I am.
She's hired. Don't let Lina
know she's on the lot.
Take care of that.
Thank you, Mr Simpson.
I'm glad you turned up. We've been
looking inside every cake in town.
Is it all right for you
to be seen with me?
You mean, lofty star
with humble player?
Not exactly. But for
lunch, don't you
tear a pheasant with Miss Lamont?
Look, Kathy. All that stuff about
Lina and me is sheer publicity.
Oh? Certainly seems
more than that...
from what I've read in all those
articles in the fan magazines.
You read the fan magazines?
I pick them up in the beauty
parlour or the dentist's office...
just like anybody.
Honest?
I buy four or five a month.
You buy four or five...?
To get back to the main point...
you achieve a kind of intimacy
in all your pictures...
Did you say all my pictures?
Now that I think of it, I've
seen eight or nine of them.
Eight or nine.
It seems to me I
remember someone saying:
"If you've seen one,
you've seen them all."
I did say some awful things
that night, didn't I?
No, I deserved them.
Of course, I must admit I was
pretty much upset by them.
So upset that I
haven't been able to
think of anything
but you ever since.
Honest?
Honest.
Well, I've been pretty upset too.
Kathy...
Kathy, look, I...
Kathy, seeing you
again now that I...
I'm trying to say something
to you, but I...
I'm such a ham.
I guess I'm not able to
without the proper setting.
What do you mean?
Well...
Come here.
This is the proper setting.
Why, it's just an empty stage.
At first glance, yes.
But wait a second.
A beautiful sunset.
Mist from the distant mountains.
Coloured lights in a garden.
Milady is standing on her balcony,
in a rose-trellised bower...
flooded with moonlight.
We add 500,000
kilowatts of stardust.
A soft summer breeze.
And...
You sure look lovely
in the moonlight.
Now that you have the proper
setting, can you say it?
I'll try.
♪ Life was a song ♪
♪ You came along ♪
♪ I've laid awake the
whole night through ♪
♪ If I but dared ♪
♪ To think you cared ♪
♪ This is what ♪
♪ I'd say to you ♪
♪ You were meant for me ♪
♪ And I was meant for you ♪
♪ Nature patterned you ♪
♪ And when she was done ♪
♪ You were all the sweet things ♪
♪ Rolled up in one ♪
♪ You're like ♪
♪ A plaintive melody ♪
♪ That never lets me free ♪
♪ But I'm content ♪
♪ The angels must have sent you ♪
♪ And they meant you ♪
♪ Just for me ♪
♪ But I'm content ♪
♪ The angels must have sent you ♪
♪ And they meant you ♪
♪ Just for me ♪
Now...
Ta, Te, Ti, toe, too.
No, no, Miss Lamont...
round tones, round tones.
Now let me hear you
read your line.
"And I can't stand him."
And I can't stand him.
"Can't."
Can't.
Can't. Can't.
Very good.
"Around the rocks the
rugged rascal ran."
"Around the rocks the rugged..."
No, no. "Rocks." "Rocks."
"Around the rocks the
rugged rascal ran."
Very good.
Hi, Don.
- Shall I continue?
- Don't mind me.
Now. "Sinful Caesar
sipped his snifter...
seized his knees and sneezed."
"Sinful Caesar snipped
his sifter..."
Sipped his snifter.
"Sipped his snifter."
Oh, thank you.
"Sinful Caesar sipped his snifter,
seized his knees and sneezed."
- Marvellous.
- Wonderful.
Here is a good one.
"Chester chooses chestnuts,
cheddar cheese with chewy chives.
He chews them and he chooses them.
He chooses them and
he chews them...
those chestnuts, cheddar
cheese and chives...
in cheery, charming chunks."
- Wonderful. Do another one.
- Thank you.
"Moses supposes his
toeses are roses...
but Moses supposes erroneously.
Moses, he knowses his
toeses aren't roses...
as Moses supposes
his toeses to be."
"Moses supposes his
toeses are roses...
but Moses supposes erroneously."
"But Moses, he knowses
his toes aren't roses...
as Moses supposes
his toeses to be."
Moses supposes his
toeses are roses...
but Moses supposes erroneously.
A mose is a mose.
A rose is a rose.
A toes is a toes.
♪ Moses supposes his
toeses are roses ♪
♪ But Moses supposes erroneously ♪
♪ Moses, he knowses his
toeses aren't roses ♪
♪ As Moses supposes
his toeses to be ♪
♪ Moses supposes his
toeses are roses ♪
♪ But Moses supposes erroneously ♪
♪ For Moses knowses his
toeses aren't roses ♪
♪ As Moses supposes
his toeses to be ♪
♪ A rose is a rose is
a rose is a rose ♪
♪ Is a rose is what Moses
supposes his toes is ♪
♪ Couldn't be a lily or
a Taffy daffy dilly ♪
♪ It's got to be a rose because
it rhymes with "mose" ♪
♪ Moses ♪
"A"
All right, here we go.
- Quiet.
Roll them.
Oh, Pierre. You
shouldn't have come.
She's got to talk into the
mike. I can't pick it up.
Cut.
What's the matter?
It's Lina.
Look, Lina, don't you
remember? I told you.
There's a microphone
right there...
- in the bush.
- Yeah.
You have to talk into it.
I was talking. Wasn't
I, Miss Dinsmore?
Yes, my dear. But please
remember, round tones.
"Pierre, you shouldn't have come."
Pierre, you shouldn't have come.
That's much better...
Hold it a second.
Now, Lina, look.
Here's the mike.
Right here in the bush.
Yeah.
Now, you talk towards it.
The sound goes through
the cable to the box.
A man records it on a
big record in wax...
but you have to talk
into the mike first.
In the bush.
Now try it again.
Gee, this is dumb.
She'll get it,
Dexter. Don't worry.
We're all nervous the first
day. Everything will be okay.
By the way. You know the
scene coming up where I say:
"Imperious princess of the night"?
I don't like those
lines. Is it all
right if I say what I always do?
"I love you. I love
you. I love you."
Sure. Any way it's comfortable.
But into the bush.
Okay.
Again.
Quiet.
Roll them.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Cut.
We're missing every other word.
You've got to talk into the mike.
Well, I can't make love to a bush.
All right, all right.
We'll have to think
of something else.
What are you doing?
- You're being wired for sound.
- What?
Watch out for those dentalised
D's and T's and those flat A's.
Everybody's picking on me.
Okay, Lina.
Now look at this flower, see?
The mike is in there.
That's it.
The sound will run from it...
through this wire,
onto the record.
It'll catch whatever you say.
Now let's hear how
it sounds, Lina.
Okay, quiet.
Roll them.
Oh, Pierre, you
shouldn't have come.
You're flirting with danger.
What's that noise?
It's picking up her heartbeat.
Swell.
Cut.
That's right. That should do it.
Now, don't forget.
The mike is on your shoulder.
And whatever you say goes through
the wire onto the record.
Now, please, Lina,
talk into the mike.
Don't make any quick movements
or you might disconnect it.
Okay, let's go.
- Quiet.
Roll them.
Oh, Pierre, you shouldn't have
come. You're flirting with danger.
What's this wire doing
here? It's dangerous.
You'd better not go in together.
Lina's probably waiting
right inside the door.
- Oh, how I wish...
- Don't worry.
I'll lead the cheering section
in the balcony. Good luck.
- Mr Lockwood.
- Hello.
What's that? The storm outside?
It's those pearls, Mr Simpson.
I am the noblest lady of the
court, second only to the queen.
Yet I am the saddest
of mortals in France.
What is the matter, milady?
I'm so downhearted, Theresa.
My father has me betrothed to
the Baron de Landsfield...
and I can't stand him.
Oh, but he's such a catch.
All the ladies of the court
wish they were in your shoes.
My heart belongs to another...
Pierre de Bataille.
Ever since I met him, I can't
get him out of my mind.
Sounds good and loud, huh?
Oh, Pierre.
You shouldn't have come.
You're flirting with danger.
They will surely find you out.
Your head is much too valuable.
She never could remember
where the microphone was.
'Tis Cupid himself
that called me here...
and I...
smitten by his arrow,
must fly to your side...
despite the threats
of Madame Guillotine.
But the night is
full of our enemies.
What you hitting him
with, a blackjack?
Imperious princess of the night...
I love you.
Oh, Pierre.
I love you, I love you, I love
you, I love you, I love you.
I love you, I love you,
I love you, I love you.
Did somebody get paid
for writing that?
Sounds like a comedy.
- It's a Lockwood-Lamont talkie.
- What?
This is terrible.
[DIALOGUE DISTORTED]
What's that?
The sound. It's out
of synchronisation.
Tell them to fix it.
Yes, sir.
What's this? Yvonne?
Captured by Rouge Noir
of the Purple Terror?
Oh, my sword.
I must fly to her side.
Yvonne, Yvonne...
my own.
Pierre will save me. Pierre.
Pierre is miles away, you witch.
No, no, no.
Yes, yes, yes.
This is a scream.
Give me The Jazz Singer.
"I love you, I love
you, I love you"...
- We're all ruined.
- You can't release this.
We're booked to open in six
weeks all over the country.
But you're such big
stars, we might get by.
I never wanna see Lockwood
and Lamont again.
Wasn't it awful?
This is the worst
picture ever made.
I liked it.
Well, take a last look at it.
It'll be up for auction
in the morning.
You're out of your mind.
It's Saturday. No bank will
foreclose until Monday.
- It wasn't so bad.
- That's what I told him.
There's no use kidding myself.
Once they release The
Duelling Cavalier,
Lockwood and Lamont are through.
The picture's a museum piece.
I'm a museum piece.
Things went wrong with the
sound. Get the technical...
No, it wasn't that.
This is sweet of both
of you, but I...
Something happened to me tonight.
Everything you said
about me is true.
I'm no actor.
I never was. Just a
lot of dumb show.
I know that now.
Well, at least you're
taking it lying down.
No kidding, Cosmo.
Did you ever see anything as
idiotic as me on that screen?
Yeah. How about Lina?
Heh. I ran her a close second.
Maybe it was a photo
finish. I'm through.
You're not through.
Why, of course not.
With your looks, you could
drive an ice waggon.
- Or shine shoes.
- Block hats.
- Sell pencils.
- Dig ditches.
Or go back into vaudeville.
♪ Fit as a fiddle and
ready for love ♪
♪ I could jump over
the moon up above ♪
♪ Fit as a fiddle and
ready for love ♪
Too bad I didn't do
that in Duelling
Cavalier. They might
have liked it.
- Why don't you?
- What?
- Make a musical.
- A musical?
Sure. Make a musical.
The new Don Lockwood. He yodels,
he jumps about to music.
The only trouble is that
after Duelling Cavalier...
nobody'd come to see
me jump off the
Woolworth Building
into a damp rag.
Turn The Duelling
Cavalier into a musical.
- Duelling Cavalier?
- Sure.
They've got six weeks
before it's released.
Add songs and dances, trim
bad scenes, add new ones.
And you got it.
Hey, I think it'll work.
- Of course.
- It's a cinch.
It may be crazy, but we'll do it.
The Duelling Cavalier
is now a musical.
- Hot dog.
- Hallelujah.
Whoopee. Fellas, I feel this
is my lucky day, March 23rd.
- Your lucky day's the 24th.
- What?
It's 1:30 already. It's morning.
Yes. And what a lovely morning.
♪ Good morning ♪
♪ We've talked the
whole night through ♪
♪ Good morning ♪
♪ Good morning to you ♪
♪ Good morning good morning ♪
♪ It's great to stay up late ♪
♪ Good morning good
morning to you ♪
♪ When the band began to play
the stars were shining bright ♪
♪ Now the milkman's on his way
it's too late to say good night ♪
♪ So good morning good morning ♪
♪ Sunbeams will soon
smile through ♪
♪ Good morning good
morning to you ♪
♪ And you and you and you ♪
♪ Good morning good morning ♪
♪ We've gabbed the
whole night through ♪
♪ Good morning good
morning to you ♪
♪ Nothing could be grander
than to be in Louisiana ♪
♪ In the morning In the morning ♪
♪ It's great to stay up late ♪
♪ Good morning good
morning to you ♪
♪ Might be just as zippy
if we was in Mississippi ♪
♪ When we left the movie show
the future wasn't bright ♪
♪ But came the dawn,
the show goes on
and I don't wanna say good night ♪
♪ So say good morning ♪
♪ Good morning ♪
♪ Rainbows are shining through ♪
♪ Good morning - Good morning ♪
- ♪ Bonjour.
- Monsieur ♪
- ♪ Buenos días.
- Muchas frías ♪
- ♪ Buon giorno.
- A ritorno ♪
- ♪ Guten morgen.
- Guten morgen ♪
♪ Good morning to you ♪
♪ Olé ♪
- ♪ Toro.
- Toro ♪
Hey, we can't make this a musical.
What do you mean?
Lina.
- Lina.
She can't act, she can't
sing and she can't dance.
- A triple threat.
- Yeah.
What's so funny?
I'm sorry, I was just thinking.
I liked her best when the
sound went off and she said:
"Yes, yes, yes."
"No, no, no."
"No, no..."
Wait a minute.
I am just about to be brilliant.
Come here, Kathy.
Come here. Now, sing.
- Huh?
- I said sing.
♪ Good morning good morning ♪
Don, keep your eyes
riveted on my face.
♪ Good morning good
morning to you ♪
Watch my mouth.
♪ Good morning good morning ♪
♪ It's great to stay up late ♪
♪ Good morning good
morning to you ♪
Well, convincing?
Enchanting. What?
Don't you get it?
Use Kathy's voice.
Lina moves her mouth and Kathy
sings and talks for her.
That's wonderful.
- I couldn't let you do it, Kathy.
- Why not?
You wouldn't be seen. You'd
throw away your career.
It has nothing to
do with my career.
It's only for this picture.
The important thing is to
save The Duelling Cavalier...
- save Lockwood and Lamont.
- Yeah.
Well, all right, if it's only
for this one picture, but...
- You think it'll get by?
- Of course.
It's simple to work the numbers.
Just dance around Lina and
teach her how to take a bow.
We'll spring it on
R.F. in the morning.
Don, you're a genius.
I'm glad you thought of it.
Oh, Cosmo.
Good night, Kathy.
See you tomorrow.
Good night, Don. Take
care of that throat.
You're a big singing
star now, remember?
This California dew is just a
little heavier than usual.
Really?
From where I stand, the sun is
shining all over the place.
♪ I'm singing in the rain ♪
♪ Just singing in the rain ♪
♪ What a glorious feeling ♪
♪ I'm happy again ♪
♪ I'm laughing at clouds ♪
♪ So dark up above ♪
♪ The sun's in my heart ♪
♪ And I'm ready for love ♪
♪ Let the stormy clouds chase ♪
♪ Everyone from the place ♪
♪ Come on with the rain ♪
♪ I've a smile on my face ♪
♪ I'll walk down the lane ♪
♪ With a happy refrain ♪
♪ Just singing ♪
♪ Singing in the rain ♪
♪ Dancing in the rain ♪
♪ I'm happy again ♪
♪ I'm singing ♪
♪ And dancing in the rain ♪
♪ I'm dancing ♪
♪ And singing ♪
♪ In the rain ♪
Why, that's wonderful.
We'll keep it secret until
we're ready to release...
just in case it doesn't come
off. I'm worried about Lina.
She doesn't like Miss Selden.
There might be fireworks.
Lina won't even know
she's on the lot.
Boys, this is great.
The Duelling Cavalier
can be saved.
Now, let's see.
The Duelling Cavalier with music.
The title.
The title's not right. We
need a musical title. Cosmo?
Hey. The Duelling Mammy.
No.
I've got it.
The Dancing Cavalier.
That's it. The Dancing Cavalier.
Remind me to make
you a scriptwriter.
Thanks. Have a cigar.
Thanks.
Now, what about the story?
We need modern musical numbers.
We throw a modern section into it.
The hero's a hoofer on Broadway.
He sings and he dances.
One night, backstage, he's
reading The Tale of Two Cities.
A sandbag hits his head.
He dreams he's back during
the French Revolution.
This way, we get in the
modern dancing numbers.
But in the dream, we can
still use the costumes.
Sensational. Cosmo, remind
me to give you a raise.
- Oh, R.F.
- Yes?
Give me a raise.
♪ He holds her in his arms ♪
♪ Would you? ♪
♪ He tells her of her charms ♪
♪ They met as you and I ♪
♪ And they were only friends ♪
♪ But before ♪
♪ The story ends ♪
♪ He'll kiss her with a sigh ♪
♪ Would you? ♪
♪ And if the girl were I ♪
♪ And would you dare to say ♪
♪ Let's do the same ♪
♪ As they ♪
♪ I would ♪
♪ Would you? ♪
♪ And would you dare to say ♪
♪ Let's do the same ♪
♪ As they ♪
♪ I would ♪
♪ Would you? ♪
Perfect. That Selden
girl is great.
I'm gonna give her a big build-up.
- Swell.
- How much is there left to do?
- One scene and a number.
- What number?
It's a new one. It's
for the modern part.
It's called "Broadway Melody."
It's the story of a young
hoofer who comes to New York.
First, we set the
stage with a song.
It goes like this.
♪ Don't bring a frown
to old Broadway ♪
♪ You got to clown on Broadway ♪
♪ Your troubles there ♪
♪ They're out of style ♪
♪ For Broadway always
wears a smile ♪
♪ A million lights ♪
♪ They flicker there ♪
♪ A million hearts
beat quicker there ♪
♪ No skies of grey on
that Great White Way ♪
♪ That's the Broadway ♪
♪ Melody ♪
♪ Gotta dance ♪
♪ Got to dance, got to dance ♪
♪ Broadway rhythm It's got me ♪
♪ Everybody dance ♪
♪ Out on that Gay White
Way and each merry café ♪
♪ Orchestras play taking
your breath away ♪
♪ Broadway rhythm It's got me ♪
♪ Everybody sing and dance ♪
♪ Oh, that Broadway rhythm ♪
♪ When I hear that happy beat ♪
♪ Feel like dancing
down the street ♪
♪ To that Broadway rhythm ♪
♪ Writhing, beating ♪
♪ Rhythm ♪
♪ Got to dance ♪
♪ When I hear that happy beat ♪
♪ Feel like dancing
down the street ♪
♪ When I hear that happy beat ♪
♪ Feel like dancing
down the street ♪
♪ Gotta dance ♪
♪ Got to dance ♪
♪ Gotta dance got to dance ♪
♪ That's the Broadway ♪
♪ Melody ♪
That's the idea. What
do you think of it?
I can't visualise it. I'll
have to see it on film first.
- On film, it'll be better yet.
- Don't forget.
Have Selden re-record
all of Lina's dialogue.
- It's all set up.
- And remember...
don't let Lina know about it.
All set in there?
Right.
Nothing can keep us apart.
Our love will last till
the stars turn cold.
All right, Kathy. Go ahead.
Nothing can keep us apart.
Our love will last till
the stars turn cold.
That's great. Perfect. Cut.
Till the stars turn cold.
Oh, Kathy, I love you.
I can't wait till this
picture's finished.
No more secrecy. I'm gonna
let Lina and everyone know.
Your fans will be
bitterly disappointed.
From now on, there's only
one fan I'm worried about.
There.
What did I tell you?
Thanks, Zelda. You're a real pal.
I want that girl off the lot at
once. She ain't gonna be my voice.
Zelda told me everything.
Thanks, Zelda. You're a real pal.
Anytime, Don.
Look, Don and I...
Don. Don't you dare call him Don.
I was calling him Don
before you were born.
I mean... You were kissing him.
I was kissing her. I happen
to be in love with her.
That's ridiculous. Everybody
knows you're in love with me.
Ha, ha. Now look, Lina.
Try and understand this.
I'm going to marry her.
Silly boy. She ain't
the marrying kind.
She's a flirt trying to
get ahead by using you.
Well, I'll put a stop to that. I'm
gonna go up and see
R.F. right now.
A little late. The
picture's finished.
If she weren't in it,
you'd be finished too.
As far as I can see, she's
the only one who's finished.
Who'll hear of her?
Everybody. Why do you think
Zelda's in such a sweat?
Kathy nearly stole the
picture from her.
She's only doing you a favour
in The Dancing Cavalier.
And she's getting full
screen credit for it too.
It'll say on the screen that I
don't talk and sing for myself?
Of course. What do you think?
- They can't do that.
- It's already done.
There's a whole publicity
campaign planned.
Publicity?
They can't make a fool out of me.
They can't make a laughing
stock out of Lina Lamont.
What do they think I
am, dumb or something?
Why, I make more money...
than Calvin Coolidge...
put together.
"Monumental Pictures enthusiastic
over Lina's singing and dancing."
I never said that.
"Premiere tomorrow night to reveal
Lina Lamont, big musical talent."
You can't pull a switch like this
on the publicity department.
We were prepared for
the Selden campaign.
Now you do this. At
least keep us informed.
Wait a minute. I don't
know anything about this.
What are we gonna do?
Nothing.
Absolutely nothing.
You wouldn't wanna call the
papers and say Lina Lamont...
is a big fat liar.
Did you send this stuff out?
I gave an exclusive story
to every paper in town.
You'll never get away
with it. Call the papers.
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
Don't tell me what to do, Lina.
What do you think I am,
dumb or something?
I had my lawyer go
over my contract.
Contract?
And I control my
publicity, not you.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
The studio is responsible for
every word printed about me.
If I don't like it, I can sue.
What?
I can sue.
If you tell the papers
about Kathy Selden...
it would be "detrimental and
deleterious" to my career.
I could sue you for
the whole studio.
- That's a lot of nonsense.
- Says so.
Right here.
Contract dated June 8, 1925,
paragraph 34,
subdivision letter A.
"The party of the first part..."
- That's me.
- You win, Lina.
We better take Kathy's
credit card off the screen.
All right, go ahead.
Let's just get this
premiere over with.
Satisfied?
There's just one
little thing more.
You want me to change the name of
the studio to Lamont
Pictures, Inc?
R.F., you're cute.
Now, I was just thinking.
You've given her a part
in Zelda's picture...
and you'll give her a
bigger one in the next.
So, what?
If she's done such a grand
job doubling for my voice...
don't you think she ought
to go on doing just that?
- And nothing else.
- You're out of your mind.
I'm still more important
to the studio than she is.
I wouldn't do that to
her in a million years.
You'd take her career away.
People don't do things like that.
People?
I ain't people.
I am a...
"A shimmering, glowing star
in the cinema firmament."
It says so...
right there.
Oh, Pierre, Pierre, my darling.
At last, I've found you.
Oh, Pierre.
Pierre, you're hurt. Speak
to me, speak to me.
♪ I'll kiss her with a sigh ♪
♪ Would you? ♪
♪ And if the girl were I ♪
Oh, Pierre, hold me
in your arms always.
Lockwood's a sensation.
Yes, but Lamont. What a
voice. Isn't she marvellous?
It's going over
wonderfully, isn't it?
Yeah.
Our love will last till
the stars turn cold.
♪ And would you dare to say ♪
♪ Let's do the same as they ♪
♪ I would ♪
♪ Would you? ♪
R.F., it's a real smash.
Congratulations. We owe you a lot.
Thank you.
- Kathy, we made it.
- It's a miracle.
It's great, Don. Just great.
You were fabulous. You sang
as well as Kathy Selden.
And I'm gonna for a long time.
What do you mean?
I mean she's gonna go
right on singing for me.
Listen, Lina.
I thought something was cooking
beneath those bleached curls.
Kathy has her own career. She
only did this for this picture.
That's what you think.
Come on, come on.
- Lina's getting carried away.
- Yeah, she is.
Listen, you boa constrictor.
Don't get any fancy ideas
about the future. Tell her.
Never mind, R.F. Listen
to that applause.
Wait till the money rolls in.
You won't give all that up because
a nobody don't wanna be my voice.
She's got something.
It's a gold mine.
Part of that choice is mine.
And I just won't do it.
You've got a five-year contract.
You'll do what R.F. says.
What's the matter? Why
don't you tell her off?
I'm confused. This
thing is so big...
- They're tearing the house apart.
- Take a curtain call.
I once gave you a cigar.
Can I have it back?
Listen. I'm an avalanche.
Selden, you're stuck.
If this happens, get a new
boy. I won't stand for it.
Who needs you? They'd come to see
me if I played opposite a monkey.
Don's a smash too.
I'll say a few words. I'm
still running the studio.
I'm not so sure.
You're Mr Producer, always
running things, running me.
From now on, as far as I'm
concerned, I'm running things.
- Lina Lamont Pictures, Inc., huh?
- Yeah.
You've gone a little too far.
- They're yelling for a speech.
- A speech?
Yeah, everybody's always
making speeches for me.
Tonight, I'm gonna do my own
talking. I'm gonna
make the speech.
- No, please.
- Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
This is Lina's big night and she's
entitled to do the talking.
- Right?
- Right.
Ladies and gentlemen.
I can't tell you...
how thrilled we are
at your reception...
for The Dancing Cavalier, our
first musical picture together.
If we bring a little joy
into your humdrum lives...
it makes us feel as
though our hard work...
ain't been in vain for nothing.
Bless you all.
She didn't sound that
way in the picture.
Cut the talk, Lina. Sing.
Sing us a song, Lina. Sing to us.
- Please.
- Come on, Lina, sing.
I got an idea. Come here.
Now, listen.
What am I gonna do?
We've got it. Get a mike set
up back of that curtain.
Kathy, come here. Kathy will
stand back of there and sing.
She'll be back of the curtain
singing, and I'll be in front...
- Like in the picture?
- Right.
You've got to do it.
This is too big.
She's got a five-year contract
with me. Get over to that mike.
You heard him, Kathy. Now do it.
I'll do it, Don.
But I never want to
see you again...
on or off the screen.
Now, come on, Lina.
What are you gonna sing?
Singing in the Rain.
In what key?
A-flat.
In A-flat.
♪ I'm singing in the rain
just singing in the rain ♪
♪ What a glorious feeling
I'm happy again ♪
♪ I'm laughing at clouds
so dark up above ♪
♪ The sun's in my heart ♪
♪ And I'm ready for love ♪
♪ Let the stormy clouds chase ♪
♪ Everyone from the place ♪
♪ Come on with the rain
I've a smile on my face ♪
♪ I'll walk down the lane
with a happy refrain ♪
♪ And singing just
singing in the rain ♪
♪ I'm singing in the rain
just singing in the rain ♪
♪ What a glorious feeling
I'm happy again ♪
♪ I'm laughing at clouds
so dark up above ♪
♪ The sun's in my heart ♪
♪ And I'm ready for love ♪
♪ Let the stormy clouds chase ♪
Stop that girl.
That girl running up
the aisle. Stop her.
That's the girl whose voice
you heard and loved.
She's the real star of the
picture, Kathy Selden.
Kathy.
♪ You are ♪
♪ My lucky star ♪
♪ I saw you ♪
♪ From afar ♪
♪ Two lovely eyes at me
they were gleaming ♪
♪ Beaming ♪
♪ I was starstruck ♪
♪ You're all ♪
♪ My lucky charms ♪
♪ I'm lucky ♪
♪ In your arms ♪
♪ You've opened heaven's portal ♪
♪ Here on earth for
this poor mortal ♪
♪ You ♪
♪ Are my ♪
♪ Lucky star ♪