Harry, answer that.
So, what do you wanna
hack for, Bickle?
I can't sleep nights.
- There's porno theatres for that.
- Yeah, I know. I tried that.
So, what do you do now?
Now? Ride around nights
mostly. Subways, buses.
Figure I'm gonna do that, I
might as well get paid for it.
You wanna work uptown?
South Bronx, Harlem?
I'll work anytime, anywhere.
Will you work Jewish holidays?
Anytime, anywhere.
All right. Let me see
your chauffeur's licence.
- How's your driving record?
- It's clean.
It's real clean,
like my conscience.
You gonna break my chops? I got
enough trouble with guys like you.
If you're gonna break my chops,
you can take it on the arches.
Sorry, sir, I didn't mean that.
- Physical?
- Clean.
- Age?
- Twenty-six.
Education?
Some.
Here, there, you know.
Military record?
Honourable discharge.
May 1973.
- Were you in the Army?
- Marines.
I was in the Marines too.
So, what is it?
You need an extra job?
Are you moonlighting?
Well, I just wanna
work long hours.
What's moonlighting?
Look, just fill out these forms
and check back tomorrow...
when the shift breaks.
O'Brien, please step up.
Take the car out through
58th Street, please.
Because it's crowded on 57th.
Hey, Rodriguez.
All right, all right,
I'm coming down there.
May 10th.
Thank God for the rain,
which has washed away...
the garbage and the trash
off the sidewalks.
I'm working long hours now.
Six in the afternoon
to 6 in the morning,
sometimes even 8 in the morning.
Six days a week, sometimes
seven days a week.
It's a long hustle, but
it keeps me real busy.
I can take in $300, $350 a week.
Sometimes even more when
I do it off the metre.
All the animals come out at night.
Whores, skunk-pussies, buggers,
queens, fairies, dopers, junkies.
Sick, venal.
Someday a real rain'll come and
wash all this scum
off the streets.
I go all over. I
take people to the
Bronx, Brooklyn. I
take them to Harlem.
I don't care. Don't make
no difference to me.
It does to some. Some
won't even take spooks.
Don't make no difference to me.
Driver, 48th and 6th, please.
Man, you are gorgeous.
Beautiful little girl.
I can't afford to get
stopped anywhere.
Oh, no. We wouldn't
want that to happen.
There'll be a big tip in it for
you, you do the right things.
You got a way.
Yeah. Now you're talking.
Driver, hurry up, will you?
Each night when I
return the cab...
I have to clean the
come off the back seat.
Some nights, I clean
off the blood.
Can I help you?
Yeah, what's your name?
My name is Travis.
That's nice. What
can I do for you?
I'd like to know what your
name is. What's your name?
Give me a break.
Look, you can tell me what your
name is. I'm not
gonna do anything.
Do you want me to
call the manager?
You don't have to
call the manager.
- Troy.
- All right. Okay, I mean...
Okay. Can I have a Chuckles there?
And do you have any
Jujubes? They last
longer. I'd like to
get some Jujubes.
What you see is what we got.
A Clark.
I'll take these.
Coca-Cola.
We don't have Coca-Cola. Royal
Crown Cola is all we got.
A dollar eighty-five.
Twelve hours of work and
I still can't sleep.
Damn.
The days go on and on.
And they don't end.
All my life needed was a
sense of some place to go.
I don't believe that
one should devote
his life to morbid self-attention.
I believe that someone should
become a person like other people.
I first saw her at
Palantine campaign
headquarters at 63rd and Broadway.
She was wearing a white dress.
She appeared like an angel...
out of this filthy mass.
She is alone.
They...
cannot...
touch...
her.
Yes. Well, you
delivered two boxes.
I think it's a total of
5000 campaign buttons.
Now, all the ones we had
before and our slogan is:
We are the people, and
are is underlined.
These new buttons
have we underlined.
That reads, We are
the people. Well,
I think there's a difference.
We are the people is not the
same as we are the people.
Let's not fight.
Look, we'll make it real simple.
We don't pay for the buttons.
We throw the buttons
away, all right?
Tom, come here a minute.
What?
What is it?
If Andy okays this canvass report,
send a copy to all headquarters.
I got to get that New York
Times article xeroxed.
- Don't forget the new photos.
- I didn't forget.
We have to emphasise mandatory
welfare. That's the issue to push.
First push the man,
then the issue.
Senator Palantine
is a dynamic man.
An intelligent, interesting,
fresh, fascinating man.
You forgot sexy.
I did not forget sexy.
Listen to you. You sound like
you're selling mouthwash.
We are selling mouthwash.
- Are we authorised to do that?
- Very funny.
You can get in trouble selling
pharmaceuticals in
a campaign office.
My uncle's in jail
because of that.
It's not really jail.
Of course, living
with his wife, anything
would be jail.
Look over there.
I love you.
Notice anything?
- No.
- Well, put your glasses on.
Okay, just a minute. All right.
That taxi driver's
been staring at us.
What taxi driver?
That one, the one
that's sitting there.
How long has he been there?
I don't know. It feels
like a long time.
- Does he bother you?
- No.
You mean yes, and
you're being sarcastic.
Oh, you're quick.
You're really quick.
Well, I try to be real quick.
I'll play the male in
this relationship...
Good luck.
And tell him to move. And I don't
need good luck. Thank you.
Oh, yes, you do. You
just think you don't.
Say, you're blocking our doorway.
You think you might move your cab?
You know, eye shadow, mascara...
lipstick, rouge.
Not rouge. Blush-on, they call it.
- The kind with the brush.
- Yeah, it's Blush-on.
Travis.
Hey, Wiz.
That's Blush-on. My wife uses it.
Ask Travis. He's a ladies' man.
A cup of coffee, please.
Anyway, whatever the fuck it
is, she uses a lot of it.
And then perfume. The spray kind.
Get this. In the middle of
the Triborough Bridge...
And this woman is beautiful.
She changes her pantyhose.
- No.
- Oh, yeah.
- What'd you do?
- I throw the metre, you know...
and I jump in the
back seat and whip
it out. I said, You
know what this is?
She says, it's love. I'm
gonna fuck her brains out.
She goes wild and she said:
That's the greatest single
experience of my life.
Then she gave me a $200 tip and
her phone number in Acapulco.
Travis, you know
Doughboy, Charlie T?
Hey, Travis. Got
change for a nickel?
Doughboy'll do
anything for a buck.
So how's it hanging?
What's that?
I turn on the radio. Some fleet
driver from Bell
just got all cut up.
Stickup?
No, he got cut up by some crazy
fucker. Cut half his ear off.
- Where?
- It was at 122nd Street.
Fucking Mau Mau land.
You run all over town,
don't you, Travis?
Travis?
Travis.
You run all over town, don't you?
Yeah.
You handle some pretty
rough customers, huh?
Yeah, I have.
- You carry a piece?
- No.
- You need one?
I know a fella who can get
you a real nice deal.
There's lots of shit around.
I never use mine. I'm
conservative, you know.
But it's a good thing to
have just as a threat.
I'm gonna go dig my dirt.
Travis.
Look.
Piece of Errol Flynn's bathtub.
Dig the symbols.
F-4-0-5-4-3-4.
And the watermark.
There's one person...
there's two persons...
and there's three persons.
I got this at his
estate, The Pines.
Why don't you take it, and
if you can sell it...
you give me half of what you got.
I don't want to.
Hey, I'm gonna get in
my cab and boogie.
- Oh, I'm so terribly sorry.
- Well...
- Nothing.
- That's very cute. Thank you.
Hey, you wanna see something?
Wait, I just typed, You
wanna see something?
- What?
- If you had...
these three fingers
missing on this hand...
and that hand missing
on that hand...
- how would you light the match?
- I wouldn't.
Go ahead. Give it a try.
Well, I don't think I could do it.
No?
It's gonna be difficult.
I'll give it a try.
I got my thumb back for
a second. Thank God.
Just a minute.
I can't do it.
The guy at the news
stand can do it.
Well, I don't work
at a news stand.
- Anyway, he's probably Italian.
- No.
- You're sure?
- He's black.
If he had been
Italian, he might've
been a thief. The mob does that.
If a thief screws up on the job,
they'll blow his fingers off.
This sounds like a
joke, but it's true.
If they kill a stool pigeon,
they leave a canary on the body.
It's symbolic.
Why not a pigeon
instead of a canary?
I don't know why not a
pigeon. Wait a minute.
You got to catch a
pigeon. A canary,
you can walk into a pet store...
boom, kill it right there.
Put it on anyone you want.
Hi. I'd like to volunteer.
Great. I'll take you
right over here.
I'd rather volunteer to
her, if you don't mind.
Why do you feel you have
to volunteer to me?
Because I think that
you are the most
beautiful woman I have ever seen.
Thanks.
But what do you
think of Palantine?
Well, I...
Palantine, the man you're
volunteering to help
elect president.
I'm sure he'll make
a good president.
I don't know what
his policies are,
but I'm sure he'll
make a good one.
- You wanna canvass?
- Yeah, I'll canvass.
How do you feel about the
senator's stand on welfare?
I don't really know his stand on
welfare, but I'm sure
it's a good stand.
- You're sure of that?
- Yeah.
We all work together
here, day and night...
so I'm sure the gentlemen
will sign you up over there.
The thing is, I drive a taxi at
night, so it's kind
of hard for me...
to work in the day.
Then what exactly do you want?
Would you like to come have
some coffee and pie with me?
Why?
- Why? I'll tell you why.
- Yeah.
I think you're a lonely person.
I drive by a lot,
and I see you here.
I see a lot of
people around you...
and I see these phones and all
this stuff on your desk...
that means nothing.
And when I came
inside and met you...
I saw in your eyes and how
you carried yourself...
that you're not a happy person.
And I think you need something.
And if you wanna call it a friend,
you can call it a friend.
- You're gonna be my friend?
- Yeah.
What do you say?
It's a little hard standing
here and asking you, so...
Five minutes, that's all. Just
outside. Right around here.
I'm there to protect you.
Come on. Just take a little break.
I have a break at 4:00.
And if you're here...
- 4:00 today?
- Yes.
- I'll be here.
- I'm sure you will.
- All right, 4 p.m.
- Right.
- Outside in the front?
- Yes.
Okay.
Oh, my name is Travis. Betsy?
Travis.
I appreciate this, Betsy.
May 26th, 4:00 p.m.
I took Betsy to Charles' Coffee
Shop on Columbus Circle.
I had black coffee
and apple pie with
a slice of melted yellow cheese.
I think that was a good selection.
Betsy had coffee and
a fruit salad dish.
She could've had
anything she wanted.
Fifteen thousand volunteers
in New York alone's not bad.
But the organisational problems.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
I got the same problems.
I got to get organised.
Little things,
like my apartment, my possessions.
One of these days,
I'll get organis-ised.
You mean organised?
Organis-ised.
Organis-ised. It's a joke.
O-R-G-A-N-E-Z-I-E-S-D.
You mean organis-ise.
Like those little
signs in offices that say, Think.
Do you like where you work?
We've got some good people. And I
think Palantine's
got a good chance.
You know you have beautiful eyes?
Do you like the guy you work with?
He's okay.
Yeah, I know. But do you like him?
He's funny, good at
his job. He's okay.
Though he does have
a few problems.
I would say he has
quite a few problems.
His energy seems to go
in the wrong places.
When I walked in and I saw
you two sitting there...
I could just tell that
there was no connection...
whatsoever.
And I felt when I walked in,
there was something between us.
There was an impulse that
we were both following.
So that gave me the
right to talk to you.
Otherwise, I never would've felt
that I had the right
to talk to you.
I never would've had the
courage to talk to you.
And with him, I felt
there was nothing.
When I walked in, I knew I was
right. Did you feel that way?
I wouldn't be here if I didn't.
Where are you from?
Upstate.
That fellow, I don't like him.
Not that I don't like him,
I just think he's silly.
I don't think he respects you.
I don't believe I've ever
met anyone quite like you.
You wanna go to...
a movie with me?
- I have to go back to work now.
- I don't mean now. Another time?
Sure. You know what
you remind me of?
- What?
- That song...
by Kris Kristofferson.
- Who's that?
- The songwriter.
He's a prophet...
He's a prophet and a pusher...
partly truth, partly fiction,
a walking contradiction.
You saying that about me?
Who else would I be talking about?
I'm no pusher. I've never pushed.
No, just the part about
the contradictions.
You are that.
I called Betsy again
at her office.
She said maybe we'd
go to a movie...
after work tomorrow.
That's my day off.
At first she hesitated, but I
called her again and she agreed.
Betsy, Betsy. Oh, no.
Betsy what? I forgot
to ask her last name.
Damn. I got to remember
stuff like that.
Don't worry about anyone
committing themselves...
until things start coming
in from California.
Listen, I think we should've
waited for the limo.
I don't mind the
cab, but I mind...
going to California
without the right
preparation. That'll
get us in trouble.
Are you Charles
Palantine, the candidate?
Yes, I am.
I'm a big supporter.
I tell everybody
that comes in this
taxi they have to vote for you.
Why, thank you...
Travis.
I'm sure you'll win. Everybody
I know's gonna vote for you.
I was gonna put one of your
stickers in my taxi...
but the company said it
was against their policy.
They're a bunch of jerks.
Let me tell you, I have
learnt more about America...
from riding in taxicabs than in
all the limos in the country.
- Oh, yeah?
- That's true.
- Can I ask you something, Travis?
- Sure.
What is the one thing about this
country that bugs you the most?
Well, I don't know. I don't follow
political issues
that closely, sir.
Oh, well, there must be something.
Well, whatever it is, he should
clean up this city here...
because this city
here's like an open
sewer. It's full
of filth and scum.
Sometimes I can hardly take it.
Whatever ever becomes the
president should just...
really clean it up.
Know what I mean?
Sometimes I go out and I smell it.
I get headaches, it's so bad.
And they just like... They
just never go away, you know?
I think that the
president should just...
clean up this mess.
He should flush
it right down the fucking toilet.
Well, I think I know
what you mean, Travis.
But it's not gonna be easy.
We'll have to make
radical changes.
Damn straight.
Here you go, Travis.
Keep the change.
Thank you.
- Nice talking to you.
You're a good man. I
know you're gonna win.
Thank you. Drive safe.
Come on, man. Get me out
of here, all right?
Come on.
Come on, baby. This
is a real drag.
Now, come on. Come on,
don't make no scene.
You wanna get busted?
Now, bitch, be cool.
Don't start no trouble.
Cabbie, forget about
this. It's nothing.
Be cool, bitch.
- Stop.
- Wanna hear something?
What's the matter, baby?
Get your ass out of here.
- Hi, there.
- Hi.
- Have a nice day today?
- Not particularly.
I got a present for you.
Now back to Gene Krupa's
syncopated style shortly.
Why'd you do that?
What else am I gonna
do with my money?
I wish you'd have
listened to this.
I would have, except my record
player doesn't work now.
Your stereo's broken?
How can you stand it? I
can't live without music.
I don't follow music too much,
but I would really like to.
Then you haven't played
this record yet?
No.
But I was thinking maybe we could
listen to it on
your record player.
Now, going back to 40
years of Chick Webb.
You got to be kidding.
- What?
- This is a dirty movie.
No, no. This is a movie that
a lot of couples come to.
- All kinds of couples go here.
- You sure about that?
Yeah, I see them all the time.
Come on.
Shut the fuck up.
- Where are you going?
- I have to leave now.
- Why?
- I don't know why I came in here.
- I don't like these movies.
- Well, I mean...
I didn't know you'd feel
that way about this movie.
- If I had known...
- These the only movies you go to?
Yeah, I mean I come and...
This is not so bad.
Taking me to a place
like this is as
exciting to me as
saying, Let's fuck.
There are other places
I can take you.
I don't know much about them, but
I can take you other places.
We're just different.
- Wait a second.
- I have to go.
- I've got to go now.
- Wait.
Wait a second, I
wanna talk to you.
Look, I have to go.
Taxi.
Can I talk to you at
least? Won't you at
least talk to me? I
didn't know you'd...
Won't you take the record?
- I've already got it.
- But, please.
- I bought it for you, Betsy.
- Now I've got two. Let's go.
Can I call you?
Jesus Christ, I got a taxi.
Hello, Betsy.
Hi, it's Travis.
How you doing? Listen, I'm
sorry about the other night.
I didn't know that was the
way you felt about it.
Well, I didn't know. If I would
have taken you somewhere else.
Are you feeling better or?
Maybe you had a
virus or something.
A 24-hour virus, you know.
It can happen. Yeah.
You've been working
hard, huh? Yeah.
Would you like to have
some dinner with me...
in the next few days or something?
How about just a cup of coffee?
I could come by the headquarters
or something, and we could...
Okay, okay.
Did you get my flowers in the?
You didn't get them? But
I sent some flowers.
Yeah. Well... Okay, okay.
Can I call you again?
Tomorrow or the next day? Okay.
No, I'm gonna... Okay,
yeah, sure. Okay.
So long.
I tried several times
to call her...
but after the first
call, she wouldn't
come to the phone any longer.
I also sent flowers,
but with no luck.
The smell of the flowers
only made me sicker.
The headaches got worse. I
think I got stomach cancer.
I shouldn't complain, though.
You're only as healthy...
You're only as
healthy as you feel.
You're only...
as healthy...
as...
you...
feel.
Let's not have any trouble, okay?
Why won't you talk to me?
You think I don't
know you're here?
You think I don't know?
- Please leave.
- Take your hands off.
I just want you to know...
Please, just leave. This
is no place to do this.
Take your hands off me.
- Take your hands off.
- Just leave.
- All right, just leave, then.
- I'm gonna tell you...
you're in a hell. You'll
die in hell like the rest.
- Come on. There's a cop.
- You're like the rest of them.
Look, I'm calling
the cop. Officer.
Officer.
Look, don't come around here,
because I'll call the police.
I realise now how much she's just
like the others, cold and distant.
And many people are like that.
Women for sure.
They're like a union.
Yo, cab.
Okay, pull over to
the kerb over there.
Right over to the
kerb. Over there.
No, no, don't... Don't... Don't...
The fucking metre.
What are you doing?
What are you doing with the metre?
Did I tell you to put? Did I tell
you to do that with the metre?
Put the metre back. Let
the numbers go on.
I don't care what I have to pay.
I'm not getting out.
Put the metre back on.
Put it down.
Put it... That's right.
Put it... Put it down.
That's right.
Why are you writing? Don't write.
Put the thing down. Just sit.
I didn't tell you to write.
I just said, Pull over.
We pulled over to the kerb.
We're gonna sit here.
We're gonna sit.
Cabbie, you see that light
up there? The window?
The light? The window
in the second floor.
The one that's closest to
the edge of the building.
The light up in the
window. Second storey.
What are you, blind?
Do you see the light?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, you see it. Good.
You see the woman?
Do you see the woman
in the window?
- Yeah.
- You see the woman. Good.
I want you to see that woman
because that's my wife.
But that's not my apartment.
It's not my apartment. You
know who lives there, huh?
No, I mean, you wouldn't know.
But you know who lives there?
A nigger lives there.
How do you like that?
And I'm g... I'm gonna kill her.
There's nothing else.
I'm gonna kill her.
Well, what do you think of that?
I said, what do you think of that?
Don't answer.
You don't have to
answer everything.
I'm gonna kill her with
a .44 Magnum pistol.
I have a .44 Magnum pistol. I'm
gonna kill her with that gun.
Did you ever see what a .44 Magnum
pistol can do to a woman's face?
I mean, it'd fucking destroy
it. Just blow it right apart.
That's what it can do to her face.
Did you ever see what it can do
to a woman's pussy? You should.
You should see what a .44 Magnum's
gonna do to a woman's pussy.
What's that?
I know you must think
that I'm, you know...
You must think I'm pretty
sick or something.
Right? You must think
I'm pretty sick?
Right? I bet you really
think I'm sick, right?
You think I'm sick?
You don't have to answer.
I'm paying for the ride.
I picked up this midget, you know.
He's very well-dressed,
Italian suit...
good-looking, with a
beautiful tall blonde.
- Was it a lady midget?
- No, the guy was a midget.
- The blonde was a lady.
- I got you.
Those midgets are funny.
Sometimes I like to hold a midget.
They're funny. They always
wanna sit in the front seat.
Then I pick up these two fags.
They're going downtown.
They're wearing
rhinestone T-shirts.
They start arguing and yelling.
The other one says, You bitch,
and starts beating him.
I say, I don't care what
you do in the privacy...
of your own home,
behind closed doors.
This is an American free country.
We got a pursuit of
happiness thing.
You're consenting, you're adult.
But, you know, in my fucking
cab, don't go busting heads.
- God loves you, do what you want.
- Tell them to go to California.
In California, when
two fags split up,
one's got to pay the
other one alimony.
Not bad. They're way ahead out
there, you know? California.
So I tell them to
get out of the cab.
One time, I saw a cop chase
this guy with one leg.
- He was on crutches, you know.
- The cop?
No, the dude he was chasing.
Fucking cops, they chase anything.
- Hey, Travis.
- Hey, you got that 5 you owe me?
My man is loaded. Loaded.
I'd be broke if I hadn't caught me
some people from
Ohio out at Kennedy.
I took them into Manhattan by way
of Long Beach, tipped me $5.
What's the action around?
It's pretty slow.
I'm shoving on.
Hey, Wiz, wait.
- Can I talk to you for a second?
- Bye, Killer.
Thank you. Night.
- You put it down.
- You can have them all you want.
Hey, don't be hitting my man.
You better take your ass out, boy.
Yeah?
I know you and I ain't
talked too much, you know.
But I figure you've been
around a lot, so you could...
Shoot, that's why they
call me the Wizard.
I got...
It's just that I got
a... I got a...
Things got you down?
Yeah, happens to the best of them.
Yeah, they got me
real down. Real...
I just wanna go out...
and you know, like, really...
Really... Really do something.
Taxi life, you mean?
Yeah, well...
No, it's...
I don't know.
I just wanna go out...
I really...
I really wanna...
I got some bad ideas
in my head. I just...
Look. Look at it this way.
A man... A man takes
a job, you know.
And that job...
you know, that becomes what he is.
You know, like...
You do a thing, and
that's what you are.
I've been a cabbie for 17
years. Ten years at night.
And I still don't own my
own cab, you know. Why?
Because I don't want to.
That must be what I want.
You know, to be on
the night shift,
driving somebody else's cab.
You understand?
You get a job, you become the job.
One guy lives in Brooklyn, one
guy lives in Sutton Place.
You get a lawyer,
another guy's a doctor.
Another guy dies, another
guy gets well...
and people are born.
I envy you, your youth.
Go out and get laid. Get
drunk. You know, do anything.
You got no choice, anyway.
I mean, we're all fucked.
More or less, you know?
I don't know. That's about the
dumbest thing I ever heard.
It's not Bertrand Russell, but
what do you want? I'm a cabbie.
What do I know?
I don't even know what the
fuck you're talking about.
Maybe I don't know either.
Don't worry so much.
Relax, Killer,
you're gonna be all right.
I know. I've seen a
lot of people...
- and I know.
- Okay.
Okay. Thanks, man.
I'll see you. I guess...
Yeah, you know. You're all
right. You're all right.
What do you think
of your opponent's
chances in the upcoming primary?
Mr Goodman is a fine man.
I would certainly, if it
came to it, prefer him...
to our opponent in
the other party.
I think that my programmes
are better defined than his.
They're more imaginative. I have
a better chance of winning.
It's academic, though. He's not
gonna win the primary. I am.
I see.
Well, one more thing
I'd like to ask you.
How do you feel your
campaign is going?
When we came up with our
slogan we are the people...
when I said Let the people rule...
I felt I was being somewhat
overly optimistic.
I must tell you that I am more
optimistic now than ever before.
The people are rising to the
demands that I have made on them.
The people are beginning to rule.
I feel it is a
groundswell. I know...
it will continue through
the primary and in Miami.
And I know it will rise...
to an unprecedented
swell in November.
That bitch, goddamn. I'll
blow her brains out.
I'll kill her, goddamn
it. I'm gonna
get my hands on
her, I'll kill her.
Shoot, goddamn it. Fucker.
I swear if I get my hands on her,
I'll kill that fucking bitch.
- Hey, Sport.
I'll kill her. Damn it.
- That guy keeps following us.
- Don't look at him.
Hey, guys.
- You wanna take a walk?
- Yeah.
Loneliness has followed me
my whole life, everywhere.
In bars, in cars...
sidewalks, stores, everywhere.
There's no escape.
I'm God's lonely man.
June 8th.
My life has taken
another turn again.
The days move along with
regularity, over and over...
one day indistinguishable
from the next.
A long, continuous chain.
And then suddenly...
there is change.
Travis, this here's Easy Andy.
He's a travelling salesman.
How you doing, Travis?
- You got a .44 Magnum?
- It's an expensive weapon.
That's all right. I got money.
It's a real monster.
Stop a car at 100
yards, put a round
right through the engine block.
Here you go.
It's a premium,
high-resale weapon.
Look at that.
Look at that. That's a beauty.
I could sell this gun to some
jungle bunny in Harlem for $500.
But I just deal high-quality
goods to the right people.
How about that?
This might be a little too
big for practical purposes.
In which case, for
you, I'd recommend...
38 snub-nosed.
Look at this.
Look at that. That's a
beautiful little gun.
It's nickel-plated
with a snub-nose...
otherwise the same as
a service revolver.
That'll stop anything that moves.
The Magnum, they use that in
Africa for killing elephants.
That .38, that's a funny gun.
Some of these guns are like toys.
That .38, you go out and hammer
nails with it all day...
come back and it'll cut dead
centre on target every time.
It's got a really nice action
to it and a heck of a wallop.
You interested in an automatic?
It's a Colt .25 automatic.
It's a nice little gun.
It's a beautiful gun.
Holds six shots in the clip,
one shot in the chamber.
If you're dumb enough
to put a round there.
Here. Look at this.
.380 Walther.
Holds eight shots in the clip.
That's a nice gun.
That's a beautiful little
gun. Look at that.
During World War II, they used
this gun to replace the P 38.
Just given out to officers.
Ain't that a little honey?
- How much for everything?
- All together?
Well, only a jackass
would carry that
cannon in the streets like that.
Here's a beautiful handmade
holster I had made in Mexico.
Forty dollars.
Three-fifty for the Magnum,
250 for the .38...
one and a quarter for the
.25, 150 for the .380.
You take this and wait here.
I'll walk down with you.
How about dope? Grass? Hash? Coke?
Mescaline? Downers? Nembutal?
Tuinal? Chloral hydrates?
How about uppers, amphetamines?
No, I'm not interested
in that stuff.
I can get you crystal
meth, nitrous oxide.
How about a Cadillac? A
brand-new Cadillac...
with the pink slip, two grand.
June 29th.
I got to get in shape now. Too
much sitting has ruined my body.
Too much abuse has
gone on for too long.
From now on, it'll be 50
push-ups each morning.
Fifty pull-ups. There
will be no more pills.
There will be no more bad food,
no more destroyers of my body.
From now on, it'll be
total organisation.
Every muscle must be tight.
Look at the size of that.
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
Oh, it looks so good.
It's getting harder and harder,
and it's throbbing now.
The idea had been growing
in my brain for some time.
True force.
All the king's men cannot
put it back together again.
Where do we get more of these?
Where do you think?
At headquarters.
All the way back there?
- Come on.
- They'll work.
- Maybe it's the speakers.
- I've done this 100 times.
- You've done this before?
- Yes, don't worry.
- When was the last time?
- I've never done this before.
Betsy.
- Betsy.
- What?
Betsy. Come here, come here.
Hey.
Hey, you're a Secret
Service man, aren't you?
Just waiting for the senator.
You're waiting for the senator?
That's a very good answer.
Shit, man.
I'm waiting for the
sun to shine. Yeah.
No, the reason I asked if you
were a Secret Service man...
I won't say anything.
Is because I...
I saw some suspicious-looking
people over there.
- You did?
- They were right over there.
They were just here.
They were very, very...
- Suspicious.
- Yeah.
Where'd he go?
Is it hard to get to be
in the Secret Service?
Why?
Well, I was just curious, because
I think I'd be good at it.
I'm very observant.
I was in the Marine
Corps, you know.
I'm good with crowds.
I noticed your little pin there.
That's like a signal, isn't it?
Sort of.
A signal. A secret signal
for a Secret Service.
Hey, what kind of
guns you guys carry?
.38s? .45s? .357 Magnums?
Something bigger, maybe?
Look, if you're
really interested, if
you give me your
name and address...
we'll send you all the information
on how to apply. How's that?
- You will?
- Sure.
Okay.
Why not?
My name is Henry...
Krinkle. K-R-I-N-K-L-E.
154 Hopper Avenue.
- Hopper?
- Yeah.
You know, like a rabbit? Hip, hop.
Fair Lawn, New Jersey.
Is there a zip code?
Yeah, 6-1-0-4-5-2.
- Okay?
- That's six digits. 6, 1...
Oh, well, 6-1-0-4-5.
Okay.
I was thinking of my
telephone number.
Well, I've got it all.
Henry, we'll get all the
stuff right out to you.
Thanks a lot. Hey, great.
Thanks a lot. Hell. Jesus.
- Be careful today.
- Right. Will do.
You have to be careful around
a place like this. Bye.
Damn it.
Yeah.
I'm faster than you,
you fucking sick...
I saw you coming, you fuck.
Shitheel.
I'm standing here.
You make the move.
It's your move.
Don't try it, you fuck.
You talking to me?
Well, then who the hell else are
you talking to? You talking to me?
Well, I'm the only one here.
Who the fuck do you think
you're talking to?
Oh, yeah?
Okay.
Listen, you fuckers,
you screwheads.
Here is a man who would
not take it any more.
Who would not let...
Listen, you fuckers,
you screwheads.
Here is a man who would
not take it any more.
A man who stood up
against the scum...
the cunts, the dogs,
the filth, the shit.
Here is someone who stood up.
You're dead.
Hey, Travis.
Hi, Melio.
Yeah, man?
Okay, shut your fucking
mouth and give
me the cash out the
drawer. Come on.
- Let's go. Give me the damn cash.
- Don't shoot.
Stop taking so long. Come on.
Let me have it. Give me the bread.
- This all you got?
- That's it.
I don't have any more money, man.
- That's all I got.
- You got more.
- I tell you, I got no money.
- Reach in your sock.
- Give me the rest of the bread.
- Hey. Hey.
- Did you get him?
- Yeah, I got him.
Shit, man.
Is he dead?
I don't know. His eyes are moving.
I ain't got a permit
for this thing.
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
Don't worry. I'll take care of it.
- Can I give you some money?
- No, man, just get out of here.
No, man. I'll take
care of it. Go ahead.
The fifth motherfucker this year.
Walt Whitman, that
great American poet...
spoke for all of us when he said:
I am the man. I suffered.
I was there. Today I say to you:
We are the people. We suffered.
We were there.
We, the people,
suffered in Vietnam.
We, the people, suffered.
We still suffer...
from unemployment, inflation...
crime and corruption.
Dear Father and Mother...
July is the month I remember...
which brings not only your
wedding anniversary...
but also Father's Day
and Mother's birthday.
I'm sorry I can't remember
the exact dates...
but I hope this card will
take care of them all.
I'm sorry, again, I cannot
send you my address...
like I promised to last year.
But the sensitive nature of
my work for the government...
demands utmost secrecy.
I know you will understand.
I am healthy and well and
making lots of money.
I've been going with a
girl for several months...
and I know you'd be proud
if you could see her.
Her name is Betsy, but I can
tell you no more than that.
Hey, cabbie, you can't park here.
Come on. Come on, let's
go. Let's go. Move it.
Bear the burden of
suffering for the few.
No more will we fight
the wars of the few...
through the heart of the many.
I hope this card finds you
all well, as it does me.
I hope no one has died.
Don't worry about me.
One day there will be a knock
on the door and it'll be me.
Love, Travis.
Don't you have some idea?
I'm not the one who wants to talk.
But you must know that the reason
that I didn't marry him...
is because I couldn't stand
to be a cause of divorce.
Now he's getting a divorce anyway.
Phillip wants to marry me, Brock.
I do love him.
What about us, June?
Our marriage?
You got to know our
marriage wasn't legal.
In the eyes of God,
we are married.
Brock, please don't do this to me.
I love him so...
Damn.
Goddamn.
They trying to get in the picture.
- You looking for some action?
- Yeah.
- You see that guy over there?
You go talk to him.
His name is Matthew.
I'll be over there
waiting for you.
Okay.
Your name Matthew? I
want some action.
Officer.
I swear I'm clean. I'm just
waiting here for a friend.
You gonna bust me
for nothing, man?
I'm not a cop. I ain't a...
Then why are you
asking me for action?
Because she sent me over.
I suppose that ain't a .38
you've got in your sock.
A .38?
I'm clean, man.
- Shit, you're a real cowboy?
- Yeah.
That's nice, man. All
right. That's all right.
Fifteen dollars, 15 minutes.
Twenty-five dollars, half an hour.
Shit.
A cowboy, huh?
I once had a horse.
In Coney Island.
She got hit by a car.
Well, take it or leave it.
If you wanna save yourself
some money, don't fuck her.
Because you'll be back for more.
She's 12 and a half years old. You
ain't never had no
pussy like that.
Do anything you want.
Come on her...
fuck her in the mouth, in
the ass. Come on her face.
She'll get your cock so hard,
she'll make it explode.
But no rough stuff. All right?
All right, I'll take it.
Hey, man. Don't take out
no money over here.
You wanna fuck me?
You're gonna fuck her,
you give her the money.
Catch you later, copper.
- What'd you say?
- I'll see you later, copper.
I'm no cop, man.
Well, if you are, it's
entrapment already.
I'm hip.
Funny, you don't look hip.
Go ahead. Have yourself a
good time. Go ahead, man.
You're a funny guy.
But looks aren't everything.
Go ahead, man. Have a good time.
You're a funny guy.
Hey.
The room'll cost you 10 bucks.
I'm timing you too.
Come on.
Are you really 12 and a half?
Listen, mister, it's your time.
Fifteen minutes ain't long.
When that cigarette burns
out, your time is up.
How old are you?
You won't tell me?
- What's your name?
- Easy.
- That's not any kind of name.
- It's easy to remember.
Yeah, but what's your real name?
I don't like my real name.
But what's your real name?
Iris.
What's wrong with that?
It's a nice name.
That's what you think.
No, don't do that. Don't do
that. Don't you remember me?
Remember when you got into a
taxi? It was a chequered taxi.
You got in and that guy
Matthew came by...
and he said he wanted
to take you away.
He pulled you away.
I don't remember that.
- You don't remember any of that?
- No.
I'm gonna get you out of here.
Listen, we better make
it or Sport'll get mad.
How do you wanna make it?
I don't wanna make
it. Who's Sport?
That's Matthew. I call him Sport.
Wanna make it like this?
Listen, I...
Can't you understand something?
You're the one that came into my
cab. You wanted to
get out of here.
Well, I must've been stoned.
- Why? They drug you?
- Oh, come off it, man.
What are you doing?
Don't you wanna make it?
No, I don't wanna make
it. I wanna help you.
Well, I could help you.
Damn, man.
Goddamn it.
Shit, man. What the hell's
the matter with you?
We don't have to make it, mister.
Damn it. Don't you
wanna get out of here?
Can't you understand why I'm here?
I think I understand.
I tried to get into your cab...
and now you wanna come
and take me away.
- Is that it?
- Yeah, but don't you wanna go?
- I can leave any time I want to.
- Then what about that one night?
Look, I was stoned.
That's why they stopped me.
When I'm not stoned I got
no place else to go.
So they just...
protect me from myself.
I don't know.
I don't know. Okay, I tried.
Hey, look, I understand.
- And it means something, really.
- Yeah, well.
Well, look, can I see you again?
- That's not hard to do.
- I don't mean like that.
I mean, you know, regularly. This
is nothing for a person to do.
How about breakfast tomorrow?
- Tomorrow?
- I get up at 1:00.
- One o'clock?
- One o'clock.
Well, I got a thing.
I don't know...
Do you want to or not?
Yeah, I want... Okay, all right.
- Okay, 1:00.
- One o'clock.
Okay. See you tomorrow.
Oh, Iris. My name is Travis.
Thanks a lot, Travis.
So long, Iris. See you tomorrow.
Sweet Iris.
This is yours.
Spend it right.
Come back anytime, cowboy.
I will.
Why do you want me to
go back to my parents?
They hate me.
Why do you think I split?
There ain't nothing there.
Yeah, but you can't live
like this. It's a hell.
A girl should live at home.
Didn't you ever hear
of women's lib?
What do you mean, women's lib?
You're a young girl. You
should be at home now.
You should be dressed up,
going out with boys.
You should be going to school.
- You know, that kind of stuff.
- Oh, God, are you square.
Hey, I'm not square.
You're square.
You're full of shit, man.
What are you talking about?
You walk out with...
fucking creeps, lowlifes
and degenerates...
and you sell your little
pussy for nothing, man?
For some lowlife pimp?
Stands in a hall.
I'm the? I'm square? You're
the one that's square, man.
I don't go screw and fuck with
killers and junkies
the way you do.
You call that being hip?
What world you from?
- Who's a killer?
- That guy Sport's a killer.
Sport never killed nobody.
- He killed...
- He's a Libra.
He's a what?
I'm a Libra too. That's
why we get along so well.
He looks like a killer to me.
I think that Cancers
make the best lovers...
but my whole family are air signs.
He's also a dope-shooter.
What makes you so high and
mighty? Will you tell me that?
Did you ever try looking at your
own eyeballs in the mirror?
What'll you do about Sport
and that old bastard?
- When?
- When you leave.
I'll just leave them.
- Just leave?
- They got other girls.
You just can't do that.
What are you gonna do?
Want me to call the cops?
The cops don't do
nothing. You know that.
Look, Sport never treated me
bad. He didn't beat me up once.
But you can't allow him to
do the same to other girls.
You can't allow him to do that.
He is the lowest kind of person.
Somebody's got to do
something to him.
He's the scum of the earth.
He's the worst...
sucking scum I have
ever, ever seen.
You know what he
told me about you?
He called you names. He called
you a little piece of chicken.
He does... He doesn't mean it.
I'll move up to one of
them communes in Vermont.
I never seen a commune
before, but I don't know.
I saw...
some photos once in a magazine.
It didn't look very clean.
Why don't you come with me?
What? Come to the commune
with you? No, no.
Why not?
- I don't go to places like that.
- Oh, come on, why not?
I don't get along with
people like that.
- Are you a Scorpion?
- What?
That's it. You're a Scorpion.
I can tell every time.
Besides, I got to stay here.
Come on. Why?
I got something very
important to do.
So, what's so important?
I'm doing something
for the government.
The cab thing is just part-time.
Are you a narc?
Do I look like a narc?
Yeah.
I am a narc.
God. I don't know who's
weirder, you or me.
Sure you don't wanna come with me?
I'll give you the money to go.
- You don't have to do that.
- I want you to take it.
I don't want you to take
anything from them.
And I wanna do it.
I don't have anything
better to do with my money.
I might be going away for a while.
You're just a little
tense, that's all.
I don't like what
I'm doing, Sport.
Baby, I never wanted you
to like what you're doing.
If you ever liked what you were
doing, you wouldn't be my woman.
You never spend any
time with me any more.
Well, I got to attend
to business, baby.
You miss your man, don't you?
I don't like to be
away from you either.
You know how I feel about you.
I depend on you.
I'd be lost without you.
Don't you ever forget that.
How much I need you.
Come to me, baby.
Let me hold you.
When you're close to me
like this, I feel so good.
I only wish every man could know
what it's like to be loved by you.
That every woman, everywhere...
had a man who loves
her like I love you.
God, it's good so close.
You know, at times like this...
I know I'm a lucky man.
Touching a woman who
wants me and needs me.
It's only you that
keeps me together.
Now I see it clearly. My
whole life has pointed...
in one direction. I see that now.
There never has been
any choice for me.
Ladies and gentlemen...
the next president of the United
States, Senator Charles Palantine.
Thank you, Tom.
Ladies and gentlemen...
we are met today at a
crossroads, Columbus Circle.
This is no ordinary place.
It is a place where many roads
and many lives intersect.
It is appropriate that
we meet here today...
because these are
not ordinary times.
We meet at a
crossroads in history.
For far too long, the wrong
roads have been taken.
The wrong roads have led us
into war, into poverty...
into unemployment and inflation.
Today I say to you, we have
reached the turning point.
No longer will we, the
people, suffer for the few.
Now, I would lie to you if I told
you the new roads would be easy.
They will not be easy.
Nothing that is right and
good has ever been easy.
We, the people, know that.
And we, the people, know the
right roads and the good.
Today I say to you, we are
the people, you and I.
And it is time to let
the people rule.
Thank you.
All right, let him
through. Pull back.
Palantine.
Thank you. Thank you.
Over there. Get that man.
Give him some air.
Give him some air, will you?
- I never saw him.
- I saw him run.
- I saw him.
- Where was he?
What's happening?
Got the money?
- Iris in her room?
- Yeah.
Okay.
Hey, Sport, how you doing?
Okay, okay, my man. How?
- Where do I know you from, man?
- I don't know.
How's everything in
the pimp business?
- Do I know you?
- No.
Do I know you?
Get out of here.
Come on, get lost.
Do I know you?
How's Iris?
You know Iris.
No, I don't know
nobody named Iris.
Iris? Come on, get
out of here, man.
You don't know anybody named Iris?
I don't know nobody named Iris.
No?
Get back to your fucking
tribe before you get hurt.
I don't want no trouble, okay?
You got a gun?
Get the fuck out of here,
man. Get out of here.
Suck on this.
Hey.
You crazy son of a bitch.
Fucking son of a bitch.
I'll kill you. I'll kill you.
I'll kill you. I'll
fucking kill you.
Crazy son of a bitch.
I'll kill you.
You fucking bastard.
You crazy son of a
bitch. I'll kill you.
I'll kill you. I'll kill
you. I'll kill you.
Stop.
Don't shoot him.
Dear Mr Bickle:
I can't say how happy Mrs
Steensma and I were...
to hear that you are
well and recuperating.
We tried to visit you
at the hospital...
when we were in New
York to pick up Iris...
but you were still in a coma.
There is no way we
can repay you...
for returning our Iris to us.
We thought we had lost her...
and now our lives are full again.
Needless to say...
you are something of a hero
around this household.
I'm sure you want
to know about Iris.
She's back in school
and working hard.
The transition has been
very hard for her...
as you can well imagine.
But we have taken steps to see...
she has never cause
to run away again.
In conclusion...
Mrs Steensma and I would
like to again thank you...
from the bottom of our hearts.
Unfortunately, we cannot afford
to come to New York again...
to thank you in person,
or we surely would.
But if you should ever
come to Pittsburgh...
you would find yourself a most
welcome guest in our home.
Our deepest thanks,
Burt and Ivy Steensma.
Eddie, the owner-operator,
comes up,
he says, Hey, I wanna swap tyres.
I say, These are new tyres.
Why not throw in something
else, like your wife?
His wife was Miss
New Jersey of 1957.
That's why the fleet
has no spares.
- Doughboy, Wizard, Killer.
- Hey.
- Charlie T.
- What's happening?
Hey, Travis, you got a fare.
Shit.
Well, see you later.
See you, Travis.
Hello, Travis.
Hello.
I hear Palantine got
the nomination.
Yeah, won't be long
now. Seventeen days.
Well, I hope he wins.
I read about you in the
papers. How are you?
Oh, it was nothing,
really. I got over that.
The papers always
blow these things up.
Just a little
stiffness. That's all.
Travis.
How much was it?
So long.