They've killed the boy!
They've killed young Paolo!
They've killed your son Paolo!
Murderers! Murderers!
My son...
All my respect, Don Ciccio.
You killed my husband because
he wouldn't give in to you.
And his oldest son Paolo...
...because he swore revenge.
But Vito is only nine.
And dumb-witted.
He never speaks.
It's not his words I'm afraid of.
He's weak. He couldn't hurt anyone.
But when he grows,
he'll grow strong.
Don't worry. This little boy
can't do a thing to you.
When he's a man, he'll
come for revenge.
I beg you, Don Ciccio,
spare my only son.
He's all I have left.
I swear to God he'll never do
you any harm. Spare him!
Vito, run!
Move and I'll kill him!
Run, Vito!
Kill him!
Any family who hides the boy
Vito Andolini will regret it!
You understand?
Anybody who hides the boy
Vito Andolini is in for trouble!
Vito, we're praying for you!
If anyone is hiding the boy
Vito Andolini...
...turn him over to us.
Don Ciccio will thank you for it!
It'll be better for the boy,
and better for you!
Any family who hides the boy
Vito Andolini will regret it!
Nurse.
Money?
Interpreter!
Where are you from?
- What is your name?
- Maria.
What is your name?
Come on, son. What is your name?
Vito Andolini from Corleone.
Corleone. Vito Corleone.
Okay, over there.
Next.
Tell him he has smallpox.
Quarantine three months.
Vito Corleone!
Here he is. This is him.
Did you bring the car keys?
Laurie! Laurie!
Mama!
- Look who's here.
- Father Carmelo.
- This is Father Carmelo.
- I'm Merle Johnson.
Mama!
- Here I am.
- After one week?
I sent the car to the airport last week
to pick you up.
It was chaos. Anyway, here I am, just
one week late. And this is for my mama!
- What is this?
- You remember Merle?
- Hello, Mama.
- Yeah, hello. How are you? Thank you.
Where's Michael? I gotta talk to him and get a
few things straight, and I can't wait on line.
You go see your children first...
and then you worry about waiting on line to
see your brother. Like everybody else.
- Ladies and gentlemen.
- Frankie, wake up.
A most distinguished guest
would like to say a few words.
Would you please welcome Senator
Pat Geary of the state of Nevada.
And there's Mrs Geary.
Thank you very much,
ladies and gentlemen.
And this is a very, very happy day
for me and my wife, Mrs. Geary.
We see Nevada far too seldom.
but particularly today when we can join
with old friends, we can make new friends...
and we help celebrate
a young man's first communion...
and also to thank that boy's family for
a magnificent contribution to the state.
I have here in my hand a check made out
to the university...
and it is a magnificent endowment
in the name of
Anthony Vito Corleone.
And the check is signed by
that young man's parents
whom I think we should recognize now.
Mike, Pat, Kay, stand up, please.
Let the folks see you!
Folks, I want you to join me
in giving a real Nevada thank you
to Mr and Mrs Michael Corleone!
We also have, as a special added
attraction, the Sierra Boys Choir
who have chosen a certain special song
and a special arrangement
to honour their host,
Mr Michael Corleone.
Boys.
The plaque.
Okay, fellas, I got that one.
Okay, this is yours.
Senator, just you and Mrs Corleone.
- Excuse me.
- This is my lawyer Tom Hagen. Senator Geary.
He's the one who arranged this whole
thing through your man Turnbull.
- Yes, yes.
- Sit down.
I was under the impression
that you and I would talk alone.
I trust these men with my life, Senator. If I were
to ask them to leave, it would be an insult.
It's perfectly all right with me,
but I should tell you I am a blunt man and I
intend to speak very frankly to you.
Maybe more frankly
than anyone in my position's
ever talked to you before.
The Corleone family
has done very well here in Nevada.
You own, or control,
two major hotels in Vegas...
one in Reno.
The licences were grandfathered in
so there was no problem
with the Gaming Commission.
Now my sources tell me
that you plan to make a move
against the Tropigala.
They tell me that within a week,
you're gonna move Klingman out.
That's quite an expansion. However, it will
leave you with one little technical problem.
The licence will still be
in Klingman's name.
- Turnbull is a good man.
- Yeah, well, let's, let's cut out the bullshit.
I don't want to spend
more time here than I have to.
You can have the licence.
The price is 250,000 dollars...
plus a monthly payment of five
percent of the gross...
of all four hotels, Mr.
Corleone.
Now, the price for the license
is less than $20,000. Am I right?
That's right.
- Now, why would I ever consider paying more than that?
- Because I intend to squeeze you.
I don't like your kind of people.
I don't like to see you come out
to this clean country in your oily hair
dressed up in those silk suits
and try to pass yourselves off
as decent Americans.
I'll do business with you, but the fact is
that I despise your masquerade,
the dishonest way you pose yourself. Yourself
and your whole fucking family.
Senator,
we're both part of the same hypocrisy.
But never think it applies to my family.
All right, all right.
Some people have to play little games.
You play yours.
So let's just say that you'll pay me
because it's in your interest to pay me.
But I want your answer and the money
by noon tomorrow. And one more thing.
Don't you contact me again, ever.
From now on you deal with Turnbull.
Open that door, son.
Senator, you can have my answer now
if you like.
My offer is this...
Nothing.
Not even the fee for the gaming licence, which
I would appreciate if you would put up personally.
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
Ladies! I didn't know you were out here.
- We have to go. We're late.
- Really? I'm sorry.
- It's been a delightful party. Thank you for inviting us.
- It's been our pleasure.
It was wonderful talking to you.
Fredo! Fredo, you son of a bitch! You look great!
Frank Pentangeli!
I thought you was never coming
out west, you big bum!
I gotta check on my boys, huh?
- What's with the food around here?
- What's the matter?
Kid comes up to me in a white jacket, gives me a Ritz
cracker and a chopped liver, he says, "canapés".
I said, "Can of peas, my ass. That's
a Ritz cracker and chopped liver!"
Bring out the peppers and sardines!
Seeing you reminds me of New York
in the old days!
You remember Willi Cicci, who was
with old man Clemenza in Brooklyn?
We were all upset about that.
Heart attack, huh?
No, there was no heart attack.
That's what I'm here to see
your brother Mike about.
- But what's with him?
- What do you mean?
I mean, what do I gotta do? Do I have to get
a letter of introduction to get a sit-down?
- You can't get in to see Mike?
- He's got me waiting in a lobby!
- Johnny Ola.
- Al Neri.
- Do you know my lawyer Tom Hagen? Johnny Ola.
- Sure, I remember Tom from the old days.
Rocco.
- What's this?
- It's an orange from Miami.
Why don't you take care of Johnny's men.
They look like they might be hungry.
Johnny.
Tom isn't gonna sit in with us, Johnny. He only handles
specific areas of the family business. Tom?
Sure, Mike.
- What are you drinking, Johnny?
- Anisette.
If you need anything, Mike, I'll be outside, all right?
Just tell Rocco
we're waiting, Tom.
- I just left Mr Roth in Miami.
- How's his health?
It's not good.
Is there anything I can do,
anything I can send?
He appreciates your concern, Michael,
and your respect.
That casino you're interested in,
the registered owners are...
Jacob Lawrence, Allan Barclay, both
Beverly Hills attorneys.
The real owners are
the old Lakeville Road group from Cleveland...
and our friend in Miami.
Meyer Klingman runs the store. He owns a piece of it too,
and he does all right. But I've been instructed to tell you
that if you move Klingman out,
our friend in Miami will go along.
That's very kind of him.
You tell him that's greatly appreciated.
Hyman Roth always makes money
for his partners.
One by one, our old friends are gone.
Death, natural or not,
prison, deported...
Hyman Roth is the only one left because
he always made money for his partners.
I can't believe out of 30 professional musicians
there isn't one Italian in the group here!
Come on, let's have a tarantella!
You, up! Come on! Up, up, up!
Questa mano!
What the hell have we here?
- I'll see my sister alone.
- It concerns me too. Is it okay if I stay?
How are you, honey? You've met
Merle, he was with me in Vegas.
- I saw him with you.
- Could I have a drink or something?
Al, would you please get him a drink?
We're going to Europe next week. I'd like to book
passage on The Queen.
So what do you come to me for?
Why don't you go to a travel agent?
We're getting married first.
The ink on your divorce isn't dry yet,
and you're getting married?
You see your children on weekends.
You know your oldest boy was picked up in Reno for
some petty theft you don't even know about.
You fly around the world with men who don't care for
you, who use you like a whore!
- You're not my father!
- Then what do you come to me for?
'Cause I need money.
Connie, Connie, Connie...
I wanna be reasonable with you.
Now, why don't you stay here
with us, with the family?
You can live on the estate
with your kids.
You won't be deprived of anything.
You can have everything you want.
Now, I don't know this Merle. I don't know
what he does. I don't know what he lives on.
Tell him marriage is out of the question
and you don't want to see him any more.
He'll understand, believe me.
Connie.
If you don't listen to me
and marry this man,
you'll disappoint me.
- Famiglia!
- Cent' anni!
What's "Chen dannay"?
"Cent' anni". It means 100 years.
It means we should all live happily
for 100 years. The family.
- It'd be true if my father were alive.
- Connie.
Hey...
Merle, you've met my sister-in-law,
Deanna.
- Fredo's wife.
- A pleasure, Merle.
With all respect, I didn't
come here to eat dinner!
I know, I know.
- What's the matter? I just want to dance!
- Dancing is one thing. You're falling all over the floor.
I know what's the matter. You're
jealous 'cause he's a real man.
- I swear to God, I'm gonna belt you right in the teeth.
- You couldn't belt your mama!
You know something? These dagos are
crazy when it comes to their wives.
Michael says that if you can't
take care of this, I have to.
- I think you'd better.
- Never marry a Wop!
They treat their wives like shit!
I didn't mean to say Wop.
Stop that!
What are you doing to me,
you big slob? Help!
Fredo!
- I can't control her, Mikey.
- You're my brother, Fredo. You don't have to apologize to me.
Clemenza promised the Rosato brothers
three territories in the Bronx after he died.
You took over, and you didn't give it to them.
- I welched?
- You welched.
Clemenza promised them lu cazzo.
Clemenza promised them nothing.
- He hated those son of a bitches more than I do.
- Frankie, they feel cheated.
Michael, you're sitting high up in the Sierra Mountains
and you're drinking...
- What's he drinking, Cicci?
- Champagne.
Champagne cocktails, and you're passing
judgement on how I run my family.
Your family's still called Corleone.
And you'll run it like a Corleone.
My family doesn't eat here,
doesn't eat in Las Vegas...
...and doesn't eat in Miami...
...with Hyman Roth!
You're a good old man. I like you.
And you were loyal to my father for years.
The Rosato brothers, they're taking hostages.
And Mike, they spit right in my face, all because
they're backed up by that Jew in Miami.
I know. That's why
I don't want them touched.
- You don't want 'em touched.
- No, I want you to be fair with them.
You want me to be fair with them?
How can you be fair to animals?
Tom, for Christ's sakes, listen. They recruit
spics, they recruit niggers.
And they do violence in their grandmothers'
neighbourhoods!
And I tell ya, everything with them is whores!
Whores and junk, dope!
And they leave the gambling to last.
Now, I wanna run my family without you
on my back. I want those Rosatos dead!
- No.
- Morte.
Now, I have business that's important with
Hyman Roth. I don't want it disturbed.
Then you'll give your loyalty to a Jew
before your own blood?
Come on. You know my father did business
with Hyman Roth. He respected him.
Your father did business with
Hyman Roth, your father respected Hyman Roth,
but your father never trusted Hyman Roth
or his Sicilian messenger boy,
Johnny Ola.
You'll have to excuse me.
I'm tired, and I'm a little drunk!
And I want everybody here to know,
there's not gonna be no trouble
from me!
Don Corleone.
Cicci, the door...
You want him to leave now?
Let him go back to New York.
I've already made my plans.
The old man had too much wine.
It's late.
How's the baby?
- Sleeping inside me.
- Does it feel like a boy?
Yes, it does, Michael.
Kay?
I'm sorry about all the people today.
Bad timing.
It couldn't be helped, though.
It made me think
of what you once told me.
"In five years the Corleone family
will be completely legitimate."
That was seven years ago.
I know. I'm trying, darling.
Did you see this?
Mmm-hmm.
Why are the drapes open?
- Kay, you all right?
- Yeah.
- Are you hit?
- No.
It's over. It's over.
Now! Shut it off!
Hold it!
They're still on the property.
Please stay inside.
- Keep them alive.
- We'll try.
Rocco! Alive!
Stay by the door.
Yeah, come in.
- Mike, are you all right?
- Yeah.
There's a lot I can't tell you, Tom.
Now, I know that's upset you in the past.
You felt it was because of
some lack of trust or confidence.
But it's because I admire you
and I love you
that I kept things secret from you.
That's why at this moment you're
the only one I can completely trust.
Fredo?
Well, he's got a good heart.
But he's weak and he's stupid,
and this is life and death.
Tom, you're my brother.
I always wanted to be thought of as
a brother by you, Mikey. A real brother.
I know that.
You're gonna take over.
You're gonna be the Don.
If what I think has happened
has happened, I'm gonna leave here tonight.
I give you complete power over Fredo
and his men. Rocco, Neri, everyone.
I'm trusting you
with the lives of my wife
and my children,
the future of this family.
- When we catch these guys do you think we'll be able to
find out who's back of all this?
- We're not gonna catch 'em.
Unless I'm very wrong,
they're dead already.
They were killed by somebody
close to us.
Inside. Very, very frightened
they botched it.
Yeah, but your people, Rocco and Neri. You don't think that
they had something to do with this?
See, all our people are businessmen.
Their loyalty's based on that.
One thing I learned from Pop
was to try to think
as people around you think.
Now, on that basis, anything's possible.
I seen them!
Right out my window!
- I wanna get out of here! They're lying there dead!
- Get her inside!
Over here! There's two of 'em.
Looks like they were hired
out of New York. I don't recognize 'em.
We won't get anything out of them now.
Fish 'em out.
All right, get rid of the bodies.
- Where's Mike?
- Rocco.
Anthony, everything's gonna be all right.
Try to sleep.
- Did you like your party?
- I got lots of presents.
I know. Did you like 'em?
I didn't know the people
who gave them to me.
Well, they were friends.
- Did you see my present for you?
- It was on my pillow.
Anthony, I'm going to be leaving
very early tomorrow.
- Will you take me?
- No, I can't, Anthony.
- Why do you have to go?
- 'Cause I have to do business.
I could help you.
Someday you will.
Get some sleep.
She's really beautiful.
You've got to see her.
Wait till you see her.
Words can't describe her.
I left Naples. I left Mama.
For a no-good tramp!
Now here I am in America,
in New York.
Alone! Thinking of my mother.
Without news from home.
Finally, a letter from Naples!
Vito, how do you like my little angel?
Isn't she beautiful?
She's very beautiful.
To you, she's beautiful. For me,
there's only my wife and son.
Our dear mother -
...is dead!
We'll go backstage later
and take her to eat.
Sit down, you bum!
Oh, excuse me, Don Fanucci.
We'll go see her backstage.
Who was that?
The Black Hand.
That's Fanucci... the Black Hand.
We'll talk about it tomorrow.
Tomorrow! Always tomorrow!
You'll pay me today!
Let's go.
Not my daughter! Let her go!
Here, take all my money!
Vito, come on.
I know what you're thinking. But
you don't know how things are.
Fanucci's with the Black Hand.
The whole neighbourhood pays him.
Even my father, in the grocery store.
If he's Italian...
...why does he bother other Italians?
He knows they have nobody
to protect them.
Forget that. Did you like my angel?
If you're happy, I'm happy.
Don't you feel well?
Is your boss treating you all right?
Forget it.
Hey, you speak Italian?
Hide this for me!
Next week I'll come and get it!
Abbandando, meet my nephew!
How's business?
It's good, it's good.
Fanucci's mad. Says the
neighbourhood's getting sloppy.
People don't pay on time,
don't pay the full amount.
Says he's been too nice to everyone.
So Fanucci's changing?
Sure. He wants double
from everybody.
Even from my father.
I'm a friend, right? So you'll
let him work here?
I've got some bad news.
I feel rotten about telling you this...
But Fanucci... he's got a nephew...
And you have to give him my job.
You've always been good to me,
ever since I came here.
You looked after me like a father.
I thank you.
And I won't forget it.
Vito!
Oh, no!
Take this to your family.
Thanks anyway. But please,
I can't accept.
What a nice pear!
I'm Clemenza, you still
have my goods?
Did you look inside?
I'm not interested in things
that don't concern me.
A friend of mine has a nice rug.
Maybe your wife would like it.
Sure she would. But who has
money for a rug?
It would be a present.
I know how to return a favour.
Yeah, sure.
My wife would like it.
That son of a bitch! He isn't home!
Damn, he didn't even leave the key.
Well, he won't mind.
Come on in.
Hey, Vito, come on in!
This is your friend's place?
This is a real palace.
One of the best.
Vito, give me a hand, will you?
Look how pretty it is, Santino!
Come on in.
It's all right. Come on. Hyman's in there.
- I was just making some lunch. Would you like a tuna sandwich?
- Uh, no, thank you.
...pick up of two by Holden.
Second and eight for S.C...
- Mr Roth?
- Come in, Michael.
Sit down, make yourself comfortable.
It's almost over.
- You follow the football game?
- Not for a while I haven't.
I enjoy watching football
in the afternoon.
One of the things I love
about this country. Baseball too.
I've loved baseball ever since Arnold Rothstein
fixed the World Series in 1919.
I heard you had some trouble.
Stupid.
People behaving like that with guns.
The important thing is you're all right.
Good health, the most important thing.
More than success, more than money.
More than power.
I came here because there's
gonna be more bloodshed.
I want you to know about it before it happens so
that there's no danger of starting another war.
Nobody wants another war.
Frank Pentangeli came to my home and he asked
my permission to get rid of the Rosato brothers.
When I refused he tried to have me
killed. He was stupid, I was lucky.
I'll visit him soon.
The important thing is that nothing
interfere with our plans for the future.
- Yours and mine.
- Nothing is more important.
- You're a wise and considerate young man.
- And you're a great man, Mr Roth.
- There's much I can learn from you.
- Whatever I can do to help, Michael.
- Excuse me. Lunch.
- Come in.
- Thank you, my dear.
- Hyman, you're gonna break my ear drums.
- Enjoy it.
- Thank you.
You're young, I'm old and sick.
What we'll do in the next few months
will make history, Michael.
History. It's never been done before.
Not even your father would dream
that such a thing could be possible.
And Pentangeli is a dead man.
You don't object?
He's small potatoes.
What's up?
We got company?
What's going on?
Michael Corleone is here.
Where is he?
He's in your den. You better hurry.
He's been waiting a half hour.
Is something wrong?
Don Corleone, I wish you would've
let me know you were comin'.
- I could've prepared something for you.
- I didn't want you to know I was coming.
- You heard what happened in my home?
- Mike, I almost died myself. We were all so relieved...
In my home!
In my bedroom where my wife sleeps!
Where my children come and play with their toys.
In my home.
I want you to help me take my revenge.
Michael, anything. What can I do?
Settle these troubles
with the Rosato brothers.
Mike, I don't understand. I don't...
I don't have your brain for big deals.
But this is a street thing.
That Hyman Roth in Miami. That--
He's backing up those son-of-a-bitches.
- I know he is.
- Then why? Why do you ask me to lay down to him, Mike?
It was Hyman Roth
that tried to have me killed.
I know it was him.
Jesus Christ, Mike.
Jesus Christ, look, let's get 'em all.
Let's hit 'em all now, while we got the muscle.
This used to be my father's old study.
It's changed.
I remember there used to be a...a big desk was here.
I remember when I was a kid, Frankie,
we had to be very quiet when we played near here.
I was very happy that this house
never went to strangers.
First Clemenza took it over. Now you.
My father taught me many things here.
He taught me in this room.
He taught me, "Keep your friends close,
but your enemies closer."
Now, if Hyman Roth sees that I interceded in
this thing in the Rosato brothers' favor...
he's gonna think his relationship
with me is still good.
That's what I want him to think.
I want him completely relaxed and
confident in our friendship.
Then I'll be able to find out
who the traitor in my family was.
- Yeah?
- Fredo, this is Johnny.
- Johnny Ola. We need some more help.
- Johnny?
Jesus Christ, what the hell time is it?
Who is that, honey?
Listen good, Fredo.
What are you callin' me here for?
I don't want to talk to you.
Pentangeli's set up a meeting with the Rosato brothers.
He says he's gonna go for their deal.
- Oh, God.
- Will he come alone?
- I don't know anything. You got me in deep enough already.
- Just go along.
Everything will be all right, Fredo. Pentangeli
says he's willing to make a deal.
All we wanna know is if he's on
the level, or if he's gonna bring his boys.
You guys lied to me. I don't want you
to call me any more.
- Your brother's not gonna find out we talked.
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- Who was that?
- Uh, wrong number.
- Frank, I got nobody here.
- Wait in the car, Cicc'.
- Frankie.
- It's okay, Cicc'.
- What's this, Rosato?
- A lucky C note for our new deal.
Ritchie. Give us a taste, huh?
Yeah, we're all real happy
about your decision, Frankie.
- You're not gonna regret it.
- I don't like this "C" note, Rosato.
I take that as an insult.
Michael Corleone says hello!
Get him in! Close the door!
Your friend the cop.
What the--
Hey, Ritch. It's dark in here.
Are you open or closed?
I just came in to clean up a little,
you know?
What's the matter?
- Is that something on the floor?
- Carmine, not here!
Anthony!
You open your fuckin' mouth,
I'll blow your head off!
Freddie. Good to see ya.
- Where is he?
- He's okay. He's in the back.
Come on, girls.
Take a hike, huh?
In this room here.
- I want to talk to him alone first.
- Come on, huh?
I thought I could help you, Senator.
Hagen?
- Listen, Hagen, I did not...
- No. It's all right.
- I didn't do anything.
- It's okay. You're very lucky.
My brother Fredo operates this place.
He was called before anyone.
Had this happened some place else,
we couldn't have helped you.
When I woke up, I was on the floor.
- And I don't know how it happened.
- You can't remember?
I passed out.
Just a game. Jesus.
Jesus, Jesus!
Jesus God!
Oh God!
I don't know, and I don't understand
why I can't remember.
You don't have to remember.
Just do as I say.
Put in a call to your office.
Explain that you'll be there tomorrow afternoon.
You decided to spend the night at
Michael Corleone's house in Tahoe.
- As his guest.
- I do remember that she was laughing.
We'd done it before, and I know
that I could not have hurt that girl.
This girl has no family.
Nobody knows that she worked here.
It'll be as though she never existed.
All that's left is our friendship.
- Yes?
- I'm sorry, Mrs. Corleone. We're not to let you through.
- I'm just going to the market.
- Well, if you'll just give us a list, we'll pick up anything you want.
- Whose orders are these?
- Mr. Hagen's, ma'am. He's coming over now.
All right, well, I'm just gonna
have to speak to Mr. Hagen.
I wanted to explain this,
but I had business in Carson City.
Now this is Michael's request for your safety.
Now we can send out for anything that you need.
- I see. I'm supposed to stay in my house?
- No, within the compound will be fine.
- Tom, I was going to take the children to New England next week.
- That's off now.
- Am I a prisoner, is that it?
- That's not the way we look at it, Kay.
All right. Come on, kids.
We're going back to the house.
Joe.
Cuba, Cuba!
Most respected gentlemen...
allow me to welcome you to the city of Havana.
I want to thank this distinguished group
of American industrialists
for continuing to work with Cuba
toward the greatest period of prosperity
in her entire history.
Mr William Shaw,
representing
the General Fruit Company.
Messrs. Corngold and Dant,
of United Telephone
and Telegraph Company.
Mr Petty,
Regional Vice President of
the Pan American Mining Corporation.
Mr Robert Allen
of South American Sugar.
Mr Michael Corleone of Nevada,
representing our associates
in tourism and leisure activities.
And my old friend and associate
from Florida,
Mr Hyman Roth.
I would like to take this opportunity to thank United Telephone
and Telegraph for their lovely Christmas gift.
A solid gold telephone.
Perhaps you gentlemen would like to take a look at it.
- Mr President?
- Yes?
Perhaps you would discuss the status of rebel activity
and what this can mean to our businesses?
- Of course.
- Heavy stuff.
I want to assure you that although the rebels have
mounted an impressive campaign in Las Villas...
my staff indicates, with assurance, that we'll
drive them out of the city of Santa Clara
before the New Year.
I want to put you all at ease.
We will tolerate no guerrillas
in the casinos or the swimming pools.
He said that they're making an arrest,
and in a few minutes
he'll let us through.
Johnny...
It's nothing.
Just some lousy bandits.
The police are cleaning them up.
Viva Fidel!
Well, I hope my age is correct.
I'm always accurate about my age.
Make sure that everybody
sees the cake before we cut it.
I'm very pleased
you were all able to come from
such distances to be with me today.
When a man comes
to this point in his life,
he wants to turn over
the things he's been blessed with.
Turn them over to friends,
as a reward for the friends he's had
and to make sure that everything
goes well after he's gone.
- Not for years.
- Hear, hear!
We'll see. The doctors would disagree,
but what do they know?
These are wonderful things
that we've achieved in Havana
and there's no limit
to where we can go from here.
This kind of government knows
how to help business, to encourage it.
The hotels here are bigger
and swankier
than any of the rough joints we put in Vegas.
And we can thank our friends
in the Cuban government
which has put up half the cash with the
Teamsters, on a dollar for dollar basis,
has relaxed restrictions on imports.
What I'm saying is that we have now
what we have always needed...
Real partnership with a government.
Smaller piece.
You all know Michael Corleone
and we all remember his father.
At the time of my retirement, or death,
I turn over all my interests
in the Havana operation to his control.
But, all of you will share.
The Nacionale will go
to the Lakeville Road Boys,
the Capri to the Corleone family,
the Sevilla Biltmore also,
but Eddie Levine of Newport will bring in the
Pennino brothers,
Dino and Eddie, for a piece
and also to handle the actual casino operations.
And we've saved a piece
for some friends in Nevada
to make sure that things go smooth
back home.
I want all of you to enjoy your cake.
So, enjoy!
- Happy birthday!
- L'chaim!
I saw an interesting thing happen today.
A rebel was being arrested
by the military police.
And rather than be taken alive, he exploded
a grenade he had hidden in his jacket.
He killed himself and he took a captain
of the command with him. Right, Johnny?
- Those rebels, you know they're lunatics.
- Maybe so.
But it occurred to me, the soldiers
are paid to fight, the rebels aren't.
- What does that tell you?
- They could win.
This country has had rebels
for the last 50 years. It's in their blood.
Believe me I know, I've been coming here
since the Twenties.
We were running molasses out of
Havana when you were a baby.
The trucks owned by your father.
Michael.
I'd rather we talked about this
when we're alone.
The two million never got to the island.
I wouldn't want it to get around
that you held back the money...
because you had second thoughts
about the rebels.
Ah, sit down, Michael. Sit down.
If I could only live to see it,
to be there with you.
What I wouldn't give for 20 more years.
Here we are, protected. Free to make
our profits without Kefauver,
the goddamn Justice Department
and the FBI.
90 miles away, in partnership
with a friendly government.
90 miles. It's nothing.
Just one small step, looking for a man that wants
to be President of the United States
and having the cash
to make it possible.
Michael,
we're bigger than U.S. Steel.
Mikey, how are you? Okay?
- Hi! Freddy Corleone.
- Mio frati.
Jesus Christ, what a trip!
The whole time I'm thinkin' what if somebody knows
what I've got in here.
Can you imagine that, huh? Two million
dollars in the seat next to me on that plane.
- Excuse me.
- It's okay.
You want to count it?
Mikey, what the hell's goin' on anyway?
I'm totally in the dark.
The family is making an investment in Havana.
This is a little gift for the President.
Well, that's great. Havana's great.
It's my kind of town.
- Anybody I know in Havana?
- Don't know. Hyman Roth, Johnny Ola?
No. I've never met them.
Listen, Mikey, I'm kind of...
Kind of nervous from the trip.
Can I get a drink or something?
I thought maybe we'd go out together.
I know a place where
we can spend some time together.
Sometimes I think I should have
married a woman like you did. Like Kay.
Have kids. Have a family.
For once in my life, be more like
Pop.
It's not easy to be a son, Fredo.
It's not easy.
Mama used to tease me. She'd say,
"You don't belong to me."
"You were left on the doorstep
by gypsies."
Sometimes I think it's true.
You're no gypsy, Fredo.
Mikey, I--I was mad at you.
Why didn't we spend time
like this before?
You want a drink, right? Waiter!
Por favor...
- How do you say Banana Daiquiri?
- Banana Daiquiri.
- That's it?
- That's it.
Uno Banana Daiquiri
and a club soda.
Senator Geary's flying in from
Washington tomorrow night...
with some people, some government people.
I want you to show 'em
a good time in Havana.
- It's my speciality, right?
- Can I trust you with something?
Of course, Mike.
Later on in the evening, we're all invited
to the presidential palace...
a reception to bring in the new year.
After it's over, they're gonna take me home
in a military car, alone...
for my protection.
Before I reach my hotel,
I'll be assassinated.
- Who?
- Roth.
It was Roth who tried to kill me
in my home.
It was Roth all along.
He acts like I'm his son, his successor.
But he thinks he's gonna live forever
and he wants me out.
- How can I help?
- Just go along, as though you know nothing.
- I've already made my move.
- What move?
Hyman Roth will never see the New Year.
He says you have to take it easy and he's gonna
give you a prescription. He'll be back tomorrow.
I want my own doctor.
Fly him in from Miami.
I don't trust a doctor
can't speak English.
- Gracias, señor.
- Buenas noches.
- Honey, go down to the casino.
- If you're sure you're feeling better.
Feel fine.
- Play the bingo game.
- Okay. Nice to see you, Mr Paul.
My sixth sense tells me your brother Fredo brought
a bag full of money. Where is it?
- You're pulling out?
- Just wanna... Just wanna wait.
- How do you feel?
- Terrible.
I'd give four million just to be able to take a piss
without it hurting.
- Who had Frank Pentangeli killed?
- The Rosato brothers.
I know. But who gave the go-ahead?
I know I didn't.
There was this kid I grew up with.
He was younger than me.
Sort of looked up to me, you know.
We did our first work together.
Worked our way out of the street.
Things were good. We made the most of it.
During Prohibition
we ran molasses into Canada.
Made a fortune. Your father, too.
As much as anyone,
I loved him and trusted him.
Later on he had an idea to build a city
out of a desert stop-over
for G.I.s on their way to the West Coast.
That kid's name was Moe Greene
and the city he invented was Las Vegas.
This was a great man.
A man of vision and guts.
And there isn't even a plaque
or a signpost or a statue of him in that town.
Someone put a bullet through his eye.
No one knows who gave the order.
When I heard it, I wasn't angry.
I knew Moe, I knew he was headstrong.
Talking loud, saying stupid things.
So when he turned up dead, I let it go.
And I said to myself,
"This is the business we've chosen."
I didn't ask
who gave the order, because it had
nothing to do with business.
That two million in a bag in your room...
I'm going in to take a nap.
When I wake, if the money's on the table
I'll know I have a partner.
If it isn't, I'll know I don't.
All right, does everybody know everybody here, huh?
This is Senator Geary, you know him.
Good to see you, Mike.
I'm glad we could spend this time together.
- This is Senator Payton from Florida.
- How you doing, Mike?
- And Judge DeMalco from New York.
- How do you do, sir?
- Fine, thank you.
- Senator Ream from Maryland.
- I've been looking forward to this.
- This is Fred Corngold from U.T.T.
- I know Fred. How are you?
- Fred does a mean cha-cha-cha so watch out later on.
- Oh, he does, huh?
- All right gentlemen, it's refill time here.
You might try some of them local drinks, you know--
uh, cuba libre, pina colada.
I think I'll try
one of those redheaded Yolandas.
- That you got! Con gusto...
- Johnny!
You don't know my brother Fredo, do you, Johnny?
Johnny Ola, Fredo.
- We never met. Johnny Ola.
- Pleasure.
Gentlemen, to a night in Havana!
- Happy New Year!
- Feliz Año Nuevo!
- Happy New Year.
Hey, Freddy,
why are we standing?
Everybody stands.
- But it's worth it. You watch. You're not gonna believe this.
- I don't believe it already.
- That's right. Fifty dollars.
- You got a bet, mister.
That's him. That's Superman.
- Jesus Christ!
- Did I tell ya, or did I tell ya?
- I don't believe it.
- That thing's gotta be a fake.
That ain't no fake. That's real.
That's why they call him Superman.
Hey, Freddie. Freddie.
Where did you find this place?
Johnny Ola told me about this place. He brought me here.
I didn't believe it, but seein' is believin', huh?
- I see it, and I still don't believe it!
- 50 bucks, Pat.
Old man Roth'd never come here, but ol' Johnny knows these
places like the back of his hand.
Now watch him. He's gonna break the cracker with it.
I wanna see him break a brick!
Relax, Senor Roth. We're taking you to the hospital.
And in my judgment you'll continue to get those...
because I don't believe that President
Eisenhower will ever pull out of Cuba.
Not as long as we have over one billion
dollars invested in this country.
Now, the American public
believes in nonintervention.
Fredo! Where are you going?
I'm gonna get me a real drink,
'cause I can't--
What kept Mr Roth?
I understood he was coming.
Hey Ream, what's the protocol? How long
should we stay around here?
Oh, I don't know. I think
a half hour oughta do it.
Just long enough
to bring in the New Year.
It's New Year's Eve.
Come on, just for a minute.
There's a plane waiting for us
to take us to Miami in an hour.
Don't make a big thing about it.
I know it was you, Fredo.
You broke my heart.
You broke my heart!
Due to serious setbacks to our
troops in Guantanamo and Santiago...
...my position in Cuba is untenable.
I am resigning from office
to avoid further bloodshed.
And I shall leave the city immediately.
I wish all of you good luck.
Salud!
Viva la revolución! Viva Fidel!
Fredo!
Come on. Come with me.
It's the only way out of here tonight.
Roth is dead. Fredo!
Fredo, come with me!
You're still my brother. Fredo!
Fredo!
I'm Pat Geary, United States Senator.
Fidel! Fidel! Fidel!
Al. Get me a wet towel.
Kay know I'm back?
What about my boy? Did you get
him something for Christmas?
- I took care of it.
- What was it, so I'll know.
It was a little car with an electric
motor that he could ride in. It's nice.
Thank you, Al.
Fellas, could you step outside
for a minute, please?
Where's my brother?
Uh, Roth got out on a private boat.
He's in a hospital in Miami.
He had a stroke, but recovered okay.
Your bodyguard's dead.
I asked about Fredo.
I think he got out.
He must be somewhere in New York.
All right.
I want you to get in touch with him.
I know he's scared.
Tell him everything is all right.
Tell him I know Roth misled him. That
he didn't know they were gonna try to kill me.
- They can come in now.
- There was something else.
What?
What? Come on. What?
Kay had a miscarriage. She lost the baby.
- Was it a boy?
- Mikey, at three and a half months...
Now can't you give me
a straight answer anymore? Was it a boy?
I really don't know.
Poor little Fredo,
he's got pneumonia.
Young man, I hear you and
your friends are stealing goods.
But you don't even send a
dress to my house. No respect!
You know I've got three daughters.
This is my neighbourhood.
You and your friends should
show me some respect.
You should let me wet
my beak a little.
I hear you and your friends
cleared $600 each.
Give me $200 each, for your own
protection. And I'll forget the insult.
You young punks have to learn
to respect a man like me!
Otherwise the cops will
come to your house.
And your family will be ruined.
Of course if I'm wrong about how much
you stole - I'll take a little less.
And by less, I only mean -
a hundred bucks less.
Now don't refuse me.
Understand, paisan?
I understand.
My friends and I share all the money.
So first, I have to talk to them.
Tell your friends I don't want a lot.
Just enough to wet my beak.
Don't be afraid to tell them!
600 bucks...
Suppose we don't pay?
You know his gang, Tessio.
Real animals.
Maranzalla himself let Fanucci
work this neighbourhood.
He's got connections with the cops, too.
We have to pay him.
$200 each... everybody agreed?
Why do we have to pay him?
Vito, leave this to us.
He's one person, we're three.
He's got guns, we've got guns.
Why should we give him the
money we sweated for?
This is his neighbourhood!
I know two bookies who don't give
anything to Fanucci.
Who?
Joe The Greek and Frank Pignattaro.
They don't pay Fanucci.
If they don't pay Fanucci, then
somebody else collects for Maranzalla!
We'll all be better off if we
pay him. Don't worry.
Now what I say stays in this room.
If you both like, why not give me
$50 each to pay Fanucci?
I guarantee he'll accept
what I give him.
If Fanucci says $200...
...he means it, Vito!
I'll reason with him.
Leave everything to me.
I'll take care of everything.
I never lie to my friends.
Tomorrow you both go talk to Fanucci.
He'll ask for the money.
Tell him you'll pay whatever
he wants. Don't argue with him.
Then I'll go and get him to agree.
Don't argue with him, since
he's so tough.
How can you get him to take less?
That's my business.
Just remember that I did you a favour.
Is it a deal?
Yes.
His family's out of the house.
Fanucci's alone in the cafe.
Vito, here's my 50 dollars.
Buona fortuna.
Are you sure he's going to go for it?
I'll make an offer
he don't refuse. Don't worry.
It looks like there's -
$100 under my hat.
I was right.
Only $100...
I'm short of money right now.
I've been out of work... so just
give me a little time.
You understand, don't you?
You've got balls, young man!
How come I never heard
of you before?
You've got a lot of guts.
I'll find you some work
for good money.
No hard feelings, right? If I can
help you, let me know.
You've done well for yourself.
Enjoy the festa!
Oh, this is too violent for me!
What've you got there?
Michael, your father
loves you very much.
Mr Cicci, from the year 1942
to the present time,
you were an employee
of the Genco Olive Oil Company?
That's right.
But in actuality you were a member
of the Corleone crime organization.
No, we called it the Corleone family, Senator. We called
it the family.
What was your position?
At first, like everybody else,
I was a soldier.
- What is that?
- A button, you know, Senator. Come on.
No, I don't know. Tell me.
When the boss says "push a button" on
a guy, I push a button. See, Senator?
Mr Questadt.
- You mean you kill people?
- What?
You kill people at
the behest of your superiors.
Yeah, that's right, counselor.
And the head of your family
is Michael Corleone?
Yeah, counselor. Michael Corleone, right.
Did you ever get such
an order directly from Michael Corleone?
No, I never talked to him.
Mr Cicci, could you amplify
your answer a bit, please?
- Do what?
- Could you expand on your answer?
I'm particularly interested in knowing,
was there always a buffer involved?
Someone in between you
and your possible superiors who gave the actual orders.
Right, a buffer.
The family had a lot of buffers!
Mr. Cicci, you may find this very amusing,
but I promise you the members
of this committee do not.
Tell me something, Ma.
What did Papa think...
deep in his heart?
He was being strong...
Strong for his family.
But by being strong for his family...
...could he...
...lose it?
You're thinking about your wife...
about the baby you lost.
But you and your wife can
always have another baby.
No, I meant... lose his family.
But you can never lose your family.
Times are changing.
It's my pleasure.
I don't want money.
Take it as a gift.
If there's something
I can do for you, you come, we talk.
Signora Colombo,
why did you come to see me?
Your wife told me to ask
if you could help me.
She's in bad trouble.
Her neighbours complained to the
landlord about her dog.
He told her to get rid of the animal.
But her little boy loves that dog.
So she hid it.
When the landlord found out, he
got mad and told her to leave.
Now she can't stay even if she
gets rid of it.
I'm so ashamed!
He said he'd get the police to
throw us out on the street.
I'm sorry, but...
I could give you a couple dollars
to help you move.
I can't move!
I want you to talk to him!
Tell him I want to stay here!
What's your landlord's name?
His name is Signor Roberto.
He lives on Fourth Street, near here.
They break the windows,
they dirty the floors...
A real pig-sty, eh?
My name is Vito Corleone.
Signora Colombo is a friend of my wife.
She says she's been evicted
for no good reason.
She's a poor widow, she has nobody
to take care of her.
She has no relatives, no money.
All she has is this neighbourhood.
I already rented the place
to another family.
I told her that I'd talk to you.
That you're a reasonable man.
She got rid of the animal that
caused all the trouble.
So let her stay.
Impossible.
Are you Sicilian?
No, I'm Calabrese.
We're practically paisan,
do me this favour.
I already rented it!
I'll look like an idiot.
Besides, the new tenants
pay more rent.
How much more a month?
Five bucks.
Here's six months increase in advance.
But don't tell her about it.
She's very proud.
Come see me in another six months.
Of course, the dog stays. Right?
The dog stays.
Who the hell are you
to come give me orders?
Watch out or I'll kick your Sicilian ass
right into the street!
Do me this favour.
I won't forget it.
Ask your friends in the
neighbourhood about me.
They'll tell you I know how
to return a favour.
What a character!
That landlord is here... Roberto,
the one who owns those ratholes.
He's been asking all around
the neighbourhood about you.
I hope I'm not disturbing you, Don Vito.
What can I do for you, Don Roberto?
What a misunderstanding! Holy Mary!
Of course Signora Colombo can stay!
I'm giving back the money you gave me.
Un, due, three, four, five, six, tutt'!
Because after all, Don Vito,
money isn't everything.
Can I sit down?
Your kindness to that widow
made me ashamed of myself.
The rent stays like before!
I'll even lower it.
I'll lower it $5.
I'll lower it $10!
Can I offer you some coffee?
I'm late for an appointment! I can't
this time! Ask me another time!
You'll have to excuse me for now.
I wish I could stay longer!
Just call me and I'll be here!
He won't be back.
He'll hide out in the Bronx!
- Vito, what do you think?
- We'll make a big business!
New York City.
Would you mind speaking up, please?
- Are you the son of Vito Corleone?
- Yes, I am.
- And where was he born?
- Corleone, Sicily.
Did he at times use an alias that was
known in certain circles as Godfather?
Godfather is a term that was used by his friends.
One of affection and one of respect.
Mr Chairman, I would like to verify
the witness's statement.
For years now, a growing number of my constituents
have been of Italian descent.
And I've come to know them well.
They have honored me
with their support and with their friendship.
Indeed, I can proudly say that some of my
very best friends are Italian-Americans.
However, Mr Chairman,at this time and unfortunately
I have to leave these proceedings
in order to preside over a very important
meeting of my own committee.
But before I leave, I do want to say this,
that these hearings on the Mafia
are in no way whatsoever
a slur upon the great Italian people.
Because I can state from my own knowledge
and experience
that Italian-Americans are among
the most loyal, most law-abiding,
patriotic, hard-working
American citizens in this land.
It would be a shame, Mr Chairman,
if we allowed a few rotten apples
to give a bad name to the whole barrel.
Because from the time of the great Christopher
Columbus up through the time of Enrico Fermi
right up until the present day,
Italian-Americans have been pioneers
in building and defending our great nation.
They are the salt of the earth, and they're
one of the backbones of this country.
I'm sure we all agree
with our esteemed colleague.
Mr Corleone, you have been advised
as to your legal rights.
We have testimony from a witness,
a previous witness, one Willi Cicci.
He has stated that you are head of the most
powerful Mafia family in this country.
- Are you?
- No, I'm not.
The witness has testified that you are
personally responsible
for the murder of a New York City
police captain in 1947
and with him a man
named Virgil Sollozzo.
- Do you deny this?
- Yes, I do.
Is it true that in the year 1950
you devised the murder of the heads
of "the Five Families" in New York
to assume and consolidate
your nefarious power?
- It's a complete falsehood.
- Mr Questadt.
Is it true that you have a controlling interest
in three of the major hotels in Las Vegas?
No, it's not true. I own some stock in
some of the hotels there, but very little.
I also have stock in IBM and IT&T.
Do you have any interests or control over gambling
and narcotics in the state of New York?
No, I do not.
Senator, my client would like to read
a statement for this committee.
Mr Chairman. Mr Chairman, I think this statement
is totally out of order at this time.
Sir, my client has answered every question asked by
this committee with the utmost sincerity.
He has not taken the Fifth Amendment, as it was his right to do, so in all fairness I think this statement should be heard!
No, no I'm going to allow Mr Corleone to read
his statement. I'll put it in the record.
In the hopes of clearing
my family name
and the sincere desire to give my children their fair share
of the American way of life
without a blemish on their name
and background,
I have appeared before this committee and
given it all the cooperation in my power.
I consider it a great dishonor to me personally
to have to deny that I am a criminal.
I wish to have the following noted
for the record...
That I served my country faithfully and honorably
in World War Two
and was awarded the Navy Cross
for actions in defense of my country.
That I have never been arrested
or indicted for any crime whatsoever.
That no proof linking me to any
criminal conspiracy
whether it is called Mafia or Cosa Nostra
or whatever other name you wish to give
has ever been made public.
I have not taken refuge
behind the Fifth Amendment,
although it's my right to do so.
I challenge this committee to produce
any witness or evidence against me
and if they do not, I hope they will have
the decency to clear my name
with the same publicity with which
they now have besmirched it.
I'm sure we're all quite impressed, Mr. Corleone.
Particularly with your love for our country.
Committee will stand in recess
until 10:00 a.m. Monday morning
at which time the committee will produce a witness who'll
corroborate the charges which were made against you today.
And at which time, Mr Corleone, you may very well
be subject to indictment for perjury.
I remind you that you're still
under subpoena. Mr. Corleone. Adjourned!
Ten-to-one shot, you said.
A ten-to-one shot
he would take the Fifth, and I lose!
You sound like my bookie.
I owe that monkey my life.
- Well, just get a good night's sleep.
- Yeah, a good night's sleep.
You got a big day tomorrow.
I got you a new suit,
a new shirt, new tie.
I'm gonna shave you myself in the morning.
You're gonna look respectable for 50 million
of your fellow Americans.
Tomorrow...my life, my life won't be worth
a nickel after tomorrow.
Come on! I saw this, I saw this 19 times.
You got a great home here, Frankie.
For the rest of your life.
Nobody gets near you,
you're not going anywhere.
Well that's great. Beautiful.
Some deal I made.
You'll live like a king. You'll be a hero.
You'll live better in here than
most people on the outside.
Some deal!
Alive. Pentangeli is alive.
- How did they get their hands on him?
- Roth. He engineered it, Michael.
Frankie went to make a deal with
the Rosato brothers
and they tried to kill him.
He thought you double-crossed him.
Our people with the New York detectives
said he was half dead, scared stiff
and calling out loud that you'd turned on him.
They already had him on possession,
bookmaking, murder one and a lot more.
The FBI has him airtight.
He's on an army base, 24 hour guards.
No way we can get to him. You've opened
yourself to five counts of perjury.
What about Fredo?
What does he know?
He says he doesn't know anything,
and I believe him.
Roth, he played this one beautifully.
I'm going to talk to Fredo.
I haven't got a lot to say, Mike.
We have time.
I was kept pretty much in the dark.
I didn't know all that much.
What about now? Is there anything
you can help me out with?
Anything you can tell me now?
They got Pentangeli, that's all I can tell you.
I didn't know it was
gonna be a hit, Mike.
I swear to God I didn't know it was gonna be a hit.
Johnny Ola bumped into me
in Beverly Hills.
He said that he wanted to talk.
He said that you and Roth
were in on a big deal together.
And that there was something in it
for me if I could help him out.
He said that you were being tough
on the negotiations
but if they could get a little help
and close the deal fast,
it would be good for the family.
And you believed that story?
You believed that?
He said there was something in it
for me, on my own!
- I've always taken care of you, Fredo.
- Taken care of me?
You're my kid brother!
You take care of me?
Did you ever think about that?
Did you ever once think about that?
"Send Fredo off to do this,
send Fredo off to do that!"
"Let Fredo take care of some
Mickey Mouse nightclub somewhere."
"Send Fredo to pick somebody up
at the airport!"
I'm your older brother, Mike, and
I was stepped over!
- That's the way Pop wanted it.
- It ain't the way I wanted it!
I can handle things, I'm smart!
Not like everybody says.
Like dumb. I'm smart
and I want respect!
Is there anything you can tell me about
this investigation? Anything more?
The Senate lawyer, Questadt.
He belongs to Roth.
Fredo,
you're nothing to me now.
You're not a brother,
you're not a friend.
I don't want to know you,
or what you do.
I don't want to see you at the hotels.
I don't want you near my house.
When you see our mother, I wanna know
a day in advance, so I won't be there.
You understand?
Mikey.
I don't want anything to happen to him
while my mother's alive.
There's more people
than at a ballgame in here.
- Hey, there's Willi Cicci!
- Frankie Five-Angels...
This committee will come to order!
- State your name, please.
- Frank Pentangeli.
- And where were you born?
- Partinico, it's outside of Palermo.
And where do you live now?
I live in an army barracks
with the FBI guys.
We have here finally a witness
that will further testify
to Michael Corleone's rule over a criminal empire that controls all of the gambling in this country. And perhaps in other countries.
This witness has had no buffer
between himself and Michael Corleone.
He can corroborate our charges on enough counts
for this committee to recommend a charge
of perjury against Michael Corleone.
- Senator.
- Thank you, Chairman.
Mr Pentangeli.
Mr Pentangeli. Were you a member
of the Corleone family?
Did you serve under Caporegime,
Peter Clemenza,
under Vito Corleone,
also known as the Godfather?
I never knew no Godfather.
I have my own family, Senator.
Mr Pentangeli, you...
you are contradicting a sworn statement you've
previously made to me and signed.
I ask you again, sir,
here and now under oath...
were you at any time a member of
a crime organization
headed by Michael Corleone?
I don't know nothing about that!
I was in the olive oil business
with his father
but that was a long time ago, that's all.
We have a sworn affidavit. We have it.
Your sworn affidavit, that you murdered
on the orders of Michael Corleone.
Do you deny this confession? And do you realize what
will happen as a result of your denial?
Look, the FBI guys, they promised me a deal.
So I made up a lot of stuff about Michael Corleone,
'cause that's what they wanted.
But it was all lies. Everything!
They kept saying,
"Michael Corleone did this"
and "Michael Corleone did that ".
So I said, "Yeah, sure. Why not?"
Mr Corleone, would you kindly identify for the committee
the gentleman sitting to your left?
I can answer that.
His name is Vincenzo Pentangeli.
- Is he related to the witness?
- He is, I believe, his brother.
- Will he come forward and be sworn, sir?
- Sir, this man does not understand English.
He came at his own expense to aid his brother
in this time of trouble.
He's not under subpoena and his reputation in
his own country is impeccable.
Are you saying he knows nothing
about these matters?
To my knowledge, nothing.
I'm going to find out what the hell happened here!
All right, this committee is now adjourned.
- The witness is excused.
- Senator!
Senator! This committee
owes an apology!
This committee owes an apology.
Apology, Senator!
- Michael, excuse me.
- Hello, darling.
The children are outside. We're going.
What do you mean you're going?
We're all gonna leave tomorrow.
Rocco?
I'll be in my room, Mike.
Michael, I'm not going back to Nevada.
I brought the children
to say goodbye to you.
I want you to know I'm very happy for you.
I suppose I always knew you were too smart
to let any of them ever beat you.
- Why don't you sit down?
- No, no I'm not going to stay long. I can't.
There are some things
I'd like to talk to you about.
Things that have been on my mind,
changes I want to make.
I think it's too late for changes, Michael.
- I promised myself l wasn't going to say anything--
- What do you mean, "too late"?
What really happened with Pentangeli, Michael?
- His brother came and helped him.
- I didn't even know he had a brother.
Where is he now?
He's on a plane, back to Sicily.
All he had to do was show his face.
It was between the brothers, Kay.
I had nothing to do with it.
Nobody is going!
Not you, not the kids. No.
You're my wife, they're my children.
I love you and I won't allow it.
Michael, you say you love me, and then
you talk about allowing me to leave!
There are things that have been going on for years between
men and women that will not change, and that's it.
You've become blind, Michael!
Look, look what's happened to us.
My god, look what's happened to our son, Michael!
- Don't tell me nothing's happened to him!
- Anthony's fine!
- Anthony is not fine!
- I don't want to hear about it.
- Anthony's friends are--
- I don't want to hear about it!
Over!
At this moment
I feel no love for you at all.
I never thought that would ever happen,
but it has.
Kay...
We're leaving tomorrow.
Kay, why don't you take the kids
back to their room?
- Michael, you haven't heard me.
- Kay, what do you want from me?
Do you expect me to let you go? Do you expect me
to let you take my children from me?
Don't you know me? Don't you know that that's an impossibility?
That that could never happen?
That I'd use all my power to keep something like
that from happening?
Don't you know that?
Kay...
Now in time, you'll feel differently.
You'll be glad I stopped you now.
I know that.
I know you blame me
for losing the baby.
Yes.
I know what that meant to you.
I'll make it up to you, Kay.
I swear I'll make it up to you. I'll...
I'm gonna change.
I'll change. I've learnt that I have
the strength to change.
Then you'll forget about
this miscarriage
and we'll have another child.
And we'll go on, you and I.
We'll go on.
Oh, Michael!
Michael, you are blind.
It wasn't a miscarriage.
It was an abortion.
An abortion, Michael.
Just like our marriage is an abortion.
Something that's unholy and evil!
I didn't want your son, Michael!
I wouldn't bring another one
of your sons into this world!
It was an abortion, Michael.
It was a son, a son and I had it killed
because this must all end!
I know now that it's over. I knew it then.
There would be no way, Michael,
no way you could ever forgive me.
Not with this Sicilian thing
that's been going on for 2,000...
- You won't take my children.
- I will.
You won't
take my children!
They're my children too.
Fredo, give this to Grandmother.
Don Ciccio, it's Tommasino.
Allow me the honour of
introducing someone.
My partner in America, in New York.
His name is Vito Corleone.
We'll send him olive oil from here.
To his company in America.
They're olive oil importers, Don Ciccio.
We'd like your blessing, and your
permission to start work.
Where is this young man
from New York?
Have him come closer.
I can't see him so good.
My respects, Don Ciccio.
Give me your blessing.
Bless you!
What's your name?
You took the name of this town!
And what's your father's name?
His name was... Antonio Andolini.
Louder, I don't hear so good.
My father's name was
Antonio Andolini...
...and this is for you!
Michael, say goodbye.
Hi, Al.
Tom. Can I speak with you
for a second, Tom?
Tom, where's Mike?
Waiting for you to leave.
- Can I talk with him?
- Sorry, Fredo. No chance.
- Can I see him?
- He's in the boathouse.
Michael, it's Connie.
Michael...
I'd like to stay close to home now,
if it's all right.
Is Kay coming?
No.
Michael, Fredo's in the house with Mama.
He asked for you
and Tom said you wouldn't see him.
That's right.
Kids, why don't you go outside
for a while?
Michael, please, I want to talk to you.
Michael, I hated you for so many years.
I think that I did things to myself,
to hurt myself, so that you'd know
that I could hurt you.
You were just being strong for all of us,
the way Papa was.
And I forgive you.
Can't you forgive Fredo?
He's so sweet,
and helpless without you.
You need me, Michael.
I want to take care of you now.
Connie.
Tom, sit down.
Our friend and business partner,
Hyman Roth, is in the news.
- Did you hear about it?
- I hear that he's in Israel.
Mmm-hmm.
The High Court in Israel turned down his request
to live there as a returned Jew.
His passport's been invalidated, except for
return to the United States.
He landed in Buenos Aires yesterday.
He offered the gift of a million dollars
if they'd let him live there.
- They turned him down.
- He's going to try Panama.
Panama won't take him.
Not for a million, not for ten million.
His medical condition is reported as terminal.
He's only gonna live another six months anyway.
He's been dying of the same heart attack
for 20 years.
That plane goes to Miami.
All right.
That's where I want it met.
Mike, that's impossible. They'll turn him over directly to the
Internal Revenue, Customs and half the FBI.
It's not impossible.
Nothing is impossible.
It would be like trying to kill the President.
- There's no way we can get to him!
- Tom, you know, you surprise me.
If anything in this life is certain,
if history has taught us anything,
it's that you can kill anyone.
- Rocco?
- Difficult. Not impossible.
Good.
Why did you ask me if something
was wrong when I came in?
I thought you were
going to tell me that
you were moving your family to Vegas
and that you'd been offered the Vice
Presidency of the Houstan hotels there.
- I thought you'd tell me that.
- I turned them down. I mean, do I have to tell you about every offer that I turn down?
- Let's do business.
- All right.
Just consider this, Michael.
Just consider it.
Now Roth and the Rosatos are on the run.
Are they worth it,
are they strong enough?
Is it worth it? You've won.
Do you wanna wipe everybody out?
I don't feel I have to wipe everybody
out, Tom. Just my enemies, that's all.
You gonna come along with me in these things
I have to do, or what?
Because if not, you can take your wife,
your family and your mistress
and move them all to Las Vegas.
Why do you hurt me, Michael? I've always
been loyal to you. I mean, what is this?
So... you're staying?
Yes, I'm staying.
What is it that you want me to do?
Hey, Anthony.
Anthony, how would you like it if I taught you
how to catch the really big fish?
- Would you like that?
- Okay.
You know, when I was your age,
I went out to fishing with all my brothers
and my father. Everybody.
I was the only one that caught a fish.
Nobody else could catch one except me.
Do you know how I did it?
Every time I put the line in the water
I said a Hail Mary
and every time I said a Hail Mary,
I caught a fish.
Do you believe that? It's true.
That's the secret.
- Do you want to try it when we go out on the lake?
- Okay.
What else you got?
Everything will be okay, Frankie, don't worry.
- Did my brother go back?
- Yeah, don't worry.
He's ten times tougher than me,
my brother. He's old-fashioned.
He didn't want to go out to dinner,
he just wanted to go straight home.
That's my brother! Hey listen, nothing could get
him away from that two-mule town.
He could have been big here.
He could have had his own family.
Tom,
what do I do now?
Frankie.
You were always interested
in politics and history.
I remember you talking about Hitler
back in '33.
Yeah, I still read a lot.
I get good stuff in there.
You were around the old-timers, who dreamed of how the
family's should be organized,
based on the old Roman legions
and called them regimes--the Capos and the soldiers.
- And it worked.
- Yeah, it worked.
Those were the great old days,
you know.
We was like the Roman Empire.
The Corleone family
was like the Roman Empire.
Yeah,
it was once.
Frankie.
When a plot
against the Emperor failed
the plotters were always
given a chance
to let their families keep their fortunes.
Right?
Yeah, but only the rich guys, Tom
The little guys got knocked off and all
their estates went to the Emperors.
Unless they went home and killed
themselves, then nothing happened.
And their families, their families were taken care of, Tom.
That was a good break, a nice deal.
Yeah.
They went home
and sat in a hot bath
opened up their veins
and bled to death.
And sometimes they had a little party
before they did it.
Don't worry about anything,
Frankie Five-Angels.
Thanks, Tom. Thanks.
- See you, Tom.
- Addio, Frankie.
Kay. You have to go.
- So pretty...
- Kay, please hurry. He's coming.
Anthony. Kiss Mama goodbye.
Anthony, will you kiss your mother goodbye!
Anthony, say goodbye to Mama.
Anthony. I love you, Anthony.
Kay, please.
All right.
Mary, come here.
Anthony.
Anthony, please. Kiss me once.
Easy.
Anthony! Anthony!
- He's here, we're going fishing.
- No!
Michael wants to take him to Reno now.
Shit!
Okay, kid, you have to go to Reno
with your pop.
- I'll take you fishing tomorrow, okay?
- Okay.
Hey, Anthony.
Listen, I'll catch one for you in secret.
Okay, Al, let's go.
- Mr Roth, you understand I have to take you into custody.
- Yes, I understand.
What's your reaction
to the Israeli High Court ruling?
I'm a retired investor on a pension.
I went to Israel because I wished to live there as a Jew,
in the twilight of my life.
Hey, Frankie! Come on out,
let's play some Hearts.
Frankie!
Is it true you're worth
over 300 million dollars?
I'm a retired investor,
living on a pension.
I came home to vote
in the presidential election
because they wouldn't give me
an absentee ballot.
Jesus Christ.
Hail Mary, full of grace.
The Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women.
Blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners.
Hey! Everybody, pay attention.
This is my friend Carlo Rizzi.
- You know my brother Fredo.
- Sure.
This is my stepbrother Tom,
and that's his girl Theresa.
This cute little thing over here, this is my sister Connie. I was telling you about her.
Come on, say hello to Carlo.
He's good-looking, isn't he?
Yes.
Oh, that droopy thing over there, that's my brother, Mike.
We call him Joe College, you know what I mean?
Go on, sit down. Talk to each other.
Hey, Mr Einstein...
- Here's the cake.
- Hey, Sally, get in here!
- I was scared.
- Come on.
- Where's your father?
- Took him on a wild goose chase. Christmas shopping.
Let's see that thing.
- Oh, honey, that's nice.
- That's beautiful.
- Should I put the candles on now?
- Go on. You help her, Carlo, all right?
- What is that? Rum?
- Yeah.
Sonny, come on, don't touch
the antipasto till Pop sees it.
He's not ugly...
What do you think, the nerve of them Japs, them slanty-eyed bastards? Dropping bombs on our own backyard. On Pop's birthday, you know?
They didn't know it was Pop's birthday.
Well, we should've expected it
after the oil embargo.
What do you mean, expected it? Expected or not, they got no right dropping bombs.
What are you a Jap-lover or something? You on their side?
- I understand 30,000 men enlisted this morning.
- Bunch of saps...
- Why are they saps?
- Sonny, come on, do we even have to talk about the war?
You talk to Carlo, all right?
They're saps because they risk their lives for strangers.
- That's Pop talking.
- You're goddamn right that's Pop talking.
- They risk their lives for their country.
- Your country ain't your blood. You remember that.
- I don't feel that way.
- "I don't feel that way." Well, if you don't feel like that, then why don't you just quit college and go to join the army!
I did.
I enlisted in the Marines.
- Mike, why didn't you come to us?
- What do you mean?
- Pop had to pull a lot of strings to get you a deferment.
- I didn't ask for it.
I didn't ask for a deferment. I didn't want it.
Come on! Come on, knock it off, come on!
- Punk!
- Sonny, Sonny, sit down.
Mommy, Daddy's fighting again!
Go show Carlo the tree.
Nice.
Break your father's heart
on his birthday.
That's swell, Mike. Congratulations.
That's right, encourage him.
Go on, get me a drink. Go on!
You gotta understand.
Your father has plans for you.
Many times he and I have talked
about your future.
You talked to my father about my future?
- My future.
- Mikey, he has high hopes for you.
- Well, I have my own plans for my future.
- Did you go to college to get stupid? You're really stupid.
He's here! Come on!
Come on.
Stupid!
Surprise!
For he's a jolly good fellow
That nobody can deny
Nobody can deny...