How you doin', Keaton?
I can't feel my legs,
Keyser.
Ready?
What time is it?
12.30.
[two gunshots]...
...[sirens]
It all started back
in New York six weeks ago.
A truck loaded with stripped gun parts
got jacked outside of Queens.
The driver saw nobody, but
somebody fucked up. He heard a voice.
Sometimes that's all you need.
NEW YORK CITY
Mr. McManus?
Christ, don't you fuckin' guys ever sleep?
We have a warrant for your arrest.
- Fuck you, pig.
Todd Hockney?
Who wants to know?
- New York Police Department.
Shit. Freeze.
Hold it.
Sure you brought enough guys?
It's quite simple.
A restaurant that changes with the taste...
...without losing the overall aesthetic.
In other words, the atmosphere
will not be painted on the walls.
Where will it be?
- Let me give you an example.
This I had to see for myself.
David.
I'm in a meeting.
- Time for another one.
Everyone, this is David Kujan.
Special Agent Kujan, US Customs.
These gentlemen are from
the New York Police Department.
You look good, Keaton.
Better than I would have thought.
Il y a un problème?
A small matter of a stolen truck
loaded with guns.
Mr. Keaton?
- Will you excuse us for a moment?
We have some questions
to ask you downtown.
Peut-être nous vous laisserions...
- No, no, no, please. Please sit down.
This is... This is a small problem.
Enjoy the meal. I'll talk to you later.
- OK.
Qu'est-ce qui s'est passé là?
- Non, c'est pas du tout un problème.
C'est la police, n'est-ce pas?
- Ça a l'air.
Ça va.
Unique.
Oui.
It didn't make sense that I'd be there.
I mean, these guys
were hard-core hijackers.
But there I was.
At that point I wasn't scared.
I knew I hadn't done anything
they could do me for.
Besides, it was fun.
I got to make like I was notorious.
[man over PA] You know the drill.
When your number is called, step forward
and repeat the phrase you've been given.
Number one, step forward.
Hand me the keys,
you fucking cocksucker.
Number two, step forward.
Give me the fucking keys,
you fucking cocksucker, motherfucker...
Knock it off. Get back.
Number three, step forward.
[thick accent] Hand me the keys.
- In English, please.
Excuse me?
- In English.
Hand me the fucking keys,
you cocksucker. What the fuck?
Number four, step forward.
[number five] It was bullshit.
The whole rap was a setup.
Hand me the keys,
you fucking cocksucker.
It was all the cops' fault. You don't
put guys like that into a room together.
Who knows what can happen?
Hand me the keys,
you fucking cocksucker.
This has really gotta be
embarrassing for you guys, huh?
They drilled us all night. Somebody was
pissed about that truck getting hijacked.
They were hoping somebody
would give them something to go on.
They knew we wouldn't fight it
because they knew how to lean on us.
Our rights went out the window.
It was a violation. Disgraceful.
They went after McManus first -
a top-notch entry man.
What truck?
- The truck with the guns, fucko.
Fucko?
He was a good guy. Crazy though.
Wanna know what Fenster told us?
Say who?
- McManus. He told us another story.
Oh, is that the one about
the hooker with dysentery?
Fenster always worked with McManus.
He was a tight-ass,
but when it came to the job
he was right-on a smart man.
What are you saying?
- I said he'll flip you.
He'll what?
- Flip you. Flip you for real.
Yeah, I'm shakin'[. ] Come on.
- OK.
Answer my question.
- Can you hear me in the back?
Hello?
I want my lawyer. I'm gonna have
your fuckin' badge, cocksucker.
Todd Hockney. Good with explosives.
Without a doubt, the one guy
who didn't give a fuck about anybody.
You don't have a fucking leg to stand on.
You think so? I could put you in Queens
on the night of the hijacking.
Really?
I live in Queens. Did you put
that together yourself, Einstein?
Got a team of monkeys workin' on this?
You know what happens
if you do another turn in the joint?
Fuck your father in the shower, then
have a snack. You gonna charge me?
When I'm ready.
With what?
- You know damn well, dead man.
But Keaton was the real prize for them,
for obvious reasons.
It was your mistake, not mine.
Did you ever stop to ask me? Hm?
I mean, I've been walking around
with the same face, the same name.
I'm a business man.
- What's that, the restaurant business?
From now on you're in
the getting-fucked-by-us business.
I'm gonna make you famous, cocksucker.
Like I said, it was your mistake. Not mine.
Now, you charge me
with this shit and I'll beat it.
OK?
Let's get back to the truck, asshole.
Argh.
[Fenster] I really, really think somebody
should do something about this shit.
So I did a little time. Does that mean I get
railed every time a truck finds its way...
Fuck 'em.
Fenster, will you relax? These guys
don't have any probable cause.
You're fucking-A right.
No PC. No goddamn right.
You do some time, never let you go.
They treat me like a criminal.
I'll end up a criminal.
- You are a criminal.
Now, what you gotta go and do that?
I'm tryin' to make a point.
- Why don't you make your point?
You're makin' me tired all over.
Well, fuck it then.
I heard you were dead.
- Oh, yeah? Well, you heard right.
Word I got is you hung up your
spurs, man. What's that all about?
[McManus] What's this?
Rumour has it Keaton's gone straight.
I hear he's tapping Edie Finneran.
- Who's that?
A heavyweight criminal lawyer from
uptown. I hear she's Keaton's meal ticket.
How about it, Keaton?
You a lawyer's wife?
What kind of retainer are you givin' her?
- Whoops.
Hey, Fenster, do your friend a favour.
Tell him to keep quiet.
Dean Keaton.
Gone clean, huh?
Say it ain't so.
Or was it you that hit that truck?
Mac, Mac, forget him.
Did you get to talk to your lawyer?
[chuckles]...
This whole thing was a shakedown.
- What makes you say that?
How many times you been in a line-up?
It's always you and four dummies. PD pay
homeless guys $10 a head half the time.
And there's no way
they'd line five felons in the same row.
And a voice line-up? A public
defender can get you outta that one.
So why the hell was I strip-searched?
- That was the feds.
Truckload of guns get snagged. Customs
comes down on NYPD wanting answers.
They come up with us.
They're clutching at straws.
I had a guy's finger up my asshole.
- Is it Friday already?
Yeah, lover boy. You want a piece?
So who in the goddamn piss hell
stole our fucking truck?
[Hockney] What did you say?
- Who stole the fucking truck?
I don't want to know.
- Who asked you, working man?
Fuck who did it.
I wanna know who's the gimp.
[Keaton] He's OK.
- How do I know that?
What about it? What's your story?
- His name is Verbal.
Verbal Kint.
- Verbal?
Yeah.
- Roger really. People say I talk too much.
I was just gonna tell you to shut up.
- We met before once or twice.
In county. I was in for fraud.
- A line-up then, too. What happened?
I walked. 90 days, suspended.
So you did it.
- All right, now, look.
We've all been put out
by this whole thing, right?
So I figure we owe it to ourselves
to salvage a little dignity, hm?
Now, me and Fenster
heard about a little job.
Why don't you just calm down?
- What do you care what he has to say?
I'm just talkin' here.
It seems like Mr. Hockney wants to hear
what I got to say. I know Fenster's down.
What about you, guy?
I'm interested. Sure.
There, see? So now I'd like
to exercise my right to free assembly.
Why don't you just shut up?
You're missing the point.
No.
I don't wanna hear anything from you.
I don't care about your job.
And, um,
I want nothing to do with any of you.
I beg your pardon,
but you can all go to hell.
Dean Keaton, gone the high road.
What is the world coming to?
Fuck him.
That was how it started. Five men
brought in on a trumped-up charge...
...to be leaned on by halfwits.
OK. Now I really can't
talk about it much here...
What the cops never figured out,
and what I know now,
was that these men would
never break, never lie down,
never bend over for anybody.
Anybody.
[bell ringing, waves lapping]...
...[horn blows]
SAN PEDRO...
Who are you?
- Agent Jack Baer, FBI. How many dead?
15 so far. They're still pulling
bodies out of the water though.
Any survivors?
- Yeah, two.
One guy's in county hospital,
but he's in a coma.
The DA has a second guy,
a cripple from New York, I think.
The chief wants this place sealed off.
If you have any questions, give him a call.
[ringing tone]
This is Dave Kujan.
I'll be in Los Angeles until Tuesday.
If you need to reach me, call Jeff Rabin
of the San Pedro PD on extension 112.
Have a nice day.
- [answering machine beeps]...
Why can't I see him?
- Dave, I told you.
The DA came last night ready to arraign
even before they moved him to county.
Kint's lawyer shows up five minutes later,
DA comes out the office looking like
he'd been smacked around.
They take his statement
and they cut him a deal.
Did they charge him with anything?
- Yeah, weapons. Misdemeanour two.
What is that?
Listen, I give the DA credit
for getting that much. Understand?
Excuse me, sir.
This whole thing has turned political.
The mayor was here last night. The chief.
This morning the governor called, OK?
I'm telling you this guy is protected from
up on high by the Prince of Darkness.
Take my word for it.
- When does he post bail?
Two hours, tops.
- I wanna see him.
No, Dave.
- I gotta see him.
Dave, no. I cannot do this for you.
- You gotta. I came a long way for this.
Dave, please.
Even if I let you talk to him,
he won't talk to you.
He's paranoid. He knows the
interrogation rooms are all wired.
I quit. This won't be an interrogation.
Just a friendly chat.
He will not go in the interrogation room.
- Someplace else.
Where?
No, no, no, no, no...
If it was a dope deal, where's the dope?
If it was a hit, who called it in?
I'm sure you have a host of wild theories.
- They know damn well what I think.
That's crazy. Besides, the guy's got
total immunity. His story checks out.
He doesn't know what you wanna know.
- I don't think he does. Not exactly.
But there's more to his story.
Jeffrey, look, I wanna know why
27 men died on that pier...
...for what looks to be $91 million
worth of dope that wasn't there.
And, above all, I wanna
be sure Dean Keaton's dead.
He's dead.
- Come on. Two hours.
Just till he makes bail.
They're all dead. I don't care how
tough a guy you say Keaton was,
nobody on that boat
could have come out alive.
Is he talking?
- He just regained consciousness.
He spoke... not English, then he lapsed.
- Hungarian.
Might have been.
- Most were Hungarians.
You gotta put on one of these.
- Burn victims are susceptible to infection.
And, of course, there's no smoking.
Keep your mask up.
Please don't touch him.
Is he gonna die?
- He has burns over 60% of his body.
A number of ribs are broken.
- Call Security. Put a man on the door.
Is he dangerous?
- Yes.
Do it.
Do it now.
- [muttering in Hungarian]
Joel? Yeah, Baer down at LA County.
Look, the guy they pulled out
of the harbour is Arkosh Kovash.
Yes. Yes. I'm sure.
No, he's all fucked up.
[shouts in Hungarian]
- What? What? I can't hear you.
Will you shut up? I'm on the phone.
Yes?
Well, not until I put a man on him. Send
me someone who can speak Hungarian.
Yeah, he's talking like a Thai hooker.
- Keyser Söze.
What?
- Keyser Söze. Keyser Söze.
[coughs and splutters] Keyser Söze.
- No shit.
Joel. Yeah, call Dan Metzheiser at Justice
and find Dave Kujan from Customs.
Mm-hm.
Verbal, this is Agent Kujan from Customs.
Nice to meet you.
He wants to ask you a few questions.
What about?
- About a Dean Keaton mostly.
But I'd like to start at
the line-up in New York.
Can I get coffee?
- In a while. Let's talk about the line-up.
I'm really thirsty.
I used to dehydrate as a kid.
One time I got so bad, my piss
come out like snot. It was thick...
I'll get your fucking coffee.
- Get me one too while you're at it.
[opens door]
That guy is tense. Tension is a killer.
I was in a barbershop quartet
in Skokie, Illinois.
The baritone was a guy named Kip Diskin.
Big, fat guy. I mean, like, orca fat.
He was so stressed in the morning...
- Verbal, we're trying to help you.
Sure. And I appreciate that.
And I wanna help you, Agent Kujan.
I like cops. I would have liked
to have been a fed myself, but...
Verbal, you're not telling us everything.
I know you know something.
[Verbal] I told the DA everything I know.
Verbal, I know you like Keaton.
I know you think he's a good man.
[Verbal] I know he was good.
- He was a corrupt cop.
Sure, 15 years ago,
but he was a good thief.
Anyway, cops wouldn't let him go legit.
- Dean Keaton was a piece of shit.
Are you trying to get
a rise out of me, Agent Kujan?
I just wanna hear your story.
- It's all there.
May I have a cigarette?
According to your statement...
- I need a light.
According to your statement, you're
a short-con operator. Run-of-the-mill...
According to your statement,
you're a short-con operator.
Run-of-the-mill scams.
- It's been suppressed. It's inadmissible.
Oh, I know. Sweet deal you have here.
Total immunity.
Well, I do have the weapons charge. I'm
looking at six whole months' hard time.
You know a dealer
named Ruby Deemer, Verbal?
Know a religious guy named John Paul?
You know Ruby's in Attica?
- He didn't have my lawyer.
I know Ruby. He's big on respect. He's a
good friend of mine, likes me very much.
I know your testimony is sealed. Ruby has
a lot of friends inside do favours for him.
What do you think he'd say if he found out
you dropped his name to the DA?
There's nothing in there about Ruby.
- I'll mention that to him.
First thing on the job
I learnt how to spot a murderer.
Say you arrest three guys
for the same killing and put 'em in jail.
Next day whoever's sleeping is your man.
If you're guilty, you know you're caught,
you get some rest. You follow me?
No.
- Let me get right to the point.
I'm smarter than you and
I'm gonna find out what I wanna know.
And I'm gonna get it from you
whether you like it or not.
I'm not a rat.
[door opens]
Thanks.
When I was picking beans in Guatemala,
we'd make fresh coffee right off the trees.
That was good. This is shit,
but, hey, I'm in a police station...
Can we get started again?
- Now, what happened after the line-up?
The desk sergeant told me he couldn't
release you. Can you believe that?
You weren't even charged.
New York police.
I want pictures taken of your face.
I'll take 'em to the DA first thing.
Forget about it.
- No. I'll have this in front of a grand jury.
Look, I don't wanna talk about it, Edie. OK?
So what did Fortier and Renault say?
They need more time to think about it.
- Dammit. More time for what, Edie?
No matter how you cover my tracks,
they'll still find out about me.
Give me some credit. I got you this far.
Let's go to the grand jury. It won't stop.
- Look, it's never gonna stop, period.
By next week every investor in the city's
gonna be walkin' away from us.
It's finished.
I'm finished.
- [footsteps]
Don't give up on me now, Dean.
It's never gonna stop.
I love you.
They ruined me in there tonight.
Do you hear me?
What?
All right.
Let's just go to my place.
[Edie] We'll worry about this tomorrow.
Let's go.
Fenster and McManus
had a cagey proposition.
A fast jump, high risk, long money.
We all knew it could be done.
The way I figured,
to do it wrong meant killing.
To do it right took five men.
Five men meant Keaton.
Keaton took convincing.
New York's Finest Taxi Service.
Bullshit.
They don't operate any more.
McManus has a friend in the 14th
Precinct. They're coming out for one job.
They're picking up a guy smuggling
emeralds. McManus already has a fence.
A fence? Who?
- Some guy in California named Redfoot.
I never heard of him.
- You have to come.
What's it to you whether I do it or not?
- They don't know me. You do.
They won't take me unless you go.
Look at me. I need this.
Oh, you're telling me you don't
need this? Is this your place?
I'm not knocking you. You got a good
scam going with this lawyer... Oh.
Sorry.
It's OK. It's OK.
You say it's the real thing, that's cool.
You OK?
- I was outta line.
But they're never gonna
stop with us. You know that.
As clean as you could get,
they'll never let you go.
This way we hit the cops where it hurts
and we get well in the meantime.
You sure you're OK?
- I'll be all right.
Look, I, uh...
I sometimes get...
- Forget it.
I'll probably shit blood tonight.
[Keaton snorts]
So, uh...
...how do they wanna do it?
McManus wants to go in shooting.
I say no.
Fenster? Hockney?
They're pretty pissed off.
They'll do anything.
I got a way to do it without killing anyone,
but they won't let me in without you.
Three million?
Maybe more.
No killing?
Not if we do it my way.
New York's Finest Taxi Service
was not your normal service.
It was a ring of corrupt cops in the NYPD
that ran a high-profit racket...
...driving smugglers and
drug dealers round the city.
For a few hundred dollars a mile
you got your own police escort.
They even had business cards.
After a while somebody started asking
questions and the service shut down.
Since then Internal Affairs have
been waiting to catch them in the act.
That's where we came in.
So, how was the flight?
- Fucking great.
Will this get me to Staten Island?
You kidding me?
This'll get you to Cape Cod.
McManus brought us the job. Fenster got
the vans, Hockney supplied the hardware.
I came up with how to do it
so no one got killed.
But Keaton? Keaton
put on the finishing touch.
A little 'fuck you'
from the five of us to the NYPD.
All right, watch this, watch this.
Whoa, whoa. Careful, careful.
Come on, asshole. Fuck.
Holy shit.
Don't move, you fuckers.
- Drop it now, motherfucker.
Hurry up.
- Drop it. Don't fuckin' move.
What do you want?
- [Fenster] Put the fuckin' thing away.
[McManus] Stupid asshole.
- [Fenster] Don't fuckin' move, mama.
[Hockney] You want
a buckshot shampoo, chubby?
[McManus] Aw, fuck.
Afternoon, pork chops. Give me the shit.
- Give him the fuckin' shit.
Give him the fuckin' thing.
Give him the fuckin' shit, man.
Hurry up.
Come on.
- Now the money.
There's no money.
- Give me the money.
There's no fuckin' money.
- Give me it.
Give me the fuckin' money.
- Give him the money.
Give me the money.
[McManus] Hurry up.
Motherfucker. You know who the fuck I
am? You people know who the fuck I am?
Fuck.
- [Hockney] We do now, jerk-off.
[stamping]
Wait a minute. What's that?
What the fuck...? Holy shit.
[McManus] Go. Go. Go.
[sirens]
Keaton made an anonymous phone call.
The press arrived before the police did.
Strausz and Rizzi
were indicted three days later.
Within a few weeks
50 more cops went down with them.
Everybody got it right in the ass
from the chief on down.
It was beautiful.
I owe you $2.50.
Dr. Keaton.
There's more here than I thought.
- When's the fence coming?
Redfoot never comes to see me.
I always go to see him.
In California?
Yes, Verbal. In California.
Fenster and I...
- Wait. Hold the fuckin' phone.
You and Fenster? No, no, no, no, no.
You fuckin' kiddin' me?
OK, so everyone's gonna go.
We all go.
What's your fuckin' problem, man?
My fuckin' problem is that
you and Fenster are off in California...
...while we're sittin' here holdin' our dicks.
- Hey. The job's over.
Cool it.
LA's a good place to lie low for a while.
You wanna dance?
Ladies...
I would like to propose a toast.
There you go.
To Mr. Verbal.
The man with the plan.
[Verbal] We're gonna miss the flight.
Don't do this. Send her a note, something.
I said we'll make it.
We're gonna miss the plane.
She'll understand.
That's heart-warming. Really.
I'm weepy.
Jeff, you wanna wait outside?
You guys wanted to know
what happened after the line-up.
Come on, Verbal.
Who do you think you're talkin' to?
You expect me to believe that he retired?
For a woman?
Bullshit. Keaton was using her.
He loved her.
- Sure.
I'm supposed to believe
hitting the taxi service wasn't his idea?
That was all Fenster and McManus.
- Keaton was a cop for four years.
[Kujan] Who'd know the service better?
- But Edie had him turned around.
Let me tell you something.
I know Dean Keaton.
I've been investigating him
for the past three years.
The guy I know was
a cold-blooded bastard.
IAD indicted him on three murder counts
before he was kicked off the force.
So don't sell me the hooker with a heart.
- You got him all wrong.
Do I? Keaton was under indictment a total
of seven times while he was on the force.
In every case the witnesses
either reversed their testimony,
or died before they could testify.
When they finally did nail him for fraud,
he spent five years in Sing Sing.
He killed three prisoners inside.
Of course, I can't prove this.
But I can't prove the best part either.
Dean Keaton was dead.
Did you know that? He died in a fire
two years ago during an investigation...
...into the murder of a witness
who was going to testify against him.
Two people saw Dean Keaton walk into
a warehouse he owned before it blew up.
They said he went in
to check a leaking gas main.
It blew up and took
all of Dean Keaton with it.
Within three months of the explosion,
the two witnesses, they were dead.
One killed himself in his car,
the other fell down an open elevator shaft.
[beeping]
- Agent Baer...
Get this show on the road.
- There are too many people here.
Doctor, we'll be out of here
before he blows his porch light.
I have a noon meeting.
- Five minutes.
Everyone, calm down, all right?
I want you to ask this man
about the shoot-out in the harbour.
[speaks Hungarian]...
He says they were buying...
- Dope. We know.
He doesn't know what they were buying,
but not dope. Uh, people.
What?
- [Kovash continues speaking]...
He needs guarantees.
- What is he talking about?
He says his life's in danger.
He saw the devil, looked him in the eye.
I'm on my way.
- No, no, no. Wait a minute.
Ask him to tell him what he told me...
...about the devil.
Who's the devil?
Keyser Söze.
Keyser Söze?
- He was in the harbour killing many men.
He saw Keyser Söze?
- [Kovash carries on speaking]...
He saw his face.
- Tell him to tell her what he looks like.
Describe him.
- OK.
[Kujan] Six weeks ago
an anonymous call tells me
I can find Keaton at Mondino's
with his attorney. And there he is.
Because he never profited
from his alleged death...
...and we convicted someone else
of the murder we tried to pin on him,
we had to let him go.
He was dead just long enough
for the murder rap to blow over,
and then he had lunch.
I don't know about that.
- Oh, I don't think you do.
But you say you saw Keaton die. You're
covering his ass and he's still out there.
I think he's behind that whole circus at the
harbour. He's using you cos you're stupid.
You tell me he's dead, so be it. I wanna be
sure he is before I go back to New York.
He wasn't behind anything.
It was the lawyer.
What lawyer?
What lawyer, Verbal?
- When I was in that barbershop quartet...
I know you held out on the DA.
What did you leave out of that testimony?
I can call up Ruby in ten minutes.
- The DA gave me immunity.
Not from me. You get no immunity
from me, you piece of shit.
Every criminal I've put in prison,
every cop that owes me a favour,
every creep that walks the street for
a living will know the name of Verbal Kint.
Now you talk to me, or that immunity
they seem so fit to grant you...
...won't be worth the paper the contract
put out on your life is printed on.
There was a lawyer.
Kobayashi.
Is he the one that killed Keaton?
- No. But I'm sure Keaton is dead.
Convince me.
And tell me every last detail.
We arrived in Los Angeles
and met McManus's fence, Redfoot.
He had a good reputation.
Seemed like a good guy.
Still, we should've known better.
How you doin'?
- Good. You?
Not bad. Can't complain.
How's it goin', Fenster?
Don't need to open it, right?
You must be Keaton.
Redfoot, Dean Keaton,
Todd Hockney and Verbal Kint.
Verbal. The man with the plan, huh?
Interested in any more work?
- We're always lookin' for extra work.
We're on vacation.
- Well, that's too bad.
I got a ton of work and I don't have
any good people like you guys.
What's the job?
- A jeweller out of Texas named Saul.
He rents a suite in some downtown hotel.
He does free appraisals for people.
Anyway, the word is
he carries around a lot of cash.
So I figure I keep the merchandise,
you keep the green. Simple.
What about security?
- Bodyguards. Nothing you can't handle.
Give me time to check it out?
- I'd expect nothing less from you, man.
Good to see you. We'll call you.
Enjoy LA, huh? Get yourself laid.
Hey, uh...
A friend of mine in New York tells me that
you know, that you knew Spook Hollis.
The way I hear it,
you did time with old Spook.
Good man, wasn't he?
I used to run dope for him.
Too bad he got shieved.
- Yeah.
I shieved him.
Better you hear it from me now
than from somebody else later.
I appreciate that.
Just out of curiosity,
was it business or personal?
A bit of both.
Well, like I said, you give me a call
if you're interested, all right?
Is there a problem?
One job. That was the deal.
One job? [McManus laughs]
One job.
That's a good one, Keaton.
Keaton fought it as best he could,
but a man can't change what he is.
He can convince anyone
he's someone else, but never himself.
It took one day with McManus
nagging him, and we went back to work.
So, I get out of my car.
I think it's wrecked.
In the back seat of the other car,
this woman's totally naked.
I'm laughin' so hard, I can't breathe.
- Get in the car, Saul.
Freeze. Freeze.
There's a second one here somewhere.
Give me the case.
Give me the fuckin' case.
I'm telling you for the last time,
give me the fuckin' case.
[Hockney] Come on.
- [Fenster] Hey. Don't move.
[car alarm]
Look, just hand over the case.
Hand over the fuckin' case.
[Hockney] Come on. Let's go.
Come on.
- Bad day. Fuck it.
Let's go. Let's go. Let's go.
[hammering]
Fuck.
[Fenster] Looks like
a lot of china to me. Shit.
Guys, come on.
- [vehicle approaches]...
What're you doin'?
- I'm gonna kill him.
We did it your way, now my way.
- You gonna kill him?
I'm gonna deal with it.
- You better.
I'm gonna deal with it. Shut up.
What am I supposed to do with that?
Feed it to the gimp, ease his pain.
I don't know what it is.
What do you mean? Sh.
- I don't know. I got this job from a lawyer.
Yeah, who?
- I don't know. Some limey.
He's a middle man for somebody, OK?
He doesn't say, I don't ask.
You're fuckin' full of shit.
- Fuck you.
Fuck you.
- Listen to me. We wanna meet him, OK?
That's funny.
He called me last night.
He says he wants to meet you guys.
OK. We'll meet him.
- I'll call you.
Good. Do that. No problem.
- I don't like it, Dean. Wait.
One more thing, tough guy. Any more
surprises and I'm gonna kill you.
Such a tough guy, McManus.
Do me a favour, get the fuck off my dick.
Fuck.
- No. No.
Better put a leash on that puppy.
You know, it's an awful shame
about Saul gettin' whacked.
The cops are gonna be
lookin' for the guys who did it.
Sooner or later they're gonna
come around askin' me.
You have a sweet night, ladies.
Fuck you.
So this lawyer...
- Kobayashi.
Came from Redfoot.
- Right.
Why leave this out
when you talked to the DA?
Dave, someone to see you.
Jack.
Been lookin' for you. Still after that coke
from the harbour blood bath yesterday?
Yeah.
- Stop lookin'. There was no coke.
I been in LA County talkin' to a guy they
pulled out of a drainpipe in San Pedro.
He came to this morning.
He's in a Hungarian mob doing a deal with
Argentinians. Says it was no dope deal.
But the $91 million...
- We know. He says no way on the dope.
He tells me they were pulling
stumps for Turkey the next day.
They had no time to negotiate that kind
of product and no means to move it.
What's the money for?
- He didn't know. No one knew.
Except for a few key people.
They were all very hush about it, he says.
Whatever it was, it was very sensitive.
- I don' t get it.
They tell me you got the cripple from
New York. Did he mention Keyser Söze?
Who?
Just bear with me here.
Who's Keyser Söze?
- Aw, fuck.
We've been going over this
for an hour and a half.
What we need to do is find Redfoot,
Keaton, and get the hell outta here.
What we need to do is think. Think back.
Somebody with power.
Somebody capable of
trackin' us from New York to LA.
Dean, what the hell are we doin' here?
- We're waitin'.
I'm out.
- Sit down.
No. It's hot and I'm fuckin' bored.
[man] Mr. Hockney, do stay.
Mr. Keaton.
Mr. Fenster I recognise from
his mug shots, as well as Mr. McManus.
I can only assume that you are Mr. Kint,
the gentleman who disposed of Saul Berg.
My employer sends his gratitude.
A most unexpected benefit.
I am Mr. Kobayashi.
I have been asked by my employer
to bring a proposal to you gentlemen.
What do you want?
- My employer requires your services.
One job. One day's work. Very dangerous.
He does not expect all of you to live,
but those of you who do...
...will have $91 million to divide
between you in any way you see fit.
Who's your boss?
I work for Keyser Söze.
Who's Keyser Söze?
- Judging by the change in mood, Mr. Kint,
I feel sure the rest of
your associates can tell you.
I come with an offer directly from Mr. Söze.
An order, actually.
- What do you mean 'an order'?
In 1981, Mr. Keaton, you participated in a
hijacking of a truck in Buffalo, New York.
The cargo was raw steel.
Steel which belonged to Mr. Söze...
...and which was destined for Pakistan
to be used in a nuclear reactor.
A most profitable violation
of UN regulations.
You had no way of knowing this
because the fellow shipping the steel...
...was working for Mr. Söze
without his knowledge.
Earlier this year Mr. Fenster and Mr.
McManus hijacked a flight out of Newark.
The plane was carrying gold and
platinum wiring, also set for Pakistan.
Two months ago Mr. Hockney stole a
truck carrying gun parts through Queens.
Gun parts which were set to be
destroyed by the State of New York.
They were to be lost in a way station
and rerouted to Belfast.
Again Mr. Söze,
using pawns who had no knowledge.
Which brings us to Mr. Kint.
Nine months ago one of
Mr. Söze's less than intelligent couriers...
...was taken in a complicated
confidence scam by a cripple.
He was relieved of $62,000.
Now, it has taken us some time to find you.
Our intention was to approach you
after your apprehension in New York.
You set up the line-up?
- Yes.
You were not to be released until I arrived.
It seems Ms. Finneran was a little
too effective in expediting his release.
Holding the rest of you was a moot point.
What about Redfoot?
- Mr. Redfoot knew nothing.
Mr. Söze rarely works
with the same people for long,
and they never know
who they're working for.
One cannot be betrayed,
if one has no people.
So, why are you telling us?
Because you have stolen from
Mr. Söze, Mr. Fenster. All of you.
That you did not know you stole from him
is the only reason you are still alive.
He feels you owe him.
You will repay your debt.
All right, fuck the debt and fuck you.
How do we know you work for Söze?
I don't think that is relevant, Mr. Hockney.
All five of you are responsible for the
murder of Saul Berg and his bodyguards.
Mr. Redfoot can testify to your
involvement and we can see to it he will.
What's your point?
- The offer is this, gentlemen.
Mr. Söze's primary interest is narcotics.
He's been competing, shall we say, with
a group of Argentinians for years now.
Competing with Mr. Söze has taken its toll.
The Argentinians are negotiating the sale
of $91m in cocaine in three days' time.
This purchase will revitalise the
diminishing strength of their organisation.
Mr. Söze would like you to stop the deal.
If you choose,
you may wait until after the buy.
Whatever money changes hands is yours.
Mr. Söze would like you to get to the boat
and destroy the cocaine on board.
And then you will be free
of your obligations to Mr. Söze.
You give me one good reason
why I shouldn't kill you right now.
A gift from Mr. Söze.
Good day, gentlemen.
My whole life's in here -
everything I've done since I was 18.
They fuckin' know everything.
Everybody I've ever worked with
or did time with.
No.
This isn't right.
- I don't know.
Who was that guy who used
to talk about Söze in New York?
Bricks Marlin.
- Yeah, I did jobs for him. Indirect stuff.
He said he always made five times
more money than the job was worth.
This guy's a pipe dream. Kobayashi's
usin' him for window-dressing.
I don't know. This is bad.
- No, it's bullshit.
This guy could be LAPD.
It's a fuckin' set-up.
The way I hear it,
Söze is some kind of butcher.
A peerless, psycho, fucked-up butcher.
- There is no Keyser Söze.
Who is Keyser Söze?
He's supposed to be Turkish.
Some say his father was German.
Nobody ever believed he was real.
Nobody ever knew him or saw anybody
that worked directly for him,
but to hear Kobayashi tell it, anybody
could've worked for him. You never knew.
That was his power.
The greatest trick the devil ever pulled...
...was convincing the world he didn't exist.
One story the guys told me - the story
I believe - was from his days in Turkey.
A gang of Hungarians
wanted their own mob.
They realised that to be in power you
didn't need guns or money or numbers.
You just needed the will
to do what the other guy wouldn't.
After a while they come into power,
and they come after Söze.
He was small-time then,
just running dope, they say.
They come to his home in the afternoon
looking for his business.
They find his wife and kids in the house
and decide to wait for Söze.
He comes home to find his wife raped
and children screaming.
The Hungarians knew Söze was tough, so
they let him know they meant business.
They tell him they want
his territory, all his business.
Söze looks over the faces of his family,
then he showed these men of will
what will really was.
He tells him he would
rather see his family dead...
...than live another day after this.
He lets the last Hungarian go,
waits until his family are buried,
then goes after the rest of the mob.
He kills their kids, their wives,
their parents and their parents' friends.
He burns down the houses they live in
and the stores they work in.
He kills people that owe them money.
And like that... he's gone.
Underground.
Nobody's ever seen him since.
He becomes a myth, a spook story
that criminals tell their kids at night.
'Rat on your pop,
and Keyser Söze will get you.'
But no one ever really believes.
Do you believe in him, Verbal?
Keaton always said...
'I don't believe in God,
but I'm afraid of him.'
Well, I believe in God.
And the only thing that scares me
is Keyser Söze.
Do you give any weight to this?
I can introduce you to Dan Metzheiser
from Justice. He has a file on Söze in DC.
Been a hobby of his. Guys equate him
to that reporter on The Incredible Hulk.
[knock at door]...
You've heard of him?
- On the street?
Yeah.
- A few times.
Outside stuff.
Somebody working for a guy...
...who worked for a guy who got some
money from Keyser Söze, shit like that.
It could be an old badge, a hex sign,
to keep people from fucking with you.
But you're here.
- Shit, yeah.
I got a guy trying to leave hospital on
a fried drumstick cos he's afraid of Söze.
Yeah, I'll run it up the flagpole.
I told it like it happened on the boat.
So what if I left out how I got there?
It's so full of holes, the DA would've
told me to blow amnesty out my ass.
That's why you never told the DA?
- You tell me, Agent Kujan.
If I said the Loch Ness Monster
hired me, what would you say?
Turn state's evidence, we'll hear it out.
- I got immunity. What can you offer me?
If there really is a Keyser Söze,
he's gonna come looking for you.
Where's your head? Where do you
think the pressure's coming from?
Keyser Söze, or whatever you
wanna call him, knows where I am.
He's got the front burner under your ass
to let me go, so he can scoop me up later.
Immunity was to deal with you.
I got a new problem when I post bail.
So why play into his hands?
We can protect you.
Oh, gee, thanks, Dave.
Bang-up job so far - extortion, coercion.
Kiss my pucker.
The fuckers that rounded us up and sank
us are now bailing me out? Fuck you.
You think you can catch Keyser Söze?
You think a guy like that comes this close
to getting caught and sticks his head out?
If he comes up for anything,
it'll be to get rid of me.
After that, my guess is
you'll never hear from him again.
[beeping]
What happened next?
The next morning Fenster was gone.
He couldn't handle slumming for Söze.
He left us a note wishing us good luck
and took a chunk of the money.
Then what?
- McManus was furious.
He was talking about tracking him down
and ripping his heart out, all sorts of shit.
That night we got the call.
- What call?
Kobayashi told us
where we could find Fenster.
[Hockney] Let's get the fuck outta here.
We gotta bury him.
- With what?
With our hands.
Oh, this is nuts.
It's dry fucking sand, McManus.
When he rots, the surfers
are gonna smell him a mile away.
Dig, you fuck.
- What we gonna do? He's gonna kill us.
I don't know about you, peg leg,
but I can run. I got no problem with that.
Kobayashi doesn't seem
to have a problem with it either.
If you run, we're gonna be
diggin' a hole for you. You got that?
This ain't my boy we're buryin'.
I don't owe anybody.
So fuck you.
- He was my partner for five years.
We did more jobs and I saw more money
than you can ever count, so fuck you.
Cos now it's payback.
- It's not payback.
It's precaution. You want payback,
you wanna run, I don't care.
I'm not doin' this for Fenster.
I'm not doin' it for you.
I'm doin' this for me.
I'm gonna finish this thing.
This Kobayashi bastard
is not gonna stand on me.
After they killed Fenster nobody'd run?
- I wanted to. I thought we could make it.
Why didn't you say anything?
- I tried, but Keaton wouldn't have it.
It was too far-fetched for him.
Keaton was a grounded guy, an ex-cop.
To a cop, the explanation is never
that complicated. It's always simple.
There's no mystery,
no arch criminal behind it all.
If you got a dead body and
think his brother did it, you're right.
Nobody argued with Keaton. They just
set their minds to whacking Kobayashi.
They're coming up.
Did you hear me? He's coming up.
He's on his way down.
[two gunshots]
Don't move.
Press 20. Do it now.
Move.
The answer is no.
- Mr. Söze will be most upset...
Listen, cocksucker, there is no Keyser
Söze. You mention him again, I'll kill you.
A strange threat. I can only assume
you've come here to kill me anyway.
We know that you can get to us.
But now you know that we can get to you.
I'm giving you one
last chance to call this off.
Mr. Sö... My employer has made up
his mind. He does not change it.
Neither do we.
You got Fenster, but you won't get all of
us before one of us gets through to you.
I believe you, Mr. McManus.
I most sincerely do.
You would not have been chosen were
you not suitable, but it's not my decision.
Whatever you threaten
me with is ludicrous...
...in comparison to what will be done to me
if I do not carry out my orders in full.
I'm the guy that's gonna get you.
I just wanted you to know that.
I'm so sorry, Mr. McManus.
I implore you, Mr. Keaton, believe me,
Mr. Söze is very real and very determined.
We'll see.
Before you do me in, Mr. McManus,
you will let me finish my business
with Ms. Finneran first, won't you?
What did you say?
Edie Finneran.
She's upstairs in my office
for an extradition deposition.
I requested she be put on the case
personally. She flew in yesterday.
No matter.
Kill away, Mr. McManus.
You're lyin'.
- Am I?
Ms. Finneran's escort while she's here in
LA. Never leaves her side for a moment.
I thought you'd be glad
to know she's in good hands.
Now rest. The boat will
be ready for you on Friday.
If I see you or any of
your friends before then,
Ms. Finneran will find herself the victim
of a gruesome violation before she dies.
As, indeed, will your father, Mr. Hockney,
and your Uncle Randall in Arizona, Mr. Kint.
I might only castrate
Mr. McManus's nephew David.
Do I make myself clear?
We'll take care of the bodies downstairs.
We'll add them to the cost of Mr. Fenster.
If you'll excuse me, gentlemen.
[sighing]
It's a logistical nightmare.
Close quarters. 10, maybe 20 men.
No tellin' how many more are below.
- Can we stealth these guys?
Nah. With all that coke,
they're gonna be ready.
Which brings me to
sunny point number two.
Even if one of us gets through and
jacks the boat, we still got nothin'.
What if we wait for the money?
- Ten more men at least.
In my opinion it can't be done. Anybody
who goes in there is not comin' out alive.
I'm gonna wait for the money.
- [Hockney] Me, too.
Did you hear what he just said?
- If I'm goin' in, I want a cut.
Me, too.
There's nothing that can't be done.
I just can't believe
we're gonna walk into certain death.
The news said it's raining in New York.
[indistinct voices]...
...[whispers] What language is that?
- I don't know.
Russian, I think.
Hungarian?
Sh.
[chatter continues]
Package has arrived.
You kids ready?
I would be, if I didn't have
to stop and answer you.
I'm ready. McManus,
you better be set up in ten seconds.
I'm ready.
I want you to stay here.
I'm supposed to cover the...
- Listen, if we fail, take the money and go.
Keaton, I can't...
- Find Edie, tell her what happened.
She knows people, she knows what to do.
If I don't get Kobayashi my way,
she'll get him her way.
What if I...
- Just do what I say. Please.
Tell her that...
Tell her I tried.
[Verbal] McManus, he's on his way.
I'm there.
[indistinct voices]...
...[addresses men in Spanish]
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven.
[chuckles] Oswald was a fag.
Hi.
How ya doin'?
Is there... Is there a problem?
Fernando...
...¿Qué hace aquí?
- Nada.
Aquí no puede pasar.
- ¿No se puede pasar por aquí?
Mejor que se regrese.
Now.
[McManus] ♪ Old Macdonald had a farm...
...♪ Ee-eye, ee-eye, oh...
...♪ And on that farm he shot some guys...
...♪ Bada-boom, bada-bing, bang, boom...
...[yelling]
Elvis has left the building.
[shouting]...
...[man screams]
No dispare. ¡Vámonos.
Oh, man.
[chuckles]
Hello.
Why didn't you run?
- I froze up.
I thought about Fenster and
how he looked when we buried him.
Then I thought about Keaton.
It looked like he might pull it off.
Dave.
A boy came across a body on the beach
this morning. Shot twice in the head.
Two men from the Bureau identified him.
- What else?
His name was Arturro Marquez,
a smuggler from Argentina.
He was arrested last year
in New York for trafficking.
He escapes to California.
They pick him up in Long Beach.
They're setting up extradition,
he escapes again.
Now, get this. Edie Finneran's brought in
to advise on the proceedings.
Kobayashi.
- New York faxed a copy of his testimony.
He was a rat.
- Yeah, a big fucking rat.
Arturro was very opposed
to returning to prison,
so much so that
he named close to 50 people.
Guess who he named in the finale?
Keyser Söze.
- [Baer] There's more.
I'll tell you what I know.
Stop me when this sounds familiar.
There was no dope on that boat.
Argh.
[footsteps]...
You, stay quiet.
- He's here. I know he's here.
That's him. I'm telling you,
that's him. I know he's here.
You can't understand. That's him.
Shut up.
- That's him. You hear me?
I'm telling you it's Keyser Söze.
[two gunshots]...
...[mechanical whirring]...
Where's Hockney?
- I don't know. There's no coke.
What?
- You heard me, you dumb fuck. No coke.
What the fuck do you mean?
- I've been in every fucking room.
There's gotta be coke.
- There is nothing. Nothing.
Don't fuck with me.
There is no... fucking... coke.
I'm outta here.
I told them nothing.
I swear.
I told them nothing. Please.
[gunshots]
McManus, what the fuck is goin' on?
The strangest thing.
Your statement says you saw a man
in a suit with a slim build.
Wait a minute.
- Are you saying you saw Keyser Söze?
You said you didn't know who it was.
- There was dope on that boat.
Stop stallin'.
- I'm not.
You know what I'm gettin' at.
- Hey. I got immunity. I won't take this.
You know... You know
what I'm gettin' at, Verbal.
I don't know.
- Yes, you do. The truth.
Try to tell me you saw someone kill Keaton.
I did.
- You're lying to me.
I am not.
- You've known this whole fuckin' time.
I don't know what you're saying.
I did see Keaton get shot, I swear.
Then why didn't you help him?
You had a gun. He was your friend.
Because I was afraid. OK?
Afraid.
- Afraid of what?
I knew it was Keyser Söze.
- But Keaton...
It was Keyser Söze, Agent Kujan.
I mean, the devil himself.
How do you shoot the devil in the back?
What if you miss?
All right. Let's get back to the pier.
[sirens]...
Arturro Marquez. Ever hear of him?
- What? No.
He was a stool pigeon
for the Justice Department.
He swore out a statement
saying that he had seen...
...and could positively identify
one Keyser Söze.
It says in the report: 'He had
intimate knowledge of his businesses,
including but not exclusive
to drug-trafficking and murder.'
I never heard of him.
His people were selling him
to a gang of Hungarians.
Most likely the same Hungarians
Söze all but wiped out back in Turkey.
The money wasn't there for dope.
The Hungarians were gonna buy the one
guy that could incriminate Keyser Söze.
I said I never heard of him.
- Keaton did.
Edie Finneran was Marquez's extradition
adviser. She knew what he knew.
I don't under...
- There were no drugs. It was a hit.
A suicide mission to whack out the
one guy that could finger Keyser Söze.
So Söze put some thieves to it, men he
knew he could march into certain death.
You're saying Söze
sent us to kill someone?
Keaton did. Verbal,
he left you behind for a reason.
Just do what I tell you.
If you all knew Söze'd find you anywhere,
why did he give you the money to run?
He could have used you on the boat.
- He wanted me to live.
A one-time dirty cop
without a loyalty in the world...
...finds it in his heart
to save a worthless rat cripple.
No, sir. Why?
Edie.
- I don't buy the reform story for a minute.
Even if I did, I certainly don't believe
he would send you to protect her.
So why?
Because he was my friend.
No, Verbal. He wasn't your friend.
Keaton didn't have friends.
- What are you doin' here?
He saved you because
he wanted it that way. It was his will.
Keaton was Keyser Söze.
- No.
The kind of man who could wrangle
men like Hockney and McManus.
The kind of man who could engineer
a line-up through all his contacts at NYPD.
The kind of man who
could've killed Edie Finneran.
She was found yesterday at a hotel
in Pennsylvania, shot twice in the head.
What do you think
about Keaton now, Verbal?
Edie?
He used all of you to get him on that boat.
He couldn't get on alone.
He had to pull the trigger himself
to make sure he got his man.
The one man that could identify him.
This is all bullshit.
You said you saw him die.
Or did you? You had to hide
when you heard the police cars.
You said you heard the shot before the fire.
But you didn't see him die.
- I knew him. He would never...
He programmed you to tell us
just what he wanted you to.
He knew we were close,
you said it yourself.
Where was the political pressure
coming from? It was Keaton.
Immunity was your reward.
But why me?
Why not Fenster, McManus or Hockney?
I'm stupid. I'm a cripple. Why me?
Because you're a cripple, Verbal.
Because you're stupid.
Because you're weaker than them.
If he's dead, if what you say is true,
then it won't matter.
It was his idea to hit the taxi service
in New York, wasn't it? Tell me the truth.
It was all Keaton.
We followed him from the beginning.
I didn't know. I saw him die.
I believe he's dead. Oh, Christ.
You're not safe on your own.
You think he's...
- Keyser Söze?
I don't know, Verbal.
Keyser Söze's a shield.
Or, like you said, a spook story.
But I know Keaton, and someone
is out there pulling strings for you.
Stay and let us protect you.
- No way. I'm not bait. I post today.
You posted 20 minutes ago.
Captain Leo wants you out of here ASAP,
unless you turn state's.
I'll take my chances.
If someone wants to get you,
they're gonna get you out there.
Turn state's evidence.
You might never see trial.
Maybe so.
But I'm not a rat, Agent Kujan.
Fuckin' cops.
Excuse me. Can I use your fax machine?
You'll have to sign for these, Mr. Kint.
One watch, gold.
One cigarette lighter, gold.
One pack of cigarettes. Thank you.
We've still got nothing, Dave.
I know what I wanted
to know about Keaton.
Which is nothing.
No matter. He'll have
to know how close we came.
[Rabin] Keyser Söze or no Keyser Söze,
if Keaton is alive,
he's not coming up again.
[Kujan] I'll find him.
[Rabin] Waste of time.
[Kujan] A rumour's not
a rumour that doesn't die.
[Rabin] What?
- Nothin'.
Man, you're a slob.
- Yeah, but it all has a system, Dave.
It all makes sense when you look at
it right. You gotta stand back from it.
You wanna see a real horror show,
you should see my garage.
[Kujan] Convince me.
When I was in that barbershop quartet in
Skokie. Where's your head, Agent Kujan?
[Keaton] We need to think back.
- [Kobayashi] You've heard many tales.
[McManus] Bricks Marlin.
- [Kujan] I wanna hear your story.
[Verbal] It's all there. Some guy
in California, his name is Redfoot.
[Kobayashi] A gift from Mr. Söze.
- [Keaton] What about Redfoot?
[Kobayashi] Mr. Redfoot knew nothing.
- [Verbal] Big, fat guy. I mean, orca fat.
There was a lawyer. Kobayashi.
When I was picking beans in Guatemala,
we'd make fresh coffee.
[Kujan] You thought he was a good man.
- [Verbal] I know he was good.
[Kujan] Tell me every last detail.
- [Verbal] How do you shoot the devil?
[Rabin] He's protected by the Prince of...
- [Hockney] What's your story?
There was a lawyer.
- What lawyer, Verbal?
I am Mr. Kobayashi.
- Kobayashi. Kobayashi.
Tell me every last detail.
- I work for Keyser Söze.
Convince me. Convince me.
Every creep that works the street for a
living will know the name of Verbal Kint.
The cripple, did you see him?
The cripple. Which way did he go?
- That way.
[Kujan] I know you know something.
I'm smarter than you and
I'm gonna find out what I wanna know.
To a cop, the explanation's simple.
- You know what I'm gettin' at. The truth.
...no arch criminal behind it all.
- [Keaton] Somebody with power.
[Kovash in Hungarian] Keyser Söze.
- Who's Keyser Söze?
You think a guy like that comes this close
to getting caught and sticks his head out?
Because you're stupid, Verbal.
Because you're a cripple.
Who's the gimp?
- You've known the whole fuckin' time.
Who's Keyser Söze?
- Who's Keyser Söze?
[Verbal] I'm sure Keaton is dead.
- [Keaton] I can't feel my legs, Keyser.
[Kujan] First thing I learnt on the job
was how to spot a murderer.
[Baer] They tell me you got the cripple
from New York. He mention Keyser Söze?
[Kujan] Who?
[Verbal] After that... my guess is
you'll never hear from him again.
The greatest trick the devil ever pulled
was convincing the world he didn't exist.
And like that...
...he's gone.