Let's see what you got.
I need more runners.
I can't write the
business fast enough.
You've got to see Granger.
8720. Yeah.
Yeah. Hold it a minute.
Beat it, Mottola!
Mr. Granger?
Chicago's on the line.
Yeah.
Granger, this is Combs.
Why haven't we heard from you?
Everybody else is in.
We had problems with
the law this morning.
The mayor promised to get tough
on the rackets again,
so he shut everybody down for a
couple of hours to make it look good.
It's nothing serious.
It just put us a little behind.
You been making your payoffs,
haven't you?
Oh, hell, yes!
He does this every year.
There's nothing
to worry about.
Okay, finish your count
and get it up here.
I don't want to
be here all night.
Yeah, well, believe me,
the man's gonna be real happy.
Looks like we cleared over
$10,000 this week.
We cleared $22,000 here.
Oh, what the hell, you got
the whole Chicago South Side.
How do you expect the eight lousy
spots I got to compete with that?
They did $14,000 in Evanston,
$16,500 in Gary and $20,000 in Cicero.
Looks like you're bringing
up the rear, Granger.
Well, I just got the count.
I'll put the take on the 4:15.
We'll be waiting.
Mottola!
Take this up to Chicago
on the 4:15.
They'll be waiting for it
at the clearinghouse.
And don't stop
for any entertainment.
You can get a cab over on 7th.
Ah, cut it out!
8720.
Hey, you there! Stop!
Hey, you!
Stop that man!
Stop him! Stop him!
He's got my wallet!
Stop him! Stop that man!
He's got all of my money!
Stop him!
Goddamn nigger-lover!
I'm gonna get you someday
for this! Sucker egg!
Don't let him get away!
He's got my wallet!
He's got all my money!
My wallet!
He's got my wallet!
We got the wallet.
We got it!
- What happened?
- Give it to me, please.
Did he get you with the knife?
You sit tight, old man.
You need a doctor. I'll call a cop.
No, no! No. No cops!
You wanted by the law
or something?
No, it's okay.
Are you nuts, carrying
a wad around like that
in a neighborhood like this?
No wonder you got hit.
Thanks.
I'm obliged to you.
I've got to get going.
You ain't going nowhere on this leg.
Let me see.
I gotta. Got to run some slots
down in West Bend for a mob here.
I got a little behind
in the payoffs.
So, they think I've been
holding out on 'em.
They gave me until 4:00
to come up with the cash.
If they don't
get it, I'm dead.
It don't look good, Gramps.
It's almost 4:00 now.
I'll give you and your friend
$100 to deliver it for me.
I don't know.
That mug that hit you
is mad enough at me.
What if he's around the corner
waiting with some friends?
He won't know
you're carrying it.
Come on. You've got to
help me out.
Hey, I'm sorry, pal. I'm gonna
maybe help you get fixed up,
get to a doctor,
but I ain't about to walk
into no knife for you.
How about you? All you got to
do is put it in the door slot.
I'll give you the whole $100.
What makes you think you can trust him?
He didn't do shit.
Hey, butt out, chicken liver!
I gave him back the wallet, didn't I?
How far is this place?
- 1811 Mason. Put it in box 3-C.
- 3-C.
You won't have no trouble.
There's $5,000 there
and here's $100 for you.
Okay, old man,
I'll make your drop for you.
And don't worry,
you can trust me.
Hey. Hey! If those goons
decide to search you,
you ain't gonna get far
carrying it there.
What'll we do?
You got a bag or something?
How about a handkerchief?
Here's a handkerchief!
Here. Give it to me.
Give me the money.
Just hurry, will you?
You got any more? Better give it
all to me if you want to keep it.
They think I've been
holding out on them.
My wife got sick and I had to pay the bill.
I wasn't holding out.
Stuff it down your pants here.
Like that. Got it?
Uh-huh. Yeah.
Hurry, will you?
Ain't a tough guy in the world
that's gonna frisk you there.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
Where to?
Which way is Mason?
Twenty blocks south.
Okay, go north,
Joliet Station, fast!
Right.
What's so funny?
I just made
the world's easiest $5,000!
- Come on, Luther!
- Hold on, man, I'm fading.
Come on!
Hustle!
In here!
Man, was that beautiful!
I thought for sure
he was on to us.
No, you had him all the way.
All the way!
All right.
Luther.
Good God!
We're millionaires.
Jesus! Did you know
he was that loaded?
Hell, no! I just cut into him.
I would've settled
for pawning one of them shoes.
Oh, God!
Come on,
let's get out of here.
We'll split it up tonight.
Hiya, Marge!
- Hi, kid.
- Hi, Hooker. She's onstage.
Hi, Hooker.
Getting married or something?
Get used to it, Leonard.
I'm going to look
this good from now on.
What do you say, Ed?
Hi, Hooker.
Hey.
I want to talk...
Hiya, Hooker.
You getting
married or something?
For Christ's sake, Ed,
did you hear that out there?
Harry drops four beats in the
middle of my goddamn routine!
Now, how long do I have
to put up with that?
Leonard, you're on.
Crystal, you want to get
out of here tonight?
I come into some dough.
Oh, I can't. I got a 10:00 show.
I need the $5.
I'll spend $50 on you.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Okay.
...opens up his pants,
the duck sticks his head out.
One lady says to the other,
"Mabel, do you see what I see?"
She says, "So what? You've seen
one, you've seen them all."
She says, "Yes, but this one
is eating my popcorn."
You see that guy Harry, he can't
keep time in a watch factory.
Supposing there's some Hollywood
movie agent out there.
All those years of training
right down the drain.
Hooker! Ain't seen you in months.
Thought you took a fall.
Nah, just a little hard times, is all.
Everything's Jake now.
You gonna have a go here?
How about $10 on the line?
There's a lot of action
there on 28th Street.
Pay you $35.
$3,000 on the red, Jimmy.
$3,000?
Are you nuts?
No, I feel lucky. Come on.
Hooker, I can't accept that.
It's too big a bet.
There's a house limit.
Take it.
But Hooker here's a--
Take it!
Twenty-two, black.
Tough luck, kid.
Lucky for me
it came up black, Hooker.
A fella could get in big trouble
around here, losing a bet like that.
Listen, Jimmy,
can't we do it again, huh?
Don't worry about it, pal.
It was my mistake.
There's always more
where that came from.
"Don't worry about it," he says.
Don't worry about it. $3,000!
Thanks, Hooker.
Comes in here with $50
he's going to spend on me!
$3000.
Thanks for the evening, Hooker.
Come on. It's not over yet.
Next time you want to
spend $50 on me, mail it.
Come on. Would you...
Listen, will you...
They found Mottola.
He was drunk in a dive in Joliet.
He never got on the train.
I don't want to
hear about his day, Greer.
What happened to the money?
He lost it to a couple of con artists
on his way out of the spot.
- How much?
- $11,000.
Okay, I better get on
the phone to New York,
see what the big mick
wants to do about it.
I have a pretty
good idea, though.
No more bets!
Ace. Bet the ace.
Bet the ace.
Ace says two.
Ace bets a deuce.
Two.
Four, five. Two spades.
Ace six. Ace deuce.
Doyle, can I talk to you?
I'm busy, Floyd.
It's important. We had a little
trouble in Chicago today.
One of our runners
got hit for $11,000.
What makes you think
he just didn't pocket it?
We checked his story
with a tipster.
He was cleaned by two grifters.
They workin' for anybody?
I don't know. Could be.
We're running that down now.
Have some local people
take care of them.
Nothing fancy.
We've got to discourage
this kind of thing.
You follow?
Johnny Hooker!
If you ain't a sharper
in them linens!
Evening, Louise.
Hey, Ma!
Child, if I didn't know you better,
I'd swear you had some class.
Luther said you was something
to see today!
I don't know, Alva.
I've got to get faster
tyin' up that bundle.
I'm still given 'em
too much time to think.
Oh! Bushwah!
I used to make that switch
with slower hands
than you got.
Course, the "Up and Down
Broadway" was my best game.
Me and Luther didn't make much
on it, but it wasn't so touchy.
Them marks can
beat you up awful bad
when they catch you
making that switch.
Come on, Leroy.
We'll be late for church.
Oh, Ma, they were closing in
on Machine Gun Kelly!
Who you rooting for anyhow?
Hey, Hooker!
Can't help you, Leroy.
You can't beat the house.
Nuts!
Since when do you go
to church at night?
Since they
started late bingo.
I'm gonna ask the Lord for some of
that cash while He's still paying off.
Luther, look in on the baby
from time to time, will you?
You, too, huh, Louise?
- Child, yeah, got to go pray. See you.
- Yeah.
Hey, Erie.
Give me!
Give me, give me!
There's your cut.
Guy turned out
to be an oil well.
Which way did he go?
Due north. He was
gonna take it all.
Aw, the bastard.
He can blow his
nose all the way.
There you go, Luther.
$6,000.
You're late.
Where have you been?
I had a couple of appointments.
How much did you lose?
All of it.
In one goddamn night?
Why are you spraying money around like that?
You could've been nailed!
I checked the place first.
There were no dicks there.
But you're a con man,
and you blew it like a pimp!
I didn't teach you
to be no pimp.
What the hell's eating you?
I've blown money before.
No class grifter would've
done it, that's all.
You think my play is bad?
I think you're the best.
I wouldn't be
getting out otherwise.
What the hell
are you talking about?
I'm getting too old
for this racket.
You hang on too long and you
start embarrassing yourself.
We just took off today on the
biggest score we've ever had.
It's nothing compared to what you
could be makin' on the big con.
But you played the big con.
You told me yourself
it was some dumb game
for mama's boys and flakes.
Hell, I never played no big con.
I hung around and
picked up a few things.
Ain't no rich boys gonna trust
a hungry nigger
enough to be conned.
But I'll tell you
I've been looking for this
one all my life, Johnny.
Now I have a chance
to step out when I'm ahead.
Come on! What would
you do with yourself?
Oh, I have a brother
down in K.C.,
runs a freight outlet.
I can go halfsies with him.
It ain't too exciting,
but it's mostly legal.
I got an old friend in Chicago
named Henry Gondorff.
I want you to look him up.
There ain't a better
inside man alive.
He'll teach you all
you got to know.
To hell with that.
I want to work
with you, Luther.
I'm out, Johnny.
Yeah, sure. If that's
the way you want it.
That's the way I want it.
How do you like that Coleman?
After five years.
Come on,
it was the only thing to do.
He knew he was
holding you back.
Yeah, but we were partners.
If it weren't for Luther, I'd
still be hustling pinball.
I don't need any more
than what I got.
Well, you won't have anything if you
don't lay off the games of chance.
There's a depression on,
you know.
There's always
a depression on.
If you saved a little bit,
you wouldn't have to grift.
I like grifting.
Maybe you could buy
yourself some things.
- What?
- Clean clothes, a car.
I got clothes, and
I don't know how to drive.
What else do you got to sell?
All right. Forget it.
Hey, Hooker!
Come on, you son of a...
Oh, hi there, Snyder.
What's the matter?
Things a little slow down at the
bunco department tonight, huh?
Somebody lose the dominoes?
You scored blood money today,
Hooker, you need a friend.
Go find yourself
a shoplifter to roll.
You got the wrong guy, pal.
I've been home
with the flu all day.
You can stake out
my toilet if you want.
Keep talking!
I'll tell you what
you did, smart boy.
You tied into a loaded mark
on 47th across from Maxie's.
And you and Coleman
played the switch for him
and blew him off
to a cab on 49th.
If he hadn't been a numbers
runner for Doyle Lonnegan,
it would've been perfect.
You're crazy.
I ain't stupid enough
to play for no rackets money.
Not intentionally, maybe.
That don't cut no ice
with Lonnegan.
He'll swat you like a fly.
Yeah, well,
Well, I'll square it
with the fixer.
Nobody can buy you a prayer
if I put the finger on you.
Now, I figure your end of the
score was at least $3,000.
I want $2,000,
no matter what it was.
My take was only $1,000.
Then you're gonna have to come up
with another $1,000 somewhere.
All right.
You're a smart egg, Hooker.
No sense getting dead
over $2,000.
Relax, Erie.
I'll bill you.
I thought you blew
all your money.
I did.
The stuff I gave him
is counterfeit.
They'll spot it the first
place he tries to spend it.
Are you crazy,
giving him counterfeit money?
Hey, wait up!
Where you going?
I'll tell you!
What the hell
are you gonna do
if Snyder puts
the finger on you, huh?
You're committing
suicide, kid.
Christ, what difference
does it make?
If Snyder knows about us,
so does everybody else.
He never gets anything first.
Hey, listen to me.
Don't go back
to your place tonight.
Don't go anyplace
you usually go.
You hear me?
Damn! There's no answer
at Luther's.
Look, you better get out
of town or somethin', huh?
Hey, lady. Lady, let go!
Ma'am! Ma'am!
I want my nickel
back for that telephone!
No, sir.
Nobody here did.
1521 North Bryant.
Luther!
Is he dead?
I don't know.
There was a big fight.
Somebody must've pushed him.
Oh!
Jesus!
Luther!
Oh! God! No!
Luther! Luther!
What happened?
God, who would do such
a thing to you, Luther?
Luther!
Alva.
Come on!
Let's get out of here.
Luther.
Hooker, come on! If Snyder
catches you here, you're dead!
Get out of here!
Out of the way.
Help me! Help me! Help me!
Ah.
Excuse me.
I'm looking for a guy
named Henry Gondorff.
Know him?
No.
You sure?
Beat it.
Luther Coleman sent me.
Are you Hooker?
Yeah.
Why didn't you say so?
We heard about Luther
last night.
Come on.
I thought maybe you were
a cop or somethin'.
It's the room in the back.
He wasn't expecting
you so soon, though.
Thanks.
The great Henry Gondorff.
Turn it off!
You sober?
Turn it off, will you?
Glad to meet you, kid.
You're a real horse's ass.
Luther said I could learn
somethin' from you.
I already know how to drink.
Sorry about Luther.
He was the best street worker
I ever saw.
He had you down as a big-timer.
What happened?
I conned a senator from
Florida on a stock deal.
A real lop-ear. Thought he was
gonna take over General Electric.
Some chanteuse woke him, though,
and he put the feds on me.
You mean you blew it.
Luther didn't tell me
you had a big mouth.
He didn't tell me
you was a screw-up, either.
You played any
big cons since then?
Oh, I lammed around
a bunch of bohunk towns,
one kick ahead of the G-men.
Would be still, if Billie
hadn't set me up here.
Don't kid yourself, friend.
I still know how.
Are you going to stay
for breakfast,
or do you already
know how to eat?
I picked something up
along the way.
Is Lonnegan after you, too?
I don't know.
I ain't seen anybody.
You never do, kid.
Doyle?
Yeah.
We just talked to Chicago.
They got one of the grifters last night.
A nigger.
How about the other one?
They're still
looking for him.
Who did Combs put on it?
He gave it to Riley and Cole.
They staked out the other
guy's place last night,
but he never showed.
They figure maybe
he skipped town.
Do you want to
keep after him?
You see that fella in the
red sweater over there?
His name's Danny McCoy.
Works a few of the protection
rackets for Carnello
when he's waiting for
something better to happen.
Danny and I have known each
other since we were six.
Take a good look
at that face, Floyd.
Because if he ever finds out I can
be beat by one lousy grifter,
I'll have to kill him
and every other hood
who wants to muscle in
on my Chicago operation.
You follow?
Yes, sir.
Good lad.
Hey, you feeling all right
this morning, Henry?
Yeah, fine.
Would you mind opening up the
round a little early today?
We got some business
coming in before hours.
- Sure.
- Check the main gearing, will you?
Man O' War started rattling yesterday
and threw a kid on its head.
Great little countess,
that Billie.
She runs a spiffy house
up there, too.
You, uh, plan to spend
the rest of your life here?
I could do a lot worse.
Listen, Gondorff, am I gonna learn
to play the big con or not?
What's your hurry?
I wanna play for Lonnegan.
You know anything
about the guy?
Yeah, he croaked Luther.
Anything else I got to know?
All right.
He runs a numbers racket
on the South Side,
he owns a packinghouse,
a few banks--
Yeah, and half the politicians
in New York and Chicago.
Not a fix in this world gonna
cool him out if he blows on you.
- I'll get him anyway.
- Why?
'Cause I don't know enough
about killin' to kill him.
You can't do it alone,
you know.
It takes a mob of guys and enough
money to make them look good.
I know plenty of guys.
It's not like playing winos.
You can't outrun a--
I never played for no winos.
You've gotta keep his con
even after you take his money.
He can't know you took him.
You're scared of him.
Right down
to my socks, buster.
You're talkin' about a guy
who would kill a grifter
over a chunk of money that
wouldn't support him for two days.
You're going to go for him.
I just don't want a hothead
looking to get even,
coming back
halfway through saying,
it ain't enough, 'cause
it's all we're gonna get.
Can you get a mob together?
After what happened
to Luther,
I don't think I can get more
than 200, 300 guys.
Luther said you learn fast.
I hope he's right.
Lonnegan gets most of his
income from the numbers
even though he's been
putting more money
into his
savings-and-loan business.
- You think he's moving out of the racket?
- No.
He owns most of
the stock that's traded.
But my guess is he's just trying to
build himself a respectable image.
He came out of Five Points,
but he's been telling everybody
he was born in Forest Hills.
He knows the market, though.
I don't think we can take him
on a stocks deal.
Twist,
what about the numbers?
Tipsters say it's run out of a
packinghouse on 14th by a guy named Combs.
Lonnegan comes out every three
weeks to check on it, but
he stays away from the day-to-day
stuff in case it's raided.
These are two of Combs' favorite
torpedoes: Riley and Cole.
You ever seen 'em?
- No.
- They're the ones who hit Luther.
They also got the numbers
runner you conned.
A guy named Mottola.
Found him in a quarry
with a knife in his eye.
Lonnegan's had seven or eight
people rubbed on his way up.
His pattern has been
to get close to a racket boss,
learn the operation,
then move in on it.
He's done it to Gorman,
O'Donnell, Buchalman.
He took the numbers
from Sharkey.
All four of these guys
are dead.
He's vindictive as hell, Henry.
Kills for pride.
Doesn't add up he'd let
Hooker get away from him.
You see anything,
kid, you let us know.
If they put you on the spot, we got
to fold the con. You got that?
Yeah. You sure it's got to be
one of these two guys?
No. They're just
the only ones we know of.
Time.
Set me up five more beers,
will you, Danny?
- You the owner here?
- That's right.
Lt. Snyder, Bunco.
That's a Joliet badge,
Snyder.
Don't cut much up here.
Looking for a guy on the lam
from a counterfeiting rap.
Thought he might've
come in here.
Don't think so.
I know everyone in the place.
And I always bounce
the lamsters.
All right if
I look around in here?
No, but you're welcome
to a free beer before you go.
I don't really
need your permission.
I don't know what to do
with this guy, Henry.
He's an Irishman
who doesn't drink,
doesn't smoke and
doesn't chase dames.
He's a grand knight
in the Knights of Columbus.
And he only goes
out to play faro.
Sometimes plays
15 to 20 hours at a time.
Just him against the house.
Roulette, craps?
He won't touch 'em.
The croupier at Gilman's says he
never plays anything he can't win.
Sports?
Likes to be seen
with fighters sometimes,
but doesn't go to
the fights or bet on them.
Jesus. Does he do anything
where he's not alone?
Just poker.
And he cheats.
Pretty good at it, too.
Where does he play?
The porters say he runs a braced
game on the Century Limited
when he comes out
here from New York.
$100 minimum, straight poker.
And a lot of high rollers ride
that train just to play him.
That sounds good, J.J.
Which way are the rooms?
Who told you this guy was in here?
Nobody. I just know what
kind of woman he likes.
I'm gonna check all the
joy houses till I find him.
Well, maybe I could help you
if you tell me his name.
I doubt it.
Which way are the rooms?
Right through there.
But I wouldn't go in there
if I were you.
What are you gonna do,
call the cops?
I don't have to.
You'd be busting in on the chief
of police just up the hall.
We'll play it out here.
And a huge duke is too simple.
With no fix, we're gonna need a
con with a sure-fire blow-off.
I think we ought to play
this guy on the payoff.
It's the tightest game
we got.
It's not all over
the papers yet.
Lonnegan is a fast egg, J.J.
He's not going to sit still
for a standard play.
So what does that leave us?
We can't con
the payoff to a banker.
We'll use the wire.
Haven't known a poker player yet
didn't wanna beat the ponies.
The wire's been
out of date for 10 years.
That's why he won't know it.
I'm not sure I know it.
It'll take two of us
working the inside.
Any objections
to Hooker as second man?
All right.
We'll give Lonnegan the hook
on the train and play him here.
J.J., you think I can
get in that poker game?
Just show up with a lot of
money and look like a sucker.
I also gotta win.
Oh, by the way, any of you guys
been passing bad money lately?
If he comes in again, stall him
so I can get a look at him.
Fella by the name of Stenner had this
place until about six months ago,
but he had to give it up.
It doesn't look so good
right now,
but maybe you can fix it up
a little bit.
Watch your step
when you come in.
There's a dip down
on the left.
How's it look, Eddie?
It looks all right, Kid.
It's big enough,
and it's off the street.
I don't know.
It's kind of short notice.
I'm not sure
we can get it all
done by Saturday.
Got to. Gondorff's riding the mark
down from New York on the Century.
We'll take it.
That building at the end of
the alley, do you manage that?
For 15 years.
I'll need a corner room
facing this way.
How much a week?
Only rents by the month.
$250 for the two of them.
Last time I expect
to see you down here.
Never heard of the place.
It's been awhile since
I stocked the wire store.
Not many mobs playing that anymore.
All we'll need
is the bookie setup for now.
All right.
I'll rent you everything
I've got in the warehouse
for $2,000.
That'll give you phones,
cages, blackboards and ticker gear.
If you want a counter and bar,
that's another $1,000.
That's pretty steep, Benny.
Gondorff's still a hot item.
Where would I be if he gets hit?
Benny, you just give us
what you can.
We'll send a truck down.
Now how do you want to work this?
Flat rate or percentage?
Who's the mark?
Doyle Lonnegan.
Flat rate.
The guy in the black hat
with the gimp.
He's not as tough
as he thinks.
Neither are we.
Mr. Shaw?
That's right.
You wanted to see me?
I hear there's a friendly poker
game on this train. Know about it?
Oh, a little.Thank you, sir.
Can you get me in that game?
Oh, don't know.
There's usually a waiting list.
That'll get you
first alternate, sir.
I'll see what I can do.
Hey, Twist!
Patty, me boy!
How are you?
How are you, Twist?
Hey, Champ,
you're looking like a million!
Good to see you!
Goldie, you old son of a gun.
I saw the Kid in Denver.
He says to say hello to you.
Joiner, are you still
working those shapes?
Any number you want, Twist!
Good to see you again, Twist.
Okay, Lacey.
Good to see you.
- It's good to see you.
- Dukey, how are you?
Come on in.
When did you get back in town?
A couple of days ago.
You heard about Luther Coleman,
didn't you?
Yeah, some of the boys
were passing the hat
for Alva and the kids.
I never seen the guys
so worked up.
Well, don't worry
about it, Dukey.
We're gonna send a little
calling card of our own.
Gondorff is setting up
a wire store on the north side.
I'm gonna need a 20-man
boost right away.
I got plenty of talent
out there tonight.
You can take
your pick. Lace!
This is a tough one, Dukey.
These boys have
got to be the quill.
Get me the sheet.
Let's see who's in town, huh?
Hey, Patty,
give me the sheet.
Sure.
Gondorff's already on...
Twist, you know this guy?
No, I never saw him before.
He's a dick, though.
Hello, Snyder.
- What are you doin' up here?
- I'm on vacation.
Hey, you seen that
friend of yours lately?
No, no.
He, uh, packed it in.
Enrolled in detective school.
When you see him,
you tell him he better pay
up before I get to him.
That son of a bitch.
Oh, thanks, Lace.
Now, let's see
what we got here.
Let's see. Horse Face Lee,
Slim Miller,
Suitcase Murphy and the Big
Alabama are in from New Orleans.
Crying Jonesy and the
Boone Kid from Denver.
Dippy Burke and Limehouse
Chappie from New York.
Well, these and
the guys outside
should give you 30 or more
to choose from.
Good, Dukey.
Have them down at Stenner's
old pool hall before 6:00.
We're gonna run
the route tonight.
Okay, Twist, but
if this thing
blows up, remember,
I can't do you no good downtown.
Gondorff is federal.
Dukey, if this thing blows up,
the feds will be
the least of our problems.
Yeah?
You in?
Yeah, I think so.
I gave the kayducer a C-note.
Did you find out the deck?
He usually plays with a Tally-Ho
Fan or a Tally-Ho Circle.
I got you one of each.
He likes to cold-deck low,
eights or nines.
That's nice work, J.J. Here.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Don't mention it, ma'am.
She picked him clean.
He never missed it.
My God, looks like
he's expecting a big night.
Must be $15,000
or $20,000 here.
He's waiting for you
in the card room.
Let him wait.
You just worry
about your end, kid.
If we ever get to it.
Excuse me.
You sure you
checked this guy out?
He seemed like a pleasant man,
a lot of cash on him.
$200 suit, expensive luggage.
I'll vouch for him.
Why isn't he here then?
Don't worry.
He'll be here.
All right.
What're you doing?
Always drink gin with a mark, kid.
He can't tell if you cut it.
$2,000 for you, Mr. Clayton.
Thank you.
All right, gentlemen.
Should we not wait for him?
Let's go.
I think that's a good idea.
Mr. Clemens, give me the cards.
Sorry I'm late, guys.
I was taking a crap.
The name's Shaw.
Mr. Shaw, meet
Mr. Jameson from Chicago.
How are you?
Mr. Lombard from Philadelphia.
Yeah.
And Mr. Lonnegan
from New York.
Pleased to meet you.
Mr. Clayton, Pittsburgh.
Any of you guys want to make
a little book in Chicago,
I'm the guy to see.
The game is straight poker
$100 minimum, table stakes.
Ah, Mr. Shaw,
this is a gentleman's game.
We assume you're all
good for your debts.
How much would you like,
Mr. Shaw?
I'll start with $5,000.
Mr. Shaw, we usually require
a tie at this table.
If you don't have one,
we can get you one.
Hey, that'd be real nice of you,
Mr. Lonneman.
Lonnegan.
Name's Curly Jackson.
Worked for Gad Bryan
out of Baldwin.
Jackson?
Jackson, Jackson.
Oh, yeah.
You ever played the wire, Curly?
Roped for it long ago.
I can shill, mark board,
anything you want.
I don't run with riffraff,
and I only drink on the weekend.
Me specialty's an Englishman.
All right, Curly.
We got a rack of suits
over there.
Pick yourself out
a nice tweed one.
That's all right.
I've got all my own stuff.
Doyle?
One.
Bill?
I'll take one.
Shaw?
Three.
And the dealer will take one.
Bet $500.
I'll call.
Call and raise.
- $300.
- I'm out.
Fold.
Your $300
and raise
$500.
That's $800 to me.
Call.
Jacks on top.
Beats me.
Three tens.
Tough luck, Lonnihan.
But that's what you get for playing
with your head up your ass.
Couple more like that,
we can all go to bed early.
The name's Lonnegan.
Doyle Lonnegan.
You're gonna remember that,
Mr. Shaw,
or you're gonna get yourself
another game.
You follow?
Bring it right up here!
Hey, Eddie, we brought you
a tap into Moe Anenberg's wire.
You'll get race results, odds,
scratches,
pole positions, everything.
And just as fast
as Western Union gets them.
Does J.J. know
how to use that thing?
All he's got to do is read.
The name is Joe Erie.
Joe Erie.
You, uh, played for
any particular mobs?
No.
You ever play
the wire before, Erie?
No.
I never played no
big con before, but, uh,
Luther Coleman was a friend
of mine, and I thought maybe
there'd be something
I could do.
You get that nose
in Duke Boudreau's tonight?
Yeah.
You got moxie, Erie.
Get yourself a suit.
Thanks.
I'll bet $300.
Call and raise $200.
Call.
No.
I'm out.
Call.
Aces over.
Three cowboys.
All red, queen high.
Well, that finishes me.
Don't worry about it, pal.
They wouldn't have let you in
if you weren't a chump!
Lombard will be joining you
in a couple of minutes.
Now, look here, Shaw
I've had enough of this game
and quite enough of this company.
Check me out, Clemens.
I guess that just
leaves the three of us.
Yes, Mr. Shaw.
that just leaves us three.
Mr. Clayton, I think we should
take a break for five minutes.
Tempers seem to be
running a little high.
Oh, come on, Linneman,
I was just
starting to do good.
Stack me a cooler, Floyd.
Oh, come on, Doyle.
We'll be in the station
in another hour.
The other guys are the losers.
You're still okay.
Fix me a deck.
Threes and nines.
I'll cut it in
on Clayton's deal.
What do you want
Clayton to get?
Nothing. I want him
out of there early.
I'm gonna bust that bastard
bookie in one play.
$400 to you, Mr. Jameson.
You're even.
Well, just wasn't my night.
I need it.
- You know what time we get in?
- No, I don't.
Hey, where's your ante?
Every time I had anything,
he stayed in front of me.
$500.
Your $500. $1,000.
I'll fold.
I'll play.
Cards?
Two.
Three.
$500.
Your $500 and $1,000.
Your $1,000.
I'll raise you $2,000.
Your $2,000.
Mr. Clemens,
give me $10,000 more.
I'll call.
Four nines.
Four Jacks.
You owe me $15,000, pal.
Must've left
my wallet in my room.
Don't hand me
any of that crap!
When you come to a game like this,
you bring your money!
How do I know you
won't take a powder?
No, no,
no, no, no, now...
All right,
I'll tell you what I'll do.
I'll send a boy around
to your room in five minutes.
You better have the money
or it's gonna be all around
Chicago that you welched.
You won't be able to
get a game of jacks!
Cash me in for
the rest of these bums.
You're on, kid.
But I can tell you,
it's a hard act to follow.
How did it go?
We got working money.
- Hey?
- Yeah?
He's steamin'.
Yeah.
Watch yourself.
Doyle, I know
I gave him four threes!
He had to make a switch!
We can't let him
get away with that.
What was I supposed to do?
Call him for cheating better
than me in front of the others?
Name's Kelly.
Shaw sent me.
Your boss is quite
a card player, Mr. Kelly.
How does he do it?
He cheats.
Well, in that case,
I'll keep my money,
and we'll just
have another game.
You don't have any to keep.
Here's your wallet.
He hired a dame
to take it from you.
Shaw's been planning
to beat your game for months.
He's been waiting for you to
cheat him so he could clip you.
Who do you think you're
talking to, errand boy?
Nobody sets me up!
Take him back to
the baggage room!
Put one in his ear!
There were four witnesses
at that table!
Then go back, get that
other goddamn son of a bitch
and we'll dump them
in the first tunnel we hit.
Doyle, we'll be in the station
in a few minutes!
It ain't gonna look too good
you killing a guy
you owe money to.
There's better ways
of taking him down.
What do you think
Shaw would do to me
if he knew I was
telling you this?
Okay.
Why the rat?
I want to take over
his operation,
and I need you
to help me break him.
Where's my money?
Shaw's got it.
How the hell could
I ask him for it back?
We're pulling in.
I'm giving you a lift home.
I was supposed to go with Shaw.
Explain it to him somehow.
Yeah, but he's expecting me.
I'm giving you a lift home.
You follow?
Yeah, sure. Sure thing.
What makes you think
you can beat him?
I've been planning this
for two years.
I know his organization
backwards and forwards.
And I need somebody who's respectable
but not completely legit.
I'm a banker, Kelly.
That's legit in this state.
All you gotta do is put down a
bet for me at Shaw's place.
I'll do the rest.
I'll supply the money.
I'll supply the information.
What about the money you come to collect?
Won't he miss it?
I'll tell him you paid it.
I keep his books.
He trusts me.
If you help me, I'll pay you back the
money he stole out of my own pocket.
It's worth that much to you?
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
Maybe a couple of million.
Where do you
come from, Kelly?
From the East Side of New York.
A place called Five Points.
But I got out of there.
Out and up, huh?
Hey, Floyd,
I'm gonna have to keep
you away from this guy.
You're liable to get ideas.
I'll be at Klein's Drug Store
660 South Marshall at 1:30,
if you're interested.
If I'm not there by 1:45,
I'm not coming.
- Hey, Hooker.
- Hey, Ed.
How did it go?
Jake.
Everything go okay?
Yeah, sure. Hell, easy.
No sign of trouble, huh?
No.
What about Lonnegan?
I gave him the breakdown,
just like you said.
And?
He's good.
He threatened to kill me.
Hell, kid,
if they don't do that,
you know you're not
getting to them.
Hello, Doyle.
All right, Riley,
what the hell happened?
We missed him.
Whoever he is,
he made a fool out of you.
There wasn't no way he could've
known we was in that room.
Somebody must've
wised him up.
What does Cole
say about that?
I don't know.
He took it hard.
Get out of here, Riley.
Put Salino onto it.
Salino? Why waste our best
people on a small-time job?
This is a nickel-and-dime
grifter we're after, Doyle.
They'll get him next time.
They had their chance.
All they did was
shoot up a neighborhood,
make a lot of noise,
wake up a few cops.
Yeah, but that was-- I told
you to put Salino onto it.
It may take
a little more time,
but there won't be any holes.
Tell Cole I wanna see him
when he comes in.
Well, he won't be coming in,
not to get bounced
off a job, anyway.
This is Salino's job, Vince.
Cole wants to muscle in on it,
that's his business.
But he's breaking the rules
and Salino won't like it.
Now, get me the books.
Joe, those odds on
the third race are wrong.
Just a minute.
I'll get them for you.
Don't worry so much, lad.
You're gonna be all right.
Just stay to the back
the first time around.
Put a little of this
on your nose.
Kelly?
You should always
look to the back, kid.
I was afraid
you wasn't gonna show.
We haven't got much time.
Get on with it, then.
Sometime after 2:00
a guy's gonna
call on that phone there
and give you
the name of a horse.
All you got to do
is take this $2,000
across the street
and down the alley
to Shaw's place,
and bet it on that pony.
There's nothing to it.
But don't take too much time.
We've only got three or four
minutes after you get the call.
You'll not break him
with a $2,000 bet.
This is just a test.
The big one comes later.
But be careful with that.
That's all I got.
And you were gonna pay me back
out of your own pocket?
I am. After the race.
I got to get back
before Shaw misses me.
Good luck.
Yeah? Go ahead.
The horse is Blue Note to win.
Fourth race at Narragansett.
Got it.
Yeah?
Blue Note to win
in the fourth race
at Narragansett.
Turning for home,
it's Lady Scout by a length.
Speed Queen a half,
Lady Trust and Miss Petrina.
Into the stretch,
it's Lady Scout ahead,
Speed Queen a half.
And at the wire,
it's Speed Queen the winner!
Lady Scout placed
and Miss Petrina showed.
Post numbers two, five,
and one.
Taking off at 23.
Look at that.
He's got his apes with him.
Yeah, we're gonna have to do
something about that.
Bubblesome is 10,
Beefsteak, 7...
Vote Boy, 8, Kerry Patch, 12
and Blue Note is 7-1.
This is your last call for the
third race at Lincoln Fields.
They're going to the post.
- You may still wager...
- There he goes.
...if you hurry.
At Detroit, the winner,
Speed Queen, paid $7.20
$4.80 and $3.40.
Lady Scout, $7.40.
Miss Petrina paid $4.
Last flash at Narragansett.
Lady Higloss, 6-5.
I'd think you'd get
tired of losing, Harrigan.
Thank you, Mr. Willis.
Blue Note,
$2,000 to win, fourth race,
Narragansett.
Make sure
you see the cash, Eddie.
He's got a name for
betting money he doesn't have.
We'll give you the results
on that one in a minute.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is Arnold Rowe,
your caller
for the fourth race.
The mile and one-sixteenth
Mansfield handicap
at Narragansett Park,
Rhode Island.
$13,000 added,
3-year-olds and up.
The flag is up,
and they're off and running.
It's Bubblesome
going to the front,
followed by Lady Higloss,
Vote Boy, Chancing,
Beefsteak, Kerry Patch
and Blue Note
trails the field.
Around the clubhouse turn,
it's Bubblesome ahead,
Chancing a half,
Lady Higloss by one
followed by
Vote Boy, Beefsteak,
Kerry Patch and Blue Note.
Into the second turn,
it's Chancing by a length.
Lady Higloss driving
on the rail and Vote Boy
followed by Bubblesome, Beefsteak,
Kerry Patch and Blue Note.
Come on, Chancing!
Hey, uh...
Lady Higloss a half,
Vote Boy by one.
That Lady Higloss is
a hell of a finisher.
Chancing's gonna have to open
up a little more on her.
Know anything about a horse
named Blue Note?
Nah, nah,
he never done much.
Probably in there
just to round out the field.
Chancing's where you want
to have your money.
Great tip you handed me, kid.
Just give him time.
Chancing by one.
And here comes Blue Note,
driving on the outside!
Nice work, Erie.
He loves you.
He's third!
Chancing is
shortening stride,
and now it's Lady Higloss
and Blue Note.
They're head to head.
They're neck to neck.
It's Lady Higloss, Blue Note.
Lady Higloss, Blue Note.
And Blue Note
wins it by a nose!
Lady Higloss is second by three,
and Chancing is third by one.
Who in the blazes
is Blue Note?
The winner, Blue Note,
paid $16, $9.40 and $6.
So you want to have
your money on Chancing, huh?
Chancing paid $3.80.
Time for the mile
and one-sixteenth.
They're going to
the gate at Belmont.
And here are the late odds.
Both those garbage men
belong to you?
Well, get them out of here
and don't bring 'em back.
This is a class joint.
Hey, you! Kelly!
Yes, sir?
Run those bums out of here.
Uh, M-Mr. Shaw, could I--
Don't give me
any of your lip, kid.
Now, run 'em out of here.
The winner is Panic Relief.
Barbara A is second...
I...
Time for the three-quarter mile:
1:11.4.
The winner,
Panic Relief, paid $12.40
$8.20 and $5.
Barbara A, $6.20 and $4.
Wilder paid $4.
They're at the post
at Belmont at 38.
We're waiting on one.
I'll call Belmont next.
That's it, fellas!
I want to repeat that--
All right, J.J.
What do you say, pal?
Yeah?
He's on his way.
Hi, Mutt.
Say, Jeff.
Well, what'd I tell you?
You got lucky once.
That's not enough.
Oh. Lucky, hell.
I can do it every time.
Why don't you then?
'Cause it's better
to do it all at once.
We're gonna put down
$400,000 next week.
At 5-1 odds,
that's $2 million.
Twenty percent of that
is yours if you stick with it.
Got a system, Kelly?
No. You can still lose
with a system.
You're past-posting,
aren't you?
Could be.
How?
You're gonna stay in?
Not until I get some answers.
I got a partner downtown.
And he runs the central office
of the Western Union.
Now, race results from all
over the country come in there
and go across his desk
to the bookies.
Now, all he does is hold them
up for a couple of minutes
till he can call us,
get a bet down on the winner.
Then he releases
the results to the bookies.
We clean up on a race that's already
been run. Now, you can't miss.
Unless the Western Union dicks
get a hold of it.
You got the $400,000 yet?
No, not yet, but...
Hey, there's only $1,000 here.
Make another bet tomorrow.
What the hell is this?
Where's my money?
I got $16,000 coming.
You owe me
$15,000 already.
Besides, if your setup's as good as you say,
there's plenty more to come.
I decide when to
place the bets!
Not if you want me
to keep making them for you.
I gotta talk to my partner.
We can't afford
to expose too much.
- I'll talk to him myself.
- No!
You've been waiting
a long time for this, Kelly.
Don't ruin it for yourself.
I'll pick you up
tomorrow at 3:00.
You follow?
Twist, I told him the tale,
but he didn't go for it.
He wants to see my partner
tomorrow at 3:00.
- 3:00?
- Yeah.
No, we'll never get a telegraph
store set up by then.
Any chance of talking him
out of it?
None. I would've stalled him, but I
didn't have many friends in the room.
Yeah. Well, all right, we'll
have to play him on the fly.
I'll get Eddie
looking for a place.
Let me know when
you got something.
Sure thing, tootsie.
All right, Hooker!
Stop him!
Hey, watch it.
Hooker! Hooker!
I'll get you, you rat!
Hooker!
Why didn't you tell me
about Snyder before?
I thought I'd lost him.
Well, you found him again.
And we're gonna have to
do something about it.
What else haven't
you been telling me?
Nothing. That's all there is.
Hold still.
Why did you move
out of your room?
It was too noisy.
You can't play your friends
like marks, Hooker.
You know how easy
it would be
for one of
Lonnegan's guys to get you?
Henry, all we need
is a couple of days
and we can get the son
of a bitch and nail him.
You just won't learn,
will you?
I come in here,
I teach you stuff
that maybe five guys
in the world know.
Stuff most grifters couldn't
do even if they knew it.
All you want to do
is run down a bullet.
I'm asking a couple
of days, that's all.
I can stay clear that long!
Christ, they'll probably
miss you and hit me.
Hey.
Hi.
What will you have?
Give me
the, uh, blue plate special.
One blue plate special.
You're done?
Yeah.
Guess I should've
had the meat loaf.
It isn't any better.
Hey, where's June?
She quit.
I'm filling in for her
a couple of days
until I can get
a train out of here.
Yeah? Where are you going?
I don't know.
Depends on
what train I get on.
Keep it.
Thanks.
Let's go.
Excuse me, ma'am, but
we're looking for Mr., uh...
Harmon.
Uh, Mr. Harmon's office.
Mr. Harmon?
Yeah.
Got a work order here
for a painting job.
For Mr. Harmon's office?
That's right, ma'am.
Well, uh, hold on.
Just a second.
Hiya.
Where to?
110 South Wabash.
Get going.
What happened to your face?
Uh, got into a fight
with a raggle down on 13th.
Cut me with her ring.
You ought to
lay off the skirts.
You don't find any of my boys
messing around
with that kind of trash.
Brigham signed it, all right.
I can't understand
why he didn't tell me.
Ah, he's like
all 'em supervisors.
They think they're too good
for regular people.
He says he was in here a while
ago and the place was a mess.
We'll hurry so we don't
keep you out too long.
Well, why can't I work
with you in here?
Look, pal, we got to cover
the floor, the furniture,
so we don't spill on nothin'.
Now, if you want to sit
in here with a tarp
over your head,
you're welcome to it.
All right.
How long will you be?
Oh, an hour or two at the most.
It's a small job.
We'll go in
the side door here.
Hiya, Les.
Uh, Les,
this is Doyle Lonnegan.
Mr. Lonnegan,
this is Les Harmon.
How do you do,
Mr. Lonnegan?
- Could we, uh...
- What did you bring him here for?
I thought it'd be a good idea
for him to see the operation.
Kelly,
I'm having the place painted.
- We can't talk in here now.
- Oh.
Well, we'll have to
find someplace else.
Excuse me, Mr. Lonnegan.
Yeah, Miss Barnes,
I'm going home a little early.
Look, if there are any calls,
tell them they can reach me here
tomorrow morning. Thank you.
Mr. Lonnegan?
I want to see it
one more time.
I can't do it.
We got telegraph
inspectors everywhere.
One more time won't
make a difference.
We got $400,000 coming in
from the coast next week.
You wanna risk that
on a lousy $15,000?
If it works again tomorrow,
I'll finance the whole thing.
$500,000.
60-40, we split.
What are you talking... I told
you, we've already got a guy.
He's gonna give us half. What
am I supposed to say to him?
Say to him what you want.
What I know about
your operation, if I were you
I'd be worried
about making me happy.
He's right, Les.
Your guy says a week.
How do we know it
won't be a month?
Lonnegan here is a banker.
He can get the money
without any questions asked.
But we can't keep
going into Shaw's place
and cleaning up on long shots.
He's bound to get wise.
All right.
We'll go for short odds.
But it's still--
You follow?
You Lt. William Snyder?
I don't know.
What's up?
FBI.
Special Agent Polk would
like a few words with you.
You got a couple of minutes?
Yeah, sure.
No, no, no. It's got to be
south of the river.
Probably this
section in here.
31st, 39th,
Morgan and Halstead.
Now, that's
this section here.
Now, let's break it
into two sections along 35th.
What is this?
I got work to do.
Sit down and
shut up, will you?
Try not to live up
to all my expectations.
Take two men with you.
work your way south
from 31st to 35th,
Morgan and Halstead.
Go into every place and
let me know what you find.
We've been told
you know a hustle artist
named Johnny Hooker.
You know him or don't you?
Yeah, but I don't know
where he is.
Well, we do.
He's chumming around
with a big "C"
named Henry Gondorff.
Ring any bells?
Sure. Every bunco man in
the country knows Gondorff.
Well, there's word
he's gonna run a con
on the South Side here.
We've got a year-old
Florida warrant on him,
but it's a thin beef.
He can beat it in court
unless we catch him cold.
All we want you to do
is pick up Hooker for us.
Why don't you
pick him up yourself?
Because if word gets out
that the feds are in on it,
Gondorff will fold up
the whole thing.
Wouldn't that be too bad?
Then you'd have to move out
of this nice office
you've got here.
Don't crack wise
with me, flatfoot.
I spent too much time
in dumps like this
eating Gondorff's dust
while you guys in
the bunco squads get rich
tipping him off!
That's not gonna
happen this time.
We're not gonna tell
the police we're here.
You keep your mouth shut
and do a job,
there'll be some
reward bucks in it for you.
And you better take it,
'cause I can make you
work for us without it.
What the hell good
is Hooker to you?
He's gonna set up
Gondorff for us.
He'll never do it.
I think he will.
He's there.
Let's get on it.
What's the line on Exponent?
Uh, 5-1.
How's it going?
Ah, nothing yet.
I had a good one on the lead
at Lincoln Fields,
but he faded.
Best we had the last hour
was Love Potion
at Rockingham
and she was 5-1.
All the long shots
coming in today.
Take 4-1
if you have to.
Okay.
You can forget
the boodle, Eddie.
He could hit us
for $15,000 at 4-1.
We can't handle that.
We'll give him
the shut-out.
Okay.
Okay, Billie, here we go.
At the wire, it's Wrecking
Crew, the winner by five.
Black Mischief, second.
Whichaway, third.
Wrecking Crew was 3-1.
That's our boy.
Henry?
Here we go, Henry.
We got a 3-1 at Belmont.
Wrecking Crew.
Yeah?
Right.
In the sixth race at Belmont.
Wrecking Crew to win,
Black Mischief to place,
Whichaway to show.
Wait here.
The winner,
Time to Go, paid $7
$5.40 and $3.80.
Joy Flag, $6 and $4.20.
Readily paid $3.80 to show.
The weather's threatening,
but the track is fast
there in Salem,
New Hampshire.
Here's a late jockey change
there in the fifth
at Rockingham.
R.C. Stark
will ride Itsie-Bitsie.
$5,000 on Black Mischief,
across the board.
The sixth at Belmont.
Would you hurry it up
there, please?
Wrecking Crew is 3-1,
Vale of Tears, 4
Black Mischief, 5,
Whichaway, 6
Chief Yeoman, 12,
Peerless Pal is 20...
Okay.
and Mariato is, uh, 40.
And here we go for
the sixth at Belmont:
it's five
and a half furlongs.
They're at the post.
- Now.
- The flag is up.
- And they're off!
- 6th race, Belmont, $15,000.
Excuse me, sir. We can't take
any bets once the race is started.
You can bet on
another race if you care to.
Going into the backstretch,
it's Wrecking Crew by two.
Whichaway a half,
Black Mischief
and Vale of Tears
driving on the outside.
Nothing, thank you.
What happened?
I didn't get
the bet down in time.
Jesus!
Heading for home,
it's Wrecking Crew all alone
by six lengths
Whichaway a length,
and Vale of Tears.
It's Wrecking Crew,
Whichaway and Black Mischief.
And at the wire,
Wrecking Crew
wins it by six lengths.
Black Mischief
is second by a head
Whichaway is third by a neck,
followed by Vale of Tears.
You should've had your money
on Wrecking Crew.
It's raining and the track is
sloppy there at Riverside Park.
There's a late scratch there.
Transmutate--Transmutate is scratched
in the fifth at Riverside.
At Belmont,
the winner, Wrecking Crew
paid $6, $4.20 and $2.80.
Black Mischief,
$4.60 and $3.20.
I'll have $500,000 here
by post time tomorrow.
Lay it on the first race where
the odds are 4-1 or better.
Make sure I get
to the window this time.
How the hell
am I gonna do that?
I don't know. Figure it out
for yourself, Kelly.
Finished?
Yeah. Meat loaf, apple pie
and a cup of coffee.
Say, what time
you get off work here?
2:00 a.m.
Yeah? Doing anything tonight?
Yeah. Sleeping.
Eighty-five.
Uh, you got a back door
to this place?
What's wrong with the front?
No time to mess around. There's a
guy out there I don't need to see.
Don't look around.
What does he want?
He'd like to kill me.
Now, look, do me a favor.
Go into the bathroom,
open the window
and wait there.
Why should I-- Just do what I tell
you, and everything will be Jake.
Please.
Thanks. Good night.
It's taken.
Thanks. See you.
Shit.
Salino. Hey, I wasn't...
Hey! Got you, Hooker!
Hey there, Snyder.
Long time no see.
Get going!
Chuck,
get this off to
the Department right away.
Yes, sir.
Hello, Hooker. Take them off.
Special Agent Polk, FBI.
Have a chair.
You want
a drink or something?
No.
We want to talk to you
about Henry Gondorff.
Yeah? I don't think
I know him.
Well, give yourself
a couple of seconds.
You wouldn't
want to lie to me.
Lt. Snyder says you've done
a lot of confidence work
in his town.
Oh, yeah? Lt. Snyder
doesn't know shit.
You ain't got nothing on me.
Yeah?
How about counterfeiting?
We've got a tip that Gondorff
is gonna run a con
on the South Side here.
All you've got
to do is tell us
when he's gonna
play his chump.
We come in at the sting,
make the pinch,
and you walk out
free as a bird.
No.
You want to spend
the next 20 years
in a federal penitentiary,
starting tonight?
I'll make parole.
Like hell.
You won't even get a review.
I'll chance it.
Okay. If that's the way
you want it.
We might even provide you
with a little company
on your way up the river.
That wife of Luther Coleman's.
Snyder, what was her name?
Alva.
That's it. Alva Coleman.
Pretty fair grifter
in her time.
Snyder's given us
quite a folder on her.
Nothing major by itself,
but, uh,
put them all together, it could
add up to a lot of years.
You stink, mister.
Don't be a sap.
It's not her I want.
If you're too dumb
to save yourself,
there's no sense
dragging her down with you.
It's over, Hooker.
You can save me
a lot of trouble.
But I'm gonna
get Henry Gondorff
whether you
help me out or not.
Will you wait till
the chump is played?
Hell, yes.
We don't care about the mark.
He deserves what he gets.
I mean completely played.
You come in before we beat him,
and I'll kill him.
All right, Hooker.
But you try to
take it on the lam,
and we'll shoot
you down on sight.
As long as I get
to finish the play.
What is it, kid?
You're not saying much.
Just got the jumps.
Come in.
Things are a little slow
tonight, Henry.
I want to open
the round for the girls.
Sure.
Take it easy, kid.
We're not gonna lose him now.
We had him 10 years ago
when he decided to be somebody.
Believe me, I've seen
enough to know. 10.
20.
30.
Go.
31.
How many guys you conned
in your life, Henry?
I don't know, 200, 300.
Sometimes we played two a day
when I was with O'Shea's mob.
Of course,
Chicago was a rigged town.
The fix was in.
The dicks took their end
without a beef.
We had it down to a business.
And it really stunk, kid.
No sense in being a grifter
if it's the same
as being a citizen.
Well, I got packing to do.
I'm gonna be a hot number
again after tomorrow.
I wouldn't ask you to do this, you
know, if it weren't for Luther.
Nothing's gonna
make up for Luther.
Revenge is for suckers.
I've been grifting 30 years.
I never got any.
Then why are you doing it?
It seems worthwhile,
doesn't it?
See you.
Looks like he missed you.
Uh, yeah. This time, anyway.
Good night,
Mrs. Hillard.
I, uh, was wondering
if you might want
to come out for a while
maybe have
a drink or something.
You move right along,
don't you?
Hey, I don't mean
nothing by it.
I just don't know many
regular girls, is all.
And you expect me
to come out just like that?
If I expected something,
I wouldn't still be
standing here in the hall.
I don't even know you.
You know me.
I'm just like you.
It's 2:00 in the morning,
and I don't know nobody.
Come on, Henry. Knock off.
You've done
everything you can.
Yeah? Polk.
Polk, this is Hooker.
You ready?
Yeah, go ahead.
Everything's all set.
There'll be a guy
or two at the door.
Nobody's carrying heaters.
You won't have any trouble.
Okay. See you there.
She was gonna kill you, kid.
Her name's Loretta Salino.
Lonnegan's people
set her up in the diner.
Come on.
Let's get out of here.
Come on!
But she could have
killed me last night.
Too many people could have
seen you go in her room.
She was a real professional.
Used to work in
the Dutch Schultz mob.
Who are you?
Gondorff asked me
to look after you.
Snyder,
we just got a tip
that Gondorff's mark
is some big New York wheel.
As soon as we're inside,
you get him out of there fast
before the reporters show up.
I don't want any
big shots around
to mess this up for me.
All right, let's go!
Let's go, guys!
The flag is up, kid.
Anytime, J.J.
I'm working on it.
Got one, Billie.
Here we go.
Okay.
Yeah?
Place it on Lucky Dan
third race at Riverside Park.
1:11.6 seconds.
They were off at 21.
Last call on
the third at Riverside Park.
They're at the post.
At Havre De Grace,
the winner, Light Chatter
paid, uh, $5.40, $3.80
and $2.40. Blacksod...
$500,000 to win.
Lucky Dan,
third race at Riverside.
You heard me.
Hold on, sir.
I'll get the manager.
...in the fourth at Belmont.
Jay Stout will
ride Flying Cross.
See that guy up there?
He just put
$500,000 on Lucky Dan.
The winner at Rockingham Park
Enfin, paid $6.10
$4.30 and $2.50.
What's your problem?
I'm putting $500,000
on Lucky Dan to win.
Third race at Riverside.
Can't lay that off in time.
A bet like that
could break us.
Not only are you a cheat
you're a gutless cheat
as well.
What are the odds?
4-1.
Take all of it.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is Arnold Rowe
calling the third race at
Riverside Park in Kansas City.
This is a claiming race for
$1,500 for 3-year-olds and up.
It's been raining,
and the track is muddy.
The flag is up and
they're off and running.
Dr. Twink is going to the front
followed by Lucky Dan,
Ima Dreamer, Orkin
Josie G.,
Chi Chi and Little Star.
Around the clubhouse turn,
it's Lucky Dan ahead
Dr. Twink a length,
Orkin a half
followed by Ima Dreamer,
Josie G.,
Chi Chi and Little Star.
Into the backstretch
it's Lucky Dan a length,
Dr. Twink a half
Orkin a head,
Ima Dreamer by one.
Sorry, I couldn't wait.
Everything going all right?
You got nothing to worry about.
I put it all on Lucky Dan.
$500,000 to win.
To win?
I said place!
Place it on Lucky...
That horse is
gonna run second!
Ima Dreamer a half,
Dr. Twink a half
and Orkin by two,
followed by Little Star.
It's a driving finish!
There's been a mistake.
- Give me my money back!
- No, I'm sorry--
I tell you
there's been a mistake!
Give me my
goddamn money back!
All right, everybody, FBI!
Don't anybody try to leave.
Stand on your feet,
put your hands over your head
and move nice and slow.
Snyder!
All right.
Get 'em up against the wall.
Make sure they're
not carrying anything.
Hello, Henry.
It's been a long time.
But it's over.
Okay, kid, you can go.
All right, I said hands up.
Keep 'em up!
Come on.
Move them back! Put them up!
Get him out. Get him out!
Come on!
Got to get you out of here!
But my money's in there!
There's a couple of
dead guys, too.
You can't get
mixed up in that.
You don't understand.
There's $500,000 in there!
He's gone.
Okay, Henry, all clear.
Can you believe it?
We pulled it off.
It's a nice con, Hickey.
I thought you were the feds
myself when you came in.
No trouble, Henry.
Snyder went for it
all the way.
You should've seen the rag
he lit under Lonnegan!
Well, kid, you beat him.
You're right, Henry.
It's not enough.
But it's close.
Okay, guys, let's take
this place apart fast.
You can pick up your splits
from Eddie at Boudreau's tonight.
Nice going, J.J.
Oh, Henry!
You're not gonna stick around
for your share?
Nah. I'd only blow it.