Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Adit Lamba 20 on 25.
Chandraprakash Siroha 17 on 25.
Gaurav Sinha 19 on 25.
Ghulam Sheikh 15 on 25.
Harish Gwalani 18 on 25.
Hitesh Shah 24 on 25.
Ishaan Awasthi...
3 on 25.
Kewal Talwar 23 on 25.
Harish Gwalani 20 on 25.
Hitesh Shah 24 on 25.
Ishaan Awasthi... 2 on 25.
Kewal Talwar 22 on 25.
Mahavir Sinha 19 on 25.
Nimesh Desai 17 on 25.
Nitin Rao 18 on 25.
Sitting with your
head in the gutter!
The bus has been waiting
ten minutes!
Can't you hear the bus honking?
Every day we're late because of you.
You want... you want? Take.
Go and wash up.
Schoolbag in your room...
in your room.
Wash your hands first.
Put that down.
Whatever do you do in school? Look
at your hands, look at your face.
Ishaan, put that down.
At least, turn off the tap.
Weren't you going to get
your exam papers today?
Did you get them?
Are you listening?
Yohan?
Drama practice cancelled.
Lily Teacher has viral fever.
I topped in all subjects, Mom.
Algebra, geometry, physics, chem,
bio, history, english, geography...
And in Hindi?
Second in Hindi, by only two marks.
How did you do?
You've almost cracked it.
Finish your homework first!
No... your school uniform...
Look.
Ball! Get the ball... quick!
Over here!
Idiot! Duffer! Look
where you threw it!
Now go get it!
I told you to go. Don't you get it?
What're you looking at?
Don't you get it?
Get the ball. Move it!
What're you looking at?
I said, get the ball!
Don't you get it?
What're you waiting for? Go!
Ranjit! Thrash him!
Your son destroyed my plants.
Have you taught him no manners?
My son is hurt, look he's bleeding!
Haven't you taught your son
anything? How can he beat up my kid?
Have you no shame? Look how
badly my son is bruised!
Come here.
Come here right now
But Papa...
Shut up, Yohan.
He even tore my shirt.
He's lying!
Look, he's hitting my son
right in front of you!
Let go!
Please leave.
- I'm going to call the police!
This is the limit! Complaints
every day...
complaints from school, complaints
from neighbours.
You step out and there's
a complaint.
If there's ever another complaint
about you, I'll...
Laughing! ...Shameless!
Shameless! If there's
another complaint...
One more complaint and I'll send
you away to a boarding school.
Right in front of us...
he picks a fight! Did you see what
he did to that boy... tore his shirt.
Worship him, that's all you do.
How many times have I told you
not to play with Ranjit.
But Mama... - Go, bathe.
I'll get some antiseptic.
Okay, you want to fight?
Fight. Come on
Papa, where are you going?
I'm going away. Forever.
Sorry Papa. I'm very sorry, Papa.
I won't do it next time, Papa.
Papa, I'm very sorry.
I'll never do it again.
Papa please. I'm sorry, Papa
Stop frightening the child.
Papa is going away for work.
Not because of you.
He'll be back by Sunday.
Any more cuts?
Show me.
Tie your laces, tighten that belt.
Prepare for battle...
...shoulder your burdens.
With files in hand and firm resolve...
...we'll take on the world.
We'll stand our ground.
It's the way of the world,
keep at it.
Your goal beckons...
...keep at it.
They sleep with one eye open,
falling behind is not an option.
Work your fingers to the bone,
do exactly as you're told.
They live on omelets,
vitamins and tonics...
...and a strict regimen
of work and rest.
Striding, striving, forging ahead.
It's the way of the world,
keep at it.
Your goal beckons, keep at it.
But here thrives another theme...
...of waking into music from a dream.
Where time comes to a standstill,
to make fantasy come alive at will.
They always wonder to themselves...
why is the world's
motto "keep at it"?
Why this steady striving
towards a goal?
Not slaves to time...
...they're carefree...
...having meetings with butterflies...
...and discussions with trees.
They spend time gathering the wind
and reading tales in raindrops...
. while painting a new world
on the canvas of the skies.
Why is the world's
motto "keep at it"?
Why this steady striving
towards a goal?
Quickly! - Madam, hurry up!
You're delaying us.
Come on... every day we're
late because of your boy.
We must also remember...
the old saying,
cleanliness is godliness.
On many occasions...
...while doing rounds, I have also found...
...that children don't keep the
school corridors clean.
It is our duty to keep our
school neat and tidy.
Unpolished shoes?
Out.
Turn to page 38, chapter
4, paragraph 3.
We're going to mark
adjectives today.
That goes for you as well,
Ishaan Awasthi.
Page 38, chapter 4, paragraph 3.
Can I have your attention, Ishaan?
I said, page 38, chapter
4, paragraph 3.
Read the first sentence and
point out the adjectives.
Page 38, Ishaan. Adit Lamba,
just help the boy.
The rest of you, look at your books.
Read the first sentence and
tell me all the adjectives.
Okay, let's mark the adjectives
together. Read the sentence for me.
Just read the sentence, Ishaan.
They're... dancing.
Speak in English.
The letters are dancing.
They're dancing, are they?
Then read the dancing letters.
Trying to be funny?
Read the sentence loud and proper!
I said loud and proper, Ishaan.
Loud and proper!
Stop it!
Stop it! Enough is enough!
Get out of my class!
Out!
You want to leave as well?
Who was laughing here?
Who wants to follow him?
I don't want to hear a titter in
my class. Look at your books.
Shameless boy.
Open your books.
Who's going to tell me what
the adjectives are?
I don't want a sound in this class.
Come on.
Punished again?
Why d'you get punished all the time?
This one's a regular.
Go in now.
Done your maths homework?
Got your test papers signed?
No?
Now, you're finished.
Yes, now you're gone.
A little sweet, a little sour.
A little close,
not too far.
All I need, all I need...
...all I need is...
...to be free.
It's close enough to touch...
...but disappears, like a mirage.
Woven of dreams, warm as a sweater...
...beyond the white clouds...
...is my world.
Let me in without a shout,
let me in, I have a doubt.
There are more, many more,
many more like me.
I'm not alone...
...dream walking, wide-eyed.
...stepping... stumbling.
I'm not alone, dream walking,
wide-eyed...
...stepping... stumbling.
Yet I have no doubt...
...just like the setting
sun will rise again...
...my world once revealed...
...will astound everyone.
Open eyed how I run, how I
run to the other side...
Then I glide like a bird,
I just want to be.
A thousand wings to fly...
...to explore open skies.
So many turns to take,
paths to follow...
...and discover... my world.
These few days of childhood...
...will never return.
So live it up now, my friend,
on credit, if you're broke.
Live it up.
Wash up, I'm serving dinner.
What's this?
Superb!
Done? Let's see.
What handwriting...
What's this,
every spelling wrong?
Table is "Tabl", then "Tabel"?
And "d" instead of "the"?
What is this? How many times
have we done this?
We went over this yesterday. How
can you forget so quickly?
Enough fooling around. You'll
fail again this year.
All your friends will move ahead.
Will you like that?
Concentrate, son.
Stop fooling and fix your spellings!
No.
What?
Brother...
Go to sleep.
No stories tonight, I'm tired.
Today I bunked school.
What?
I just walked out.
When?
After the first period.
Why?
I hadn't done my maths homework
nor my test papers signed.
Where did you go?
Nowhere, I just wandered the roads.
Roads? Alone?
No fear.
Look at your guts!
You know how dangerous that is?
Anything could've happened...
you could've had an accident,
or got kidnapped.
Papa's not at home too.
Idiot.
Did you tell Mom?
Shall I tell her?
- No, no.
Then?
Write me an absent-note, please?
What?
Absent-note.
No...
I'm not writing fake absent-notes.
Go to sleep, I'll
tell Mama tomorrow.
Dada, please
Absent-note, teacher.
How are you feeling?
99 degrees. Go
Children...
Surprise maths test
The marks on this test will count
in the final exam, so be careful.
Take one and pass the rest.
Here.
Fearless Captain Ishaan sets
out on mission impossible.
His mission... to take the third
planet from the Sun... Planet Earth...
and yank it "into" the ninth planet
in the solar system... Pluto.
Three into nine.
Goodness!
Scorching hot Mars will melt
Captain Ishaan's firm grip on Earth.
Saved!
Hi Jupiter... bye Jupiter!
Hi Saturn, having fun? Bye.
And now 3 gets ready to go into 9.
Pluto is destroyed!
It's no longer a planet.
Fearless Captain Ishaan has
discovered the answer.
3 X 9 equals 3.
Time up.
How did the test go?
No fear.
Thanks, Yohan.
Papa's back.
Papa, when did you come?
- Late last night, You were asleep.
Bye Papa. Bye Inu.
Bye
What did you get me?
That.
Strawberries?
And for Dada?
Same.
For both?
Wash them first.
Papa, aquarium.
Let's go to the aquarium today.
We're going to the aquarium
today, okay?
Maya, did Ishaan have
fever on Thursday?
No.
What's this absent-note?
I didn't write this note.
Come here.
Come here, right now!
What's this?
What's the meaning of this note?
Answer, or I'll give you
such a thrashing...
Don't look down...
Iook up... in my eyes.
And answer me.
Where the hell were you on Thursday?
Let me... where did you go, son?
- If not to school, then where?
Where, son?
Answer!
What's he saying?
- Bunk.
What?
You bunked school?
Bunked school and did what?
Where did you go?
Road.
What road? Which road? With whom?
Alone.
Alone? Are you out of your mind?
Are you out of your bloody mind?
Wandering the streets alone? Any
idea what could've happened?
What's going on? Did you hear that?
If he got lost, where'd
we go looking?
And who wrote this,
who wrote this absent-note?
You can't even write properly!
If you could write, you'd pass!
Who wrote this note?
- Tell me. Who?
This is the last time I'm asking you
Who wrote this absent-note?
Who wrote it? Speak up!
No improvement in class-work
or homework.
He's still where he was last year.
Books are still his enemies.
Reading and writing are
like punishment for him.
Sometimes his English handwriting
resembles Russian.
Repeats his mistakes on purpose,
never pays attention in class.
All the time asking for permission
to go to the toilet.
I'm thirsty, I want
to go to the toilet
Disturbs the whole class
with his silly pranks.
You must've seen his test papers?
Zeroes in all subjects.
You sent his test papers?
Last Wednesday, for parents'
signatures. They never came back.
They were a sight, I
tell you Mrs. Awasthi.
In fact, I sent a letter
specially to meet you
Look at this maths test.
Three into nine equals
three. That's all.
Not another question answered.
No one will believe
he's Yohan's brother.
Mr. Awasthi...
- Yes?
This is your son's second
year in third grade.
At this rate, I won't be
able to help you anymore.
Maybe he has a problem.
What do you mean?
Perhaps, he...
Some children are less fortunate.
For them, there are special schools.
Clear out, get out of my way!
Worthless brats!
She thinks my son is a retard.
She thinks my son is abnormal.
Sixty kids stuffed into a class...
...how can a teacher give
attention to each?
Nonsense!
What haven't I done?
I sacrificed my career
for the children.
It's a daily struggle
to get him to study.
No Maya, it's not your fault.
He needs something else.
I'll be there in the morning.
Thank you very much. Good night.
Done
But... in mid-term?
Suresh's uncle is the school's
founder trustee.
I'll pay the fees tomorrow.
No, I won't go!
Shut up and eat your dinner!
"Won't go."
Let's wait till next year...
He has never stayed away from me.
He'll have to learn.
You heard the principal.
Next year, she'll throw him out.
Then where do we go?
Look... Iook at him glaring.
No bloody regret on his face
Out there they'll beat
you into shape.
He got Yohan to write
that note. What next?
Trust me, I'm his father.
We can't afford it, but
we'll manage somehow.
Term begins after Diwali.
Please, don't send me away.
I won't go to boarding school.
I don't want to go.
Please tell Papa. I don't want
to go to boarding school.
Hush.
Yes... wake up.
Mama?
I'm right here.
I don't want to go
to boarding school.
You have to.
I don't want to go.
It's a nice school.
- I don't want to be sent there.
I'm knowing, I'm trying, see...
Really, I know it all.
I can learn more.
I won't even ask for fireworks.
I won't celebrate Diwali.
But I don't want to go
to boarding school.
No fireworks this year? Scared
of going to boarding school?
Admit it.
- I'm not afraid.
You're afraid, I know.
I'm not afraid!
- You're afraid, I know it.
I'm not afraid.
He's crazy!
I won't go!
Your father tells me
you're very stubborn.
Let's get one thing straight.
In this boarding school,
we live by one rule.
Discipline
Don't worry, Mr. Awasthi.
Here we've broken
the wildest horses.
Come on, we're getting late.
Done? Come on, child.
I've never told you,
how scared I am of the dark.
how much I care for you.
Get changed for dinner.
But you know, don't you, Ma?
You know everything...
...my Ma.
Don't leave me alone in crowds...
...l'll lose my way back home.
Don't send me to places far away...
...where you won't even remember me.
Am I so bad, Ma?
Am I so bad...
You haven't changed yet? Come
on, change your clothes.
Come on.
Nine o'clock. Lights out.
Good night, sir.
When sometimes, Papa swings me.
...too high in the air...
...my eyes search for you...
...hoping you'll come
and hold me safe.
I don't tell him...
...but I get petrified.
I don't let it show...
...but my heart sinks.
You know everything, don't you Ma?
You know everything...
...my Ma.
You aren't dressed for class yet?
Look at your tie. Didn't
Mummy teach you anything?
Boys,
this is Ishaan Nandkishore Awasthi.
Step forward... come on.
With your bag.
From now on, your place is here,
in front of my eyes,
beside Rajan Damodaran.
Rajan Damodaran always
comes first in class.
His company will have a good
effect on you, I hope.
Understand? Sit down.
Today's subject, interpretation
of poetry.
Page 28, "Perspective".
Rajan Damodaran, you
will recite the poem,
and Ishaan Nandkishore Awasthi,
you will interpret it.
Right?
Proceed, Rajan.
"Perspective"
"When I look from above, you are..."
"a cloud-filled piece of sky."
Until a thirsty elephant comes
by, or my friends jump in,
or a bicycle bell,
or a pebble or two...
...or even a blind man's
cane will do.
Then the picture dissolves and
you become our river again.
Excellent!
Now explain the meaning of the poem.
What we see, we feel is...
And what we don't see, we feel isn't.
But sometimes...
...what we see, actually isn't. And...
what we don't see...
...actually is. I mean...
What's all this..."is
- isn't"?
Minu Patel, you explain.
The poet says, when
he sees the river...
...he sees the sky in it.
Using different objects, he
demolishes the reflection.
And then we realise it's a river.
Good. Very good. Minu
Patel, sit down.
You explained the true
meaning of the poem.
Others just said what they crammed.
Tiwari-sir is very strict.
So remember what he says,
and just parrot it.
How come you joined in
the middle of the term?
My father, he...
Come on... art class.
You always come first in class, so
why did your parents send you here?
Meaning?
I mean, why did they send
you here to punish you?
I'm not a boarder. My father is
the school's estate manager.
I live in the staff quarters,
with my parents.
And who told you everyone's
sent here to be punished?
Children, open your sketchbooks
And take out your pencils
Without using a ruler,
copy the shapes.
The lines must be perfectly straight,
or five raps on your knuckles.
Hey, new boy.
Eyes on the blackboard. Show us...
...where did I make the dot?
Show us the dot.
Why are you staring like a frog?
Don't laugh
Where did I make the dot?
Show us.
I don't see it.
You don't see it?
Satyajit Bhatkal...
- Yes sir?
Come here and show him where I made
the point on the blackboard.
Now you see?
Very good.
Step forward.
Quickly.
Five raps on your knuckles, so
your attention never wanders.
Put out your hand.
Clench your fist.
Get on with your still life study.
I want perfect shapes. Otherwise,
five on the other hand.
Go!
Forward march!
Left, right, left... left,
right, left.
What are you doing?
Halt
You're ruining the marching order.
Out.
A noun is a naming word, a pronoun
is used instead of a noun
An adjective describes a noun, a
verb describes the action of a noun
An adverb describes the
action of a verb...
...a conjunction joins
two sentences
A preposition describes
the relationship...
...between a noun and a pronoun
And an interjection is a word
thrown in to express feeling
Have you got it, Mr. Ishaan
Nandkishore Awasthi?
Why?
Why can't you?
Idiot
What's the problem?
Why are you so dumb?
Why zeroes in math?
And punishment daily?
Grammar pathetic, spelling
all wrong!
Are you tripping?!
Idiot.
- Hey duffer!
Lazy!
- Crazy!
Garbled sentences...
...and answers all wrong?
Why don't you try?
You're a failure...
...your handwriting is terrible,
homework incomplete...
...why's your attention adrift?
Why?"
Idiot... duffer... lazy... crazy.
This child can drive anybody mad.
Someone please call up his dad.
What's your problem, son?
King of the Morons!
Awful scores...
...dreadful results.
Geography makes you dizzy?
Answer me, answer me!
Five on the knuckles!
Ishaan, open the door
Open up. Your Dada is here too.
Talk to him.
Inu... champ, open the door
Please open the door.
What is it, champ?
Let's go.
I've taken permission
from the house master.
Don't be angry anymore.
Come... come along, son.
One extra mattress, please.
See what I got you. Water colours.
24-colour pack
Hit it when it rises... excellent!
Stay focused... good Yohan!
My eyes are empty...
...tears too have left me.
Silence fills my heart.
I feel pain no more, I'm numb.
All feeling has left me, I'm empty.
You know everything...
...don't you, Ma?
What are you up to?
What are you doing? Get down!
Why did you climb up there?
Come... we're late.
What's the matter?
Oh, don't you know?
Holkar-sir is gone...
to teach all of New
Zealand how to draw.
We've got a new temporary teacher.
I hope he's different
from Holkar-sir.
Come, we're late. Oh, come on.
Look there, is that a tree?
Or a man covered by a cape?
Is it raining? Or has the sky...
left the taps on by mistake?
The world is what you make of it...
...it's in the eye of the beholder.
So free your mind...
...spread your wings...
...let the colours fly...
Come on, let's spin new dreams!
Shake it!
Swing-a-long!
Shake a leg!
It's fun!
Swing-a-long, shake a leg,
have lots of fun...
Who says fish don't fly?
Ever thought of it?
Does the sun bathe everyday?
Or does he just wet his hair
and pretend to be clean?
These stars... are they twinkling?
Or in anger, grumbling
at each other?
So free your mind...
...spread your wings...
...let the colours fly...
Come on, let's spin new dreams!
Why cram until your head is full?
Head is full, head is full!
In a blink, your mind goes blank!
Mind goes blank, mind goes blank!
Go ahead, unlock the doors...
Unlock the doors, unlock the doors!
And fearlessly, take wing!
Take wing, take wing!
I'm with you...
- I'm with you!
You're with me...
- You're with me!
You and me, let's all together...
...swing-a-long...
...shake a leg...
...let's have lots of fun!
Why is the world so colourful?
Ever wondered?
Lmagine...
Choosing these colours so lovingly...
...someone has decorated
this world with them.
So beautiful is our universe...
I suspect its creator
is surely an artist.
So free your mind...
...spread your wings...
...let the colours fly!
Come on, come on...
...let's spin new dreams!
Here's one for each of you.
Draw, paint, do whatever you like...
...while I put this away.
But what do we paint, sir?
There's nothing on the table.
This table?
This table is too small for
your beautiful imagination.
Peek into your mind...
...and pull out an image...
...then slap it onto the paper!
Have fun. In here, you're free.
Lost somewhere, friend?
Looking for inspiration?
No problem, there's no hurry.
What is the matter, child?
Don't you like painting?
What's your name, son?
Sir, his name is Ishaan Awasthi.
Where have you been?
Your mother called.
Wait by the phone.
She'll call again.
Is Ishaan there?
Yes one moment, he's here.
Here.
Say hello, son.
Look Inu...
we can't come on Saturday.
On Sunday, Dada has his
inter-school tennis finals.
I know you're very angry with Mama.
Mama is very bad.
I'm very sorry, Inu.
But what can Mama do?
Dada is very tense about
the final match.
Will you talk to Dada?
Here, talk to Dada.
And wish him all the best.
Inu, are you there?
I'll miss you at the finals.
Son, talk to Mama.
He's left.
He left?
- Yes.
Sorry.
What happened?
He didn't say a word.
Don't worry, we'll go next Sunday.
What are you putting in there?
The kids' class-work.
So what? Holkar never used that
space. It's meant for books.
So where do I keep these?
Return them to the boys.
What use are they anyway?
What a racket they're making
in your class, Nikumbh.
Like a fish market.
They're kids, it's natural.
And if kids don't express emotions
in an art class, where will they?
That may be, but go easy. The
headmaster likes discipline.
I believe you sang in class
yesterday and played a flute?
Yes I sang, played a flute...
kids happy, I'm happy.
But our students aren't
like those kids.
What do you mean?
You teach in Tulips School,
don't you...
mentally retarded, abnormal kids?
In those schools, experiment all you
like, what difference will it make?
They have no future, anyway.
No seriously, Nikumbh.
This is a formal school.
Your singing-dancing style
won't work here.
Here, we prepare children
for life's race.
Kids have to compete, succeed,
make a future.
Our school's motto is...
"Order, Discipline, Labour".
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from OpenSubtitles.org