One will do for you two.
Ah, here we are.
Some more of those there.
- Hello, Max. Still at it?
- Yeah, still at it.
This paper, what does it mean?
It's a campaign for nuclear disarmament.
It's a "Ban the bomb" march.
- I see, that's nice.
- Nice?
- Yeah, you must be foreigner, eh?
- Yes, I am from Austria.
Oh. Now, let me see.
In Deutsch that's...
Der Marsch gegen der atomisch Bomber.
Ach, natürlich.
You speak German well.
I wish I did.
I'm studying it at night school.
I take lessons also.
Look, we got people from all countries
going on this march.
Why don't you come with us?
It's a protest to
stop them making the bomb.
- It is difficult for me.
- Look, you don't have to decide now.
I would have to ask.
I'm with a family, an Au pair.
Well, look, think about it.
I've got to be going.
Must... You must leave?
Well, I've got to get rid of this lot
and I'm late already.
You know, I've got an idea.
We could help each other.
With the languages, I mean.
You know, we could teach one another.
Yes, but my English is so bad.
Oh, that don't matter.
- Are you doing anything tonight?
- I was going to a club in Bayswater.
It's very nice. You can dance
and all the foreign students go there.
- Yeah, I'll bet it's for members only.
- Not if you’re invited.
- I'll be there at 9:00.
- Oh, I don't know about dancing.
I ain't much good at this twisting lark.
Oh, you have to be a contortionist.
Oh, look, come on.
Look.
Max, listen to the music.
Listen to it? It's deafening me.
Look, pretend you're drying your back
with a towel.
- That's it, swing the hips.
- Yes.
That's it.
Oh, that's all right, 'innit?
- Ta.
- Thank you.
- I told you I don't dance.
- Max, now you're angry.
You're so serious, but I like it.
Well, I'm not a playboy
if that's what you mean.
Well, what with working
at the library all day
and evening class at night,
it don't leave much time for dancing.
Tell me about your job.
Oh, I told you
I work at the public library, don't I?
- You work so hard.
- I like books.
I do a lot of reading on the side.
Technical writer,
that's what I want to be.
Yeah, we got
a foreign languages section, too.
Goethe, Schiller, Thomas Mann.
We had them at school in Austria.
My father reads Schiller.
You're lucky. My old man don't read
anything but the newspapers.
And then that's just
to see what's on television.
You live at home?
What? It's like bloody Coronation Street
down there.
No, I got out
as soon as I got me first job.
You quarreled with your parents?
Oh, no, we didn't quarrel.
No, I just had to get out of that place.
You see, we didn't
talk the same language.
Here, tell me.
What do the Austrians think of Hitler?
- Oh...
- May I?
- Please.
- Please yourself.
Thank you.
- You're German, aren't you?
- No, from Austria.
Oh, it's near enough.
They all little darlings like you?
Oh.
- Who is the boyfriend?
- Oh, that's Max.
Oh, is he "the" boyfriend?
Well, he's very nice.
Oh, I don't think he's exactly
mad about me, somehow.
- What's your name?
- Eva.
- A very pretty name.
- Thank you.
Mine's Elliot.
- Max taking you to supper?
- No, he didn't say so.
Well, he's missed his chance then,
hasn't he?
- You know the Maroc?
- What's that?
Well, it's a nightclub.
- I've never been to a real nightclub.
- Oh.
Where I come from
there are no nightclubs.
What are we waiting for?
I would like to. No I can't,
not tonight, I invited Max.
Tomorrow then?
Um...
- I'll have to ask.
- What? Max?
- No, the family I am with.
- Oh.
Ring me up, Flaxman, 83-22.
Flaxman, 83-22.
Right, I'll phone you.
Tell me, what do the Austrians
think about Hitler?
- Thank you.
- That's all right.
Thank you.
- Enjoy it?
- Yes.
You have to go to bed now.
Eva, there's a telephone call for you.
Oh!
It's all right. I'll look after him.
Thank you, Mrs Millar.
Come on.
It's time you're in bed, isn't it?
Yes, please. Elliot.
Tonight? I don't know.
One moment, please.
- Mr Millar.
- Yes, Eva?
It's Elliot.
He has tickets for the theatre.
Do you think Mrs Millar
would mind if I went out tonight?
Well, that's the third time
you've been out with him this week.
- I suppose it's all right.
- Thank you.
Elliot, it's all right.
Yes, I'll be ready.
See you soon. Bye.
- Eva and her boyfriends.
- Oh, it's natural, I suppose.
Wouldn't mind dating her myself.
I wonder what you'd find to talk about.
I wonder what any of them do.
This Elliot she's been going out with
sounds quite intelligent.
And Max works in a library.
Didn't she have a date with Max tonight?
Yes, she did.
Going to be a bit of a mix-up
if they arrive at the same time.
That's just like Eva.
Absolutely nothing up here.
- Would you like a drink, darling?
- No, not just now.
Still, one can't help liking her.
And Nicholas adores her.
Yes, but she's
a bit of a responsibility.
I'm damn sure she couldn't
go out like that at home.
At home? She has to be in by 10 o'clock.
She said so.
Anyway, I've told her.
All these young men
she's going out with
are only after one thing.
Enjoying yourself?
- Like anything else?
- I'm completely fed up.
Oh, I hope not.
Waiter.
- Liqueur, sir?
- Yes.
What would you like, darling?
Cognac, Tia Maria, something like that?
Elliot, you know I don't drink.
You already had some wine.
A little, and only because
you ordered Liebfraumilch.
Oh, come on, have something.
This is a celebration.
Please, no.
- I'll have a large brandy and coffee.
- For two, sir?
- Yes, for two.
- Thank you.
It's cabaret time
at the Latin Quarter.
To open our show tonight
we have pleasure in presenting
the fabulous Margo.
Elliot, why is it a celebration?
Oh. For us.
For you and me.
You know, Eva,
in my business, advertising,
there's so much insincerity.
Everybody's always trying
to sell, sell, sell.
That's why it means so much
to meet a girl like you.
- Why me?
- Because you're so direct.
Because you always say
exactly what you mean.
You like that? I'm not clever enough
to say anything else.
You're very, very sweet.
Why you are not married,
a handsome man like you?
There you go.
- Tell me, why?
- Big question.
You are divorced?
No, I suppose
I never met the right girl.
There was a girl once. We were engaged.
- Or as good as.
- And?
She met a man she liked better.
Well, after that, it rather finished me
for that sort of thing.
But that's terrible.
You ought to have a house and children
and someone to look after you.
Oh, feel like taking me on?
Well, I'm too much of an old bachelor
for the patter of tiny feet,
nappies hanging on the line.
- You like children, don't you?
- I love them.
When I marry I'm going to have six.
Are you, indeed? That's a warning.
I tell you what. Let's finish here
and go back to my place for coffee.
Elliot, I can't.
It's late and I promised Mrs Millar.
Oh, what's it to do with her?
They treat you as though
you were still in pigtails.
It isn't that. Elliot, no.
What is it then, Eva?
Because you have been so kind to me,
taking me out,
and it's wonderful being with you.
And I don't know what I shall do.
Now you look just like a little boy.
I've never been with a man.
Oh, now look, just don't worry.
Waiter! Bill.
- Oh, leave those for the morning.
- All right.
- Will you lock up?
- Yes.
I say, Eva's a bit late, isn't she?
I expect she'll look
like death warmed up again tomorrow.
Eva!
- Can we do it again?
- Yeah, of course.
Eva!
Off you go.
Hey. It's me afternoon off.
I thought I'd find you here.
I've been ringing you
for the past fortnight.
They said you'd ring me at the library.
Um, Mrs Millar must have forgotten.
Like you forgot our date, remember?
Eva!
Okay, but be careful.
Look, if you don't want
to go out with me
you've only got to say so,
I can take the hint.
But, Max, I do.
Oh, it's starting to rain again.
I must get Nicholas home.
- Look, I only came to remind you.
- Remind me?
Well, it's next weekend.
You said you was coming
on the march, from Aldermaston.
"Ban the bomb", that's right.
So, what, are you coming?
It'll do you good
to get out in the country.
- Nicholas, come along!
- Look, there's a crowd of us going.
The special leaves Paddington,
7:30, Friday night.
I can meet you
at the station if you like.
Max, I'll see.
I promise.
Ring me tonight and cheer up. Nicholas.
Ban the bomb, join the march!
I told you, you shouldn't have
worn daft shoes like that.
You told me we were taking a train.
Only to Didcot.
This is a demonstration, not a picnic.
Look, we're stopping for lunch
in three-quarters of an hour.
Three-quarters of an hour.
Come on. Come on.
The march is now 10,000 strong.
All right,
I'll go along with you on that.
Greece at the time of Pericles
was more civilised than we are now.
People will confuse
material progress with civilisation.
Yeah, but you see,
the Greek civilisation
was based on slavery,
and you can't call that democracy.
Plato didn't believe in democracy.
Oh, you can't blame him
when you look around today.
- Hello, Ted.
- Hello, Max.
Eh, this is Eva, she comes from Austria.
- Hello.
- Hi.
These are friends of mine.
- Ted works at the library.
- I'm so thirsty.
- Hi.
Oh.
I believe they are
starting up in Austria.
Please?
He means the campaign against H weapons.
Oh, it's time, isn't it?
Nothing personal,
but it was Hitler that started it all.
It was no more Hitler
than you or me.
The bomb was a historical necessity.
Given the scientific know-how,
the productive capacity...
But Hitler was the catalyst.
Oh, I'm not blaming him any more
than the Americans or the Russians
or ourselves, come to that.
- Do you talk about these things at home?
- Please?
Like giving the Wehrmacht
nuclear weapons?
What the Wehrmacht do I don't know.
We don't like the Germans in Austria.
Max, do you have a shilling?
I would like to have another coke.
Yeah, I'll go.
No, you stay here with your friends.
We walked so much.
How'd you like to go to war with that?
If she's representative of
the post-war generation, God help us.
She's only 18,
only been here a couple of months.
Have you made the grade yet?
Going steady with her, aren't I?
When? Haven't missed you
in night school.
What's all this talk of going out
steady, anyway? Where will that get you?
You get married, you settle down.
Then kids come along.
Some bloody brass hat
presses a button and boom!
That's the sort of mess
we're trying to clear up, innit?
Look, we all know that sex
is a physiological need,
but why be so sanctimonious about it?
Unless someone had, you wouldn't
be here to talk about it, would you?
Anyway,
who said anything about marrying?
Oh, no. Max is a regular Don Juan.
You know what I found him doing
the other day in the library?
Lay off it, Ted.
Mugging up a book
on the technique of sex.
Time we turned in, ain't it?
- Here?
- Well, where do you think?
I keep telling you,
this ain't a luxury tour.
Well, look, we can
take a look around if you like.
What about this? It's all right, innit?
Put your bed out and we're away.
- Make yourself comfortable now.
- But how about you?
I'll be all right.
I'll kip over there.
That is, unless you'd like me
to sleep outside?
- Max.
- Make yourself comfortable, okay?
- Look, we've got to get some sleep
we've got a long way to go tomorrow.
You're so uncomfortable. Max, come here.
- It isn't that I don't like you.
- Then what is it?
I don't exactly sleep around myself.
- No, Max.
- Why not?
Because it isn't possible.
Please, try to understand.
Oh, I get it. Never been
with a man before, that's it, innit?
Max, please.
There's a dictionary in my bag.
Dictionary?
Oh, I get it. I know about women.
That's all right.
Good night, Eva.
The march is now assembling.
The march is now assembling,
and we'll be moving on
at 9:30 precisely.
These are your positions and
will you please follow them carefully.
- At the front...
- Hello, Max, where did you disappear to?
- Hello fellas.
- Have a good night?
- Oh, you know.
- Where's the glamour girl this morning?
She's about.
Max, Max, I just heard.
We're not even halfway to London.
But I told you, love,
tonight we stop at Slough,
Sunday we move on to Acton...
- No, Max.
- You mean you're packing it in?
I can't, not another three days.
What's all this, then, trouble?
Look, you stay out of this.
She's going to make
a damn fool of me if she backs down now.
Oh, come on, Max.
She's not exactly dressed for hiking.
She's had a rough night.
She came on this because
she wanted to, didn't she?
Well, you might have explained...
Well, Eva can do
what she bloody well pleases,
I couldn't care less.
He gets like this.
Look, if I was you,
I'd take the bus back to town.
- He's so upset.
- Oh, Max'll get over it.
I'll stake you for the fare.
There's a bus stop just down the road.
Come on, I'll show you.
- Would you like a lift?
- Oh, yes, please.
- Where are you going?
- Well, London.
Then hop in.
I lost the bus.
Lucky I was passing.
I'm so untidy. I was with the marchers.
You were? Hard on the feet.
Go on, take your shoes off.
Not what you've been marching in,
are they?
It was a big mistake.
'Cause I agree
with this "ban the bomb" crowd.
It's absolute lunacy,
testing and things,
poisoning the atmosphere.
But if the other lot have them,
what can we do?
I mean, I'm damn sure they don't
allow marches over there.
- Are you a racing driver?
- No, strictly amateur.
I've always liked messing about
with motor cars.
My father gave me this
for my 21st birthday.
What is that number painted on the side?
That. I was over at Brands Hatch
on Saturday.
You mean racing? Did you win?
No, I came a bad sixth.
Look, if I'm going too fast for you
just tell me.
I love it. It's exciting.
- Give my love to Nicholas.
- I will. Thank you very much.
Glad to help out.
We must meet again sometime.
I usually go to La Bazura
in the evenings.
- La Bazura?
- Yes.
It's a club in Bayswater
for foreign students.
Must look in sometime.
Bye, Eva. It's been fun.
Bye, Keith.
Hi. Sorry, Janet.
He went rambling up about metallic
fatigue and the theory of structure.
- I just couldn't get a word in.
- That's all right.
Hey, wait a sec.
My lecturer's still away on holiday.
Did you enjoy your weekend?
Did the car go well?
All right, the valves need fixing.
- Like a coffee?
- Hmm.
Picked up a smashing blonde
on the way home.
- Oh, yes?
- Oh, nothing.
She was just a refugee from
the "ban the bomb" march.
I gave her a lift.
- How about you?
- Oh, you know. I gave Mum a hand.
I tried to get on with my French thesis.
Dad was gardening.
As if you didn't know.
I've been thinking.
I want to talk to him, Janet.
- But what about?
- We've got to have it out with him.
- Why now, so suddenly?
- Suddenly?
- Janet, you've said you'll marry me.
- Yes, when you've finished your degree.
What difference does that make?
You know how my parents feel about you.
They'll help us
till I begin with the firm.
No, my father feels differently.
I told you he came up the hard way.
He started off as ordinary porter
at King's Cross.
And now he's a traffic manager. So what?
I'm sorry, Janet. I admire him for that.
You know I do.
But what's that to do with us?
All right, Keith. You talk to him.
But don't say I didn't warn you.
If it's the money side
that's bothering you, Mr Bates,
you needn't worry.
My parents will look after that.
Your dad could have all the dough
in the world. And probably has.
But it's your future I'm worried about.
How I look at it,
a young man should stand
on his own feet.
You've a fine career in front of you
and I don't want to see you spoil it.
Mr Bates, it's always been understood
that I'm going into
my father's business.
Yes, once you've got
your engineering degree.
It won't help your studies
to have a wife on your hands.
Too many other things to think about.
But a couple of blokes in my year
are married already.
- Things have changed.
- Good luck to them.
But I still say, one thing at a time.
I never went to college, Keith.
But I do know a thing or two
about marriage.
How long do you need
before you finish your course?
Eighteen months,
if I pass my exams in June.
Just if. And if not?
Another year.
Well, Janet can do
what she likes once she's 21.
Though I still hope she takes my advice.
Don't get me wrong,
you two have been going out together.
And Janet's mother and I
would like to see you getting married.
Eighteen months isn't too long to wait.
She's worth it, isn't she?
Don't take it too hard, son.
Talk it over with Janet.
- I told you, Keith.
- What does he know about it anyway?
Oh, I hope you didn't say that to Dad.
Honey, when he was young,
people didn't have
six-year degree courses.
It's not natural to wait so long.
Poor old Dad, he never had
the chance to take a degree.
- They scraped to send me to university.
- What's it to do with us?
They had to wait, too. He was earning
30 bob a week at your age.
It's all so bloody silly
when there is no money problem.
- What had he to say to that?
- Oh, you know.
"Hard work never did anyone any harm"
and all that stuff.
- You must have thought about it.
- Thought about what?
Well, sex.
It's not natural for two people
to see each other
as much as we do without...
Oh, it's all so stuffy and suburban.
- But I'm a suburban girl, Keith.
- No, you're not, Janet.
- I didn't mean it like that.
- Then what did you mean?
Look, I'm not that kind of girl
and you wouldn't respect me
for it if I was.
And you needn't be
so damn smug and prissy about it.
Oh, I never knew it was prissy
to wait until you were married
before sleeping with a man.
But I've asked you to marry me.
I've gone down on my hands and knees!
- Of course, if you can't wait...
- You speak just like your father.
What you don't understand is
it's so much easier for a woman
than it is for a man.
Is it? Who put that into your head?
Look, I've done my best.
But I'm damned if I'm gonna submit
to your family's views
on love and marriage.
They're out of the ark.
If you feel like that,
there's nothing I can say.
- I thought you'd forgotten.
- Of course not. I've been very tied up.
- I was just passing by...
- Oh, yes. And you know something?
I was looking for you every night.
- How's Nicholas?
- Nicholas is fine.
Aren't you going to ask me for a dance?
In England, the man usually asks,
but let's go.
It's a bit hot in here.
Is it always like this?
Keith, there's a wonderful
party tonight.
- Really?
- Hmm. It's in the country.
It wouldn't take long to drive.
- But I haven't been invited.
- Doesn't matter. Everyone is invited.
- We're all going.
- Some party. I don't know about tonight.
I mean, if it's in the country,
it'll be all night.
- And what about Nicholas?
- Oh, the Millars won't mind.
So long as I'm home in time
to get him up.
- How far is it?
- Let's see... Oh, Virginia would know.
- Virginia, where's the party?
- It's on the Thames at Weybridge.
- Are you both coming?
- I would love to. Hmm?
All right, let's go.
Jimmy, bring me a towel!
How about a swim?
Come on in. It's warm.
- But I haven't a swimsuit.
- Neither's she.
- There's music. What else do you want?
- Okay.
Right. Meet you here in two minutes.
- It's cold!
- Come on, Eva!
It is cold.
Come on, Eva.
- I must look a sight.
- You look wonderful.
What a crazy idea!
Lucky it's a warm night.
- Had enough? Want to go home?
- Soon. I would love a cigarette.
Thanks.
- No matches.
- Oh. It doesn't matter.
- You're not cold?
- No, I'm not.
Eva?
A kiss.
I must go now.
Anyway, you have plenty of time
for Nicholas.
Eva. There's something
I want you to know.
Tomorrow.
Eva?
Elliot! Oh, I didn't know you were back.
That's a lie.
You saw me well enough at the club.
- I can't talk now. I must go in.
- Oh, no, you don't.
Who was that? Oh, go on. Who was it?
- Hold on. Look, Eva, I had to go away.
- Yes. For two weeks.
All right! Two weeks.
It was a business trip.
I couldn't help it. I had to stay on.
Well, I wrote to you, didn't I?
Look, Eva. Doesn't anything
we did together, doesn't it...
Doesn't it mean anything to you?
- You know I liked going out.
- Oh, you liked going out. Is that all?
I thought I'd met someone
who was different.
But you were different.
You were unspoilt.
I enjoyed being with you.
But can I help it if someone young
comes along and I like him?
No, you can't help it.
You can't help a thing!
And I didn't go near a woman
the whole time I was away.
I lay awake at night
just thinking about you
like a 20-year-old kid.
And you don't give a damn
because you're another little tramp!
Elliot, I go in now... Don't...
- You're coming back with me.
- No!
Let me go!
No!
- All right, miss? Hold on.
- Yeah.
He got clean away. You feel all right?
You'd better come down to the station
with me and make a statement.
Now, take it easy, dear.
Come along, now.
There's a good boy. There's a nice boy.
Did you get a clear look at him?
Would you recognise him
if you saw him again?
He came from behind.
But you told the constable
that he stepped out of a side turning.
It was dark.
Are you quite certain
you've never met him before?
Look, I know you've had a fright.
I'm glad it was nothing more.
But if you know anything,
it's your duty to tell us.
In the interests of other women
as well as your own.
You haven't given us much to go on.
I'm sorry.
Very well. We shall have to book it,
- "Assault by person unknown."
- Can I go now?
Well, I can't force you
to do this. It's up to you.
But I'd like you to see
the police surgeon.
But I told you,
he didn't interfere with me.
All the same,
I think it would be sensible.
A matter of routine.
He's here now. It won't take a moment.
- I must get back.
- You'll be through in 10 minutes.
Good afternoon.
You're a new patient, aren't you?
- I brought this from the police surgeon.
- I see.
I don't know why he send me.
I expect he thought
you should have a check.
There's nothing to be frightened about.
Now, there are just one or two details
I should like.
First of all, your name and address.
Nobody will know. Treatment here
is absolutely confidential.
Once I've filled in your card,
I shall give you a number.
Then when you hear it called out,
you'll go straight in to the doctor.
Now, your name first.
Koenig. Eva Koenig.
And your address?
So, you've been suffering
from a sore throat and a rash.
It was nothing.
I've had sores all winter. But this...
A great many women contract
venereal disease without realising it.
Oh, please don't get upset.
The great thing is you came to see us.
Now, tell me about your boyfriends.
You do understand me?
- Where do you come from?
- Austria.
Oh, fascinating country.
I've spent holidays in the Tirol.
Now, I know these are intimate questions
but I need the details.
- Has there been more than one?
- Yes.
Now tell me about
your most recent boyfriend.
When did you first
have intercourse with him?
It only happened once,
and just two days ago.
I see.
Did either of you use contraceptives?
Did you know him well?
Have you got his name and address?
I only want to know
in case you have to trace him.
- I could find him.
- Very well.
Now, you said there'd been
a second friend. When was that?
It was some weeks ago.
Now, I'm going to take a little blood
so that we can make a test.
It isn't painful.
Just keep your arm steady.
Syphilis?
I told you already.
It's easy enough to pick up.
The main risk is for anyone
to have sex outside marriage.
We'll get you right. It's lucky
you came to us in the early stages.
You'll have to attend here regularly,
mind you.
A girlfriend of mine told me
they stick needles into you
and they expand like umbrellas.
Oh, come on now.
You'll have your penicillin daily
and in a fortnight,
the course will be completed.
After that you'll need periodic checks
for two years.
- When do I start?
- Now.
Oh, cheer up.
It's no worse than the blood test.
I'll take you through to Sister now.
But there's one other thing.
I want you to give one of these slips
to each of those boyfriends
you told me about.
- So that they come here for examination.
- Oh, must I?
You caught syphilis
from your first friend.
In all probability,
you've infected the other two.
Oh, no.
And the Millars.
Could I have given it to them?
I was coming to that.
Syphilis is normally passed on
by sexual intercourse.
But that rash of yours
means the disease has spread.
Chance infection could occur
if you were handling a child.
Nicholas. It's awful!
I don't say it's likely.
Now, I'll take you through to Sister
for your injection.
And after that you have a word with
the almoner. I'm sure she'll help you.
I know how you feel.
We've all done things without thinking
of the consequences to other people.
What am I to tell Mrs Millar?
They've been so kind to me.
It's up to you, Eva. We can't force you.
Don't you see? They'll send me
straight back to Austria.
And I can't face my father. I can't.
I can't promise anything,
but the Millars sound
sympathetic sort of people.
It's a child.
If I were you,
I'd make a clean breast of it.
Tell Mrs Millar to go to their family
doctor who can get a report from us.
Now that you're getting
regular injections,
there'll be no danger to Nicholas,
if that's what's worrying you.
- Um, I'll try.
- You do that.
Now, about these young men.
You say you can't contact
this first friend?
Eva, I've heard about the assault.
Are you certain you don't know the man
who attacked you?
I... I...
Nothing you say to me
will go outside these four walls.
Not even to the police?
I think it'd be sensible
for you to tell the police.
But as far as we're concerned, no,
not even to the police.
Yes. It was Elliot.
My first friend.
But I'm frightened,
frightened of what he'll do.
In that case,
you can send him the slip by post.
If I know his sort,
it won't be the first.
- You know his address?
- Yes.
Then we seem to be on the way
to settling our problems.
You'll see the other two
and speak to them?
I don't know where Keith lives.
I don't know anything about him.
Except he's wonderful.
But he'll ring me
or turn up at the club, I'm sure.
Keith.
- Hello, Janet.
- You've been avoiding me.
Well, after that row, I didn't think
you wanted to see me again.
Oh, you know that isn't true.
If two people can't have a row
without one of them going off
and sulking... Oh, come on now.
I've been thinking about you
all the time.
Well, maybe it was my fault.
I suppose
I must have sounded pretty smug.
Honestly, Keith,
the way you put it to me.
I behaved like a bloody fool.
I don't know what came over me.
Then what's the matter?
- Janet, it isn't that.
- What?
Well, after we quarreled,
I was feeling pretty fed up.
I went to a club.
You know that girl I told you about,
from Austria?
The blonde?
I'm sorry, Janet.
I'll never see her again.
Keith, you didn't...
Oh, Keith. Why did you have to tell me?
Oh, I suppose you were right.
I'd have been much unhappier
if you’d simply gone on
as if nothing had happened.
I must dash now.
Shall we go out tonight?
Yes, let's. Where?
Let's go to the pictures.
We'll go and see a sad film
and have a good cry.
- Fine.
- Bye.
Eva, I just don't know what to say!
Oh, I'll have to tell my husband.
Well, obviously we'll all
have to go to the doctor
first thing in the morning.
I did warn you.
If only you'd paid
the slightest attention to what I said.
- I'm sorry, Mrs Millar.
- It's a fine time to say you're sorry.
When I think of Nicholas...
Oh, it's all so loathsome.
I didn't know.
I didn't think I was harming anyone.
Oh, now come on, Eva.
At least you had the courage
to tell me straight out.
And you said they said at the clinic
that it wasn't very likely that...
There's your family to think about.
- Hello, Keith. Will you come in?
- Hello.
All right. Just to say hello.
You thought you were in for
a rough time with Dad, didn't you?
They've gone out for the evening.
Oh, well, that's a relief.
Fine way to start an evening.
Oh, I've got some new records.
You must hear them.
But if we’re going to the pictures...
Oh, let's not rush off to the pictures.
I haven't seen you for ages.
I'll fix us some supper.
That's if you could make do with
scrambled eggs or baked beans on toast.
Anything.
Then have a drink
while we make the big decision.
- Dad's got some beer on the ice.
- Beer's fine.
Difficult, aren't you?
Sorry, I'm on my best behaviour tonight.
If I'm gonna slave over a hot stove
for you, I'll just run up and change.
The beer's in the fridge. Help yourself.
Okay.
Janet?
Jan?
Are you there?
Janet.
You don't have to do that.
I want to.
I was wrong.
Everything you said was right.
- I nearly lost you.
- You never lost me.
I always wanted you.
- Even...
- And I want your children.
Keith, the lights.
Darling.
We must be careful. If I'd have known...
Darling, I knew.
Yeah, she gave me that form
a fortnight ago.
But I knew there was nothing
to worry about.
Oh, how?
Well, you see, I work in a library.
I looked it up in a medical dictionary.
I see.
Well, I knew I needn't worry.
After all, we didn't sleep together.
And if we did, I'd have taken
the necessary precautions.
I'm sorry to tell you that if you
have intercourse with a woman
suffering from venereal disease,
no precautions are safe.
Well, then, like I said,
that question don't arise.
But there was sexual contact?
If you can call it that.
You know how it is.
I petted her a bit. Kissed her.
- On the mouth?
- Yeah.
Then what decided you to come here?
Well, now that you mention it.
It was a sore I've got
just inside my mouth here.
Well, I mean nothing much.
But me neck's swollen a bit there.
Thought I might as well
come for a check.
- Let me see, please.
- Can't do any harm.
Open your mouth. Wider.
Hmm.
I'll be giving you
a thorough examination next door,
but unless I'm very mistaken,
that's a syphilitic sore on your lip.
She was so young and inexperienced.
Of course, I won't be seeing her again.
Won't catch me with that kind of girl.
Hello, Eva.
So you finished the course now?
Yes, I just had my last injection.
Sister told me to come back
in a month for a check.
You're staying as long as that?
The Millars are so kind.
At first they said I was to go home
after the injections, then...
They found they couldn't manage
without you.
How's the little boy?
How old did you say he was?
Half past three.
Half past...
Oh, you mean three and a half.
- My English.
- And he's well?
Yes, they are all well.
It was a false alarm.
Well, that's a relief.
Oh, by the way, I understand that
one of your friends has reported here
for treatment.
You did send off that letter?
To Elliot? Yes, the same afternoon.
By registered post like you said.
It's over a fortnight,
he ought to have had it,
or the post office
would have sent it back to you.
Well, in view of what he attempted
to do to you,
he's probably gone
for treatment elsewhere.
I tried to find...
I tried to find Keith.
I went to the club each evening.
I see. And he hasn't turned up?
- Or phoned you?
- Nothing.
I wish I could warn him.
I have no way.
I don't know his full name, anything.
Except that he's wonderful.
Well, don't worry too much.
Of course, if he does get in touch
with you... He sounds sensible.
If he has the infection,
he's probably seen a doctor.
I haven't walked so far for ages.
- Oh, it's been lovely, though.
- Yes.
I must put them in water
when I get back.
- Don't shut the lid, you'll kill them.
- They'll be all right.
- Keith?
- Yes.
I've been trying to tell you
all afternoon.
What is it?
Just...
I'm going to have a baby.
Are you sure? I mean sometimes...
Three months ago now, I missed twice.
And then I went to the doctor last week
and he sent me for a test.
I see.
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
There was nothing you could do,
you'd only have worried.
We both knew it was a risk,
but some people try for months with...
I don't regret it, do you?
Of course not. If you love someone,
you want their children.
Don't you see?
It was the only possible way
for us to get married,
with dad feeling like he did.
- Have you told them?
- Not yet.
We'll see them together
and get it over with.
Your father will be after me
with a shotgun.
- Please, take me home.
- I'm sorry, Janet, that wasn't funny.
I know I've been unfair to you.
After all you said to me about waiting.
I thought about it, night after night.
It just didn't seem any other way out.
I don't blame you.
If anyone's to blame, it's myself.
Don't worry, darling.
We'll see it through.
There's no point in putting it off.
- Will your father be in now?
- No, Keith, let me tell him
I forced this on you. I can see it now.
From now on I'll do the worrying.
Hello, may I speak
to Miss Koenig, please?
Please.
It's you. Quite a time.
You led me a regular dance, didn't you?
Never mind.
We won't say anything more about that.
I've been along for my medicine,
like a good boy.
I don't want to speak to you.
Mr Millar says you're not to ring.
You haven't been telling stories,
have you? Not to the police?
I didn't tell the police
anything about you.
There's a sensible girl.
I don't want to talk to you.
I'm going back to Austria
I ran into your boyfriend the other day.
Haven't been seeing him, have you?
- Hello?
- You mean Keith?
Yes, that's right, Keith Murray.
Small world, isn't it?
I told you I was in advertising.
We handle his fathers account.
Murray Construction.
I bumped into him at their offices.
With his fiancée.
- His fiancée?
- Yes, I thought you'd be interested.
Now, look, Eva, about us...
Keith.
I thought you were not coming.
Eva, what can I say?
I behaved very badly.
I should have rung you or something.
- How did you find my number?
- It doesn't matter.
Keith, I couldn't tell you
on the telephone.
Eva, what is it?
They told me to give it to you at once.
I didn't know how to find you.
I thought you would ring me.
"Kensington Hospital."
I don't get it.
They want you to go.
There's a special clinic.
They'll explain to you.
You see, there was someone else
and he was sick.
I didn't know about such things.
You know, the notices in toilets.
Oh, my God!
They give you injection.
Make you better soon.
There's no need for anyone to know.
No.
I didn't tell you I'm engaged.
I heard. A friend told me.
What you don't know is, she's pregnant.
- Oh, hello, Keith.
- Hello, Ruth.
- Have you come to see Roger?
- Yes.
- Well, come in, then.
- Thank you.
Hello, Tracy.
Haven't seen you for ages.
- You know, exams and everything.
- I have to congratulate you.
We read the announcement
in the local rag last week.
- Thanks.
- We met her, remember?
You're a very lucky young man.
Oh, that damn telephone.
The secretary is away this afternoon.
- Roger won't be too long.
- Don't worry about me.
- Hello, Keith. Nice to see you.
- Hello, Roger.
- Come on through.
- Thanks.
I was delighted to hear about
the engagement, Keith. Really delighted.
Roger, I think I'm in a hell of a mess.
Oh, what kind of mess?
I've just been handed this.
I see.
Well, suppose you tell me all about it.
I don't want you to think
I've been sleeping around.
Especially now.
It only happened once and
there were reasons for that.
Yes, I'm sure.
Look, I'll go to the clinic
if you think I should.
But I just wondered if there was
some way of checking privately.
Tell me, have you noticed any rash,
any spots on your genitals?
No, nothing.
Well, first of all
I'll give you an examination
and then I'll arrange for a blood test.
Hugh Price can do that for us.
If it should prove to be positive
I could, of course,
arrange to treat you privately.
But my advice would be to
take advantage of the clinic.
Anyway, lets get on
with the examination.
Hello?
Eva?
Are you alone?
Oh, it's you.
Elliot, stop it.
I won't listen, I won't!
What on earth's the matter with Eva?
Another of those obscene phone calls.
- Becoming a real menace.
- Him again.
He's got Eva really scared.
The man seems to have
some kind of obsession about her.
Well, we've got to do
something about this.
Do you think you could persuade her
to go to the police?
It would've saved a lot of trouble
if she had done it before.
Well, it's asking an awful lot
of the girl in her present state.
But I'll try.
Eva.
Oh, Miss Koenig.
I believe you have
some further information for us.
I was so frightened.
- I couldn't tell you.
- You think you could identify
the man who assaulted you?
I know him.
Why didn't you tell us this before?
It was some months ago now.
- What made you change your mind?
- Because he keeps phoning me.
It's not only myself, the Millars...
These telephone calls, are they abusive?
Does he threaten you?
He says such terrible things,
what he'll do to me.
Improper use of the telephone
is an offence.
There's no need to be frightened,
now that you've come to us.
Can I have his name, please?
Collier. Elliot Collier.
And do you know where he lives?
Yes, he has a flat.
Number 11, Alban Court,
in the King's Road.
Well, that's not too far away.
We'll soon put a stop to this.
Sergeant Davis, please.
Collier left that address
rather hurriedly, some weeks ago.
The day after the incident in the mews,
I expect.
We shall have to get
the Millars' permission
- to have their telephone monitored.
- Please?
Oh, it means that if anyone rings up,
we'll be listening.
And the next time Collier rings you,
keep him talking.
But you needn't listen
to what he has to say.
Just let him talk.
We need time for what we've got to do.
So at all costs, you must keep him
on the other end.
It may not be very pleasant.
Will you do it?
Yes, I will.
What I don't understand is how
I could've caught this without knowing?
You were unlucky.
There's usually a sore on the genitals,
but sometimes
it's no more than a pimple.
It doesn't hurt and it soon disappears.
Doesn't that mean it's cured?
No, it means that the infection has
entered on a more serious stage.
No one can be cured
of syphilis or gonorrhea
without professional medical treatment.
It never crossed my mind.
It rarely does.
Anyone who indulges in, shall we say,
casual intercourse,
would be well-advised to come in
for a regular check.
Especially if they’re
thinking of marriage.
I'll give it to her today.
- I don't know how I'm going to tell her.
- Well, if you'll go back
to waiting room now,
there are some further tests to be made.
- Doctor.
- Yes?
She'll be all right?
Oh, I see no reason why not,
provided she reports promptly.
After all, we don't know
that you infected her.
And the baby?
You say she's rather more than
two months pregnant?
Oh, the baby, too,
if we see her in time.
- Can I tell her that?
- You can.
But send her here soon,
that's the important thing.
Thank you, sir.
Yes?
- Am I disturbing you, Doctor?
- No, Sister, come in.
Makes you think.
That young fellow I just saw,
decent, well-educated young boy,
and he risks his marriage
through crass ignorance.
That, and a lack of moral sense.
Like you, I'd blame the parents
as much as anybody.
Young people should be told,
and told early.
There's a lot I'd like to tell these
young things who come sailing in here.
It's so often a matter of ignorance.
These latest figures. 140,000 new cases
a year, and most of them young people.
They should know what happens
when syphilis goes untreated.
Heart disease, paralysis with blindness,
insanity, stillbirths.
And with gonorrhea, sterility
in women and children born blind.
Mild enough diseases at the start.
But over the years
they take a terrible toll.
Listen, down the slope and past the hut.
I'll come with you if you like.
No. No, thank you.
Well, you'll see the notice,
"Special Clinic".
Thanks. It's a great help.
Janet, please don't take it like this.
I've never been to a doctor
to tell him I'm an unmarried mother
and that the man
who got me pregnant has VD.
I know.
- But we're over the worst.
- Are we?
You say it can't hurt the child
but I've read about cases.
Have you ever seen a mentally
deficient child? Because I have.
Janet, the doctor told me
it'll be all right.
This just doesn't happen to people
who respect their own bodies.
I feel so cheap, like a common tart.
We're over the worst of it.
Will you stop saying
we're over the worse of it!
I mean, we've told your parents
about having the baby.
There's no need for them to know
anything about this.
It doesn't make it any better
by hiding it.
You haven't told them?
No, I haven't.
It doesn't make me feel any better.
Look.
As soon as we're both in the clear,
I'm going straight
to the registry office
to arrange about getting married.
Just a few weeks now.
No, you're not, Keith.
There isn't going to be a marriage.
Eva, I think you'd better answer that.
Hello?
This is you-know-who.
Now, you listen to me.
Is someone there? I can hear music.
I was listening to the records.
Eva, are you still there?
Don't hang up on me.
Yes, I'm still here.
Yes, I heard you, Elliot.
Women Police. Sergeant Carnall speaking.
Oh, you have.
He's on the line now?
Have you traced the call?
Yes, of course I'll wait.
Call box, Chelsea Manor Street,
Embankment Inn.
Thanks a lot. I'll pass it on.
I've done nothing wrong!
Let me go!
You can't do this to me!
Hey, Max, remind you of someone?
- Should it?
- Well, it could be, couldn't it?
Hey, that girl really did
something to you, didn't she?
She taught me one thing.
No mucking about from now on.
The next girl I go out with
is going to be steady.
And when I get married
she's got to be a virgin.
Oh, come on,
don't take it so much to heart.
Oh, look, let's go.
We got to get cracking
if we’re gonna get rid of this lot.
- Miss Bates?
- Yes?
You don't know me, but...
Did Keith send you?
No. No, he had nothing to do with it.
Oh, well, come in then.
Thank you.
- Please sit down.
- Thank you.
I'm leaving for home tomorrow.
- You're going back?
- Yes.
I wanted to see you and say I was sorry.
Oh, it was his fault more than yours.
I didn't know
that he was engaged to you.
We weren't engaged then.
It was just something
that was understood.
Will it be all right? About the baby?
Well, I'll have to go back
for observation
and I'll be making blood tests
for a long time.
Well, you must know yourself.
- They say I'm all right.
- I'm so happy.
Have you seen Keith lately?
I phoned to say I was going home.
He would like to see you. He's so upset.
He's upset?
If he would like to see me...
Oh, why are men so stupid?
Janet!
- Oh, hello.
- We must talk.
Eva rang me. She told me what you said.
I mean, about the medical check.
And I suppose that makes
everything all right.
Of course it doesn't.
That's why I had to see you.
Look, I've spoken to my father.
The baby's my responsibility
as well as yours.
I don't want any money from you
or your father,
- if that's what you're getting at.
- You must be realistic.
We may not be millionaires,
but we'll manage.
- He'll be brought up at home.
- And later on?
I mean, you've got to face it,
your father isn't so young.
I'll get myself a job
as soon as I've finished at college.
I'm not as helpless
as you seem to think.
I never thought
you were helpless, Janet.
That wasn't why I asked you to marry me.
What will you call him?
You seem to think it'll be a him.
Keith, that isn't fair.
- I do have my feelings.
- So do I.
And you're not giving me a chance,
Janet.
Look, maybe you'll marry somebody else.
But the baby needs a father.
I'll never marry anybody else.
How could you be so cruel?
All this talk about money. Can't you see
it's not your money I want, it's you.
You said...
You shouldn't listen to what I say,
you ought to know how I feel.
Silly.
Well, if we're going to be unhappy,
we'd better be unhappy together,