The beautiful North woods.
Rest and relaxation.
Solid, but solid! Those trees. Those birds.
Those peace and quiet.
What a vacation spot!
Flatbush was never like this.
Nothing to do but sleep.
I'm going to pound my ear for a week.
It sends me right down to
my bobby socks.
Woodpeckers. What a cheerful sound!
That ain't no woodpecker.
What gives here?
A lumber jackson. One of the local yokels.
I'll fix that icky!
You don't have to
fly off the handle like that.
This is going to be a tough job.
Calls for a whole flock of axes.
Flock of axes? This calls for real strategy.
This oughta do it!
Doggone it!
Hold it, stupid!
So you're the one behind all this.
Read, fat boy!
You vex me, you understand?
Cease that chop-chop, chubby!
Blow, Joe. Hit the road.
I'm going to get me a little shuteye.
And so are you. Now scram, ham!
I guess I fixed that square for fair.
"Paper Boy in the sixth."
Some guys don't never learn.
What a charming chapeau.
Toodle-oo, Myrtle.
Doggone squirrel!
Wait right here, pork chop. Don't go away.
Bon voyage, tubby.
I thought you'd never get here.
Which way did they go?
They went that-a-way, Sheriff.
You can head them off at the pass.
Wait a minute.
That little doggone...
And that is that. So, to bed.
I'm not so stupid.
I see you, you little varmint!
You're just a bundle of nerves, butterball.
You need a vacation worse than I do.
You rat in squirrel's clothing!
I'll fix you.
I'll kill two birds with one stone.
I'll blow up the tree
and get rid of that doggone squirrel, too.
"Paper Boy in the sixth!"
English