[RANK GONG]
[CHURCH BELLS RINGING]
[CROWD SINGING "AULD LANG SYNE"]
[CROWD LAUGHING AND SHOUTING]
[BAND PLAYS "AULD LANG SYNE"]
[CROWD CLAPS AND CHEERS]
[BAND PLAYS DANCE MUSIC]
Ah!
Now, this I CAN do, so
don't mess it about.
The moment of truth...
...I married a square!
A happy New Year, doctor.
Same to you.
Aha!
Even squares have their moments.
She's cute.
She's a nurse.
So was I - and look what
happened to me!
Well, in those days...
...a marriage licence only cost
about two pounds.
That's a real bargain!
That's nearly six times more
than a dog licence.
- That's a fascinating thought.
- Exactly.
- So don't knock it.
- No, no.
Just supposing your decision had...
...gone the other way?
You might have been here tonight
Cha-Cha-ing with a great dane.
Well... at today's prices!
Oh, shut up...
...and buy me another drink
before we go.
Who said we were going?
Well, darling, we have got the...
- ...car and the ferry by ten.
- Supposing we...
...started out from here?
Wouldn't be so terrible would it?
Well, no... I just...
- ...thought that---
- Look, I'm on holiday, Julie.
No more surgery for two
weeks, so let's stop...
...planning, eh? Just for tonight.
Let's unwind a bit.
Hmm.
Ah, two gin and tonics.
Yes, sir.
Was I being Nurse Nightingale?
You were being all the
things I ought to be.
Sensible, logical, organised.
In other words a dull drab!
Well, if you're discussing...
- ...me I'll leave... waiter!
- Doctor Radley...
...as Resident Medical Officer...
...what is your diagnosis...
...of a wife who tries to put her...
...husband to bed on...
- ...New Year's Eve?
- I'm all for it!
As long as she stays here!
Nice to feel wanted!
- What are you drinking, Jim?
- Ah, nothing...
...until I've danced with your wife.
Well, I think she's a drear and a...
...bore, and I'd love to dance.
Two gin and tonics.
Make mine a double!
And watch the doctor's wife unwind.
Sir.
My wife was joking!
I haven't really stopped you from
going home, have I?
You've stopped me from trying
to be the perfect wife.
For which, many thanks.
Uh, excuse me? Would
you care to dance?
I thought I was!
Oh, I'm sorry - if you'd
rather be alone---
I'm always alone. Take me!
[BROOKS GIVES A LITTLE LAUGH]
May I?
I've seen you before.
[BROOKS GIVES A LITTLE LAUGH]
Your brandy's over on that table.
[DRUNKENLY SLURRING HER WORDS]
What's it doing over there?
Um... we were going to dance.
Ooh! Goody!
Where did you come from?
Bristol. I've been here a week.
Why?
I was posted here.
I work at The Nightingale Hospital.
So does my husband.
All day, all night, all year after
year, after year...
- ...after year---
- No kidding?
- Yes.
- Well, I'm only a House physician.
Your husband's probably a consultant.
Is he here tonight?
No, we're safe!
Have you seen Clifford Preston anywhere?
No, I've seen Ruth Preston, and uh...
...she's seen the new House man!
Uh, hey! I don't think we're
supposed to go in there.
Relax. What's good enough
for the Romans...
...is good enough for us.
Ah, Clifford borrowed my...
...camera. I thought he might
have brought it.
Well, he's taken ward duty tonight.
Why is there always...
...some reason I have...
...to go back to that hospital?
You know at fifty point two...
...grains per head, I estimate...
... it'll take half the city's supply
of bicarbonate of soda...
...to settle this lot's hangovers.
Well, to ease the situation
I've arranged to have...
...mine in Le Touquet.
Try not to miss us too much.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to intrude.
Oh, Steven!
Hello, Ruth.
Happy New Year, darling.
Yes, Happy New Year, Doctor Monks.
Thank you, Brooks.
Well, I'd better be getting off...
...before the lads s-start sending
out a search party.
Dear old...
...faithful old Steven.
If they ask me "Who would you like...
- ...for New Year's---"
- Ruth.
If nobody mixes that boy up...
...he's going to be a good doctor.
Did I stop you...
...being one?
I was able to "un-mix" myself.
Were you, Steven?
I thought Clifford might have
given you my camera.
Clifford never gives me anything.
[RUTH GIGGLES]
We're leaving in the morning, and I...
...don't want to go without it.
Well, do you... [LAUGHS SOFTLY]
...do you think anyone still remembers...
...where the Sextus Quad is?
- And the steps of Greece
- Ruth, you'll...
...break your neck in those heels.
Who'd care?
Look...
...why don't we go and get
some coffee?
Or some healing waters...
...from the hot springs.
Do you think it would heal
my complaint, Sextus?
[DRUNKEN GIGGLING]
Let's find out.
Wheeee!
[LOUD SPLASHING NOISE]
Ruth, for heaven's sake!
I'm taking "The Cure" - it's wonderful.
[RUTH GIGGLES AS SHE SPLASHES]
Come on out at once!
Come on!
Oh, you're so stuffy.
Ooh!
Come on!
You should be in it,
for the water.
Give me your hand.
Steven.
That was a very stupid thing to do.
And you'll very likely catch your...
- ...death of pneumonia.
- Do you realise...
..that I'm probably cured of
rheumatism, fibrositis...
...sciatica and gout and...
- ...and hayfever?
- And you'll be the...
...fittest person that ever died of exposure.
- Woo!
- Come on.
A doctor who knew his job...
...will prescribe a large...
- ...warming brandy.
- This doctor says...
...the sooner you get out of that dress...
- ...the better.
- Oh.
[RUTH GIGGLES DRUNKENLY]
Julie will fetch you a wrap or something.
Waiter!
Sir?
Do you know my wife, Mrs Monks?
Yes, sir.
Ask her to come here, would you?
She's probably dancing
with Doctor Radley.
Right, sir.
Ruth?
I left my cigarettes...
...in the left-hand pocket of my jacket.
Skol!
Ruth!
[RUTH MAKES A MUFFLED NOISE]
Wasn't brandy. Whiskey!
Naughty porter had a secret cellar.
Ruth. How much you drink is your...
- ...business. I'm merely...
- Ooh!
- ...trying to save you...
- Come on!
- ...the embarrassment.
- It's New Years Eve.
Unbend!
What happened?
She fell in.
I did not! I took "The Cure".
- Help her dry off, would you?
- Mmm, I'll get a towel.
I'll go and get the car.
You mean we're leaving?
I think we've stayed long enough.
Then we can drop Ruth home.
Can't go home tonight!
See you outside.
Supposed to celebrate tonight.
I'd say you've done quite enough!
- Come on, turn round.
- Woo hoo hoo.
Celebrate all the wonderful
things that...
- ...didn't happen last year.
- That's right.
Because this year, they're not
gonna happen again!
[RUTH MAKES SHIVERING NOISES]
Step out.
- You know why I like you, Julie?
- No.
- Tell me about it tomorrow.
- 'Cause...
...you don't heckle.
Not like Clifford. You don't
keep saying I'm...
- ...an exhibitionist and things.
- I don't have to...
- ...because you already know it.
- You take Ruth...
I'll get over to the NH...
...and chase up the camera.
Oh, that's a great idea!
And you're all right too, for a man!
That's high praise.
Now, come on. In you get.
Ooh, can't!
Earrings too heavy!
Pick you up in about twenty minutes.
I think you're underestimating the situation.
Steven Monks...
- ...if it wasn't New Year's Eve---
- Don't worry, I'll get a cab.
Hey, I'm cold! What about
some brandy?
Now, you be a good girl
and go to bed.
That's a very confusing order!
Right!
It's all systems go!
I hope to see you later!
[LOUD PARTY NOISES]
[CHURCH BELLS RINGING]
[RUTH HUMS TO HERSELF]
[RUTH SINGS]
"Happy New Year all you people."
Will Clifford be home?
You're kidding, of course?
Key?
Sorry I messed up your evening.
You haven't.
I was ready to leave an hour ago.
- [RUTH SHOUTS] The exalted circle!
- Ssh!!!
If all the stethoscopes in this circle...
...were laid in the Sahara desert...
[RUTH SHOUTS]
...it would be a wonderful thing!
Go on in.
And, if you like, I'll even make
you some coffee.
Coffee, coffee. Who wants coffee?
What we need is a New Year drink!
What you need is a New Year
kick in the pants!
And if I were Clifford I'd give it to you.
[RUTH SHRIEKS WITH LAUGHTER]
Clifford!
He doesn't even know I'm
there when I'm there.
Up!
Yes, nurse.
[RUTH SINGS TO HERSELF]
Trouble is I resent you two.
You know where you're going.
Got everything it takes.
All set out neatly in a folder.
"Julie Monks: This Is Your Life!"
I wish it were that easy.
Mine's all falling apart.
- Can't find the pieces.
- You're pickled...
...that's your trouble.
My trouble is it's wearing off!
- patient needs more anaesthetic nurse
,.
- Look, any...
...minute I'm about to say
to hell with you...
...and go home!
Don't do that, Julie.
- Don't leave me!
- All right.
- Not yet.
- Get up!
- I'm not really a drinker, you know?
- Oh, that's good news.
I could stop immediately!
Good.
Just like that!
But there has to be a reason.
A purpose to justify my existence.
Being a wife won't do?
Ooh! Doctor's wife.
Position in the communitity.
I've let the side down,
haven't I, Julie?
Yes, Ruth.
I'm not a wife.
Clifford wants children, I don't.
Children frighten me!
[RUTH MAKES SILLY NOISES]
[RUTH MAKES A CRYING BABY NOISE]
So I'm not even a woman.
Just a nothing.
Ooh, to sleep...
- ...and sleep and sleep.
- You can start right now.
Here are your earrings. Now,
where's your nightgown?
Ooh, you're so wifey!
[RUTH STARTS TO SING]
"Should old acquaintance be forgot..."
"...and never brought to---"
You know something?
I've forgotten most of my...
- ...men by the next morning!
- Shoes.
Why do I do these silly things?
Wouldn't be so bad if one of
them meant something.
But they never do.
Clifford must have meant something.
But he doesn't know how to help me.
Clifford's a saint - way up there.
[RUTH SNIFFS]
And I can never reach him.
He doesn't know how to help me.
Oh, come on now, Ruth.
You're getting yourself into a jag.
Not "getting" into one - trying to stay in one!
Must keep things out of focus!
They're sometimes less frightening
if you face them.
[RUTH SLAMS THE COFFEE CUp DOWN]
Oh, you're so smug, Julie Monks!
I didn't mean to be.
All right then - face this...
...the human race is practically...
...extinct and so is marriage!
Ooh, don't let me outstay...
- ...your welcome.
- Just wondering if either of us...
- ...is going to get any sleep at all.
- Of course, you must hurry home...
...to Steven.
Steven's at the hospital.
[RUTH GIGGLES]
Good for him, he's fairly safe there.
It's only those lectures in London...
... that are dicey.
Are you sleeping in your gloves?
Or are you pro marriage?
Me Ug - me big hunter!
Bring back bear for little Ug.
A lot of marriages are doing all right.
Yours, for instance?
Mine, for instance.
[RUTH GIVES A LITTLE LAUGH]
I wouldn't bet on it, Mrs Steven Monks!
I wouldn't bet on it.
What exactly does that mean?
[RUTH STARTS TO SING SLEEPILY]
"Should old acquaintance be forgot..."
"...and never..."
"...brought to---"
[GENTLE MUSIC pLAYS]
- I'll be five minutes.
- Okay, sir.
Is, er, Doctor Preston, still here?
Oh, yes, sir. He was up in D Ward.
Chase him up for me, will you?
I'll be in the common room.
Common room? Yes, Doctor. Thank you.
What happened?
Is the trip off?
Don't even say that in fun!
Well, when they told me
you were here I---
No, I came for the camera.
Oh, the camera.
I'm sorry.
I meant to give it to Ruth.
It doesn't matter.
I'm a bit worried, as a matter of fact...
...about a woman upstairs.
I was hoping you might look
at her for me.
Oh, look - Tewson will be on
in a couple of hours.
Tewson wasn't out East...
...and I think that's...
...where this thing might
have come from.
You're an authority.
Look - five minutes, Steve. I'd
really appreciate it.
Who is this woman of yours?
Davis.
We've just moved her into
a side ward.
How long has she been in?
Two days. You won't have seen her.
What's the history?
Went to bed with severe...
...frontal headache and pains in the...
...back, four days before being admitted.
Which makes it a week ago.
She also has a rash on her face...
...thighs and abdomen I'd like
to know more about.
What sort of temperature is she running?
Yesterday's peak was a hundred and four.
It's now dropped to ninety-seven
point eight.
Doctor Monks! I thought you
were on holiday?
So did I, Sister.
I've asked Doctor Monks to
look at Mrs Davis.
Of course, I'll get the case sheet.
Has the pulse dropped as well?
I'm afraid not.
This is up to two a.m.
Thank you, Sister.
- Where is she?
- Number one.
Last injection six hours ago.
Ten milligram of physeptone.
How do you feel?
[MRS DAVIS GIVES A COUGH]
Better.
Good. This is Doctor Monks.
This is a fine time to come visiting, isn't it?
Don't worry. You're properly peppered.
Mrs Davis, have you been in contact with...
...anybody from the Far East?
My boy.
Your boy?
My son.
On the India run.
What does your son do, Mrs Davis?
He's a steward.
Home on leave.
He's all right.
[MRS DAVIS COUGHS AGAIN]
A steward on an airline?
Oh, no...
...ship.
Eastern Cargo Line.
He's all right.
When did your boy come back, Mrs Davis?
I don't remember.
On leave.
What's the matter with me?
You're all right.
Are you sure you...
...can't remember when your
son came home?
[MRS DAVIS SpEAKS BREATHILY]
H-he's on leave.
Am I bad, Doctor?
No, not very.
She's been talking a great
deal about her son.
I think he must have been
home a good...
...two weeks, Doctor - or maybe three.
The India run.
- Fetch a hot water bottle.
- I'm cold!
I'm cold!
Well, what do you think it is?
Have you sent her blood?
Yes, it's gone to the lab. We're
waiting to hear from them.
What do you think it is?
I think it's smallpox.
Are you sure?
No... I said I "think" it is.
Better call George Willis.
[TELEpHONE BEING DIALLED]
If he hasn't completed the analysis...
...ask him to go down to the lab
and do it right away.
Sister.
Do this, would you?
I think Doctor Preston would like you to...
...call Matron and ask her...
...to come over as soon as possible.
Very well, Doctor.
[DOCTOR PRESTON ON TELEPHONE]
George?
Oh, I'll use the office.
I'd also be prepared...
...for the immediate vaccination of
everyone in the building.
How many night staff on duty?
Four seniors, eight auxiliaries and
a couple of orderlies.
Is it as ominous as it sounds?
It could be Variola Major.
We're waiting for the report.
I see.
The night staff may have to
stay on for a while.
- Of course.
- Doctor Preston will advise you.
We'll know within the hour. They're also...
...trying to contact Ruddling in the Pump Room.
I shouldn't say too much on the
phone, if I were you.
No, of course not.
I was going to pick up Ruth...
...I suppose she'll get home all right.
Mmm, she's already back.
Julie drove her.
Oh, that was kind of her.
I'm sorry I dragged you into this, Steve.
Sorry to spread alarm and despondency.
I could be wrong.
Look after yourself.
[TELEpHONE RINGING]
- Welford!
- Yes, sir?
Let me have a dressing gown, please.
Certainly, Doctor.
I'm afraid all this has to go through
the "Bug Morgue".
Oh, that is a pity. A beautiful
suit like that!
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
[BUZZER]
Robert?
Doctor Monks.
Do I still have a taxi out there?
Pay him off, would you please?
I'm going to be longer than I thought.
Thanks.
I'm afraid Big Bertha rather...
...knocks the life out of your clothes, sir.
Tends to shrink them, too.
I'll just have to diet.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
Something nasty we're in for, Doctor?
All illness is nasty.
Can I borrow a cigarette?
[TELEpHONE RINGING]
Six-five-double eight.
Sorry if I woke you.
You're joking, of course!
You sent me on a mission
of mercy, remember?
Oh, she was in great form.
Well, you know...
...Ruth when she's sloshed!
I've been delayed, Julie...
...about an hour.
I'll explain when I get back.
You can tell me over breakfast...
I'm about to start making it.
And Steve, I---
[CLICK AS STEVEN pUTS THE PHONE DOWN]
[DIAL TONE]
- How much is it?
- Four shillings.
- Thanks.
- Hello!
I left yours inside...
...in case there was anything else
you wanted to pack, and I---
No, let me guess...
...you, er, went for a swim in it?
No, I've been through the "Bug Morgue" -
clothes and everything.
Oh, poor Steven.
No one can say it's been a dull night!
Next New Year's I'll stick with you.
I may take you up on that.
Is this coffee perked?
Should be.
What happened at the hospital?
They've got a woman up there
with suspected smallpox.
Local woman?
Yes, uh...
...switch this off, would you?
I didn't tell you over the phone...
...it might have been overheard.
We don't want to start a panic.
How long has she had it?
Mmm... two or three weeks.
Probably came in with her boy.
He's a ship's steward.
Anyway, the machinery's working...
...they'll have it all sewn up...
...by the time we get back.
Here you are.
So it's been in town for three weeks?
[STEVEN SOUNDING TIRED]
Yes.
Course, my, er...
...diagnosis doesn't have to be right.
It could be nothing worse
than impetigo...
...or severe chickenpox.
Did you examine her, then?
Yes, Clifford asked me to.
It's his patient.
So you touched her?
Oh, don't worry - I'm perfectly safe.
So are you. I've been disinfected completely.
[STEVEN EXHALES LOUDLY]
So have my cigarettes!
How much time do we have?
Oh, darling, you're such a damned
fool, sometimes.
You know we can't go now.
"Can't go"?!
Why not?
Well, darling - let's be honest.
If the boy's been around
for three weeks...
...this isn't just an isolated case.
It could be the start of an outbreak.
All right, so it could be an outbreak.
I-I'm not the only doctor in town.
I'm tired - washed out.
I need this holiday, Julie.
Of course you do
You've been working non-stop for years...
You deserve it - but I don't.
- And what does that mean?
- I'm staying.
You're staying?!
- But why in the name of---
- Because I can help.
How?
They might call for volunteer nurses.
I'm still qualified.
You think you're dedicated to
crisis by birth, don't you?
It has some sort of...
- ...fascination for you.
- Not dedicated, just obstinate.
I'll get my cases.
Julie!
Should have married someone outside
your own profession, Steve.
Someone who wouldn't know
about these things.
So I'm supposed to...
...go off alone, having a wonderful spree, while...
...you stay here and play the martyr!
Darling, don't turn this into a duel.
You need the rest. It might even
be good for us to be...
- ...apart for a while.
- No, I-I-I'm not...
...going to let you make me ashamed
of this holiday, Julie...
...you can't.
Not often we have a bust-up, is it?
This isn't a bust-up.
For you it is.
I need you with me.
You owe this to me, Julie.
[TELEpHONE RINGING]
Shall I get it?
Hello.
It's Clifford, Steve.
You were right.
The Lab's confirmed it. We've
had a second case...
...brought in and the M.O.H....
...is circulating all General Practitioners.
So perhaps you'd leave a
note for your locum.
Of course.
Who's the second case?
Commissionaire.
The Theatre Royal.
The hospital's under immediate quarantine.
You just got away in time.
I'm not away yet.
How far is the first case from the theatre?
Three miles across town.
Which means it's travelled through about...
...eighty thousand people.
Steven, I've been trying to get
Ruth. There's no reply.
You said Julie took her home?
Yes.
Yes, she did.
Well, I wouldn't worry...
...she's probably asleep.
Yes, thanks Clifford.
Well?
He, er, can't get any reply
from Ruth.
Oh, the hell with Ruth!
It is an outbreak, isn't it?
Why don't we get some sleep, Julie?
May not be any for some time.
You don't have to stay, Steve, you're right.
You're not the only doctor in town.
I'm the only doctor in town whose
wife always wins.
Wish I could believe that.
We're all right, Julie.
We're all right.
[CHURCH BELL CHIMES]
Disinfection unit reporting, Sarge.
Disinfection? Who for?
Oh, nothing personal, Sarge -
so don't take offence.
- It's too early for laughs.
- Some place at Fairhaven.
Chief Health Inspector said report to him here.
Better report then.
Oh!
Standing by, sir.
The M.O.H. will be wanting you shortly.
Ready when he is, sir.
'Ere, what's all this, then?
There's a meeting.
What, eight o'clock?
M.O.H.'s office.
Yeah, well, no one's been up this
early since the Royal visit.
And I've also given instructions that...
...once an ambulance has been
used to pick up a case...
...it must not be used for any
other purpose.
I'll advise my men.
Yes, try and keep the same
vehicle for all new cases.
Sounds like you're expecting more.
I wish I wasn't so sure.
Sorry, we've been waiting for...
...confirmation of another case.
- A third.
- Did you get it?
It's in a modified form, but I'm...
...afraid it's number three.
Where?
The Davis house again. The woman's son...
...the steward.
- He's quarantined, of course?
- Yes, indeed.
As soon as we knew about
the first case.
We also found out the
boy went to the...
...Theatre Royal on his first
night's leave...
...which ties up the two cases.
So there's no doubt - he's
the missed case?
In my opinion, none.
Top priority now is to identify
all primary contacts...
...and the immediate vaccination of all
police, emergency services...
...postal staff - in fact every public
servant in the city!
Look, I don't want to underestimate
the situation...
...but after all... three cases, I mean...
...take precautions, yes.
But don't you think we're
blowing it up a little...
...out of proportion?
Mr Town Clerk...
...I cannot say this too emphatically...
...this virus is a killer!
Yes, we do only have three cases...
...but tomorrow it could be thirty-three.
In two weeks a thousand and three
unless we contain it now!
Fair enough.
Next question...
...how much of this do I
give to the press?
Everything, as far as I'm concerned.
We desperately need their help.
Ask them to try and put this
over to the...
...public without causing a panic.
In that case I'd better talk
to the Editor...
...unless there's something else.
No, I don't think so.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
- We can't get things moving too quickly.
- You'd better alert the transport department.
- I'm going over to the Chronicle.
- Call the doctor in, would you...
...see if Doctor Preston's left yet?
- Yes, sir.
- Mr Buckridge!
I know you'll instruct your inspectors
very thoroughly.
They're in my office now.
You've a tough assignment...
...but you'll have a team of six doctors...
...working in liaison with you.
Make it seven.
- Good morning.
- Hello, Steve.
Doctor Boswell.
- I'll report back later.
- Doctor Preston left...
...half an hour ago.
When he arrives tell him I've gone...
...to the Davis house.
He won't arrive.
I've sent him home to bed.
No, he was frankly out on his feet.
He'd been working for sixteen hours.
I'm here instead.
Well, it was your diagnosis.
Can I leave a message for Doctor Preston?
Have you heard the latest?
Ruddling told me.
Aren't you supposed to be abroad?
I decided to stay and save money.
I can think of pleasanter ways!
I bet your wife can, too.
As a matter of fact, it was her idea.
This is the path of the virus.
From the Davis house to the theatre here.
By now there'll be a good few sidelines.
We have a list of all the places...
...the boy Davis can remember going to...
...since he became infectious, twelve days ago.
The theatre...
...two cinemas...
pump Room dance
......
...Colonnade Restaurant...
...and an unidentified coffee bar.
Our urgent job is to find every person...
...who was in any of these places on...
...the dates he was there.
Is that clear?
- Yes, sir.
- And when we find them?
Report their names and addresses
to the doctors.
They'll be vaccinated...
...isolated to their houses...
...or wherever they are for sixteen days
- What powers do we have?
- The powers of persuasion.
Are all contacts infectious, sir?
Not until the symptoms show up.
Which is some time after the tenth day.
And Davis has been around for
nearly three weeks.
Fowler...
...Thompson...
...the cinema.
He can't remember where he sat.
Just somewhere in the stalls.
Saunders, Pump Room.
This lot's liable to involve half the city!
So is an epidemic.
You take the Colonnade Restaurant.
The rest of you...
...find that coffee bar.
Not yet... I haven't finished.
We've borrowed a snap-shot
of the boy Davis...
...and the Chronicle's making some prints.
Pick them up.
[TELEpHONE RINGS]
Buckridge.
Yes?
Whereabouts?
Whitney Lodge.
Right...
...give me the details.
His daughter.
Have we a list of her movements?
Yes.
Another one?
Suspected.
Now, how many of you have
been vaccinated...
...in the last twelve months?
Right, you four get going.
Use your own cars - we'll pay for the juice.
Not you, Newton.
The rest of you downstairs.
You'll find two pretty nurses
who'll want you with...
...jackets off and left sleeves rolled up.
I was done about eighteen months ago.
So was I and I'm not griping.
- I wasn't griping---
- Downstairs and get scratched.
[BELLS RINGING]
Did you mean me to go too, sir?
No.
You'll cover this with me.
Yes, sir.
Get onto police Superintendent Goffe.
This is absolute priority.
Ask if their information room...
...would get a message through...
[POLICE CAR RADIO]
"...to Doctor Boswell..."
"...Medical Officer of Health."
[POLICE CAR RADIO]
"Message starts..."
"New area of risk at Whitney Lodge..."
[POLICE CAR RADIO]
"...Lansdowne Crescent."
[POLICE CAR RADIO] "Now being covered
by Chief Public Health Inspector."
[POLICE CAR RADIO]
"Message ends. K.G. Over."
Yes, we got that.
Doctor Boswell's not here yet...
...but there is something arriving now.
K.G. one-four. Over.
Morning, Doctor.
Hello, Cleaver.
This the house?
Yes. Everybody's in.
This just came through from the P.H.I., sir.
How many of these people would...
...crowd round an unexploded bomb?
All of them.
Er, they won't open, sir, unless I tell them to.
Get their names...
...and where they live on this street.
...and ask them to be kind enough...
...to go home and wait for
us to visit them.
I should say you'll have a job.
Oh, no, sir...
...I live on this street myself.
Oh, it's all right - it's the Medical Officer.
May we come in, Mr Davis?
[LOUD POp MUSIC COMING FROM
INSIDE THE HOUSE]
Hello, this is Doctor Monks...
..he'd like to make a brief check-up.
How is she, Doctor?
Is there any change?
I'm afraid we can't expect much
change, Mr Davis.
I see.
- In here?
- Yes.
[MUSIC IS MUCH LOUDER
IN THE ROOM]
Hello.
Come on, Daph. It's your go.
Have you been told what all
this is about?
Mr Cleaver explained.
Sidney, turn that down a bit!
It's meant to be loud, it's no
good if it's not!
Well, take it off!
Do you understand how you...
...can help us, then, by...
...staying in your house for a
couple of weeks?
What about my job?
I mean, supposing they stop...
- ...my wages?
- They won't.
[KETTLE STARTS TO WHISTLE]
- Sidney, the kettle.
- Okay, Dad.
Where are we going to do all this?
Well, you can use the girls' room.
Right. Take the ladies
first, shall we?
Good! Me first!
I said to make yer beds.
Well, you know you make yer...
...beds, what does it look like?
Mine's made!
Right.
Now, which of you two
is the healthiest?
Me.
I've got a cold nose.
Feel.
Mmm. Ice cold.
Now the other one.
Now, take your top off.
How about you, Daphne?
No spots or aches anywhere?
No.
Mind you, the boy didn't feel...
...good since he came home.
But he fought it.
You know? On leave - don't want
to miss anything.
Well, he'll be all right.
It's pretty bad, isn't it?
With the wife.
It could be worse.
Things can always be worse.
[FRONT DOOR BELL RINGS]
All right.
Who is it?
Cleaver, sir.
No trouble at all, sir.
They're all waiting at home for you.
Oh, good work.
And there's also a list of sixteen other...
...people who called here in
the last ten days.
Including tradesmen?
Milkman, postman, paperboys, insurance
and rent collectors.
Phone them right away for
the Health Department.
Can we start preparing for
disinfection now, sir?
Yes, come in.
Upstairs. Both rooms.
I'll be up in a minute.
Examined, vaccinated and
ready for breakfast.
Yes - I want some porridge.
Yes, all right. In a minute.
Would you like a cup of tea?
No, thanks. We have so much to do.
- Let me have your arm, please.
- There's no milk, anyway.
Well, why not?
Well, I suppose because no-one ordered it!
How are we going to have...
...porridge without milk?
- Would you like a Welfare Volunteer...
...to live in and help?
Er, er, no, we'll be all right, er...
...I-I think we'd rather be on our own.
We'll be all right.
Your groceries and things will be delivered
They'll be put in a special bin outside...
...so that they'll keep clean and dry...
...until you fetch them in.
I see.
Yes.
You do understand?
No one must go out - for any
reason whatsoever.
Yes, that'll be all right.
We don't have anything, do we?
No, of course not.
It's only a precaution.
One of the inspectors will come
and see you every day.
He'll bring you news of
your wife and son...
...so you won't really be
out of touch.
Thank you.
[JAZZ RECORD PLAYING ON THE JUKEBOX]
[NEWSREADER ON RADIO]
"---in particular the Bath Medical Authorities..."
"...are anxious to trace anyone..."
[NEWSREADER ON RADIO]
"...who was at either of the local cinemas..."
"...or the Colonnade Restaurant..."
[NEWSREADER ON RADIO]
"...Broad Street, on these dates."
"And in addition to these places..."
[NEWSREADER ON RADIO]
"...anyone who visited the Theatre Royal..."
"...for the evening performance on..."
[NEWSREADER ON RADIO]
"...December the twentieth..."
"...should, likewise, go to their doctor..."
[NEWSREADER ON RADIO]
"...for immediate vaccination."
"Any person who attended the dance..."
[NEWSREADER ON RADIO]
"...at the pump Room last Saturday..."
"...December the twenty-second..."
[NEWSREADER ON RADIO]
"...is asked to report---"
Six hundred and fifty-four admissions.
It would have to be a Saturday night!
That's about the usual weekend figure.
Can you remember anyone personally?
We might have had a few table reservations.
Any names at all will give us
something to start on.
[AMBULANCE BELL RINGING]
Ah, Doctor!
You'll have to excuse us...
...we're sort of roughing it this morning.
Where's the day staff?
Helping out on the switchboard.
We've been jammed with...
...calls ever since it was on the radio.
Oh, and there's a note for you
from Mrs Monks, sir.
My wife been here?
No. Taxi left it down at the gate...
...along with her suitcases.
Seems she's volunteered to...
...move in with the rest of us.
[WELFORD GIVES A LITTLE LAUGH]
I'd say we're daft, the lot of us.
Er, no offence to Mrs Monks.
I think I'd better let my department
know where I am.
Yes, of course. Welford will see to it.
And take Mr Buckridge through disinfection.
Right. This way, sir.
See you later, I expect.
Yeah.
[WELFORD LAUGHS]
You know, one old lady...
...called up in a panic and said...
...that she'd spoken to a contact
on the telephone...
...and was she still safe?
[JULIE'S VOICE]
"Please don't be angry..."
"...but they've appealed for volunteers..."
[JULIE'S VOICE]
"...up at the hospital and..."
"...I've decided to go for a few days."
[JULIE'S VOICE]
"Mrs Chalmers will look after you..."
"...and I've arranged the food and clean things."
[JULIE'S VOICE]
"Don't overdo it, darling. See you soon."
[CRASH AS CLIPBOARD HITS THE FLOOR]
- I'm so sorry.
- No damage.
I wasn't looking either.
By the way, Doctor - you know she died?
Half an hour ago.
What?
Mrs Davis.
Oh, yes, yes. Of course.
Her son's taking it rather badly.
Is anybody with him?
Yes.
Doctor preston
.
- Side Ward Three.
- I see, thank you.
Sister, would you have any ideas...
...where my wife's working
at the moment?
She's with one of the mobile units, Doctor.
They could be practically anywhere.
Yes, of course.
I know she'll be at the Assembly
Rooms this evening.
They're opening an emergency clinic.
Apparently the surgeries...
...have been swamped since the broadcast.
She's helping out...
- ...before moving in.
- I see, thank you.
Are you going back into town, Doctor?
I am.
There are some letters for the post.
I wondered if you'd be...
- ...kind enough?
- Yes, of course, Sister.
They're all in a polythene bag,
in the Clean Room.
It's my fault.
- It's my fault. I brought this in.
- It's nobody's fault.
It could happen to any of us.
It's my fault Mum's dead.
It's my fault.
God's will can never be your fault, son.
Why pick Mum?
Sh-she never done anything. Why Mum?
Ah, I'm afraid there are lots
of "whys" we can't...
- ...answer - we just have to accept them.
- Roll over, old chap.
Hold steady.
I'm sure it's the same on your boat.
We all think we know better than
the Captain sometimes...
...but he's the boss.
- They hate me, don't they?
- Oh, no.
Nobody hates you.
Nobody blames you, either.
I brought it in.
They hate me.
The whole town...
[BRIAN WHISPERS SLEEplLY]
...hates me.
Who's the priest?
Maguire.
He came to see the boy's mother.
Has she been moved yet?
No. There's a problem.
The M.O.'s insisting on cremation.
So what's the problem?
She was a Catholic. Cremation's not allowed.
Not allowed?!
This is a plague, Clifford. Do they allow that?
I'm going to talk to Maguire...
- ...there just hasn't been a minute.
- There's another case...
...on her way. That makes four.
Yes, it's a little frightening.
That means another sixteen days to go.
- Sixteen if we're lucky!
- Doctor Preston.
I'd like to go and see the boy's
family, if I may?
I take it there's no problem.
Not at all.
It'll be greatly appreciated.
We have another problem, Father.
Oh, yes, yes. I know.
Well, of course there'll be a special dispensation.
Yes, news has an extraordinary way...
...of getting around a hospital.
I suppose you'd call it a kind of,
er, "bed-pan telegraph".
Now, which way is the, er...
...decontamination? Ah, yes.
How old?
Nineteen.
Dear God!
Thanks. I can manage now, chum.
We'll be up next trip.
They'll take care of you in here.
Yes, sir.
[SOUND OF THE LIFT GOING UP]
Give them a chance.
Steven, what shall I do about Ruth?
Ruth?
When I got home she'd gone.
Gone where?
London.
She sometimes stays with a girlfriend.
I phoned, but her friend said she
was out shopping.
Well, at least if she's out of town...
...she's not exposed to risk.
That's true.
Now, get your ambulance fumigated.
Lock it and give the key to
the Chief, please.
Right-o, sir.
Hello, no one in charge?
Apparently not.
There's a man taking a shower in there.
He said to put everything in the barrel.
Oh.
Marvellous, isn't it?
Never know what's gonna hit
you next, these days.
Get across the street
safely, there's a...
...bloody jet fallin' on yer house!
That is if you don't die of cancer
smokin' thirty a day.
And that's peace time, that is...
...without the bleedin' bomb!
[SUSpENSEFUL MUSIC]
[BELL STARTS TO TOLL]
[DOG BARKING]
[TELEpHONE RINGING]
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
[CROWD NOISE]
[AMBULANCE BELL RINGING]
I suppose they'll still hold the
football on Saturday?
Well, I can't wait.
I've got to get me old man's dinner.
Well, I wouldn't volunteer, I...
...told her, even if they all looked
like Ben Casey!
Mind you, I don't really
believe in it...
- ...but if it's free, why miss it?
- Why do they pick...
...the coldest night of the year?
Think they'd organise it better,
wouldn't you?
'Ere, someone's passing out, mate.
Where? Who?
Me, for want of a pint!
[RAUCOUS LAUGHTER]
[NOISY CROWD]
That's it, Captain.
Off you go. Keep the dressing on till...
...Saturday. And don't scratch it.
Here, put this on in three days' time.
Oh no, it mustn't show. I'm a
photographic model!
All right, let's have the thigh.
Right up, please.
In front of this lot?
Oh, come on dear. You've
shown more than that.
Ouch!
[JULIE GIVES AN EXASpERATED SIGH]
And don't let anyone take it
off for three days.
Left sleeve up, please.
Oh, come on - you've had this
before, haven't you?
No, never.
Well, it won't take a minute.
Mrs Monks, I...
- ...think he's feeling---
- Let me finish it, we...
...won't get him here again.
Right. Dressing.
[MAN GIVES A LITTLE SNORT]
Can you manage?
We've got him.
Hi.
Steven!
Did I just miss a drama of modern surgery?
Just missed a beautiful blonde model.
Well, I was hoping to talk to a
beautiful brunette nurse.
- Evening, Doctor.
- Hello.
What's the score?
We've lost count.
Is Mrs Morris in yet?
- Just arrived,
- Right.
Back in half an hour.
Ask Susan to change the bin
before she leaves.
Right.
Have fun.
With her husband?
Next, please.
If I faint, will you put an
arm round me, too?
Any other time it would
be a pleasure...
...but right now, we're just
a shade busy.
How's it been going?
Fast and furious.
My back aches...
...and I'm fume drunk from
surgical spirit.
And you?
Routine.
With the odd surprise here and there.
You got my note?
Yes, I got your note.
[CHILDREN SHOUTING]
Where shall we eat? The
Hole in the Wall?
Oh, I'm past food. But if you're really...
- ...hungry, then we---
- No, not really.
Besides, Mrs Chalmers will have
left something out for me.
You do understand?
Of course.
It's obviously the migrating
season for wives.
Clifford's has flown, too.
Ruth?
She's left town to stay with a girlfriend.
Poor Clifford.
One day he'll be knocking on our
door and asking for help.
That marriage is past help.
How do you know when a
marriage is past help?
When two people stop liking each other.
People can't like each other all the time.
Even if they're still in love.
Is that why you left?
I've gone out.
You know other people's wives are...
...helping without packing their bags.
Thanks.
Maybe I've used this as an excuse to step...
...outside our marriage for a while and...
...try to take a look at us from a distance.
Are we that unbearable, close to?
We haven't been "close to" for a long time.
Even when we're together we're not
really together any more.
We're never relaxed with each other.
- Like now?
- Like now!
There's always a...
...antagonism, I don't know.
Such as arguing about when
to leave a dance?
- Oh, that's not important.
- Or how a doctor...
...shouldn't run away on a holiday?
Oh, leave it, Steve. Drop it!
Drop what?
Nine years of our lives?
Darling, we're both too tired to think or
feel or understand anything.
Let's leave it until all this is finished.
Us or the epidemic?
For God's sake, Julie. Of all times to play...
- ...games with our marriage!
- That's just it.
Well, look at us! Right now - at this minute.
We were having a tough enough time when...
...things were normal, but now...
...with all this on top of us...
...well, what chance do we have?
What with fatigue and tension and
frayed nerves I...
...I'm scared we're not going to make it.
And I do want us to make it.
Desperately.
I just hope you do, too.
[AMBULANCE BELLS RINGING -
GETTING LOUDER]
Thirty-three, Oakwood Close.
Name of Whitcombe.
- Do you have your car?
- Yes.
I'm sorry about this, Doctor - but
everyone else is out.
Couldn't even find transport.
Do we know degree of contact?
Probably first.
She's a waitress.
Sombrero Coffee Bar.
We tracked it down.
The one the steward was at.
Betty Whitcombe.
Another member of the nightmare.
She'd been off two days.
When they found her she was ill in bed.
[TRAFFIC NOISE]
[NEWSCASTER]
"This is T.W.W."
Latest news of the epidemic in Bath.
Three new cases were confirmed today.
This brings the total number of persons
still infected up to fifteen.
There have now been eleven deaths.
Although many hundreds of people...
...are still under observation in
house quarantine.
The Ministry of Health state that...
.."all steps are being taken to"...
..."prevent the outbreak"...
..."from spreading to other districts".
As a precautionary measure...
[NEWSCASTER]
..."an observation barrier..."
"...has been placed across..."
[NEWSCASTER]
"...the western suburbs..."
"...and the Salisbury district."
[NEWSCASTER]
"According to reports..."
"...more than twenty-one thousand people..."
[NEWSCASTER]
"...have been vaccinated..."
"...since the beginning of the outbreak..."
[NEWSCASTER]
"...just over a week ago."
[TRAFFIC NOISE]
[CHURCH BELL CHIMES]
The backlog of bedding, clothes and laundry...
...to be disinfected is so out of hand...
...we had to burn half of it.
Our own disinfection units are over-worked...
...and absolutely inadequate for the situation.
[TELEpHONE RINGING]
I've already asked Civil Defence to co-operate.
Doctor Ruddling.
Oh.
That's the Editor of the Evening Chronicle...
...he's outside.
- He wants a word with you
- Gracey?
- Ask him in.
- What's his trouble?
All right.
So what about the disinfection machines?
Two more arriving by road today.
The C.D.'Il look after them.
Where?
Recreation ground.
The area's been roped off.
Come in, Mr Gracey.
You know everyone.
What can we do for you?
I want to know, can we help?
You've already helped a lot.
I can't go on saying that it's
all under control.
What else can we publish?
Well, plenty of sunshine cruise pictures...
...football and comic strips.
That's my prescription.
They don't want escape.
They want to be told. They want to...
...know have we licked it, or haven't we?
No, Mr Gracey, we haven't.
That was your office.
An ambulance has just collected
one of your typesetters.
[NOISY pRlNTlNG MACHINERY]
And your name, please?
Smith.
Sub-Editor.
Married. Thirty-two.
[COLLINS ASKING SUB-EDITOR QUESTIONS]
Children?
Address?
You feel perfectly fit?
Yes, I always am.
Are you a personal friend of this man?
Not personal, no. We work here.
Press that on tight, please.
Yes.
Oh, just a minute.
- put that on in three days
.
- Yes.
Well, that's the last one, Doctor.
The man with the glasses.
He hasn't been done yet.
That's the Editor.
- Mr Collins said he was vaccinated---
- Don't argue with me...
- ...get him here!
- Yes, Doctor.
What's the situation now?
You have to be scratched.
I ought to be loaded with the...
...stuff. I was done last month for Cairo.
I congratulate you. You ought
to be well protected.
Look, I know you're pooped out.
But I'd like to know the situation.
I'm responsible for these chaps - as well as
for getting the paper out.
The situation isn't in my hands.
Ask Mr Collins, he knows all the answers.
They'll be spraying you with formaline soon.
Does that mean evacuation?
How long are we out of action?
Twenty-four hours.
You mean we can't work in here
during all that time?
Not unless you're a formaline addict!
Joe!
Yes, Guv?
You can get off now.
Yes, Doctor.
I know.
I'm the worst, aren't I?
Cup of tea, Doc?
What?
Uh, no - no thanks.
- Where can I wash?
- The bottom of the stairs.
Doctor!
Doctor Monks!
There's a message from the hospital, sir.
They're keeping your wife there.
- It's been confirmed, I'm afraid.
- What's been confirmed?
You ought to call them, sir.
There's a phone there.
Look, I'm Doctor Monks. Is it my wife
you're talking about?
Yes, Doctor.
[JULIE TALKS SOFTLY]
Going alone.
Out of this.
People pushing, no more waiting.
First time really alone.
- I'm tired, Steven, I'm so tired.
- Now drink this, if you can.
If I can.
You should let me sleep.
It's the first thing you should learn.
Drink up.
Mmm.
[JULIE GIVES A LITTLE COUGH]
What did you dope me with?
Now stop chattering or Father Maguire will go.
He can't stand women who chatter!
Father Maguire?
That's me.
I'm not a Catholic.
No, well, I'm not a woman...
...but I thought I'd like to talk
to you, just the same.
You shouldn't wake a critical patient.
You're not "critical". Yours is "modified".
Too early to find out.
Do you know how long you've been here?
All night.
All two nights! It's "modified" and
you're going to be all right.
I don't need any false comfort, thank
you. I know, I'm a nurse.
You're a blinkin' nuisance, you know?
And so are you!
It's wonderful to lie here and tell that
to a full-blown Matron.
Do you know what sort of
person she is, Father?
Do I still call you "Father" if
I'm not a Catholic?
Oh.
You can call me a "blinkin'
nuisance" if you like.
Should wear your mask.
Didn't they tell you?
Well, if you don't believe what they
tell you, why should I?
Did they send for you or did you just come?
Just came...
...to see if there was anything
I could do for you.
Anything I can get?
I can't really ask a priest for a bedpan!
Where are they kept?
I don't want one. I just said it
out of devilment.
I'd like to shout awful things at Matron.
Trouble is, I wouldn't really mean them.
She runs this place like a battleship, and I
admire competent people.
Are you competent, Father?
Me? Well, I'm sure I wouldn't have
got my Eleven Plus.
You've come to give the Last Sacrament.
I could hardly do that.
You belong to a "rival firm", don't you?
[JULIE SPEAKS SLEEPILY]
Didn't you meet me...
...sometime...
...sometime ago?
I haven't been here very long.
I-I mean, before.
Poor Clifford.
He's too good.
Gets hurt.
Ruth hurts him.
Ooh, you're so smug, Julie Monks.
It's difficult.
So difficult.
I'm so cold!
I'll call Matron.
I'm not frightened.
I want that understood - I'm not frightened.
[JULIE GIVES A LITTLE SOBBING NOISE]
I love you, Steve.
That was a stupid thing to do, Father,
for a man of your intelligence!
We're exposed to gross contamination
in here - all of us, every minute.
There's no time for dangerous heroics.
They tell me you run this place
like a battleship, Matron.
I try to run it like a hospital.
And all I ask is that you don't do
such a foolish thing again.
Yes, Matron.
Matron!
Now, we don't want...
...you in a state, Doctor...
...trying to do everything at once...
...because it's all been done.
I'm sure it has.
She's in Side Ward Two and
she's very comfortable.
- I'll be around if I can be of any help.
- Thanks.
What happened?
She collapsed - the night before last.
They found her in the disinfection shower.
Night before last?!
Why wasn't I told?
Mainly because your wife asked us not to.
She insisted it was merely fatigue
and the heat of the steam.
But we took precautions and
put her to bed.
I see.
She's just gone to sleep, Doctor.
- She hasn't had much sleep, lately.
- So unless you really need to disturb her..?
- No, no, I won't disturb her.
- Oh, excuse me, Matron...
...there's some volunteers at...
...the front gate.
They want to help.
The police say shall they let them up?
Let them up?!
They can drive them up...
...in state!
[GENTLE MUSIC STARTS TO PLAY]
[STEVEN'S THOUGHTS]
"Oh, Julie."
"Dying isn't a reason for loving..."
"...or for being loved."
"But it's you I want, Julie."
"I know now."
"Don't let it be too late."
[STEVEN REMEMBERING]
JULIE: Wish I could believe that.
STEVEN: We're all right, Julie.
STEVEN: We're all right.
[STEVEN'S THOUGHTS]
"If you're going to die, Julie..."
"...you have to know what's possessed me."
[STEVEN REMEMBERING]
STEVEN: I was able to "un-mix" myself.
RUTH: Were you, Steven?
[STEVEN'S THOUGHTS]
"What did you ever do to make me..."
"...less glad to see you?"
"What have you done now to make me..."
"...need so much to see you again?"
[STEVEN REMEMBERING]
RUTH: Steven.
Darling?
I've been a great help, haven't I?
Go back to sleep.
I'll be here.
Nightingale rides again!
I should have checked your take.
You hadn't taken.
It's my fault.
Rushing around, being so competent.
Just forgot.
Listen, Julie.
You mustn't touch me, Steve.
I touch what I like and what I love.
Beautiful.
But you mustn't.
I've wanted to tell you... why I've been
so... impossible lately.
- It isn't easy, and I'm---
- Then don't.
Is it all right, now?
It's going to be.
I've got to work it out - when there's
time and some peace.
Poor love.
I'm not much help.
Came on me while I wasn't watching.
Know what I'm trying to say?
And then I was in it - up to my neck.
Steve?
If I die---
You won't die, Julie.
I might. There's a fifty-fifty chance.
I've been infectious for two weeks, Steve.
I want you to have a test.
Now, you stop worrying.
I'm still organising, aren't I?
Doctor Monks, you really must let her sleep.
Matron where's Doctor preston
,?
I ordered him to go down and eat.
And I wouldn't be surprised if that
didn't apply to you, too.
And you're not getting enough sleep, Matron.
You should be a good judge of that, Doctor Monks!
A glass of wine wouldn't do you any harm.
Clifford, you're sure it's "modified"?
You can see the report for yourself.
Do we know where she picked it up?
The Sombrero Coffee Bar. I saw
her name on the list.
Her vacc. hadn't taken, of course.
Why wasn't she checked?
You know Julie.
Anyway, you're lucky. Luckier than I am.
You just heard your wife isn't
going to die, and...
...I'm terrified of losing mine in a different way.
Is she still in London?
Yes.
Let's get out of here.
You don't really mean you're
afraid of losing Ruth?
Did I say that?
Have you heard from her?
Look, Steven...
...there's enough trouble around without...
...trying to find more, but...
...I'd like to get something straight.
Have you and Ruth ever stayed
anywhere together?
I-I mustn't leave any doubt
as to what I mean.
Have you ever made love to her?
Why torture yourself?
There won't be a brawl or
anything like that, it's...
...just that I must know.
Yes, I have.
I knew it.
I had to be sure, so I could... face up to it.
Would it help you to know it was...
...all over a long time ago?
With Ruth it's never over.
We got a new one - right out of nowhere!
Place called The Crossings Hotel...
...on the Bristol Road. A man named Bradley.
What do you mean "right out of nowhere"?
Well, it's not on any of our lists.
Must be a missed case.
God help us if it is.
Who's there?
Nobody yet.
The hotel just telephoned.
People there sound a bit weird, but...
...from what we can gather the man's...
...very ill and we don't have a doctor.
Well, find one.
- Where's the M.O.H.?
- Well, he's gone off...
...to Shipton Lane.
- I thought we'd sent Doctor Scott-James?
- Yes, yes I know, but there's a...
...fog coming up on the outskirts
and he's lost in it!
All right, then. Call the hospital.
They must have someone.
If not, find whoever's off duty and...
- ...pull them out of bed!
- Right.
If there's a carrier still moving...
...we've got to know about it - and fast!
You all right, sir?
It's beating us.
What are we going to do?
You come and sit in the car for a while.
Come on.
Oh, I'm sorry. I-I can wait.
No, come in.
It's Doctor Monks, isn't it?
Yes. I'm through, now.
Well, how's your wife?
The fever's abated a little.
Oh, good.
I was talking to her, earlier on. She was...
...good enough to receive me.
I'm sure you did her a lot of good.
[FATHER MAGUIRE GIVES A LITTLE LAUGH]
She hadn't much time for me, but...
...still - she did her best to entertain me.
That does sound like my wife.
Mmm. You're more sure of your
feelings now, are you?
I don't know.
You don't know.
[MAGUIRE MAKES A TUTTING NOISE]
Then you must be taking stock.
Of course, that's what usually happens.
I suppose you said to yourself...
..."If I could have her back, everything'd be different."
And now she is back...
...everything IS different.
Isn't it?
I wish I felt that.
I wish I knew what I felt.
These things are happening to me all the time.
I don't feel them.
I didn't love my wife.
Then I thought she was going to die.
Now she's not...
...and the most I can feel is that
other people are different.
She's different, too.
You're listening, aren't you?
- Yes, I'm listening.
- It's not enough!
Maybe I'm...
...changed by these things -
but it's not enough!
I ought to...
...FEEL them. I ought to be moved by them!
[STEVEN SHOUTS ANGRILY]
I don't register anything!
It's not that you don't.
But you daren't.
What do you mean?
Well, you're afraid of showing your feelings.
You don't want people to see them.
Huh?
I've been shouting.
I'm sorry.
[MAGUIRE GIVES A LITTLE LAUGH]
Ah, that's all right.
Sure, it did you good.
Yes. You think everything does
you good, don't you?
Getting drunk, shouting...
...making love to another man's wife.
Would you say that did you good?
[STEVEN SHOUTS]
Would you?
You all right in 'ere?
Yes, yes. We're perfectly all right, thank you.
Anything you want?
A couple of cigarettes wouldn't go amiss.
Ah, now, you'll have to wait
till you go through.
- I'll leave them in the porter's Office.
- I have some in the Clean Room.
- You see, I'm trying to cut down and---
- Yes, yes, an excellent idea.
Yes, shouting is a good outlet.
Shouting and crying are the simplest
forms of communication.
We can't stand suffering alone anymore...
...we want somebody to share it.
And when they don't... well, we get
angry and frightened.
But you needn't worry.
I can take all you can give.
What about those cigarettes?
You see, I leave them in there purposely.
Because if you haven't got it...
...you may want it - but you can't have it.
As the Duchess said to the...
...to the sailor.
Yes, that's right, it was a sailor
the last time I heard it.
D'you---
Oh, thanks.
Do you remember what you were
saying to me, just now?
I think so, why?
Well, you mentioned something about adultery.
Did I?
Well, I... I'm not sure.
Well, if I did I'll stick to it.
It's true.
I'm out of gas.
Ah, thanks.
I suppose I've just been given Confession?
As you're so fond of saying, "it did me good".
I'm sorry there's no penitence...
...only regret.
I don't mean I regret doing it...
...I'm just sorry it was done.
Mmm... you'd like everybody to...
...forget about it. Is that it?
I'm sorry for the man, that's all.
But not your wife, no?
No, because she doesn't know...
...about it, so she isn't hurt by it.
It doesn't... diminish her.
Ah.
I'm speaking quite normally, aren't I?
Oh, yes, "quite normally".
I'm sorry for the man because it's hit
him where it hurts most.
Yes, well, you see, this man has
asked me for advice.
And what have you advised him?
I thought I'd talk to you first.
And now that you've "talked"?
Well, I'm still not sure.
And he feels very strongly that he ought to...
...talk to your wife, when she's well enough.
And tell her I've been unfaithful...
...is that what you mean?
I broke into his house so, naturally, he has
the right to break into mine!
Ah, well, then...
- ...not exactly that.
- It's exactly that!
I'm not objecting. It's "jungle logic",
and I accept it.
Mmm...
...well, after all, you "broke into his house"...
...to ravish his wife, didn't you?
Oh, come... what?
I'm liable to be amused at the idea of...
...my wrenching at the front door with a jemmy and...
...rushing upstairs to pin a screaming
woman to the bed!
Ah, well now, it wasn't I who introduced
the simile of housebreaking.
All right, I chose a bad phrase.
In cold, hard fact...
...we met in London by mutual consent.
And shared a very civilised meal...
...before retiring to an anonymous hotel room.
Mmm hmm.
And you find this extenuating?
I find it very hard to defend myself against
your sort of blackmail, Father.
It's not a question of blackmail.
No, he just wants to...
...tell my wife and remove the barriers.
I take it that means the natural reserve...
...of privacy that exists between...
...two people who spend their lives together.
And is there a need for, er...
- ...privacy?
- Yes.
I think the idea of...
...complete intimacy between two human beings is...
...undignified and... insufferable.
Must they...
...clean their teeth in front of each other and...
...leave the lavatory door open?
Yes, well, he thinks you can't open up...
...your mind to your wife anymore
without watching your step.
Without having to remember...
...well, a certain place, a certain time.
You know, in case you make a slip.
So what do you suggest I do?
Ah, it's not for me to suggest.
Well, what does HE want me to do?
He threatens to...
...hurt my wife and embarrass me by...
- ...exposing an affair that's best forgotten.
- I know.
All right. Well, what are his terms?
Are you prepared to meet them?
I am not prepared to let anyone bust in
and break up our future.
If he's so insistent about it...
...I'll tell her myself.
You understand, at last.
What do I understand?
That those would be his terms.
Oh, excuse me.
The M.O.'s on the phone for you, Doctor.
It's through to the porter's Office.
Right-o, thank you.
And your gear's nearly done, Father.
Just the way you like it...
...rare inside and flared on the outside.
Yes.
Yes, Tim.
Sorry to do this to you, Steve...
...it's an M.O.H. emergency call.
The Crossings Hotel.
I've no idea, but there's an Inspector
waiting at the Guildhall. He knows.
Ah, it seems they're short of
doctors down there.
- Can you still stand up?
- No!
But since when did that matter?
Right.
I have some work to do in town.
Just in case you thought I was running out on you.
Oh, not at all. Of course not.
Pity, isn't it...
...that a disinfection room can
only cleanse the outside?
Trouble with Buckridge is he's so worried...
...somebody isn't going to do it...
...right, he does everything himself.
I'd say he's heading for a nervous breakdown.
A nervous breakdown is a great institution.
It's when you don't have one that you
come apart at the seams.
Well, that's comforting.
You know this road pretty well?
Like the back of my hand.
Mind you, I've a suspicion he realises...
...we've a few half-wits in the department.
- Are we anywhere near?
- What?
The Crossings Hotel.
About two miles.
There's an AA box.
Hotel's almost opposite.
Look at this mad---
[SOUND OF SCREECHING AND SCRAplNG]
Are you all right?
[SOUND OF A CAR CRASHING IN THE DISTANCE]
He's turned over.
- Found it?
- In the ditch.
How many in there?
Nobody!
Turn that bloody engine off!
Have a look around.
They must have been thrown out.
HELLO! ARE YOU THERE?
I'll bring the car back.
Use the lights.
Find anyone?
No! They're not under the water. Here,
let's have that torch.
Well, they couldn't have been thrown out.
Must have climbed out - through here.
Well, they've cleared off.
How do we know?
We've looked. We've shouted.
- Well, if they're unconscious---
- They climbed out.
Ran off a bit...
...lost consciousness again.
And you're a doctor, you know it could happen.
My common sense tells me they cleared off.
- probably a stolen car---
- Well, I'm going to keep on searching.
All right, you keep on searching.
I'm going up to The Crossings Hotel.
I'll call the police.
But they might be dying!
Someone's dying at the hotel.
I'll see to him first, since the
others aren't available.
[CROWS CAWING]
[A HORSE WHINNIES SOMEWHERE IN THE FOG]
[DOGS BARKING]
Who is it?
A doctor, to attend someone here who's ill.
Good afternoon.
May I use your telephone?
- Over there.
- Thank you.
I'm sorry to appear like this, there's
been an accident along---
Er, the Bath Police. Thank you.
An accident?
Are you hurt?
No, no. Not hurt. Er, we were in a-a ditch.
Er, this is Doctor Monks.
I'm at The Crossings Hotel.
There's been an accident.
About two miles away.
Between here and the Lower Bath Road.
There was no sign of the driver.
An estate car.
Husky... blue, I think.
I'm sorry, I didn't get the number.
Right, thank you.
We have an estate car.
They're very popular.
The, er, gentleman who's ill.
I should like to see him.
Mr Bradley - he's upstairs.
I'll show him. I'll show him.
[DOGS BARKING OUTSIDE]
There's another man on his way.
A colleague of mine.
This could be him now.
[TWO LOUD KNOCKS ON THE DOOR]
Open the door, Clara.
My name's Bennett - I'm a Health Inspector.
I'm up here, Bennett.
Someone came along from a nearby cottage,
They're looking for the driver.
They say the car belongs to this place.
From here?
From here?!
Blue Husky: J-G-L-three-three-four.
It's ours!
It's our car, mum!
How bewildering.
- But Mummy, how could---
- Tell Williams to go and find out.
Tell Williams - he'll know.
Which room is Mr Bradley in?
He's very ill, Doctor.
How long has he been in bed?
Three days.
Why in heaven's name didn't you report...
- ...this sooner, with an epidemic on?
- We must be quiet.
Please go in, I-I'll wait for you downstairs.
How do you feel, Mr Bradley?
[MR BRADLEY FEEBLY WHlSpERS]
Bad!
Feverish, hmm?
Have I got it?
Can you answer a few questions, Mr Bradley?
Would you mind if I finish my examination first?
Go ahead.
Any headache?
Yeah.
Where? Front or back?
There... at the front.
Mmm.
Any pain in the back?
[MR BRADLEY'S VOICE GETTING WEAKER]
Yes.
Where's she gone?
Where's who gone?
My wife.
I haven't seen her.
She's probably somewhere around.
She's not ill?
No.
But I've got it.
Haven't I?
You're showing some of the symptoms...
...but, we'll catch it early.
There's no real worry at this stage.
We'll get you to hospital...
...and you can have a thorough check-up.
All right. You can go ahead, now.
And... keep your distance.
When did you last visit Bath, Mr Bradley?
Can't remember.
It would be helpful if you tried.
Was it within the past two weeks?
Came from Ireland....
...a month ago.
Yes, but Bath?
Three... weeks.
I'm going to name four places.
Please try and remember if you've
visited any of them recently.
The Sombrero Coffee Bar?
[OMINOUS MUSIC]
The Pump Room?
Theatre Royal?
Colonnade Restaurant?
Theatre... Royal.
There was a pantomime on. Do you remember?
He's a Royal.
We'd better get hold of his wife...
...she'll be a primary contact.
Go down and telephone...
...see if the ambulance has left.
- I'm not finished yet.
- That's an order, Bennett.
While you've been here...
...has your wife borrowed the car at all?
Sometimes.
What's your wife's first name, Mr Bradley?
Tell me...
...if I've got the disease.
- I want to know.
- This woman...
...we'll call her your wife.
Her name's Ruth, isn't it?
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
[RADIO ANNOUNCER]
"There is still no news of Mrs Bradley..."
"...a guest..."
[RADIO ANNOUNCER]
"...from The Crossings Hotel on the..."
"...outskirts of Bath..."
[RADIO ANNOUNCER]
"...who disappeared after being involved..."
"...in a car accident..."
[RADIO ANNOUNCER]
"...yesterday afternoon."
You've no right to be out of bed, Mrs Monks.
- You - of all people!
- I feel so good, Carol!
Well, you won't do if you carry on like this.
Besides which you'll get me into trouble with the...
- ...prison governor.
- With who?
Well, we call this the "Big House" now...
...and we're all serving a stretch.
Matron's the governor...
...the doctor's are warders...
...and, in solitary tonight, there's...
...fish or shepherd's pie.
- Um... shepherds pie!
- Right.
[JAZZY MUSIC PLAYS ON THE RADIO]
What are you doing?
Flying!
Don't you ever fly, Clifford?
Not often.
It's only because I feel so much better...
...and I'm not going to die.
What have you been crying for?
Dear life.
Lie down a minute.
Has Steven been to see you?
He said he'll come this evening.
I'm crying for that, too. Is that stupid?
No.
I suppose being happy is like being tight.
Unless others are tight, too, you're just a bore.
You're not happy, Clifford.
Hasn't she telephoned yet?
No.
She knows how busy you are.
Yes.
I think Ruth is so right to stay
up in London, Clifford.
There's nothing she can...
- ...do here, I mean, if she was.
- It doesn't matter that she hasn't phoned me.
Oh? What does matter, then?
She's not faithful.
I see.
It doesn't come as a shock to you?
Infidelity?
You forget I'm an infidel.
Well, you must have faith in something?
In people, at least?
You've been cooped up here too long, Clifford.
Just because Ruth is...
...free and away from you...
- ...in London, doesn't mean that she's---
- No, it isn't that.
I... know it's true.
I suspected it long ago.
And when I couldn't bear with it any more...
...I asked the man.
That was brave of you.
No.
He's not a bad man, you see.
- And he said it was true?
- Yes.
That was brave of him.
Or he may not care.
People should care.
They MUST care!
Doctor Monks to see you, Mrs Monks.
[SMASHING GLASS]
Your wife's much better.
Hello, Steven.
Hello. How do you feel?
Well, you can see the effect you have on me.
All right, Nurse - we'll do that later.
[TINKLING OF GLASS]
Very good, Doctor.
Oh, Steve. It's so good to see you.
What was all that about?
Has, er...
...he been upsetting you?
Not really. He's worried about Ruth.
Can you sit down, or don't you have time?
Mmm... what about Ruth?
He was telling me she'd been unfaithful.
There's no reason for him to upset you about it!
- He must be out of his mind.
- Yes, I think he is.
He can keep his problems to himself...
...while you're trying to get better, or...
...exercise them on somebody else.
Maguire, anybody - but not you.
[TINKLING OF GLASS]
Did you know about Ruth?
Yes.
I guessed it, too.
Did you?
Does he think she's playing around in London?
Yes, I expect so.
Well, tell me what's happening?
Happening?
Yes, in town. I hear there's another...
...carrier. What's her name, Mrs Bradley?
Her husband's a new case, isn't he?
Yes.
You don't want to talk about that.
I know, but you came to talk to me and...
...cheer me up, so I'm just trying to help.
[JULIE GIVES A LITTLE LAUGH]
I used to see the strangers...
...in the ward on visitor's day...
...curled up with embarrassment with...
...one eye on the clock and...
...the relief on their faces when the time was up!
Come on - into bed.
I saw one man jam his hat on and run.
They found him later in the nurses' room...
...because he'd lost his way in his hurry.
He was madly in love with his wife.
They'd only been married a year.
And he was off like a shot...
...when the time was up.
And his poor little wife was in tears about it, well...
...she was a post-caesar and a bit weepy, anyway.
When they told her that he'd been...
...dragged out of the nurses' room
she was hysterical!
So, if they find you in the nurses' room later,
darling, I won't cut up rough.
You should tell me to shut up, Steve,
untll you're less busy.
[GENTLE ROMANTIC MUSIC]
Julie, are you...
...when this is over, are you coming home?
I haven't been very certain that
you wanted me home.
That's why I'm asking.
With things on your mind, Steve, you...
...weren't very easy to get through to any more.
Am I so... difficult to understand?
You're a very private person, Steve.
People think you have no heart...
...because you don't flash it around.
Only thing is, it makes it difficult for me...
...to get through to you when I must!
And there are times when I must
because I love you.
I want you back, Julie.
Thanks.
I'll, er...
...try and have the place cleaned up a bit.
[STEVEN GIVES A LITTLE LAUGH]
Er, Mrs Chalmers never waters anything...
...but I've, um...
...looked after your pink cyclamen...
...and it's going strong.
I'm a bit weepy, I'm sorry.
Well, you'll feel better if I go.
Yes, I-I can enjoy my cry!
[MR BRADLEY MUMBLES INCOHERENTLY]
That should settle him down for the next two hours.
Am I disturbing you?
Shall I call you or Sister if necessary?
I'll be on call.
Somebody telephoned about...
...ten minutes ago, Doctor, asking about him.
She wouldn't give her name.
If he regains consciousness, tell him, please.
Meanwhile, spray the nose, mouth and throat...
...and keep up with the compresses.
[MR BRADLEY MUTTERING]
No...
I understand he refused to see Father Maguire.
But if it becomes necessary, you
could ask him to come here.
[MR BRADLEY CONTINUES TO BABBLE]
Doctor Monks, this woman's been
exposed to gross contamination.
Wherever she goes, she's a
menace to human life.
If you're quite sure about this thing...
...I think Doctor preston should be told.
Look, if I thought it would help us to find her...
...I'd tell him. But it won't!
He must have some idea.
No, he hasn't. He thinks she's still in London.
- Where in London?
- I don't know.
I tried to ask, but...
...I-I can't press the point.
Mr Buckridge...
...Doctor Preston is doing four men's work...
...up at the hospital. He's as tired and...
...exhausted as you and I.
God knows what this'd do to him, right now.
You see, I'm not used to this sort of thing.
- I'm sorry for Doctor Preston.
- Well, then, let's try and help him!
What I don't understand...
...she's...
...she's a doctor's wife!
She must realise she's a carrier.
Why run away?
Because there were people coming from here.
People who might recognise her.
She must be staying somewhere, with someone?
I believe she's isolated herself
of her own free will.
- Then she's mad!
- No... desperate.
She left her jewellery - everything - when she fled.
I think she's keeping away from people...
...till she knows whether she's infected or not.
Yet according to you she's just
used the telephone.
Leaving the virus on the mouthpiece...
...the flex---
[A KNOCK ON THE DOOR]
What is it?
You asked for more coffee.
Oh, did I?
- Doctor?
- No, no, thanks.
Have you finished with the tray?
Is the new master list ready?
Oh, the stencils are cut...
...but Mr Collins said not to run them...
...until Doctor Boswell got back.
Why?
In case he had anything new to add.
You tell Mr Collins...
...no, I'll tell him.
While this woman is at large...
...we're sitting on a volcano.
But, I'll go along with you.
Thank you.
Up to a point.
If I tell anyone her real name...
...it'll be because it'll help to trace her.
- That's all I can promise.
- That's all I can ask.
I know, I'm late.
Hello, Steve. You look terrible!
Let me return the compliment.
I had to deal with a fire, coming back.
Fire?! Anyone hurt?
No, just an A.A. box.
- An A.A. box?
- Yes.
What happened at The Crossings Hotel?
We filled it with formaline and sealed it up...
...moved the family to a vacant house.
Where was this A.A. box?
Up at The Crossings.
Yeah, what about that family?
Well, you've met them, haven't you?
Wanted the dogs vaccinated, too.
You should have seen...
- ...Scott-James' face---
- Tim, was there a telephone?
What?
In that box?
Yes... that's about all there was.
Four gutted uprights and a smashed telephone.
Probably some irate member.
I think Doctor Monks...
...believes it might have been Mrs Bradley.
Are you serious?
A woman telephoned the hospital
asking for Bradley.
She wouldn't leave her name.
The operator thought it came from a call box.
But why should Mrs Bradley set...
- ...fire to a call box?
- It's a drastic measure of disinfection...
...knowing it might have been contaminated.
Well, that's presuming the woman...
- ...has some knowledge---
- Do we have to presume she hasn't?
It's a theory, Tim!
If we want to find this woman...
- ...we shouldn't sneer at theories.
- All right, Steve - simmer!
We'll let the police comb over the whole area.
Maybe the Army will help, too.
A Sergeant's calling you...
- ...from downstairs, Doctor.
- Anything to add before we run, sir?
Yes, Smiths.
Doctor Monks.
There's a lady wishing to see you, Doctor.
Well, outside, sitting in a car.
She wouldn't give her name.
Just said it was personal and very urgent.
I'll be down.
Dear God, no!
Pardon me!
[CHURCH BELL RINGING IN THE DISTANCE]
Doctor Monks?
Doctor Steven Monks?
That's right.
Can we talk in here?
It's about Ruth.
Ruth Preston.
Where is she?
I was hoping you could tell me!
Are you a friend of Ruth's?
Joanna Druten. I've known her for ages.
So naturally I've... heard about you.
I see.
I'm sure I can talk in confidence?
You can.
When did you last see her?
New Year's Day.
Well, she arrived at my place, in London.
She was depressed and hungover and wanted...
- ...to stay the night.
- Mmm... I'm ahead of you.
When she heard about the outbreak...
...she told everybody she was still with you, and...
...came down here to stay with Bradley
at The Crossings Hotel.
How much of this do you already know?
It doesn't matter - I know Ruth.
She told me where she was, so that I...
...could cover for her from my end.
When did she meet him?
- Brad?
- Mmm.
Oh, years ago.
It was a big thing.
Then it suddenly broke up and he went abroad.
And now they've met again.
Mmm, two months ago.
So when they broadcast for "Mrs Bradley"...
- ...you knew who they meant.
- Well, I was frantic!
I rang the hotel...
...they said that everybody had left...
...and they were sealing the place up.
I couldn't ring Clifford.
No.
So I came down here to see you.
The whole thing's pretty messy, isn't it?
Yes.
But necessity drives us a long way.
If I hear anything I'll let you know.
Thank you. Joanna Druten - I'm in the book.
I wish I didn't feel so hellishly responsible.
We have a lot in common.
[OMINOUS MUSIC]
[DOGS BARKING]
As there have been no new cases...
...for, uh, nearly a week, would you say you've...
...beaten the epidemic, Mr Buckridge?
There are four more days of infection period.
If we stay in the clear that long...
...then I think we can say we've beaten it.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
Any optimistic hope that we're on...
...top of this epidemic is madness...
...until we find Mrs Bradley!
Do you know for certain she's infected?
Sharing her husband's bed, I'd say
it's almost a certainty.
So by now she must be dangerously ill.
[TELEpHONE RINGS]
Yeah.
What I don't get is why she...
- ...doesn't want treatment.
- Right. thank you.
It's very odd.
Very odd.
Is it another one?
No.
Bradley's died.
See that his name is changed to
the proper column.
That makes it seventeen.
Housewife, doorman, debutante...
...typesetter, prostitute, stockbroker.
But the urns are all the same shape.
Buckridge.
Bad news?
I came to let you know - I've decided to tell Preston.
That's the best news I've heard for three weeks.
I had no right to try meddling in his affairs.
Now he can let the police have
something for their dogs.
A glove or a shoe.
- It's a hell of a time afterwards, but---
- Mmm... I should have told him...
...before - as soon as I knew.
As a friend, it was generous of
you to try and shield him.
Generous?
Yes, I'm always generous to my friends.
- Do you have a cigarette?
- Here.
Officially, it's my job to tell him...
...but he's a Catholic, isn't he?
[STEVEN EXHALES LOUDLY]
What's the difference?
Well, perhaps Father Maguire could do it.
I'm not trying to get out of it...
...but Father Maguire could...
- ...give him strength---
- I'll tell him myself.
And the dogs can have their glove.
It's not only that.
By God, it's not!
- Let me get hold of Father Maguire.
- Damn Father Maguire!
Well, I expect you'll be going home shortly, Mrs Monks?
Tonight.
Oh, as soon as that?
Pulled a bit of rank. Doctor's wife.
In capable hands.
- And does he know the glad news?
- Not yet.
Think he wants me there.
He said so.
- Aren't you sure?
- Yes.
Just saying it aloud, I suppose.
Like looking at a present again.
Do you mind being out here?
I've been shut up for so long.
Well, you deserve your happiness, I must say.
I don't think so.
I was a dreary wife.
[FATHER MAGUIRE GIVES A LITTLE LAUGH]
Being a doctor's wife...
...isn't easy.
Oh, I ran things competently, if
that's what you mean.
I didn't wink at the man next door.
It's not important, really.
Well, some people think it is.
You mean people like Clifford?
They didn't have a chance, those two.
Why is he so surprised that Ruth
does those things?
Poor Clifford. He's so good, yet so naive.
His very perfection alone must have driven her away.
Well, it could have inspired her instead, couldn't it?
She wanted to be treated as a human...
...he tried to make a saint out of her.
And do you think he should justify...
...her infidelity, by calling it "human"?
Not "justify". Try to understand, and then help.
And would you condone infidelity...
...in your own marriage partner...
...on the same grounds...
...of human weakness?
- Is that Sister Durrell, please?
- No, it's Nurse Monks.
Oh, I'm sorry, we're looking for Sister Durrell.
Hey, are you allowed to be out?
Coming in right away.
Well, I mustn't keep you.
Your question wasn't very subtle, Father.
It stuck out like a sore thumb.
Ruth told me about it one night.
She was rather tight.
She didn't actually say it happened...
...but I knew.
The whole thing meant nothing to her...
...it was just an incident.
Yes, but it was more than an incident
to you, wasn't it?
Oh, at the time, yes. It was a shock to my...
...ego, and an affront to my dignity.
Then all this...
...the long hours lying in bed...
...trying to make sense of the news...
...that I wasn't going to die!
And then suddenly, everything came into focus.
That if he'd really wanted Ruth instead of me...
...he would have gone to her.
I've had nine years with Steven...
...most of them happy. Ruth has had an affair.
I must go now.
Yes... yes.
Well, I told you this, Father Maguire...
...because it worried you.
You think broadly for a woman.
Have you known many women, Father?
Mmm... are you taking the Confessional?
I'm sorry.
I don't understand.
It's not Bradley's wife.
It's Ruth.
You mean it was Ruth at that hotel
with Bradley? Ruth?
Yes.
- Staying with him at the hotel?
- Yes!
No!
Not Ruth!
Then it's all gone.
Everything.
All gone!
We'll find her soon.
How long have you known?
Since I brought Bradley in.
Well, why didn't you tell me before?
I should have.
Why didn't you?
Why?
You couldn't have done anything, Clifford.
Except go and look for her.
I've been to look for her every day.
Once in the night, after the police had gone.
Why didn't you tell me?
You couldn't have done anything, Clifford.
He never talked about his wife.
We wondered about that.
She meant nothing to him.
But did he know who I was? Did he?
No, I don't think so.
What have I done?
Why couldn't I help her more?
Nobody could help her.
She said once she came to "tap" my virtues.
Wasn't it an odd way of putting it, Steven?
"To tap my virtues."
Well, I knew what she meant.
I was so sure I could help her.
She took our faith and... for a time---
Does Father Maguire know?
No.
He would have told you himself.
You look tired, Steven.
You people outside are working...
- ...harder than we are.
- She met him...
- ...by chance, Clifford.
- Yes...
- It wouldn't have happened if---
- ...yes. Yes it would!
She's Ruth!
I'm sorry for Bradley.
Why must you always...
- ...pity the people who---
- You don't understand, do you?
Not pity them?
How can you not pity them?
Do these things make them happy?
Was she happy with you?
No.
I'm afraid the police will want to
publish a photograph of her.
And you might let them have something of hers
for the dogs to get a scent from.
There'll be a lot of morbid interest, I'm afraid.
You may decide not to help them.
Not help them to find Ruth?
It won't be very easy for you.
You don't really think the scandal worries me?
Then you must get in touch with them.
Thank you for coming to tell me.
I'm sorry it was so difficult for you, but...
...you see, it was shock.
Post-operative shock.
[CLIFFORD BREAKS DOWN CRYING]
Sorry... I had no idea.
Steven?
Julie?
Is that Julie in there?
What other nurse calls you "Steven"?
I'm obviously at the wrong session.
Seven to eight... woman's hour.
That's what the board said.
That board's right.
I wasn't thinking.
Are you going right through?
I mean to the Clean Room.
Are you going home?
I should never have left in the first place.
It was cowardly of me letting you cope
like that. Please forgive me.
Forgive you?
Forgive you?!
You see, martyrs sometimes follow the wrong cause.
Julie, when they first brought you here, and I...
- ...thought you were going to die---
- That's past, Steve.
There was so much I wanted to say, but I...
...panicked, and---
Well, thank you and goodnight!
Yes, you... out!
- May I say in my defence---
- You can say it to Matron...
[TELEpHONE RINGING]
If you're not out of---
Sorry, Doctor.
No, you're absolutely right.
And that'll be Matron agreeing with you!
Come on.
Get your clothes on...
...and let the men have a go.
[AUXILIARY ON THE pHONE]
"Yes... just a moment, please."
A call for you, Doctor.
Right.
What will he think of me?
Yes, Doctor Monks here.
Hello, Steven.
I just wanted to talk to someone.
Ruth!
[RUTH ON TELEpHONE]
"Yes."
Well, where are you?
[RUTH ON TELEpHONE]
"It doesn't matter, Steven."
Julie!
But it does matter, Ruth.
I've got to talk to you.
It's Ruth.
Find another phone - trace this call!
Can you hear me, Ruth?
I'm a little tight, Steve.
Because it's so lonely here.
I'm gonna die.
[STEVEN ON THE TELEPHONE]
"You may not, Ruth - with help."
I just wanted someone to know.
I loved Brad.
He was the first man I ever really loved.
And he's dead.
That's pretty rough, even for a witch like me.
Steve, you there?
[STEVEN ON THE TELEPHONE]
"I'm here."
You don't mind knowing, do you?
I'm glad you called me, Ruth.
Now, I want you to do something for me.
Give me a chance to help you.
[RUTH ON TELEpHONE]
"Sweet of you, but some other time."
Crossings Hotel.
- Crossings!
- I've told the police.
Now listen, Ruth...
...listen carefully.
I'm coming to help you.
It's too late, old boy...
...I've got a wonderful rash.
Nobody can say I'm not fashionable.
You'll have to go through again...
...quick, before me.
[RUTH ON TELEpHONE]
"Steven, don't go away..."
"...don't leave me, Steve."
I haven't left you.
It's... getting cold.
It's dark here.
[STEVEN ON TELEPHONE]
"I'm coming to help you."
"Do you understand that?"
Dear old boy.
I'll miss you.
Poor Steven.
That wasn't much of an evening I gave you...
...but you said you understood.
Yes, I understood.
Finished!
[RUTH'S VOICE GETS WEAKER]
Of all the people who...
...made my life worth...
...getting through...
...you, Steven...
...you and Julie.
Oh, God!
Ruth...
...loves...
...Brad!
[BANG AND CRASH AS RUTH FALLS
DOWN THE STAIRS]
Ruth?
[POLICE CAR BELLS RINGING]
What happened?
It was well alight when I got here.
Were they... able to---
No.
The trouble is...
...it's been boarded up.
They thought it was empty.
[SOLEMN MUSIC STARTS PLAYING]
At least it's the way she chose.
I'm sorry for Clifford.
There was a time when you couldn't
feel anything for Clifford.
That was a long while ago.
Not so long.
It was before I heard you were
going to be all right.
All new things began from there.
We're going to be all right, aren't we, Steve?
Yes.
We're going to be all right.
[HOPEFUL MUSIC - END THEME]