The story
begins on Lake Como,
many years ago during
that last fantastic Summer
before the war.
Hello.
Returning
to the lake
has always seemed
like coming home.
Everyone is so friendly.
Everyone is welcome.
The Villa Barbianello
basks all day
in the lakeside sun,
which is hotter than usual
for late April.
Oh! Oh, it's always
you running away!
Buon giorno,
Miss Bentley.
To Bellinzona to fetch
the new nanny.
Oh, of course.
I totally forgot.
I hope she's strictly.
When will you
be back?
Tomorrow afternoon,
in time for a nice cup
of tea. Hmm?
I'll miss you at dinner.
Arrivederci,
Miss Bentley.
Likewise, Miss Bentley.
Toodle-oo!
Arrivederci!
Bye!
Father and I
came here every Summer
for 16 years.
In a way I'm surprised
that the place is still here.
It should have died with him.
So far, I'm the only
English guest.
Quite alone.
Until today that is.
We have a new arrival.
I like his ears.
Did you
visit Oxford?
Oh, yes, it was
just perfect.
Oh, no, no.
Yes, I think my most
favorite English city
of all is Oxford.
It's lovely the way the
river flows through it.
Oh, and that beautiful bridge.
And the swans.
I want that bridge for my garden.
It might prove
a little awkward at customs.
She's gonna be wanting
a thatched roof next!
So, tell me, Major,
just exactly where
are you from?
I mean, what city
in England ?
Oh!
No, the man in the hat.
He's inglese.
Um, Major Wilshaw.
Grazie.
Buon giorno, Enrico.
Buon giorno,
Signorina Bentley.
A small cup of
coffee, please.
Thank you.
Major Wilshaw...
Wilshire. Yes.
Excuse me.
I wondered
if I could just look
at your newspaper.
I won't keep it.
I just wanted to
look something up.
Do, by all means.
It's, uh, last week's,
I'm afraid.
Oh, I'm used to being
behind the times.
Is it doing well?
Hmm?
The financial index.
Oh!
Better than of late.
Thank you.
No, no.
Will you join me?
Oh, I don't wish
to intrude.
No, no, you're not.
Nice to hear spoken
English again.
Well, you were surrounded
by English last night.
Yes, American
Not quite the same thing.
Why, there used to be
so many of US here.
You've obviously
been before.
Yes, many times.
So where are they?
I don't know.
Talk of war,
I suppose.
You staying long?
Well, I don't know.
Family at home?
Heavens.
A lot of questions.
Hmm.
Sorry. It was
very rude of me.
Oh, I must be off.
I'll be late.
Thank you so much
for the coffee.
No, no, not at all.
Um...drink this evening?
So 7:30?
Oh! Thank you.
Tell me, Major,
why do you...
Carry 2 tennis rackets?
Oooh, you never know
who might like a game.
I'm going to
stay here another month.
I've always had a thing
about men's ears,
and I'm quite transfixed
by Major Wilshaw's.
He has the ears of a gentle
and kind man.
I wonder if I'm right.
Hello.
Miss Bentley!
Oh, ha ha!
Welcome back!
Thank you.
Miss Bentley, I'm pleased
to introduce to you
enchanting new addition
to our happy family--
Miss Beaumont.
Uh,
excuse me, ladies.
I must go
to change myself
before dinner.
Well, you-you're not
quite what I imagined.
Old and starchy?
Well, um, you are
rather unsevere.
You haven't seen me
in action.
Oh. Well.
I'm sorry
to be a bother,
but you don't have
anything to eat, do you?
I'm famished.
Well, um, there's a piece
of Kendal mint cake,
if you'd like.
It's all I've got left,
I'm afraid.
Whatever.
You better come in.
Sorry about the mess.
Here. Here we are.
Did you have far to come?
No. Switzerland.
Finishing school.
Finished me nearly.
After a couple of terms,
I just left.
And you didn't want
to go back to America?
My mother's
not ready for me yet.
I've been exiled to Europe
for the school year,
and that's that.
But a nanny?
It wasn't my idea,
I assure you.
Are you
a photographer?
Well, that's a matter
of opinion.
Cigarette?
No thanks.
So what's
it like here?
Well, I love it,
but then I'm not
as young as you.
Well...I'm sure I'll find
something to occupy myself.
I do hope so.
I would so hate
for you to be bored.
Dinner soon.
I'd better go.
Thanks for
keeping me going.
Ah, there you are!
I am.
I wondered where
you got to.
We were going to
meet for a drink.
Well, I assume it
was an invitation,
not a summons.
Oh, dear.
Now I've made you cross.
Hmm?
Your ears
have gone bright red.
What?
I've made a study of ears.
Yours are definitely cross.
What utter nonsense,
Miss Bentley.
Hmm. I'm flattered,
Major .
You know my name.
Ah, Miss Bentley.
Buona sera!
Buona sera.
No, no, we bring them too,
and I can't cope.
Oh, they're cherubs--
heavenly creatures!
Aren't I right,
Signora Bonizzoni ?
Why not?
Bon appetit!
Grazie.
Julia...
Buona notte!
We've not been
introduced.
My name is Wilshaw.
Major Wilshaw.
How do you do?
Beaumont, Miss.
French name.
Gallic blood?
Yes, but on
my mother's side.
Staying long?
A few days.
I'm not
staying long myself.
Back to your wife?
Uh...alas, no.
Come along, angels!
Angels? Do these angels
believe in magic, I wonder?
Whoo!
Ha ha!
Delightful.
Now, we've had a long day
and we must go to bed.
Buona notte, Major
Buona notte!
Buona notte.
Miss Bentley,
would you be so kind
to take these 2 ladies
to the Lido, so they
will not be lost?
With pleasure.
Ciao.
Morning, Major
Good game?
Good morning!
Not much competition.
My word.
Pray, that good?
Well, shortage of partners,
in fact.
Do you play?
Oh, not
for years. Heh.
I'll give you a game,
if you like.
Oh,
I don't know.
Go on,
Miss Bentley.
Don't be shy.
I'll book a court then.
This afternoon suit you?
Root for Miss Bentley!
We're rooting
for you, dear.
Ok.
Did you ask them?
Just being friendly.
I wish it weren't
quite so public.
I shall be
very gentle.
Rough or smooth?
Uh, smooth.
Rough.
Me to serve.
Right, let's play!
Prego, Signora .
Ohh, grazie.
Sorry.
Heh.
Sorry!
Ohh! Ha ha ha!
Bravo!
30-love!
But I didn't know
we were scoring yet!
Of course!
Ohh ho ho ho ho!
Bravo! Ha ha!
Yes!
Sorry.
40-15!
Out!
40-30.
Yes!
Deuce. Sorry!
Sorry!
Will you please
stop saying that?
Aah!
Nice.
Miss Bentley!
Whoo hoo hoo!
Aaah!
Are you all right?
We'll get it later.
Oh, no, we won't.
Ball, please!
Listen, I never said
I couldn't play.
I just said I hadn't
played for years!
It doesn't matter!
It seems to matter
very much!
And you attracted
those wretched Italians!
I didn't know they were
going to be there
any more than I knew
about your lot!
Well, you
encouraged them!
Oh, piffle!
I tell her
time and again
not to touch the water.
Drink it boiled,
and time and again,
I catch her putting
her glass to her lips,
ready to die
for her big-headedness.
Their sanitation
is not like ours.
I mean, it isn't.
Good evening.
Oh, heh heh.
And how was your day?
Just perfect,
Major.
Oh, I'm so glad.
Oh, how nice
to see you.
Major
Bellagio.
Day return, please.
1 and 1/2, please.
Thank you.
Ah.
Hmm.
Buon giorno, Signora
We'll pretend
I haven't seen you,
if you like.
Bit late for that,
isn't it?
Sorry. Heh.
Pax?
Pax.
Ohh, thank goodness.
Beautiful.
My father
adored this lake.
Oh, so that's
who you came here with.
He painted every view
imaginable. Heh.
I do a spot of painting
myself when I've the time.
He was a good artist.
Nothing very bohemian.
Society portraits,
and houses, horses,
you know,
that sort of thing.
He--he was
painting a duchess
the evening he died.
The next morning,
she demanded
her money back.
But he wouldn't
have found
anything odd
in that.
Ha. But you did.
Yeah.
Was that long ago?
January. He'd been
ill for years.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Your mother?
Oh, she ran off
when I was a child.
I couldn't even
describe her. Heh.
On your own, then?
You're inquisitive,
Major.
Well, does it matter?
My father taught me
it's better to observe
than to be observed.
In your case, that's
a wasteful philosophy.
Never trust
flattery.
You should try.
You're not a bad sort,
Miss Bentley.
Well, that's a compliment
I can understand.
We ought to keep
an eye on the tide.
It's three o’clock
The steamer leaves
at ten to four
Well, we don't want
to get too late.
It's the last one.
Hands and the ears.
The bane
of father's life.
He could never
get them right.
You can tell so much
about someone
by their ears.
Yes. Mine,
for instance--
red.
Ha ha ha!
Only when you're angry.
But they're really
very nice.
Ahh.
I think we ought
to be getting back.
Oh, it's
so peaceful here.
Mm.
What'd you say
the time was?
It's three o’clock exactly!
No, it's five to four!
But my watch
keeps perfect time.
Sit down!
Oh, God!
I forgot to wind it.
Miss Bentley,
will you sit down?!
Don't go so fast!
You try
to keep up!
I can't! It's miles!
You have
another suggestion?
Signora,
where you go?
Sorry?
Are you lost?
We missed the boat.
My fault.
It's a long way to walk.
I give you a ride.
Well, I--
I don't know.
Your husband
can come with me!
I'm not
her husband!
Good God!
Major
you go with me!
No, I do not.
If you were sensible,
Miss Bentley,
you'd stay here with me!
I'm not halfway
sensible, Major!
Ha ha ha!
Bye-bye!
Bye!
Ciao!
Arrivederci!
Bye, now!
Driver!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
That man--
he is
your boyfriend?
Absolutely not!
He's not my type!
Uh-huh.
And I'm certainly
not his.
And who is your type?
Move over!
Move over, damn you!
Ah!
Oh, push over!
Hey, Enrico !
Whoo! Ohh!
Ay-ay-ay-ah!
Whoo-hoo! Ha ha!
Oh, wasn't that
breathtaking, Major ?
I haven't had
such excitement for years!
I knew you were an
odd one, Miss Bentley,
but this really
takes the cap.
Biscuit!
What?
Miss Bentley?
Miss Bentley--
Miss Bentley.
Maria.
What time is it?
11:00?
Ohh, crikey!
Where did these
come from?
"Pax again."
Pronti!
Lovely. Enrico
UN belle sorriso.
Heh.
Great.
Oh! Grazie.
Grazie.
Don't you want
to go upstairs?
Uh-uh.
Order me a gin.
I'll be right down.
Signora .
A gin and vermouth,
and a jug
of boiled water
with lots of ice.
I think it's only fair
to warn you,
the ice isn't made
with boiled water.
Miss Bentley,
I don't give a heck.
Oh! Hello.
How was the expedition?
We went down
to the village market
for this,
that, and the other.
We would've asked you
to join us, of course,
but you weren't
at breakfast.
I overslept,
I'm afraid.
You were
ever so thoughtful
to send
those flowers.
I think I should've
sent some to you.
I lose my sense of humor
sometimes.
Ha.
Well, I shall miss this place.
Well, not for
a while yet, I hope.
Yes, yes,
I'm off in the morning.
But you--you've
only just arrived.
Besides, you fit in
so well here. Heh.
Well, it's very kind
of you to say so,
but it's all arranged,
I'm afraid.
Then unarrange it.
Life's not that simple,
Miss Bentley.
Would that it were.
I tell you what, though.
As a peace offering,
would you do me
the great honor
of dining with me
tonight?
Oh, thank you. Yes,
that would be lovely.
Good.
7:30?
Uh...heh.
I don't often make
the same mistake twice.
Miss Bentley,
come and join us.
Buona sera,
Miss Bentley.
Ciao.
Come on.
Ahhhhhh.
You'll like it.
Penny?
Shilling, then.
Heh. So, you will
leave tomorrow?
I'm afraid so.
Work beckons,
and all that.
But I'm not sure
that the business
doesn't run itself better
when I'm away.
Perhaps you like to feel
you're needed.
Well, it's only recently
that I've allowed myself
to leave it at all.
Can't you stay
a little longer?
No, I've made my plans,
and I must
stick to them.
Don't, um,
don't you have any reason
for going back
to England ?
None whatsoever.
Tell me,
were you never married?
No. Uh, yes,
I would've been,
but he already had
a wife.
Fourteen years
that went on.
Became such a habit
that when she died,
well, I suppose
he couldn't face--
anyway, I never
saw him again.
Were you
ever married?
Before the war, I was
engaged to be married,
but by the time
it was all over,
that had changed.
One lost a lot of friends
in the war,
and, uh,
I found it hard
to make attachments
after that.
It seems we've both
been unlucky in love.
Mm.
Perhaps we should stick
to tennis.
Major ,
your carriage awaits!
Good gracious me.
What on earth's going on?
Oh, I couldn't let
my friend go in a taxi.
No, no, no, no, no.
Ha ha.
Today it will be
my pleasure
to take you
to the station myself.
Why, that's terribly
kind of you.
Quite sure?
It's a long way.
You will be doing me
a favor.
My family this morning
are going to the Lido,
which, you know,
I do not enjoy.
Uh, Miss Bentley,
do you like to come with us
to say "cheerio"?
Oh, no, thank you. I'm not
very good at all that.
Never mind.
Uh, Major, we depart,
or we miss your train.
Indeed.
So, good-bye, then.
I suppose it is.
Scusi!
Ciao.
Grazie.
Prego.
Major !
Dear Major,
I'm so sorry you're going
before we've had a chance
to get to know each other.
Such a waste.
Here.
Souvenir.
Better not miss your train!
No.
Arrivederci!
That was a cruel
thing to do.
What do you mean? He went
away happy, didn't he?
He took you
seriously.
Finish?
Sì, finito.
No.
Meringata?
Crema di amaretti?
No, thanks.
No hungry?
Mm-mm.
No good.
Too thin.
Hello.
Major  !
Major !
Major, are you there?!
Oh.
I'm--I'm sorry. Um...
Wrong room.
Scusate. Sbagliate.
I thought you'd mistaken
the time of your train.
No, no, I didn't.
Oh, you
unarranged things, then?
Are you all right?
Yes, perfectly.
Oh, good. Heh.
So, are you going
to tell me?
Tell you what?
Well, something
changed your mind.
Ohh, yes.
Well, you know,
an unexpected impulse,
I suppose.
You probably
don't have such things.
Oh, come on, Major.
You and I have wild,
unconquerable desires.
Yes, but one that stops you
dead in your tracks,
like a voice.
Do--
I'm not sure i--
do you feel that--
what? Sorry.
Do I feel what?
That life has
a predetermined pattern?
Lordy, I hope not.
So how long
will you stay
now that you're back?
Won't you be missed?
No, not really.
I have my own business,
you see.
Industrial engineering,
light metal, and so forth.
No, it more or less
runs itself nowadays.
I assumed
you were in the army.
Yes. Sappers--
long time ago.
So perhaps you should
stay a whole month.
At least until another
impulse strikes you.
Well...
Yeah, we'll see.
Hey, presto!
Ah!
Surprised
to see me?
That trick's
already in danger
of becoming stale.
Know what you said when
I left this morning--
that we should get to know
each other properly?
Did I say that?
You did.
I remember every word.
Miss Beaumont,
how long are you staying for?
Oh, I really can't say.
Will you join me
for a drink this evening?
W-Well...
Major!
Miss Bentley.
Hello.
Ah! Hello.
Want anything
from town?
I'm just going
to pick up
a couple of things.
Must have something
new to wear
if I'm going to stay
another month.
No, no.
No, thanks.
Want me to take
the children?
Oh, would it be
too much trouble?
Oh,
absolutely not.
Uh, did--do--
Miss Beaumont!
They left an hour ago.
They've gone
for the day.
Hmm?
The Bonizzonis.
With Miss Beaumont,
of course.
I know. She told me.
You needn't have
got up so early.
Oh, well.
Can't sit around all day.
Major.
Buon giorno, Signora .
Just to let you know
that I shan't be in
for lunch today.
Are you going
somewhere nice?
Yes, I thought I'd take
the steamer for Menaggio.
Ah. Well, if you hurry,
you will catch
Miss Bentley.
Ah.
Is there a bus
for Trumetsa?
A bus?
Of course.
Hey, stop! Stop!
Oh, no!
You--oh!
Maggiore, I have
a message for you.
Shh, shh.
Grazie.
You waiting for someone?
Uh, yes,
Miss Beaumont.
She was coming down
for a swim at eleven o’clock.
What time is it now?
Oh, it's quarter past.
She hates getting up
on her day off.
Some people do, you know.
Yeah.
I don't suppose--
No.
You're asking me
to come for a swim?
Uh, yes.
Yes, I'm so sorry.
Uh, yes,
of course I am.
Ah.
Thank you.
Should we go?
There you are.
Where have you been?
Well, I've been
waiting since eleven o’clock
I--i thought you'd
changed your mind.
I've been here,
by the wretched boat,
where you said.
Oh, good lord, I--
I'm so sorry.
Well...if we're going.
I'm going to
grab some huts.
Be nice to him.
Be serious.
I think he may be,
that's all.
That's his funeral,
then.
Well, now you mention it,
he is getting on a bit.
I should introduce
him to my mother.
Sad, really.
A man that rich
going lonely to his grave.
Only two of them left,
I'm afraid.
Do you mind sharing?
Terribly sorry.
Liven things up a bit
in the evenings--
I thought I might
do a conjuring show.
Children are very keen
on the idea.
Might be rather fun,
what.
Hmm. Good idea.
You could make
one of us disappear.
Coming in?
It's a bit chilly.
I didn't know
you swam so well.
It's me, Vittorio,
you remember?
Oh, hello again.
Sit down.
Haven't seen you
at the Lido before.
How did you get
so brown?
You always come
in the mornings.
I usually come
in the afternoons
when you're napping.
Would you like to have
a drink with me?
I don't think my friend
would like it.
He can be
very jealous.
Well, it's good
to be jealous.
Well, I'm not sure.
You're much too close.
You like
the gardens, huh?
Yes.
Vittorio...Vittorio.
Maggiore and--
What's happening?
Excuse me.
Please let me through.
Signora fascista,
photograph, please.
Smile, please.
Hey!
Whoo! Ha!
Oh, you're hurt!
I--I'll take you
to my sister's house.
She will make it well.
She's a nurse.
Oh, no,
it's nothing.
It's not safe!
Quickly, Signorina,
we must go from here!
Quickly!
I'm perfectly all right.
You can let go now.
My sister is a doctor.
I really have to be
going back.
Why are you
always in a hurry?
I'm not!
Then do as you're told!
Sorella!
Prego.
Uh, I don't know
where she can be.
She has a very
masculine taste.
Oh, really,
I might have known.
Give me that key.
For heaven's sake,
I'm old enough
to be your mother.
English girls and
Italian men are good.
I am an English woman.
There's a difference.
Oh, crikey.
I am Italian.
Aah!
You will not regret.
Unh!
Signore Balsari.
You are definitely
not a gentleman!
Ah, you're very strong.
So are you,
but you won't hurt me.
You better give me
that key.
I do not
understand you.
Please.
So now you're going
back to your Major.
To make love to him?
Or does he prefer
the pretty girl--
the young one?
This is siesta time.
What do you think
they are doing?
Nothing like that,
I can assure you.
Your Major ...
He would be very angry
if he thought
you had been with me.
I don't think
he'd believe it.
Yes, but I'm sure
he would be jealous.
Would you be
so interested in him
if this girl is not there?
Yes.
Yes?
Well, no.
No.
I don't know.
You want
I should tell him?
Oh, don't you dare.
I try only to help.
Scusa.
Mama!
Vittorio,
how would you like to have
your photograph taken?
Why?
Never mind why.
I like taking photographs.
All right. All right!
Over there.
There?
There.
This is not my room.
This is my friend's,
guido.
Papa--my papa--
he makes motor tires
in Milano.
He has a big contract
for the army.
So when the war comes,
we will be many times
millionaire.
I'm sure.
You know Hatfield?
A little village
near London?
Heh. For one year
we lived there.
I had a good time.
Incredible.
English girls.
Tell me--
why so many
are called "Doris"?
Beautiful.
Well, I'm not,
so don't expect me
to tell you.
It's finished?
Already?
Mm-hmm.
You come again?
Don't think so.
Thank you.
Ooh, I must be off.
With a bit of luck,
they'll be wondering
where I've got to.
You want I take you there?
Mm.
Oh, yes. Yes.
Yes!
Hey!
Oh, Miss Bentley.
Are you all right?
Yes, of course I am.
We wonder
what happen to you.
Major said you disappeared
from the beach,
and then there was
a big parade.
We imagine--
oh, I don't know.
It was so unlike you.
I even phoned the police.
Oh, you needn't have.
You're so kind.
Honestly, I can
look after myself.
I'm sure you can.
I'm happy
you're not afraid.
But me--
me, I am afraid.
Of so many things.
So many things.
But whatever happens
to us all,
I want you to know
this will always be
your home.
Signora, thank you.
Si, si.
Si, Signora.
You disappeared rather
swiftly this morning.
Did I?
I thought so.
I didn't want to be
the gooseberry.
I don't know
what you mean.
The three of us
went off together,
and so I thought...
Then you weren't
at lunch, either.
No, I was at a cafe.
With your young
Italian friend?
Yes.
He's rather nice.
Hmm.
I didn't think
you were a pickup.
He's what
thousands of women
would give
their eyeteeth for.
Well, I find it most
surprising in you.
He's a boy.
Miss Beaumont's
hardly antique.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Well, I'm sorry
I made you angry.
You didn't.
We were simply worried,
that's all.
Quite understandably,
as it turned out,
with these political
shenanigans going on.
You might've been
hurt, you know.
Miss Bentley,
the conjuring show--
I really need
a collaborator
for one of the tricks.
Ooh.
What does it entail?
Well, I thought that
we might rehearse it
a bit tomorrow night.
Oh.
Oh, I can't tomorrow night.
I'm dining in Como
with my Italian boy.
Hello?
Come in.
Oh, Major.
Signore Bonizzoni
is waiting for us
in the car.
He sent me up to see
if you were ready.
I'm trying to get these
wretched children dressed.
Angeli, button it,
or I'll choke you
to death.
Do you think
we should wake her up?
Oh, let her sleep.
She must need it
after yesterday.
Poor old dear
must be exhausted.
"Old dear"?
Hmm.
Little cow.
Hello.
I've wondered
where you've been.
I haven't seen you
all day.
Well, you spent most
of the day with the Major.
He tells me you're
off to Como for dinner.
Oh, news travels fast.
Gosh!
Did you take those?
Uh-huh.
You hot ticket, you.
Oh, whoever
would've thought it.
I insist you give me
all the details.
I'll tell you everything
later, my dear girl,
but not now.
You'll make me late
for dinner.
Ooh.
These pictures were definitely
of the same young man?
Oh, yes.
Whatever else, she's
a good photographer.
I'd know that face
anywhere.
With no shirt?
Well, I didn't make
a close inspection.
She certainly is
quite a girl, I'd say.
Wow. You women--
you really are
extraordinary.
You never cease
to surprise me.
Good.
I'd hate to be
predictable.
Like you--
everything you do
is so...
Obvious.
Some girls like that.
They feel safe.
Miss Bentley says
you have money.
Oh, does she?
Well, she hasn't any right
to say that, has she?
I think she was
trying to get me
interested in you.
Ah.
And did she succeed?
Wouldn't you
like to know?
You drink rather a lot,
don't you?
Didn't you,
at my age?
Do you know
what you remind me of,
sitting there
all prim and upright?
Go on. What?
Ha. Ha ha.
A candlestick.
Ha ha ha ha!
Candlestick.
I think
I could probably
just blow you
right out.
Ooh hoo hoo hoo!
Ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha!
Ooh.
God, you're so boring.
I want to have fun.
Well, look, let's go
and dance, shall we?
In this mortuary?
Yoo-hoo!
Hey, candlestick!
Ha ha ha
ha ha ha ha!
This is the style!
Come on, old man,
show me what you're made of.
Major                                                                                  wilshaw:
Oh! Hoo!
Miss                                                                                         Whoo!
Go!
Candlestick,
set yourself alight!
A-whoo hoo hoo!
Ho ho!
Ah ha ha ha!
Ohh!
Oh, bugger!
Oh!
Ho ho! Ho ho!
* ah ho ho ho ho
Whoo hoo!
Oh, shh, shh, shh.
Ooh. Ahh.
If you're going
to kiss me,
you can kiss me.
Don't creep
all over me.
Ohh!
Idiot.
You should be in bed.
Hello?
Can you spare me a minute, please?
I'm very busy.
Well, for the conjuring
show this evening.
You see, I--I'm still
rather hoping
that you might perhaps
give me a hand.
Oh, well...
I wish you'd find
somebody else.
Well, you're
the only person
that I can trust.
I'm hopeless
at that sort of thing.
It's terribly simple.
You see, I invite--
I invite everyone
to write something down
on a piece of paper.
Um, well, I mean,
like, well,
"shall we join the ladies?"
And then they seal it up,
put it back in the envelope.
But for the trick
to work,
I really need
to know now
what it is that
you are going to write.
Well, that sounds
awfully like cheating.
Well, just think of it
as a game--
something
for the children.
Those little monsters?
Well, all right,
then--for me.
Please?
Just say the first thing
that comes into your head.
Spring
in the mountains.
Very good.
Aha. Tremendous.
"Spring in the mountains."
Yes. Very good.
Thanks.
You appear to be
leaking, Major.
Oh, God.
Oh, hell's bells.
I still haven't got it
right.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Signores, Signoras,
will you give me
your kind attention?
A few examples
of the magic art.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Paulo the magic wanderer
would like to borrow
an egg.
Can anyone
oblige me with--
oh, I say.
I think I can see one.
Ha ha ha!
Oh!
Oh, what a lovely egg.
Thank you very much.
I shall put it
in my hat--
keep it nice and safe,
you see?
Now...
You know, I say,
you've got one
under yours, too.
Ha ha!
How clever.
Lovely. Now I think
I need one more.
Signora Bonizzoni,
how lovely.
Oh ho ho ho ho!
three lovely fresh eggs.
And now I need
my magic wand.
Pow.
The magic words--
abracadabra,
sack of potatoes,
corned beef and cabbage.
And...
Hey, presto!
Bravo!
Signore Bonizzoni
would you very kindly
distribute these for me?
Great pleasure.
Thank you.
There you go.
Miss Bentley.
Now, it's very easy.
Each of you writes down
on your piece of paper
a very simple phrase,
like "water on the brain"
or "better late
than never."
You put it in the envelope,
you seal it up,
and then, without
opening the envelopes,
I shall tell you
what is written
inside each one of them.
Easy one.
A light.
Lights.
Light.
Miss Beaumont.
Grazie.
Ha ha ha!
Miss Bentley.
I am now ready
to read your minds.
The first envelope.
Yes, yes, I think--
yes.
I think
I can penetrate the veil
of this first mind.
The words which this
envelope contains are...
"Spring in the mountains."
Did anyone write that?
"Spring in the mountains"?
I did.
Ohh.
Ah!
Bravo!
Oh, yes.
"Spring in the mountains."
There we are.
Now, uh...
The next envelope.
Um...
Yes, I think...
I, um--
Patience, Signores, Signoras.
The words...
Did anyone write
"candlestick"?
Hmm?
Did you?
I did.
Hmm. Well, now...
I think something's
gone wrong.
Um...
I'm really--
I'm terribly sorry.
Uh, yes.
I think that's it.
Thank you, Major,
for such a wonderful show.
He's very kind to
give us so much pleasure.
Bravo!
Now for something
not so good.
My dear signore Bonizzoni
and his family
must return to Milan
the day after tomorrow.
But we must not be sad.
This is a special evening
for good friends,
so I have arranged a party
in the dining room
to celebrate
this wonderful evening
of enchantment.
The coming back
of happiness.
Brava!
Grazie, maggiore.
Oh ho ho! Signora Fascioli.
Grazie.
Ha ha.
I have a good idea.
What about a picnic?
A farewell final picnic,
tomorrow in the mountains.
Like lost deers, huh?
Oh, yes.
The trouble is,
we are one more this time--
and my little car.
Oh, no, but
we could hire another.
The Major and I could
perhaps stand for that.
Invite your
Italian boyfriend.
He drives, doesn't he?
An Italian boyfriend?
No, he's--
wonderful!
We just had a swim
together.
Oh.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I thought it was lunch.
And dinner.
And photographs.
Well, of course.
Invite him.
The car
will be most useful.
What is his name?
Balsari.
Vittorio Balsari.
Oh.
Nice boy.
I know his father.
Major,
a good trick, that--
the one with
the envelopes.
Thank you.
How's it done?
Easy. It's as old
as the hills.
Good night.
Wait a minute,
young lady.
What did you mean
by that?
That joke's
an old Chestnut.
I learned it
at school.
Don't be so spiteful!
He thinks the world of you!
Then he's an idiot!
No, he's not!
He's kind!
Maybe he tries too hard.
All he requires is
a little indulgence from you.
If it means
so much to you,
why don't you
indulge him yourself?
Everything all right?
Ohh!
Uhh. Ohh.
Sorry.
Don't worry. I should've
locked the door.
No. I should've
knocked.
I'm sorry
about last night.
I probably deserved it.
You probably did.
God, you remind me
of my mother.
And you remind me of mine.
Well...
The Major might say...
Pax.
But you did lead him on.
You made
a complete ass of him.
Admit it.
Is that all
the thanks I get?
If I hadn't led him on,
he wouldn't still
be here, would he?
True?
Hmm.
True.
Good morning, everybody!
What a wonderful day.
Oh, morning, Major.
Vittorio.
I'm not late, am I?
Oh, no, no, no.
To our holiday!
Viva!
Hey!
Very nice.
Major, will you
come back to the lake?
Oh, by George,
yes, I hope so.
Oh. Miss Bentley,
of course.
Well, we'll see.
You must prefer Como.
Well, Como--
Como is very nice,
but not so nice
as this.
I hate Como.
It's so boring.
The nicest place
I've been to
in Italy
is a little town
in one of the valleys
between Bolsano
and Venice.
They grow tobacco.
Stupid, though. I can't
remember its name.
Venezia.
Vittorio's family
have a palazzo there.
In Venice?
My family has 4 houses
and 27 servants.
Hmm. Well,
you won't have them
much longer though,
will you?
They'll all be
called up
if there's going
to be a war.
You're right.
This country's
not just for tourists.
My father's factory
has to work 24 hours a day
for the army.
Very soon, we shall
all be in uniform.
I sincerely hope
that that will not
prove to be the case.
Yes.
This is
a beautiful place
and a beautiful day.
Why do we talk
of such things?
You're
absolutely right.
Besides...
I'd look ridiculous
in uniform.
Well, now, who's for
a game of cricket?
Good idea.
Oh, bellissimo.
Come on, Major.
Vittorio...
Ahem.
Guess what?
The Bonizzoni’s
have given me notice.
It seems I'm not
the world's greatest
nanny after all.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Liar.
So--so, you...
You're going home?
God, no.
My mother would
have me arrested.
She already thinks i'm
a delinquent as it is.
She's probably right.
And then what?
When one door closes...
Good luck!
Oh!
Too late.
The ball!
Oh!
1, 2...
3. Ha ha!
I win, I win!
Aah! Ohh!
Where are you going?
For a stroll.
Penny.
How long are you
staying for?
Two days.
Two?
Mm-hmm.
I thought you said
a whole month.
I did...
But I changed my mind.
Ah.
Ah. Mmm.
Oh oh!
Damn.
Oop.
Ahem.
We must go home now!
Oh oh!
This is
the BBC world service
from London.
The time is six o’clock.
Today,
Winston Churchill, MP,
had a private meeting
with Von Ribbentrop,
the foreign minister
of Germany,
to discuss a case for
an Anglo-German alliance
in which Germany
would stand guard
for the British Empire.
In exchange,
Germany requested
the return
of her colonies
and that Britain
grant her a free hand
in Eastern Europe.
It was clearly indicated
by Churchill
that the British government
would not concede
to such terms.
Great Britain would never
disinterest herself
in the fortunes
of the continent
to an extent
which would enable Germany
to gain domination
of central and Eastern Europe.
Von Ribbentrop replied,
"The Fuhrer is resolved
that nothing will stop him,
and that war
is inevitable."
May I join you?
Yes.
That looks rather good.
I'll have one of those,
too, please.
You go ahead, please.
The sun's really quite warm
when you consider
that it's only May.
Mmm.
Yes, it's really been
exceptionally warm
all month.
Yes, I've heard even
the Italians say,
"it has been
exceptionally warm."
It's awfully
quiet here
without
the Bonizzonis.
Mm, yes, very cheerful,
weren't they?
Mmm.
You were saying.
No, I was
only going to say,
you seem to have
got up rather early.
Were you thinking
of going for a swim?
No, I was thinking of going
up into the mountains again.
Apparently there's a bus
that takes you
most of the way.
Don't suppose
you'd care to come?
I really ought
to do my packing.
Well, it shouldn't
take too long.
We could be back
by three o’clock.
Oh, I can't.
I've simply got
too much to do.
Well, you've got until tomorrow.
What time's your train?
Well, and then
there's another thing.
I really ought to get
my sleeper ticket.
I've got an open one.
I should've got it
yesterday.
Oh, very well.
I expect you'd rather say
good-bye to Como, anyway.
Maggiore.
Good God.
What?
Your ears have gone
bright red.
Well...
I'll tell you what.
If you don't stay
for a month,
I shall chuck you
in the lake.
I dare you.
Oh, yes. Lake is magical,
for as we kissed,
I could swear
that music played.
Now the war's over,
we've come back.
To our relief,
the villa is still here.
Last night
we drank champagne,
and we raised our glasses
to Miss Beaumont.
After all, it's thanks to her
we are together.
And she was magical, too.
Our holidays are planned
till the end of time.
Every year we'll spend
springtime in the mountains,
and every Summer,
a month by the lake.