My mommy always said
there were no monsters.
No real ones.
But there are.
We've seen
no additional defects.
She's perfect.
Mm-hmm.
Careful.
Two centimeters.
Okay.
Yeah.
Ready with that amnio.
Oh.
And...
there it is.
No.
Be careful.
Jesus.
Clamp.
What about her?
Can we keep her alive?
How's the host?
Doing well.
Sew her back up.
Excellent work, everybody.
And how is
our Number 8 today?
Appears to be
in good health.
Hmm?
How good?
Excellent,
as in completely off
our projected charts.
Look at the scar tissue.
See the recession?
This is from three days ago?
Exactly.
Oh, this is good.
This is very good.
You're gonna make us all
very proud.
No.
Don't. I'm all right.
Now try this.
- Hand.
- Close.
Glove.
Number 8?
Fruit.
Good. Cherries.
It's unprecedented.
Totally.
She's operating...
at a completely adult capacity.
What about her memories?
There are gaps.
- And some degree ofsynaptic dissonance.
- - You know this.
- She's freaked.
- Come on.
It has connective difficulties,
caused by a biochemical imbalance,
causing emotional autism.
Certain reactions—
All right,
wait a second!
It has memories.
Why does it have memories?
Well, I'm guessing, but...
inherited memories,
passed down generationally
at a genetic level...
by the aliens, like its strength.
Plus a, uh,
highly evolved form of instinct.
An unexpected benefit
from the genetic crossing.
Oh, ho, ho, ho, ho.
I see.
Stupid me.
Ofcourse.
An unexpected benefit
ofthe genetic process.
Oh! And I didn't
even think ofthat!
Let's try this one.
Ripley?
Ripley.
Ripley, what is it?
Ripley? Ripley?
You're not thinking
termination?
Oh, boy,
am I thinking termination.
General,
we do not perceive this
to be a problem.
Ellen Ripley died trying to
wipe this species out.
For all intents and purposes,
she succeeded.
I'm not anxious to see her
taking up her old hobbies.
That won't happen.
We won't tell her.
Oh, I see.
And that's supposed
to comfort me?
Identification, please.
Please try again.
Thankyou, General Perez.
Bottom line is,
she looks at me funny
one time,
I'm putting her down.
Okay, as far as I'm concerned,
Number 8...
is a meat... by-product.
Her Majesty here
is the real payoff.
When does she start producing?
Days.
Less maybe.
We need the cargo.
I told you,
it's on its way.
Fork.
- Fuck.
- It's-It's "fork."
How did you—
How did... we get you?
Yes.
Hard work.
We used blood samples...
from Fiori Sixteen on ice,
where you died.
We've remade you.
We cloned you.
Fiori Sixteen.
Does that ring a bell?
Are you remembering something?
- Does it grow?
- Yeah.
Very rapidly.
It's a queen.
How did you know that?
She'll breed.
You'll die.
Everyone in the company
will die.
In the— In the-
In the company?
Weyland-Yutani.
Ripley 8's
former employers.
Terran growth conglomerate.
They had...
defense contracts
under the military.
Oh, they went under
decades ago, Gediman.
Way before your time.
Bought out by Wal-Mart.
Fortunes ofwar.
I thinkyou will find
that, uh,
things have changed
a great deal since your time.
I doubt that.
We're not flying
blind here, you know.
It's United Systems Military,
not some greedy corporation.
Oh.
Well, it won't
make any difference.
You're still gonna die.
How do you feel about that?
I wish you could understand
what we're trying to do here.
The potential for this species
goes way beyond
urban pacification.
New alloys, new vaccines.
Nothing like this we've ever seen
on any world before.
You should be very proud.
Oh.
I am.
And the animal itself-
wondrous.
The potential, unbelievable,
once we've tamed them.
Roll over. Play dead.
Heel?
Mm-hmm.
You can't teach it tricks.
Why not?
We're teaching you.
Hey, son, I'll give you
my authorization code.
It's E-A-T-M-E.
I'm sorry, sir.
Could you repeat that?
Little prick.
You know,
no matter how many times
you see it,
the sight ofa woman
all strapped up
in a chair like thatjust—
What?
Just bring us in on
a 3-0 descent, would ya?
And ride the parallel.
Darlin', it is done.
Good girl.
You, uh, want
anything there, trigger?
Hmm. Yeah.
How 'bout a cup ofcoffee?
Anything else,
while your mouth's warm,
I mean?
Little milk.
Hey, don't cut thrust
till about 600 meters,
and we'll give 'em
a little scare.
Vriess. Call.
Lock down.
We're gonna dock.
- Hey, Call?
- Yep?
What has two thumbs,
one eye,
a pink tongue...
and screws like a god?
What?
Two thumbs, one eye,
a pink tongue...
and screws like a god?
What?
Time to enjoy some of
the general's hospitality, Christie.
Great.
Army food.
Yeah. It'll do
till we get the family wagon
up to spec, I reckon.
Yeah.
That is ifthe natives
are friendly.
How's that?
Good.
We expecting any,
uh, trouble?
Nah. From Perez, I doubt it.
But you never know.
We've been there before.
What is wrong with you?
Just a little target practice.
Vriess isn't complaining.
Goddamn it!
Johner, you son ofa bitch!
Come on, man.
You didn't feel a thing.
You are an inbred motherfucker,
you know that?
I'll take the knife
back now.
Whoa.
Call, forget it.
He's been sucking down
too much home brew.
The knife.
Son ofa bitch!
Don't push me, little Call.
You hang with us for a while,
you'll find out
I am not the man
with whom to fuck!
It's about time
we start associating
with a better class of people.
I am Father.
Welcome to the U.S.M. Auriga.
Step forward for
contraband and weapons search.
Please report
any infectious diseases...
to the medical officers.
Levels 7 through 1 2
are off-limits to civilians.
Thankyou foryour cooperation.
Go.
Get your hands up,
please, sir.
What?
Could you get
your hands up, please?
There are no weapons
allowed on board, sir.
My own recipe.
Way more dangerous.
Nice welcome, Perez.
What the hell is this?
What, are you afraid
the six of us are gonna hijack
your damn ship or what?
Just a minor concern
that one ofyour
asshole crew members...
is gonna get drunk
and put a bullet
through the hull.
We happen to be
in space, Elgyn.
No shit. Howyou been?
Wanna check the chair?
Elgyn, these were very,
very hard to come by.
So was our cargo.
- You're, uh, not about to plead
poverty on me, are you, General?
- No.
Just saying very few people
deal in cash nowadays.
Just the ones don't like
to keep business records.
- Yourself, for example.
- Drink, Elgyn?
Constantly.
Now, I'm gonna take
a wild guess here, General,
but I'm thinking whatever
you got going on here,
it, uh, ain't exactly approved
by Congress.
Who's the...
new fillyyou got
on board, Elgyn?
Call. Little girl
playing pirates.
She makes an impression.
She is severely fuckable,
ain't she?
Mighty handy
with a monkey wrench too,
I might add.
I think Vriess
has got a bit ofa light
in his eye for her.
Fine little ass like that'd
make a man walk.
You know what I mean?
Mind you, uh, I think
she'sjust a tad curious...
about, uh,
this little transaction ofours.
I mean, I can't say as I blame her.
It's awfully cloak-and-dagger stuff.
It's a military operation.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
Correct me if I'm wrong,
but, uh,
I was under the impression
that, uh,
most army medical labs
don't have to operate
outside of regulated space.
- What do you want, Elgyn?
What can I do foryou?
- Me?
- Yeah.
- Oh, two days bed and board.
You know,
Vriess might wanna snag a part
here or there, whatever.
I mean, uh, if it's not imposing.
I don't see any problem.
Couple ofconditions
though.
Ah.
Conditions?
Not you...
nor any ofyour...
formidable crew members...
will go anywhere near...
restricted areas.
Rule number two:
No trouble.
Good behavior.
- No fights.
Mi casa es su casa.
Please direct cargo
to med lab center, area "G."
Follow the lit path.
Do not deviate.
Cargo status: stable.
Life-forms intact.
Stasis uninterrupted.
Med lab center
is off-limits to civilians.
Thankyou.
Oh.
Hey. Chill.
Oh, please.
You know I can't lay offthe tall ones.
Howyou doin'?
How about a little
one-on-one?
What do you say?
You got some moves
on you, girl.
Oh, man.
Mm-hmm.
Well, now, ifyou don't
wanna play basketball,
I know some other indoor sports.
Come on, now.
Give me the ball.
Okay, I got a new game.
Tag!
Ripley? Ripley.
You've had enough fun.
What the hell are you?
Something ofa predator,
isn't she?
Yes, she continues
to make us all very proud.
We're coming up on just
one minute and 30 seconds left...
to order this one-of-a-kind
collector's item.
Jesus Christ,Johner,
what do you put in this shit,
battery acid?
Just for color.
So, we're a fast learner.
Now here's a fine item.
This is a really good show, man.
It's from the Gut Cutter's
Celebration Collection,
makers of premier
knives and edge ware.
The knife features
a stainless steel blade,
perfect for any use
in hunting or in the home.
The pro handle
is made from authentic
antique plywood...
and stained in brilliant colors
for an uncanny charm.
Hey, man, that shit
is not easy to come by!
Why don't you take
a walk outside?
...to a cutting edge
that will rip through anything—
Great!
- I'm so sorry.
- Now I smell like this shit!
Ifbitches
can't handle this shit,
bitches should stay away
from this shit!
Go to bed. Fucking bitch.
Identification, please.
Please try again.
Thankyou, General Perez.
Well?
You gonna kill me,
orwhat?
There's no point,
is there?
They've taken it
out ofyou.
Where is it?
Is it on the ship?
You mean my baby.
I don't get it.
Ifthey took it out,
why are they
keeping you alive?
Well, they're curious.
I'm the latest thing.
Look.
I can make it all stop.
The pain, this nightmare.
That's all I can offeryou.
What makes you think...
I would let you do that?
Who are you?
Ripley, Ellen,
Lieutenant First Class,
number 36706.
Ellen Ripley died
200 years ago.
You're not her.
I'm not her.
Who am I?
You're a thing, a construct.
They grew you in a fucking lab.
And now they brought it
out ofyou.
Not all the way out.
I can feel it...
behind my eyes.
I can hear it moving.
You gotta help me stop this thing
before it gets loose.
It's too late.
You can't stop it.
It's inevitable.
Not as long as I'm around.
You'll never get out of here alive.
I don't care.
Really?
I can make it stop.
Go on. Get out of here.
They're looking foryou.
I think you're gonna find
that this was very ill-advised.
Where are her friends?
They're in
the mess hall, sir.
Well, you find them, now.
Quietly.
What the hell
is going on here?
Smells like
a double-cross, boss.
Where's the other one?
With the chair?
Don't ever touch me.
Ever.
You wanna tell us what this is?
You wanna tell me
who you're workin' for.
What?
- Wren, they got nothing
to do with this.
- To do with what?
Do you know what
the penalties for
terrorist activity are?
No goddamn terrorists
on my crew. Call, there
something you wanna tell me?
Look. I don't care whether
you knew or not. You brought
a terrorist on board a military vessel.
And as far as I am concerned,
you all die with her!
Do you understand?
Yeah.
I understand.
Christie.
Down!
Freeze!
Stop! Drop your weapons!
And you!
Drop that piece ofshit,
or I blow his head off!
- Can't do that, man.
- Drop it now!
- Can't do that.
They're attached to me.
- I'm not fucking with you!
You're all under arrest
for a code eight,
which is concealed weapons,
and a code 1 2, which is murder!
Release Dr. Wren!
Kiss my ass.
Put down yourweapons
and assume the fucking—
Everybody okay?
Real easy, soldier boy.
Security.
Get up!
There is a serious problem
in the mess hall.
You lie to me now,
little girl,
I will cut your throat
and leave you here to die,
you understand me?
This is security, Section 2.
We do not read you.
Hello? Goddamn it! Hello?
We do not copyyou.
Please repeat.
Hello?
Gediman!
He's conducting
illegal experiments.
He is breeding some sort of-
Ice the goddamn mole!
Listen to me!
He is breeding an alien species.
More than dangerous.
Ifthose things get loose,
it's gonna make
the Lacerta plague look like
a fucking square dance!
Shut up!
Listen.
Your attention, please.
Security breach, med lab,
Level 1 5.
Go. Let's get back to the Betty.
Doctor and soldier boy here
can see us to the door.
- What about Vriess?
- Fuck Vriess.
Your attention, please.
Unauthorized opening
ofcage three.
ofcages five,
seven, eight, 1 0-
- Move it! Now!
- Evacuation.
- Go! Go now!
This is not a drill.
- Evacuation.
- Move it! Go! Get on board!
Your attention, please.
Nonhuman presence detected,
Levels 21 , 23,
27, 1 4,
Level 38, Level 39.
Evacuation.
Proceed to lifeboats.
This is not a drill.
Thankyou foryour cooperation.
I'll give you holes,
you slimy bastard!
Move it! Let's go!
Final lifeboat ready for launch.
Get aboard!
Go!
Complete evacuation now.
Grenade.
Alert. Alert.
Evacuation incomplete.
Civilian presence detected
in area "H." Warning.
Main vessel
declared uninhabitable.
Elgyn, come on.
Let's move, man.
Yeah.
Elgyn? Elgyn, where are you?
Elgyn, where are you?
Elgyn?
Elgyn!
- God. Elgyn?
- Elgyn?
Elgyn!
Easy, Hillard!
Christie, give me a hand here!
Get him up!
Give me a hand here!
Come on! Let's get him up!
Move out ofthe way!
No!
Ah, shit.
What the fuck did this?
What's in this place?
- Call, get down!
- What the fuck is that?
Don't shoot!
It's in front ofthe hull!
What is that?
Come on, man.
Time to go. Time to go!
Get back!
Damn!
Call, time to go!
Come on, Call!
Get the goddamn door open!
We can't open it!
We can't open the door!
- We gotta go back!
- I'm not going back!
You go back!
What the fuck?
Was it everything
you hoped for?
Leave him alone!
What do we do now, man?
Same thing we're doin'.
Get the hell outta here!
What ifthere's more?
I say we stay here, man.
Let the army guys deal.
Where the fuck
are the army guys?
They're dead!
Well, then we don't need
this asshole anymore.
- Step back!
- No, you step back!
- Stop it!
- You got no authority here!
Doctor, that thing
that killed my partner,
that's your pet
science project?
Yes.
- Let me do him right now, man!
- I should let him do you right now!
How many more are there?
Twelve.
Twelve?
There'll be more.
So,
who do I have to fuck
to get offthis boat?
I can get you off.
Maybe not the boat, but-
Let's get out of here.
No, wait a second here.
She was the host
for these monsters.
Wren cloned her because
she had one inside her.
She's not human.
She was part of his experiment,
and she will turn on us
in a second.
I don't give a shit
what she is.
She's too much ofa risk.
We have to leave her.
- She comes.
- We can't trust her!
I don't trust anyone.
Ifwe're gonna survive this mess,
we all stick together.
Agreed?
Hillard, we gotta go.
It's not over.
We gotta get to the Betty.
Make a nice souvenir.
I can't believe
you did that.
Did what?
Killed one of'em.
It's like killing
your own kind.
It was in my way.
Oh, man!
Who were you expecting, Santa Claus?
Thought you were toast
for certain, man.
Shit. Where's Elgyn?
Oh, shit.
Hey, man, what if
we get to the Betty
and they're all over it?
- All the activity's been in the aft sector
by the barracks. Why would they move?
- They won't.
Ifthey send anyone out,
it'll be, uh, here,
where the meat is.
Yeah. Well, I say
ifwe wanna make any decent time,
I say we ditch the cripple.
- No offense, man.
- None taken.
Nobody is left behind.
Not even you,Johner.
- What's the quickest way out of here?
- After the cooling tower,
there's a freight elevator.
It runs from the top
ofthe ship down to
Engineering Level 1 deck.
- Take us straight to the dock.
- Sounds reasonable. Let's do it.
We're moving.
- What?
- The ship is moving.
I can feel it.
The ship has stealth run.
There's no wayyou can tell.
She's right.
The ship's been go since the attack.
That's a standard
emergency procedure.
That's right.
Any serious problem,
and the ship autopilots
back to home base.
And you were planning
on letting us know this?
Nobody asked.
What's home base?
Earth.
Oh, great.
- Bastard.
- Earth?
I'd rather stay here
with the things, man.
How long until we get to Earth?
Three hours almost.
We gotta blow the ship.
Call, you're not blowing this ship.
Not while we're on it, okay?
We get out ofthis shit,
you do as you please,
all right?
Earth, man.
What a shit-hole.
It's clear.
Hey, Ripley.
I heard you, like,
ran into these things before.
That's right.
Wow, man.
So, like, what did you do?
I died.
Not that way!
Ripley.
Ripley, come on.
Ripley, we got no time
for sightseeing here.
Ripley, don't.
Hel—
Kill... me.
Kill me.
Don't do it, Ripley.
Don't do what?
What's the big deal, man?
Fuckin' waste ofammo.
Let's go.
Must be a chick thing.
Am I dreaming, or is this not
the shit we brought with us?
Yeah, it's the same shit.
Stinks in here, man.
Let's keep moving.
Get away from me!
Drop the rod, man.
- Do it!
- Get away from me.
Get away from me.
Who are you people?
- What's happening here?
- Calm down.
What's happening here is
we're getting the fuck off
this ghost ship, okay?
Ship? What ship?
Where am I?
I was in cryo, right?
On my way to Xarem, right?
Work crew for the nickel
refinery, right?
I wake up.
I know I don't understand.
Oh, God. Uh, I s- I saw—
I saw horrible things.
Look, you're coming with us.
It's too dangerous foryou here.
Leave him.
Fuckyou.
We're not leaving him here.
He's got one inside of him.
I can smell it.
Inside me?
What's inside me?
Hey, man.
I don't want one ofthose things
birthing anywhere near my ass.
It's a bad risk.
- What's inside me?
- Look, we can'tjust leave him here.
- I thought you came here
to stop 'em from spreadin'.
- What's inside me?
- There's gotta be a process.
Can't you stop it?
- Got no time for that.
- I can't do it here.
The lab is out oforder.
- What's inside me?
I could do him.
Back ofthe head.
Painless.
It might be the best way.
- What's inside me?
- No, there's got
to be another way.
What ifwe freeze him?
What's in-fuckin'-side me?
A parasite!
Foreign element.
There's a monster in your chest.
These guys
hijacked your ship,
and they sold
your cryo tube...
to this... human,
and he put an alien inside ofyou.
It's a really nasty one.
And in a few hours,
it's gonna burst its way
through your rib cage...
and you're gonna die.
Any questions?
Who are you?
I'm the monster's mother.
Look, he comes with us,
we freeze him on the Betty,
- then the doctor
can remove it later.
- Fine with me.
Since when were you
in goddamn charge?
- Since you were born without balls!
- Ease off, people.
All right.
You come with us.
You might even live.
Get twitchy on me,
and you'll be shot.
Let's move out.
It's a mess down there!
Is this the only way?
Vriess, we gotta lose
the chair.
I know.
Kawlang maneuver,
all right?
Yeah,just like old times.
Yeah.
Must be the cooling tanks.
Somebody must have
opened the valves.
The nasties couldn't have
done this, could they?
We're at the bottom
ofthe ship.
We have to go through
the kitchen, maybe 90 feet,
to the freight elevator
on the other side.
- I don't like it.
- What's to like?
This sucks!
- Wren, are you sure
about the distance?
- Yes.
- You ready to get wet, partner?
- Yeah.
Hey, uh, do your weapons
fire underwater?
- Yeah, they're disposables.
They can take it.
- Disposables?
Hey, I heard about those. Yeah.
- How many rounds?
- Twenty.
Split points give you a good hole,
even at the smaller caliber.
Oh. Hey, that's cool.
Yeah. They're big with hitters
'cause you, uh, throw 'em away
after thejob.
Nobody likes to throw away
a weapon they're attached to.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
Guess I don't have to tell everyone
to take a deep breath.
Hey, Christie,
do me a favor.
When we hit the surface
on the other side,
no backstroke, okay?
Jesus Christ!
They set a goddamn trap.
It's a goddamn ambush!
Distephano!
It won't break.
Give me yourweapon.
You really are way too trusting.
No!
You killed her!
You bastard!
I'll get you!
Father, lock the door.
Christie! Climb! Climb!
I'm doin' it, man!
Come on!
It'sjammed!
Move it!
Get off my foot, bitch!
Get off me!
Johner!
Aaah!Johner!
Die, motherfucker!
Do it, man!
Hey!
Real nice party, ain't it?
Christie! Christie!
Christie! No!
Christie!
What are you doing?
Don't do it!
Don't!
We can make it!
No!
Damn!
This way.
Come on!
Baby, am I glad to see you.
I was sure that asshole got you.
Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
You got body armor on?
Yeah. Come on.
You took it in the chest.
I saw it.
You're a robot?
Son ofa bitch!
Our little Call
isjust full ofsurprises.
I should have known.
No human being is that humane.
I thought synthetics
were supposed to be
all logical and shit.
You'rejust
a big old psycho, girl.
- You're a robot?
- You're a second gen, aren't you?
You're an Auton.
Robots designed
by robots, right?
Hah!
Oh, yeah. That's right.
I remember.
Now, they were
supposed to revitalize
the synthetic industry.
Instead, they buried it.
They didn't like
being told what to do.
Government ordered
a recall.
Now, I heard—
I had— I had heard...
that only a few-
just a few-
had gotten out intact.
Man, I never, never thought
that I would see one!
Great. She's a toaster oven.
Can we leave now?
How long before we land?
- Just under two hours.
- Hey, Vriess.
You got a socket wrench?
Maybe shejust needs
an oil change.
I'm sorry. Access denied.
I can't believe I almost fucked it.
Yeah, like you
never fucked a robot!
You know, ifWren gets in the computer,
he could really screw us.
We gotta find a terminal.
No, there's no console on this level.
We'd have to go back.
Well, we can't go back.
- And I don't know
any ofWren's access codes.
- Help me.
Call.
No. I can't.
Right. You're the new model droid.
You can access
the mainframe by remote.
No, I can't.
I burned my modem.
We all did.
Call, you can still patch in manually.
You know that.
There's ports
in the chapel, up there.
Call.
You're programmed
for that?
Don't make me do this.
Don't make me make you.
I don't want to go in there.
It's like my insides are liquid.
It's not real.
Get over it.
You can blow the ship
before it reaches Earth...
and kill them all.
Just give us time
to get out first.
Damn it.
Anything?
Hold on.
Breach in Sector 7,
Sector 3.
Sector 9 unstable.
Engines operating at 41 %.
Eighty-six minutes
until Earth dock.
We burned too much energy.
I can't make critical mass.
I can't blow it.
Then crash it.
Yeah.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
Really.
I feel good.
Ground level recalibrated.
New destination:
7-6-0-4-0-3.
Uninhabited quadrant.
Braking systems off-lined.
Acceleration increase.
Time until impact now
43 minutes, 8 seconds.
Try to clear us a path
to the Betty...
and start her up.
Okay.
Please wait.
Emergency override
in console 45V, Level 1 .
It's Wren.
He's almost at the Betty.
Father, locate
the power drain. Report.
Father? Father!
Father's dead, asshole.
Intruder on Level 1 .
All aliens,
please proceed to Level 1 .
You got a mean streak.
Damn it.
Let me see.
- Don't touch me.
- Come on.
You must think
this is pretty funny.
I'm finding a lot ofthings
funny lately,
but I don't think they are.
Why do you go on living?
How can you stand
being what you are?
Not much choice.
At least there's
a part ofyou that's human.
I'm just— Look at me.
I'm disgusting.
Why did you come here?
To kill you,
remember?
Before the recall,
I accessed the mainframe.
Every dirty little covert op
the government ever
dreamed of is in there.
And this-you, the aliens,
even the crew from the Betty-
I knew ifthey succeeded,
it would be the end ofthem.
Why do you care
what happens to them?
Because I'm programmed to.
You're programmed
to be an asshole?
You're the new asshole model
they're putting out?
Come on.
I couldn't watch 'em do it.
I couldn't let 'em
annihilate themselves.
Do you understand that?
I did once.
I tried to save...
people.
It didn't work out.
There was this girl.
She had bad dreams.
I tried to help her.
She died.
Now I can't even
remember her name.
I guess we're almost there.
Right.
Do you dream?
I— Well, we have
neuroprocessors that- Yes.
When I sleep,
I dream about them— it.
Every night.
All around me, in me.
I used to be
afraid to dream,
but I'm not anymore.
Why?
Because no matter
how bad the dreams get,
when I wake up,
it's always worse.
It's not so far now!
God, I'm so tired.
Sleep when you die, man.
Oh, no. This is bad, right?
- I think we're near the nest.
- Well, then we'll go another way.
We don't have time.
We got nearly 90 minutes.
- Not anymore.
- What are you saying?
- What did you do, robot?
- Let's go. Come on.
Hey! You want to die here
with your little brothers
and sisters, that's cool!
But I plan to live past today!
Ifthis little hunk of plastic
is pulling any shit,
I'm gonna kill her!
Kill you!
Does that compute?
Or do I have to
drawyou a schematic?
Hey!
You want another souvenir?
- How far are the docks?
- A h-hundred yards.
Ripley.
Come on.
Ripley, we have to go.
I hear them.
They're so close.
Ripley.
It's the queen.
She's in pain.
Ripley!
Wait!
Oh, my God.
We gotta be moving.
The best thing you can do
is pray for a quick death.
Come on. Come on.
It's not right.
I've been saying that all day.
It's up to you now, Call.
I need you to patch into
the ship again and open the hatch.
Johner, we should put Purvis
in the freezer now.
All right, little buddy.
Nap time.
Oh!
Nobody moves,
or I put a cap...
right where
this little droid's brain is.
Distephano, take the weapons.
Begging your pardon, sir,
but fuckyou!
Oh, fine. Then I kill her,
and you kill me,
and we all die,
and nobody goes home!
Now drop the weapon.
Then this little
synthetic bitch...
is gonna plug into the Auriga,
and she is gonna take us
right back to home base,
according to the standard
emergency procedures.
- No, she's not.
- Are you crazy?
You still want to bring
those things back to Earth?
- Haven't you been paying
any attention today?
- Ah, the intellectual speaks.
Stay there!
Listen, ifyou don't—
Don't you ever shut up?
Why does nobody listen to me?
I told you.
At first, everything was normal.
The queen laid her eggs.
But then she started to change.
She added a second cycle cell.
So,
this time there is no host.
There are no eggs.
There is only herwomb...
and the creature inside.
That is Ripley's gift to her:
a human reproductive system.
She is giving birth
foryou, Ripley,
and now she is perfect!
You are...
a beautiful,
beautiful butterfly.
No.
No. No.
Ah, look. Look.
Beautiful, beautiful
little baby.
Look. It thinks
you're its mother.
Come on.
Yeah.
Civilian vessel on line.
Emergency departure
authorized.
All right. She's hot.
I'll open the Auriga's air locks,
pull the holding clamps on your mark.
Right. I-I just need
to find, uh, the, uh—
th-the vertical thrust lock.
Are you sure you guys
can fly this thing?
Yes!
Launch status is go.
No!
Ripley.
- Hey.
- I thought you were dead.
Yeah, I get that a lot.
Why are we still here?
Uh, I'm just, uh, finding
the, uh, manual override.
- For Christ's sake.
- Hey, Ripley.
Good memory. Excuse me.
Ripley's back, man.
Is that it?
Nope.
You can't fly one of
these things too, can you?
Are you kidding?
This piece ofshit
is even older than I am.
Goddamn it.
We've still got breach. The hatch.
- I closed it.
- Fixed the goddamn hatch
a hundred times, man!
I'll get it. I'll get it.
Approaching Earth's atmosphere.
Window ofdeparture
now 46 seconds.
Call, we have to go.
Call.
We've gotta get out of here.
Window ofdeparture
now 20 seconds.
Grab on to something, Call.
We're outta here.
Come on, baby.
This thing is gonna fall apart.
Pressure's unstable!
Go help Call turn on
the auxiliary pump!
Distephano?
Come on! Step on it!
Hey, I'm not the mechanic
here, Ironsides!
I mostlyjust hurt people!
Shit. Call!
Call, get back up here!
Call! Call!
Ripley!
Hey, Ripley!
Johner, where are you,
you son ofa bitch?
- Get on it, bastard!
- What am I supposed to do?
Grab the sticks.
Put her down.
Oh.
Ripley!
Oh, no!
I'm sorry.
No!
U.S.M. Auriga
will impact in five seconds.
Four. Three.
Two. One.
Thankyou.
- What's burnin'?
- Us!
Shit! You're right!
So this is Earth, huh?
This is Earth.
This is
my first time here.
I suppose the military will be
sniffing around here pretty soon.
Bet you're not
too anxious to see them.
Not really.
You know,
a person could get pretty lost
around here ifthey wanted to.
What do you think?
What should we do?
I don't know.
I'm a stranger here myself.
English - US - PSDH