It's a little girl, my lady.
She's beautiful.
My baby.
Poor little creature.
I'd like to see you grow.
But you must survive.
Take her to the convent.
Please promise you'll protect her.
And don't let them take her.
Swear. Swear.
I swear.
I will protect her.
I'll take her to the convent.
Justine, at last you're here.
This way Justine.
We were so sorry to hear
about your parents' death.
We've been expecting you
for several days now.
Come on.
Come on!
Here she is, Justine.
Yes Mother Superior, I know Danielle
has been very happy here with you.
- Excuse me mother.
- That's alright.
They were just leaving.
Now young lady,
I hope you will not forget us.
No of course not.
She'll be back again next summer.
You've done wonders and soon
she'll be able to do things for herself.
Won't you darling?
I'm sorry I can't stay,
but we have to get back to the village.
Patients get restless you know.
Mother... This is Justine.
- Reverend Mother.
- Now child.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Life must go on.
What you need now is rest.
- Is the room ready Sister Angelica.
- Yes Mother.
Remember Justine.
From now on, this is your home.
- Sister Angelica will show you the way.
- Thank you.
You will find a new life here Justine.
Come along.
Now you have to think of yourself.
Remember the Lord will always be
here to guide you. And so will I.
Come right this way Justine.
This is your room.
Let me open the window
to let in some fresh air and sun.
And this... is your bed.
Now promise me
you'll try to get some rest.
- We'll call you in time for supper.
- Thank you Sister.
- Justine.
- Yes?
I hope you'll be happy here.
But if ever you're in need or troubled
Please don't hesitate
to call on me. Alright?
Thank you, Sister.
Hello.
I'm Alucarda.
- My name is Justine.
- Who's that?
My mother and my father.
- Mother just died.
- I never met my mother or my father.
- I'm sorry.
- I've got something to show you too.
These are things I never show anyone.
They're secret.
Every day I find a new secret.
Look.
Look at all this.
It belongs to me.
This for instance.
It means I like you.
And this.
Do you know how
small creatures love each other?
No.
I'll show you. I'll take you
to the gardens, to the woods.
Everything is there.
What's that?
I've never seen
anything like them before.
It's one more secret.
One is identical to the other.
It's like an image in a mirror.
Like you and me.
Do you want us to be sisters?
Come on. Come on.
Look.
They are burying a sister.
She killed herself.
They will bury her in unhallowed ground.
I'm afraid of funerals.
We have to die.
All of us has to die.
And there's no way we can avoid it.
Don't be afraid.
It's not very far.
Come on.
Well, well, well.
What have we here?
Would you like to see...
Oh, please.
Please don't be afraid of me. I was just
in the middle of an interesting game.
Would you like to know what it is?
I think we should start back.
Would you like to know
how someone will die.
Or would you like to buy an amulet?
Which will bring good luck.
Lots, lots.
I have many more things
myself, in these woods.
Follow. Don't be afraid. Follow.
Come on.
No.
Come on. He won't hurt us.
Justine!
Alucarda!
Don't believe such a creature.
He'll only tell you lies.
Better let me read your hand.
- Oh, my God...
- What did you see?
Nothing.
Perhaps a reflection of her own dreams.
I see nothing.
Only shadows...
Take care.
She's yours.
Sell her your charms
for the supernatural.
Look at the
marvelous things that I have.
Among other things I profess the useful
art of alchemy. I can turn dust
into precious stones.
and these, in dreams never imagined.
And you, young lady.
Look.
This knife was the tear
of a gypsy girl.
What strange eyes
this girl has. Deep, sharp,
mysterious.
As the birds in the forest.
I see clearly.
Your past and future, your dreams.
You've come from the dew in the forest
and there they will be waiting for you.
Strange creatures they are,
and you must take care.
If it obsesses the young lady,
here I am and here is my box of charms.
If she wishes I will
make her free from such a dream.
then if the dream comes true,
I shall be expecting her.
Hey, where are you going?
Did I offend her?
Alucarda!
Alucarda, wait.
Look.
It looks so familiar.
- Let's go inside.
- No! This place scares me.
Let's go back.
Are you afraid?
Justine
This is simply beautiful.
Come.
I hear the voices from the past.
I feel as if I've been here before.
I remember every stone and branch.
It's as if I lost this world
a long time ago.
One can live eternally instead
of turning into a little pile of dust.
Are you...
- Are you afraid of dying?
- Yes.
Everyone is.
I mean dying, loving each other.
Dying together, to live as one forever.
With the same blood always flowing
through our veins.
Darling. Darling Justine.
I live in you.
Would you die for me?
I love you so.
I have never been in love with anyone.
And never shall.
Unless it's with you.
- Do you mean that?
- You're quite right to ask.
You don't know how dear you are to me.
I hope you love me as I love you.
Call me cruel and selfish,
but love is always selfish.
You don't know how jealous I am.
I want you to love me to death.
Alucarda, for the love of God,
Don't talk to me of death.
I have a dream.
The memory of a night.
I was almost murdered.
Wounded here.
I was never the same again.
- Were you near death?
- Very close.
Let's make a pact.
If we ever depart from this life,
we shall do it together.
We shall do it together,
Alright. If it makes you happy.
No, Alucarda!
Wait.
Lucille died in 1850.
15 years ago Justine.
Our age.
See what's there.
I'm afraid Alucarda.
- Let's open it.
- No.
My God!
I told you this place frightened me.
Look what it's done to you.
Please let's go back.
It's cold. I'm shivering.
We have to
Go back.
Go back. Go back!
The devil enters the body of
the person he wants to control.
Uses the organs of that body
for his own pleasure.
And performs feats,
far above the capacity, strength
and ability of
the person thus possessed.
Here in the holy book
for the knowledge of mankind,
since the days of our lord, and even
before, Satan and the other demons
have persecuted the souls of Christians.
they make no distinction
between men, women and children.
He, the devil,
uses the bodies of others as his own,
destroying those he wants to dominate.
Perverting their language
and distorting their lips.
Froth exits their mouths
rather than words.
Lead a virtuous life and place
yourselves in the hands of Our Lord.
You must live within
the rules of our religion.
The only true religion.
Otherwise
the devil will find
a place inside our bodies
and take our souls away.
And then...
we shall burn in hell forever.
Throughout eternity.
Your souls will find no rest.
Your bodies will suffer eternal torture.
The wrath of Satan has no mercy.
Repent!
Oh, God, please help me.
I don't want to burn in hell.
Calm down.
Justine, what's wrong.
Answer me.
Are you feeling better now?
What happened?
I don't know.
She shouldn't be left alone.
She should rest for a while.
I can look after her.
Please don't leave me alone.
I can stay with her.
Would you like to stay Alucarda?
Alright.
We'll leave her in your care, Alucarda.
If you need anything, I won't be far.
Monsters! Monsters!
They have done this to you.
Justine. Don't tell of our secret.
I hear voices.
Voices from the past.
The same dark voices.
They were soft at first.
I was looking at the trees
and the voices began to speak to me.
Coming from the forest.
I can hear them clearly Justine.
Only you and me.
Only you and me Justine.
My God, I'm so scared.
We will make them pay. Bit by bit.
For all they have taken away from us.
Alucarda.
Lucifer.
Satan! Lucifer!
Alucarda, for God's sake.
What's happening?
Please!
Alucarda, please stop it.
Death! Death! Death!
- Death.
- Alucarda. Please, no.
Alucarda. Answer me.
Answer me, please. Answer me.
We'll make a pact
and seal it with our blood.
We'll make them pay.
You're right.
To start with, a little rain.
Thunder!
Call him. Call him. Call him!
Lucifer!
Satan!
Look at me.
You're so beautiful, Justine.
Look at me. Look at me.
Now you shall blend. One with the other.
one with the other.
And then...
blend into me.
Look at me, dear Justine.
Welcome Justine.
Giver of all gifts.
Of flowers and fruits.
Jesus. give me strength.
Please.
Behold the body of thy new servant.
My Lord.
Don't abandon me.
Manifest your spirit.
Satan... Lucifer.
Do not abandon me Lord.
We beseech thee, Satan.
God!
Save Justine.
Don't abandon her Lord.
Please keep her from harm.
Today we will continue studying
the teachings of Saint Theresa.
And this is what the devil does.
To beget his evil
he obtains help from our virtues.
Even if the gain is small,
his harvest is great.
But God in his infinite wisdom
understands the wiles of the devil.
And so gives us the strength
to face them with noble thoughts
and prayer.
In this way,
I trust that you have been listening.
Yes Sister.
Then you can repeat
what I have just read.
Well, Alucarda?
Stand up child.
And this is what the devil does.
He grants us virtues
to expand his kingdom.
The only valid one.
God with his lack of knowledge
does not understand this truth,
and opposes it with
false thoughts and prayers.
God. Silence!
I renounce the other God
and all the saints.
Don't listen, don't listen to them.
Lord and master.
Don't listen. Go out of the room.
Go, go, go.
I promise to do all that is evil.
I will declare you name to all and will
not cease to serve the Lord of Darkness.
My body, my soul
and my life belong to you.
Call the Mother Superior, quickly.
What's wrong with you girls?
God help up, please.
Please, stop it.
Alucarda, my child.
This is blasphemy.
Listen to me sisters.
This is blasphemy. God help me.
How dare you blaspheme.
Are you mad?
Have you taken leave of your senses?
Answer me. Answer me.
I only repeated what you said.
God forgive you.
You have just invoked the
kingdom of darkness
and rejected the infinite wisdom of God.
And now you deny it.
And Alucarda too.
Liars. Repent.
Here in front of the cross.
Beg. Ask for forgiveness.
- Sister Germana
- Reverend Mother, thank god you're here
I have to inform you of the strange
and blasphemous behaviour of these girls
Mother, in front of me
Sister Mary and all the pupils.
Justine and Alucarda
denied the Lord our Christ.
They used the most evil language to
recognise Satan as their Lord and Master
- I can't believe it.
- But it's true.
What have you to say for yourself?
Sister Mary.
Send for the doctor,
perhaps they are ill.
Father Lazarus will be here soon.
I want them both
to be prepared for confession.
- Go, hurry now.
- Yes.
- I need more light.
- She gets worse by the minute, doctor.
- How long has she been like this?
- Since this morning.
But she has got much worse.
Her pulse is faint.
Her heart is weak.
This girl is very sick.
Pray, Justine.
Pray, my child.
Pray for the sake of your soul.
Pray. Pray Justine. Pray.
What is it girl?
What's the matter?
Easy girl. Easy.
It is your turn now Alucarda.
- Yes my child.
- I... I...
- Yes, go on.
- I was told to come to you.
Speak up then.
I was asked to answer a question
and I did.
And Sister Germana is angry with me.
And for a very good reason.
I am not what you may think father.
The facts were
explained to me my child.
You have sinned.
I don't recall doing anything wrong.
Liars rot in hell for eternity.
I know for sure
that you are doing wrong.
Don't miss this opportunity
which has been granted you.
You can tell the truth
here and now.
Perhaps I have done wrong.
I couldn't have lied.
I love life... with
With...
- Go on.
- Justine.
is a close friend of mine.
I love her.
You call yourself blessed, and
believe in eternal life and worship God.
I worship life, you worship death.
I love Justine.
You love to kill.
We have made a pact
and sealed it with our blood.
Justine and I
The fault isn't ours, but yours.
You cover your body with a black cassock
as if you are ashamed of it.
But you'd like to
possess me wouldn't you?
Take me.
Take off your cassock.
- What happened Father?
- What happened?
Please sister, get her out of here.
My God, no... no.
All we can do is wait.
We'll know better tomorrow.
- I hope she'll recover.
- I'm convinced she will
with the help of the Lord.
The things she said were so horrible.
Please Lord do not abandon us
in such times of difficulty.
You did not hear what she said.
It was the devil.
As if the devil himself
was speaking through her mouth.
These words cannot come from
anyone else, only the devil.
- The devil.
Father Lazarus.
Do you really believe that because
we belong to the church
we are safe from the devil's influence?
I remember when I visited
the archives at the Vatican.
I read many incidents
that had been confirmed.
Incidents like this.
In 1491, at the monastery of Cameron
some nuns became immensely strong.
They barked like dogs
and predicted the future.
They contaminated
the rest of the community,
and made the monastery
a temple of the devil.
In 1550 the nuns
of the convent of Nazareth
became possessed.
They climbed trees like cats
and levitated for hours.
In 1555, in Rome itself,
in an orphanage just like this one,
three orphans were responsible
for horrible things,
which could only be the work
of a diabolical mind.
Two of them became seriously ill.
And the third finally died,
killing all three.
Justine and Alucarda may be possessed.
Mother
The devil is elsewhere,
not in those poor girls.
It looks like we are
the victims of a conspiracy.
Justine and Alucarda
are possessed by the devil.
It's not surprising that Satan
has chosen these delicate creatures.
His plans are directed against
the Holy Church and its representatives.
They may not be possessed
by the devil himself
but at least by
one of his evil messengers.
What are we going to do?
We must pray that God can help us.
Jesus Christ
Deliver us from this nightmare.
Don't let them...
possess us.
How long has Justine been like this?
Almost a week.
And then she became ill.
She fainted during the hymns
and said the light affected her.
That's it.
A heliophobic demon.
A sixth category devil
who hates light.
He acts at night, when
the shadows protect him.
We must destroy him
in order to free the girls.
We must prepare...
an exorcism.
Justine. Poor Justine.
I won't let them harm you.
I won't let them take you away.
I'll take you somewhere
where you can be safe.
My poor Justine.
You've got to help me.
- No.
- You must get up.
Sister, what d'you think you're doing?
Open the door.
Come child.
Do not despair my child.
We are here to deliver you from evil.
It's not the child, but
the demon inside her that's resisting.
I shall prove this by
exposing la marca diaboli.
The devil's mark she has on her skin.
The mark of the devil.
Remove her clothing.
God of heaven. Jesus Christ.
Die soon!
This is all the evidence I need.
You have all seen her.
They cannot stand the name
of our Saviour. They are possessed.
You'll die soon!
Silence her.
I order thee, evil spirit
in the name of the one who judges.
the one who has created
and can destroy the world,
The one who has the power
to send you to hell.
Go! Depart!
Leave the bodies of
these two servants of God.
They must return to the Holy Church.
By the power of my faith
and of the Holy Ghost
I demand that you
return to your bottomless pit.
Humble yourself at the feet of Christ,
because his faith is greater than yours.
Christ before whom you tremble.
Christ who takes lost souls from the
fires of hell, to the light of heaven.
Now depart.
Back where you belong, evil spirit.
God commands you.
Do not resist.
God the Father commands you
God the Son commands you
God the Holy Ghost commands you.
The Holy Cross commands you.
The faith of St. Peter
and St. Paul commands you.
All the saints command you.
The Holy Cross commands you.
All the faithful command you.
Depart, seducer. Enemy of virtue.
Stop it.
Stop it, I say.
Doctor, how dare you
interrupt our holy ritual.
Holy ritual. This is the most
shameful thing I have ever witnessed.
This is not the fifteenth century.
I thought reason
had replaced superstition.
This is not an act of faith.
This is the most primitive expression
of ignorance I have ever seen.
You...
You have just killed Justine.
How dare you.
Damn you! Damn you!
Release her.
I'm taking this girl with me, before
you kill her, as you killed Justine.
My Lord.
Oh, my Christ.
You were witness.
How did this happen.
Where is the love he spoke of, Mother?
To cleanse her spirit
you have destroyed her body.
But the Lord will not abandon her soul,
because it is pure.
May he have mercy on you
for all that you have done.
Enough Sister.
- Yes? Who is it.
- Open the door please.
- Doctor, what's happened?
- She's been hurt. We must care for her.
- How is she doctor?
- She's alright. Bring the stethoscope.
It's alright.
Don't touch me.
Nobody wants to hurt you.
Everything's alright.
Father...
I'm scared.
- Is anything wrong?
- It's Alucarda.
She had a nightmare.
Don't be scared, darling.
She just had a nightmare.
Who is she?
Don't be afraid.
It's only me.
Daniela.
You just had a bad dream.
You're safe with us.
Try to rest now.
Can I stay with her
for a little while father?
Yes, darling, but not too long.
I'll be downstairs if you need me.
- Your father want to frighten me?
- He doesn't Alucarda.
- You were dreaming.
- I'm afraid of dreams.
The things I see are so real.
My father is a good doctor.
He'll cure you.
- Have we ever met before?
- I don't think so.
Because...
I do remember people's voices.
- You are very pretty.
- And you are beautiful.
Please don't go.
Stay with me.
Rubbish, pure rubbish.
- Who is it.
- It's me doctor, Felipe.
Something terrible has happened
at the convent.
- You've got to come.
- But it's five in the morning.
The Reverend Mother sent me.
You are to come right away.
I'm familiar with the terrible things
at the convent. What is it now?
She didn't say.
Only that you had to come.
I'll be right down.
Thank God you've come, Dr. Hasley.
Justine's shroud.
- Who did this?
- That's what we would like to know.
She was brought here
to be prepared for burial.
She was here all night,
until a few hours ago.
- Who was with her?
- Sister Veronica.
- Where is she now?
- We don't know doctor.
The least you should have done
was to say with her yourself.
Doctor.
Doctor, please.
No one in the convent
has been sleeping since Justine died.
We have been flagellating ourselves
as we flagellated Justine.
- Then someone took Justine's body.
- There's no other explanation.
- I must notify the authorities.
- No. They'll want to know how she died.
- Our religious community. The scandal.
- Don't worry.
The death certificate will say Justine
died of an unforeseen accident,
which is partly true.
Doctor, Mother Superior, Doctor.
Come quickly.
Oh, my God.
She's been burned to death.
It looks as if
the fires of hell have reached her.
Take her to the chapel.
I want to look at the corpse again.
- I'll go with you.
- No.
I want to examine it alone,
if you don't mind.
Take her to her cell.
Father, what is the meaning of this?
This nun was dead, and yet...
She moved.
The devil moved her limbs.
She was dead.
But the forces of evil
had not abandoned her.
How can you explain this
from a scientific point of view?
It happened, is happening
in front of your very eyes.
Do you still doubt?
I don't know.
You're the only one here
who has the answer.
These are the doings
of the transgressor,
The seducer, the enemy of virtue.
The perpetual persecutor of innocence.
The arch enemy of Almighty God.
You mean... the devil?
The devil.
I still can't believe it.
And yet this destruction was by someone
who hates all religious manifestation.
To that being, this chapel
was a terrible antagonist.
When I studied at the University
of Paris, I was taught
that demonic possession
was pure nonsense.
Or the sad result of
the workings of an insane mind.
They taught me that religion
was a farce and a form of slavery.
That the time has come to
break the chains of superstition.
I'm a man of reason.
And I'm faced with
something supernatural,
which frightens me.
This woman was dead.
Yet there was evil inside her ready
to come alive and attack the innocent.
This could only be as you say,
the work of what you call the devil.
Yes. It was the devil,
who entered our sister's body.
And turned her from the altar of the
Almighty to the fires of hell.
- Someone must have contaminated her.
- Justine.
And we must find her...
before there are more victims,
more corpses, more possessed.
Yes, we must find Justine,
or what is left of her.
You won't believe how things were.
But that's why we exorcised
Justine and Alucarda.
They were possessed by the devil.
Is that why Alucarda
was at the ceremony?
Her behaviour was evil, diabolical.
- Oh, my God, no... Daniela.
- Doctor
Daniela’s alone with her.
Daniela.
Thank you father.
- Mother Superior. Daniela's gone.
- I understand.
We must find them immediately
or Daniela also will be possessed.
- We'll all search for them.
- Thank you Mother.
- Are you ready Doctor?
- Yes Father.
We must find Alucarda.
Where should we start looking?
- I think I could help find her.
- How would you know, sister Angelica.
I remember some of the places
they used to go together.
- Let's go then.
- Promise me you won't hurt her.
- Please Doctor.
- Don't worry.
This way doctor.
Mother Superior,
please bring Father Lazarus.
- Yes doctor.
- Sister Theresa, where's your cross?
I've lost it.
Thank you sister.
Doctor.
They used to come here.
There seems to be another way out.
Come on Brother Felipe.
Please, no!
Justine.
Oh, God. Justine.
You're just killing her.
Doctor...
Alucarda...
The convent.
Alucarda at the convent.
Of course. That would be
the last place we would look for her.
She must be there.
Burn them.
Lucifer.
Doctor, what's happening?
Alucarda!
Take her out.
Satan.
Let it down.
Lucifer.
Alucarda, please.
Daniela.
God the Father commands thee.
God the Holy Ghost commands thee.
Subtitles: Corvusalbus