JOAQUINITO!
DOWN! DOWN!
ON THE GROUND!
EVERYBODY OFF THAT PLATFORM.
LET'S GO.
HERE, CHICK, CHICK,
CHICK, CHICK.
SHUT YER YAP AND SHUFFLE
THEM FEET, AMIGO!
WE'RE NOT FALLING
FOR THAT DODGE.
LITTLE MONKEY RUN RIGHT IN HERE.
I SEEN HIM.
SPREAD OUT AND KEEP LOW.
WE'LL FLUSH HIM OUT!
TRY NOT TO SHOOT US,
GREENHORN.
THERE HE IS!
GET ON HIM, BOY!
THOUGHT I HAD HIM.
SHEE-IT.
Y'ALL FELLAS MIND STANDING GUARD A MINUTE?
I GOT TO IRRIGATE.
I DON'T WANT 'EM TO CATCH ME WITH MY PANTS DOWN.
THEM GOOGOOS'RE ALL
HALFWAY TO DAGUPAN BY NOW.
GODDAMN.
O LORD, HAVE MERCY.
AAAAH!
AAAH! AAAAH!
SOMEBODY HIT?
NO, IT'S JUST SHANKER
DRAINING THE SNAKE.
I'M SICK, SERGEANT.
I GOTTA GO BACK.
IT BURNS ME.
OL' DEADEYE HERE
MISSED ONE.
I EXPECT HE'LL GET
ANOTHER CHANCE.
I NEED TO KNOW
WHO THE HEAD MAN IS.
BUSCA LA CABEZA.
THIS BUNCH
LOOK ALMOST WHITE.
TIME TO JOIN THE PARTY, FELLAS.
VAMOOSE.
ARE YOU WITH US, SHANKER?
I'M DYIN' HERE, SARGE.
SERVES YOU RIGHT.
THE CABEZA DE BARRIO...
IS THAT ONE.
THESE HERE WERE LOCKED UP OUT BACK, LIEUTENANT.
WE HAVE BEEN PRISONERS
OF THE INSURRECTOS...
AND OF THESE POOR COWARDS
AND SINNERS.
YOU SPEAK ENGLISH.
I COMPREHEND
THIS LANGUAGE, YES.
THE CABEZA IS THIS ONE.
YOU.
ON YOUR FEET.
WHAT IS YOUR NAME?
SU NOMBRE.
WHERE ARE
ALL THE YOUNG MEN?
THEY HAVE GONE AWAY TO FIGHT IN THIS UNHOLY REBELLION.
I'M ASKING HIM.
I KNOW THIS ONE.
HE IS A LIAR.
ASK HIM.
AS YOU WISH.
HE SAYS THEY ARE HIDING.
WHERE?
HE WON'T TALK.
HIS OWN BROTHER IS THE JEFE OF THE INSURRECTOS.
THEY HAVE BEEN
KEEPING US PRISONERS
SINCE THE SURRENDER
IN BATANGAS.
TELL HIM...
THAT IT DOESN'T MATTER
WHERE THE INSURRECTOS ARE.
IF THEY DON'T SURRENDER,
WE WILL HUNT THEM DOWN
AND KILL THEM.
YOU ARE CAPABLE OF THIS?
TELL HIM.
HIS NAME IS
RAFAEL DACANAY,
AND HE HAS BEEN
CABEZA DE BARRIO HERE,
AS WAS HIS FATHER
BEFORE HIM,
FOR TEN YEARS.
IT IS HE WHO COLLECTS THE TAX
FOR THE GOVERNMENT.
GOOD DUTY
IF YOU CAN GET IT.
AND WHAT HE IS
NOT ABLE TO COLLECT,
HE MUST PAY
FROM HIS OWN POCKET.
NOT SO GOOD.
BRASS ON THE HORIZON,
LIEUTENANT.
EVERYTHING LOCKED DOWN HERE, LIEUTENANT?
YES, SIR.
WE TOOK THE BARRIO
WITH NO RESISTANCE--
ONLY A COUPLE OF RUNAWAYS.
PICK TEN YOU CAN TRUST
AND WORK OUT THE BILLETING.
SIR?
CAN'T HAVE THE MONKEYS
SNEAKING IN BEHIND US
WHILE WE'RE CHASING AGUINALDO
UP THE ISLAND.
I NEED A GARRISON HERE.
MY BOYS ARE HOT TO GO,
COLONEL.
STAYING HERE WOULD BE--
I NEED A GARRISON.
YES, SIR.
HELL, FOR ALL I KNOW,
OLD AGGY'S HIDING RIGHT IN THIS VILLAGE.
YOU COULD SMOKE HIM OUT
AND END THE WAR.
LORD KNOWS I CAN'T TELL
ONE FROM THE OTHER.
MAY I THANK YOU,
COLONEL,
THAT YOU DELIVER US
FROM CAPTIVITY.
THIS IS PADRE HIDALGO.
THE LOCAL INSURRECTOS
HAD HIM CAGED UP IN THE BODEGA
ALONG WITH A COUPLE OF DONS
THEY CAUGHT.
WE'LL GET YOU BACK TO MANILA
AS SOON AS WE CAN, PADRE.
THESE ARE MY CHILDREN.
THEIR SOULS ARE IN MY CARE.
I CANNOT LEAVE THIS PLACE.
YOU GOT YOURSELF
AN INTERPRETER, LIEUTENANT.
ZUÑIGA!
YOU VAMOS WITH US.
YOU HOLD ONTO A SIGNALIST
AND SOME COOLIES
TO HANG THE WIRE TOMORROW,
AND YOU KEEP IT SINGIN'.
GET THESE PEOPLE UP OUT OF THE DIRT,
FOR GOD'S SAKE.
WE'RE SUPPOSED TO BE WINNING
THEIR HEARTS AND MINDS!
YES, SIR!
WHATLEY AND NINE
I CAN TRUST, SERGEANT.
WHATLEY, THOMAS...
CASEY, DORTMUNDER...
LYNCH, PEDERSON,
FITZSIMMONS, ANDREWS,
SHANKER AND McBRIDE--
YOU WILL REMAIN HERE ON GUARD!
THE REST OF YOU FALL OUT
AND FORM UP BEHIND THE COLONEL.
ON THE DOUBLE!
WHOSE SHACK IS THAT?
IT BELONGS TO
THIS SAME MAN.
IN THAT CASE, TELL HIM
HE'S GOT FIVE MINUTES
TO REMOVE
HIS PERSONAL ITEMS.
THAT'LL BE MY HEADQUARTERS.
TELL HIM WE'RE STAYING HERE TO PROTECT
HIS VILLAGE FROM THE LADRONES.
TELL HIM HE'S STILL HEAD MAN,
WHICH MEANS IF THERE'S TROUBLE,
IT'S HIS HEAD.
HOLD THAT FIRE!
DO NOT SHOOT!
IT IS THE TIME OF THE ANGELUS.
THIS IS HIS DUTY.
PRAYERS.
EVERY DAY AT THE SIX.
IT IS OUR CUSTOM.
HAVE SOMEBODY CLIMB UP THERE AND
YANK THE CLAPPER OUT OF THAT BELL.
LYNCH.
WHEN THE SUN IS UP,
YOUR GOOGOO JUST LAYS AROUND
EATING BANANAS
AND WATCHING CHICKEN FIGHTS.
BUT THE MINUTE IT GETS DARK,
HE LIKES TO CREEP UP
THROUGH THE JUNGLE
WITH THAT BOLO HE CARRIES,
AND THEN CHOP-CHOP!
WE LOST MORE GOOD AMERICANS
THAT WAY
THAN WE EVER DONE
IN BATTLE.
DEADEYE'S RELIEVING YOU,
PRIVATE. GET SOME SLEEP.
I WAS SUPPOSED TO BE OVER HERE
KILLING SPANIARDS.
JUST KILL SOME
IN YOUR DREAMS.
CHANGE YOUR POSITION
EVERY NOW AND THEN.
THEY CAN'T SHOOT FOR SHIT,
BUT NO SENSE MAKING AND EASY TARGET.
RIGHT.
FOUR HOURS, SON.
DON'T LET US DOWN.
POSTED?
FOUR CORNERS.
I TOLD THE REST OF THE BOYS
TO SLEEP WITH THEIR BOOTS ON
JUST IN CASE.
MY FEET HAVEN'T BEEN DRY
SINCE CALOOCAN.
GRAB A SPOT.
EASY DUTY HERE.
MIGHT BE.
PLAY CARDS...
AND SWAT FLIES.
YOU WERE OUT WEST.
REGULAR ARMY.
FIFTEEN YEARS.
DRAGGIN' REDSKINS
BACK TO THE RESERVATION.
YOU?
BEFORE I VOLUNTEERED
FOR THIS MESS,
I BUILT HOUSES...
GREAT, BIG ONES.
LIEUTENANT.
THAT PADRE...
HE'S GOT HIS OWN DEAL
RUNNIN' HERE.
I WOULDN'T TRUST HIM.
RELIGION IS A CIVILIZING INFLUENCE, SERGEANT.
AND IF HE CAN HELP
KEEP A LEASH ON THESE PEOPLE,
HE'S WELCOME TO THEIR SOULS.
YES, SIR.
AND I DON'T TRUST HIM.
TO YOUR POSTS!
DON'T SHOOT
TILL YOU SEE SOMETHING!
THEY COMIN'?
I DON'T KNOW.
I THOUGHT THERE WAS
SOMETHING OUT THERE.
WELL, THERE'S ALWAYS SOMETHING
OUT THERE, DAMNIT.
WHAT DO WE DO,
SARGE?
WE WAIT TILL
THE SUN COMES UP.
I'LL LET THE OTHERS KNOW.
THERE DAMN WELL BETTER BE
A DEAD GOOGOO OUT THERE, BOY.
ATTAGO, DEADEYE.
AT LEAST YOUR AIM
IS GETTING BETTER.
I ATTENDED SEMINARY
IN VALLADOLID,
BUT I WAS BORN IN TOLEDO.
THE ALHAMBRA.
YOU HAVE BEEN THERE?
NO. I STUDIED THE BUILDING.
SO YOU DECIDED
TO BE A MISSIONARY.
THE FILIPINAS ARE
A COLONY OF SPAIN--
"WERE."
WERE A COLONY OF SPAIN.
SERVICE HERE IS NOT ONLY
A RELIGIOUS DUTY,
BUT A PATRIOTIC ONE.
WE ARE SOLDIERS OF GOD.
THE PEOPLE HERE LISTEN TO YOU?
THEY LISTEN, BUT THEY
DO NOT ALWAYS OBEY.
I'M GOING TO NEED YOUR HELP.
WHICH I OFFER FREELY
IN ANY MATTER THAT DOES ENDANGER
THE MORALS OF MY FILIGRESES.
I DON'T THINK THAT'S
GOING TO BE A PROBLEM.
YOU'RE NOT A CATHOLIC.
NO.
I MUST WARN YOU
THAT THE MORAL PATH
IS NOT ALWAYS
THE MOST OBVIOUS.
CAN YOU WALK?
IF IT GETS ME
TO THE CLAP SHACK,
I'LL CRAWL BACK
TO MANILA.
I'M PUTTING THESE PEOPLE
IN YOUR CARE.
NO SWEAT, SARGE.
ALL RIGHT, YOU DAGOES--
VAMOOSE!
THERE ARE TWO HARVESTS.
ONLY DURING JULY AND AUGUST
DOES THE LAND REST.
AND THE VILLAGERS
OWN THE LAND TOGETHER?
HE OWNS THIS LAND,
AND THAT.
THE PEOPLE ARE KASAMAS--
THEY WORK FOR A PORTION
OF WHAT THEY HARVEST.
SO AMIGO HERE HAS GOT
THE WHOLE DEAL SEWED UP.
THE LANDS BEYOND,
AND MANY MORE YOU CANNOT SEE,
ARE MINE.
WHEN I AM PRISONER, THE PEOPLE,
THEY DO NOT CARE FOR THEM.
BUT IF THEY'RE WORKING
FOR SHARES...
THIS IS THE POLO--
A WORK THAT IS A DUTY
OVERSEEN BY THE CHURCH
AND THE GUARDIA CIVIL.
AND YOU RAKE IN ALL THE PROFITS.
I'VE SEEN ENOUGH.
TELL HIM THE PEOPLE CAN DO FOR THE CROP JUST LIKE ALWAYS,
ONLY THAT DIKE THERE,
THAT'S THE DEAD LINE.
ANYONE STEPS PAST THAT WITHOUT PERMISSION,
WE SHOOT THEM.
AND TELL HIM FROM NOW ON
HE CAN WORK HIS OWN DAMN FIELDS
WITH EVERYONE ELSE.
IT WOULD PLEASE ME
TO DO THIS.
ALL RIGHT! HUSTLE, BOYS!
DO YOU HEAR ME?
WE'RE COMIN' WITH THAT WIRE.
CHOP-CHOP!
HEY! BOSSMAN!
YOU WORKEE COOLIE TOO HARD.
WHERE YOU HEADED?
BACK TO MANILA.
SO'S YOU CAN INFECT THE REST OF THE WHORES IN SAMPALOC.
THAT'S A NICE
LITTLE CREW YOU GOT.
YEAH, THAT'S, UM,
THAT'S CHOP-CHOP,
AND THE SOURPUSS THERE
I CALL "CHUCKLES."
THAT'S, UM, "SKINNY,"
AND THAT ONE THERE,
THAT'S "MOON."
THERE'S A GANG HANGING WIRE
UP FROM SANTA ANA
WHERE BATES HERE IS GOING,
WE'RE GONNA MEET 'EM HALFWAY.
I'LL GIVE 'EM YOUR REGARDS.
YOU SURE YOU GOT A DOSE
OR YOU JUST GOLDBRICKING?
YOU WANNA SEE IT?
NOT ON A BET.
I'LL DRINK SOME OF THEM
COLD SAN MIGUELS FOR YA.
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S HUSTLE THOSE POLES, BOYS!
COME ON! HURRY! HURRY!
WHO NEEDS A DAMN TELEGRAPH?
I HEAR THAT YOU THE BIG BOSSMAN AROUND HERE, AMIGO.
GOTTA BE ROUGH, HAVING TO HUNKER DOWN,
GET YOUR HANDS DIRTY.
JUST LIKE YOUR OLD DADDY
BACK ON THE PLANTATION.
WE WAS SHARECROPPERS.
NIGGERS ON BOTH SIDES OF US,
CHOPPIN' THE SAME DAMN COTTON.
AI.
AH GA. OGALOGO.
GA GA GA.
WHAT'S HE SAYIN'?
IT'S ALL GOOGOO TO ME.
ALL RIGHT, THE PROVISIONS
OF GENERAL ORDER 100.
"ANY DISTRICT OR COUNTRY
OCCUPIED BY AN ENEMY
"STANDS UNDER THE MARTIAL LAW
OF THE INVADING COUNTRY.
"GREAT SEVERITY
IN THAT MARTIAL LAW
MAY BE EXERCISED IN REGIONS
WHERE ACTUAL HOSTILITIES EXIST."
"MEN WHO COMMIT HOSTILITIES
"WITH INTERMITTING RETURNS
TO THEIR HOMES AND AVOCATIONS,
"DIVESTING THEMSELVES OF THE
CHARACTER AND APPEARANCE OF SOLDIERS,
"SHALL BE TREATED
NOT AS COMBATANTS,
BUT AS BANDITS
AND MURDERERS."
"GUIDES, WHEN IT IS PROVED THAT
THEY HAVE MISLED INTENTIONALLY,
"AND THOSE DISGUISED IN THE CIVILIAN DRESS OF THE COUNTRY
"BUT EMPLOYED IN OBTAINING
INFORMATION FOR THE ENEMY,
SHALL BE TREATED AS SPIES
AND SUFFER DEATH BY HANGING."
*
COMO SE?
CAPITAN.
CAPITAN...
YOUR FILIPINO...
IS LIKE A MIX BETWEEN
A MEXICAN AND A CHINAMAN.
THE MISSING LINK.
A STUNTED RACE.
HELL, EVEN THEIR HORSES
ARE PUNY.
WE MISSED OUT ON
THEM CUBAN WOMEN.
WHORES ARE WHORES.
NOT THE WHORES--
THEM TOBACCO-ROLLING
SEÑORITAS,
THE ONES THEY SHOW
ON THE CIGAR BOXES.
YOU'RE AS GREEN
AS DEADEYE HERE.
MAYBE I OUGHTA GIVE THESE GOOGOO DOLLS A TUMBLE.
WIND UP LIKE SHANKER.
SHANKER DIPPED IT IN
THE WRONG PUDDLE IS ALL.
CAN'T GO PICKING YOUR PUTAS
WHEN YOU'RE BLIND DRUNK.
SOMEBODY BLIND DRUNK?
BEENO.
YOU'RE SHITTIN' ME.
UNH-UNH. SOME OLD-TIMER
IN THE VILLE HERE MAKES IT.
I THINK IT'S FROM COCONUT PALMS.
I DON'T CARE...
IF IT'S FROM
BUFFALO PISS.
HAND IT OVER.
WE'RE ON AN OPEN CIRCUIT
HERE IN THE FIELD.
THEY DIDN'T WANT TO LOOP US
INTO THE MAIN LINES,
SO EVERYTHING THAT
WE SEND OR RECEIVE
WILL BE RELAYED ON FROM
THE STATION AT SANTA ANA.
FROM NOW ON,
YOU SLEEP NEXT TO THIS RIG.
IF A MESSAGE COMES IN--
IT MAKES A SOUND.
ENOUGH TO WAKE YOU?
LIKE A BUCKET
OF COLD WATER.
DUTCH! YOU OUT THERE?
YEAH, YEAH!
I GOT THE
QUICK-STEP AGAIN.
OH, BOY,
WHEN IT HITS YOU...
I'M HERE TO RELIEVE YOU.
HE STILL OUT THERE?
WHO?
THE AMIGO.
WITH THE WATER BUFFALO.
HOW LONG YOU BEEN IN THERE?
ANYTHING?
I TESTED IT LAST NIGHT.
BUT YOU'RE GETTING
NOTHING BACK FROM SANTA ANA?
LINE MUST BE DOWN SOMEWHERE.
WHOO!
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
THE PRINCIPLE.
WELL, YOU'VE SEEN OUR BATTERY, RIGHT? YEAH.
THERE'S COPPER SULFATE SOLUTION
ON THE BOTTOM,
AND ZINC SULFATE SOLUTION ON THE TOP-- WHOA.
WHOA.
I SAID I DON'T UNDERSTAND IT,
NOT THAT I WANT TO
UNDERSTAND IT.
DOWN!
TWO AT A TIME,
IN RUSHES.
FIND YOURSELF
SOME COVER.
OH, GOD.
HEY.
DON'T TELL NOBODY ABOUT THAT AMIGO SLIPPIN' OFF MY WATCH.
FOUND 'EM TWO MILES
DOWN THE SOUTH ROAD.
GOT THE LINE BACK UP,
BUT THEY CAN CUT IT ANYTIME THEY WANT.
MURDERERS.
ASK HIM WHAT
HE KNOWS ABOUT THIS.
WHAT HE SAYING?
HE'S A LIAR.
WHAT'S HE SAYING?!
HE SAYS HE HAS NOTHING
TO DO WITH THIS.
TELL HIM HE CAN HELP
BURY THIS BUNCH.
AND YOU CAN DO THE CEREMONY.
THESE MEN
WERE HEATHENS.
WHAT CAN I DO FOR THEM?
MAKE SOMETHING UP.
WHATLEY!
YES, SIR!
NEXT DAMN HOLE I DIG...
IS GONNA BE YOURS, AMIGO.
*
LONG MESSAGE.
MILITARY PARLANCE, SIR.
WHAT'S THE GIST OF IT?
THEY WANT US
TO HOLD THE FORT.
THEY'RE ALL AROUND US.
FALL BACK!
EVERYBODY FALL BACK!
HOLD FIRE!
HOLD FIRE TILL
YOU SEE A FACE!
TAKE COUNT.
DORTMUNDER!
YO!
LYNCH!
YO.
PEDERSON!
YO!
CAUGHT ONE IN THE BACK.
ONE OF OURS?
THAT'S A MAUSER WOUND.
OURS'D MAKE A BIGGER HOLE.
IS IT SAFE?
WHAT'S IT LOOK LIKE TO YOU?
HER NAME WAS
ESPERANZA BANAAG.
HER FATHER WAS WITH
THE INSURRECTOS.
HE WAS KILLED BY OUR GUARDIA
FOUR YEARS AGO.
NICE DIGS.
EVERYBODY'S TALKING ABOUT CHASING
THE DIRTY DAGOES DOWN IN CUBA,
SO ME AND MY BUDDY TOM
SIGNED UP,
ONLY HE GOT SO SICK IN CAMP
BACK IN SAN FRANCISCO
THEY DIDN'T EVEN
LET HIM ON THE BOAT.
HELL, THE TRIP OVER HERE
WOULD HAVE KILT HIM.
DOWN IN THE HOLD...
THREE BUNKS,
ONE ON TOP OF THE OTHER,
AND...
THE FOOD THEY GIVE YOU...
IF WE HADN'T GOTTEN
TO STOP AT HAWAII--
YOU EVER BEEN TO HAWAII?
'COURSE
YOU HAVEN'T.
YOU'RE AWFUL PRETTY
FOR A...
WELL, YOU KNOW,
FOR ONE OF YOU.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT I'M SAYIN', DO YOU?
THEM HAWAIIAN GIRLS
WAS PRETTY TOO,
THEY WERE DARK LIKE YOU....
MAYBE DARKER,
BUT...
REAL PRETTY, YOU KNOW?
MOST DAYS I WISH I'D JUST
STAYED HOME IN LUBBOCK.
THAT LITTLE FELLA
WHO OWNED THIS PILE
WAS SOME KIND OF MUCKITY-MUCK
IN THE GOVERNMENT.
WE SHIPPED HIM OFF TO GUAM.
POST AND BEAM.
HUH?
THE, UH...
THE ROOF HERE SITS SQUARE
ON THE FOUR CORNER POSTS...
SO THE WALLS
BEAR NO WEIGHT.
EARTHQUAKE COUNTRY.
WHAT'S YOUR BAILIWICK AGAIN?
SAN ISIDRO.
ZONE TWO, HUH?
YES, SIR.
THEM INDIANS
BEEN UP TO MISCHIEF?
SNIPING MOST NIGHTS.
THEY CUT OUR TELEGRAPH LINES
ONCE A WEEK.
MURDERED OUR COOLIES, SIR.
WE TAKE A TOWN,
AND IF WE DON'T
GARRISON IT,
THEY'RE BACK IN BUSINESS
A DAY LATER.
IF WE DO GARRISON IT,
THEY SIT OUT IN THE DAMN JUNGLE!
IT'S AWFUL HARD TO TELL THE INDIANS FROM THE AMIGOS, SIR.
WELL, GENERAL MacARTHUR
IS TAKING COMMAND,
AND HE WANTS US TO PUT SOME
TEETH INTO GENERAL ORDER 100.
THEM GLOVES ARE COMING OFF, GENTLEMEN.
FROM NOW ON THERE'S NO MORE
EASY COME AND GO.
WE CONCENTRATE
THE POPULATION
AND ISOLATE THE LADRONES
OUT IN THE BOONDOCKS.
CONCENTRATE, SIR?
WITHOUT THE SUPPORT
OF THE PEOPLE,
THEM BANDITS WILL STARVE.
NOW, WE MAKE IT
VERY SIMPLE FOR 'EM.
YOU'RE EITHER UNDER
AMERICAN PROTECTION,
UNDER AMERICAN CONTROL,
OR YOU'RE CONSIDERED TO BE HOSTILE,
ARMED OR NOT.
THERE IS TO BE NO TRAVEL
BETWEEN BARRIOS
WITHOUT SAFE CONDUCT PAPERS,
WHILE TRANSPORT AND
SANITARY IMPROVEMENTS
WILL BE UNDERTAKEN AND SUPERVISED BY GARRISON COMMANDERS.
AND THERE WILL BE A CURFEW
AT SUNDOWN,
AND VIOLATORS WILL BE SHOT.
NOW, WE HAVE DONE WITH THE CARROT
FOR THE MOMENT, GENTLEMEN...
AND IT IS TIME
TO EMPLOY THE STICK.
NOW WHAT?
IF IT DON'T STOP RAININ',
I'M GONNA SHOOT MYSELF.
BE MY GUEST.
CALL YOU.
KINGS.
SHIT ON A STICK.
NO, YOU CAN'T PLAY.
WHAT?
AT LEAST NOT TILL YOU
PAY ME WHAT YOU OWE ME,
SO'S I CAN PAY
THIS SIGNAL CORPS SUMBITCH,
WIPE THAT GRIN OFF
HIS COUNTENANCE.
I CAN'T PLAY CARDS,
WHAT THE HELL AM I SUPPOSED TO DO?
THAT SUICIDE DEAL
SOUNDED PRETTY GOOD.
USE MY RIFLE.
THE BARRELS GOT COBWEBS IN IT.
OH.
YOU STARTLED ME,
SKEAKIN' UP LIKE THAT.
WHAT'S THAT, COFFEE?
SOME KIND OF SOUP.
OH!
DAMN, IT'S HOT.
DID YOU MAKE THIS FOR ME?
GEE, THAT'S SWELL OF YA.
IT'S NOT THAT SPICY STUFF,
IS IT?
OH, THAT'S GOOD.
I LIKE A LITTLE PEPPER
IN MY GREENS,
BUT SOME OF THE STUFF
YOU FOLKS EAT--
SERGEANT RUNNELS'D NAIL MY HIDE
TO A WALL IF HE CAUGHT YOU HERE,
BUT...
I DON'T GIVE A DAMN.
I SURE AM SORRY ABOUT
KILLING ALL YOUR BUFFALOS.
I DON'T NEED YOUR HELP
TO TAKE A SHIT...
SONNY!
YOU FELL DOWN THE STEPS,
YOU FELL IN A PUDDLE...
"ME WANT AMIGO."
JESUS,
YOU'RE A MESS...
SWILLIN' THAT TUBA DOWN.
GET YOUR PANTS DOWN.
FALL IN THE DAMN SLIT TRENCH
AND DROWN.
HA HA HA!
TAKE MY HAND.
HEY.
THERE'S SOMEBODY
LOOSE IN THE CAMP!
HEY, GIL--
HEY!
HOLD UP THERE!
DON'T YOU MOVE!
GET TO YOUR POST, DAMNIT!
FULL ALERT!
WHO THE HELL IS THIS?
WHAT WAS THIS ONE DOING?
FAR AS I CAN TELL,
HE WAS LEADING THE OTHER ONE TO YOU, LIEUTENANT.
ONE MAN WITH A BOLO?
MAYBE HE'S ONE OF THEM AMOKKERS,
HOPPED UP ON BEENO.
PUT HIM BACK IN LOCK-UP.
YES, SIR.
COME ON, YOU.
GET THE REST OF THESE PEOPLE
BACK INSIDE.
YES, SIR. LYNCH.
COME ON, SARGE.
COME ON, LET'S GO. MOVE!
COME ON, LET'S GO!
SOMEBODY GOT SHOT.
THESE THINGS
ARE JUST FALLIN' APART.
WHAT IS THIS,
FIVE WEEKS OF RAIN?
IT'S A WONDER MORE PEOPLE IN THIS
COUNTRY AREN'T BUGHOUSE CRAZY.
WHO SAYS THEY'RE NOT?
I DO NOT UNDERSTAND
WHY YOU DO NOT APPOINT A CABEZA,
AS WAS DONE BEFORE.
SATURNINO HERE--
HE WILL BE JUST AS ELIGIBLE
FOR THE JOB AS EVERYONE ELSE.
THE WHOLE POINT OF THE ORDER IS TO GET
THEM USED TO THE WORKINGS OF DEMOCRACY.
THESE ARE CHILDREN!
AND CHILDREN NEED TO LEARN WHAT'S GOOD FOR THEM!
IN YOUR ARMY,
ARE THE OFFICERS ELECTED?
LOOK, THIS COMES FROM THE TOP.
ELECTIONS WILL BE HELD.
WHAT'S HE ASKING?
HE DOUBTS THEIR CHOICE
WILL BE ACCEPTED.
TELL HIM THAT IN AMERICA,
THE WILL OF THE PEOPLE IS SACRED.
HOW MANY MEN OVER TWENTY-ONE
HAVE WE GOT?
NOT MUCH OF A TURNOUT.
WELL, LET'S GET THIS
OVER WITH.
YOU COULD
LET THE WOMEN VOTE.
DON'T BE RIDICULOUS.
THREE TO ONE THEY GO FOR
WILLIAM JENNINGS BRYANT.
WE'LL COUNT THEM
IN THE CHAPEL.
WE'LL COUNT THEM RIGHT HERE.
VERY WELL.
A SURPRISING
DEMONSTRATION
FOR MEN WHO CANNOT
READ OR WRITE.
IS THIS
WHO I THINK IT IS?
NOW DO YOU SEE?
YOU WILL FORCED TO CONTRADICT YOURSELF BEFORE THEM.
THE WILL OF THE PEOPLE
IS SACRED.
COME ON OUT.
AND SHE CAN'T JUST STAY
WHERE WE HAD HER?
SHE HAS
THE COUGHING DISEASE.
TUBERCULOSIS?
THIS ONE, YES.
DACANAY WISHES PERMISSION
TO BUILD HER HOUSE AGAIN.
AND WHO'S GONNA BUILD IT?
GET A FEW OF OUR SHOVELS
ON THAT.
YES, SIR.
I MUSTA TORCHED A HUNDRED OF THESE
DAMN THINGS BETWEEN HERE AND MANILA.
NEVER THOUGHT
I'D PUT ONE UP.
I DIDN'T THINK THE LITTLE
MONKEYS HAD IT IN 'EM.
THEY ARE A VERY
CLEVER PEOPLE.
ALWAYS SMILING,
EVEN WHEN AT LABOR.
IT'S NOT SUCH A BAD THING.
ONE MUST NEVER FORGET WHAT LIES BEHIND THE SMILE.
WHAT DOES HE WANT?
ON THE DAY OF OUR SAINT
FOR WHICH THE BARRIO
IS NAMED
IS THE TRADITION TO CELEBRATE WITH A FIESTA.
A CELEBRATION.
PARTLY RELIGIOUS
AND PARTLY PROFANE--
LIKE SO MANY THINGS
IN THIS POOR COUNTRY.
MIGHT BE NICE TO LET THE FOLKS
BLOW OFF SOME STEAM.
THE DRUMMER USED TO COME AROUND OUR PLACE ONCE A MONTH.
SELL YOU STORE GOODS,
HARNESS LEATHER, LAMP OILS.
YEAH. WHAT DO YOU
SUPPOSE THIS IS?
DON'T TOUCH IT.
*
HEY.
UH...
I DON'T KNOW IF THIS IS
ALL RIGHT, BUT I...
I SEEN THIS
THEY WERE SELLING,
AND I THOUGHT IT WOULD
LOOK NICE ON YOU.
FOR YOU.
TAKE IT.
CAN YOU PUT IT ON?
PUT IT ON?
TOO RISKY, HUH?
YOU'D PROBABLY CATCH HELL
FROM YOUR PARENTS.
LOOK, I'M JUST GONNA...
OUT IN FRONT OF EVERYBODY,
I KNOW WE CAN'T LIKE...
UM...
I'M JUST GONNA...
STICK PRETTY CLOSE
TO YOU, ALL RIGHT?
IF I GET ON YOUR NERVES,
YOU JUST TELL ME TO GO SHOO.
SHOO.
I'VE HAD HOME-BREW
OUTTA PEACHES,
HOME-BREW OUTTA APPLES,
HOME-BREW OUTTA, UH, CORN,
SUGAR CANE,
BUT THIS TUBA
IS THE DAMNDEST STUFF.
WHATEVER YOU SAY, JOE.
JUST KEEP IT COMIN'.
HILARIO...
NOT A BAD TUNE.
IT IS THE AIR THAT OUR CAZADORES
HEAR WHEN THEY MARCH INTO BATTLE.
NICE OF THEM TO PLAY IT
FOR YOU.
THEY ARE WONDERFUL MIMICS.
IF THEY
ADMIRE A MELODY...
NO, NO, NO!
YOU DON'T PUT SAUCE
ON BARBECUE!
HOLY MOLEY,
WHERE YOU FROM?
SOUTH CAROLINA.
WELL, THAT EXPLAINS A LOT.
WHERE DID THEY LEARN THAT?
AS I SAID, THEY ARE
WONDERFUL MIMICS.
YOU SHOULD STAND UP.
*
WHY IS EVERYONE
TAKING OFF THEIR HATS?
THEY BELIEVE THIS IS
YOUR NATIONAL ANTHEM.
YOU'RE DRUNK.
I'M OFF DUTY, SARGE.
IT'S 10:00,
AND YOU GOT SENTRY
ON THE SOUTH END.
THERE AIN'T ANY BANDIDOS
LEFT OUT THERE.
IF I CATCH YOU SLEEPING...
OHH.
YOU GONNA WAKE UP
IN THE HOOSEGOW.
MOVE.
I TAKE BACK EVERY GOOD THING I EVER SAID ABOUT YOU.
AH.
THE THING IS...
WHEN YOU'VE GOT A LOT OF PEOPLE
YOU'RE RESPONSIBLE FOR...
YOU...
YOU'VE GOT YOUR ORDERS,
AND YOU'VE GOT
ALL YOUR PEOPLE...
THEIR LIVES.
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT THE HELL
I'M TALKING ABOUT, DO YOU?
OR MAYBE YOU DO.
NICE PARTY.
*
NO.
GODDAMNIT!
TO YOUR POSTS!
YOU'RE UP EARLY, SIR.
THERE'S A SENTRY BACK THERE WHO DESERVES A FIRING SQUAD.
WHAT IS ALL THIS?
A FIESTA--
SAINT ISIDRO THE LABORER.
YOU'RE GETTIN' PRETTY
COMFORTABLE HERE.
IT'S BEEN QUIET, SIR.
NO SNIPING, NO THIEVERY...
SAN JUAN HAS BEEN HIT
ONCE A WEEK.
AND THEY BURNED
HALF OF ROSARIO DOWN.
AND BOTH
OF THOSE BARRIOS
HAVE GARRISONS TWICE THE SIZE OF YOURS.
WHY DO YOU THINK
THAT IS?
WE HAVE MADE EFFORTS AT--
AT UNDERSTANDING, SIR--
IT'S BECAUSE
THE LADRONES
HAVE PEOPLE WORKING
FOR THEM HERE!
THEY'RE GIVING THEM
FOOD, INFORMATION...
WE GET A TELEGRAPH MESSAGE
ONCE A WEEK MAYBE.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT INFORMATION THEY--
A SUPPLY TRAIN WAS AMBUSHED ON THE SOUTH ROAD
OUTSIDE OF SANTA CLARA
YESTERDAY!
KILLED A TEAMSTER,
RAN THE MULES OFF
AND PINNED THE REST DOWN TILL A
SQUAD WANDERED UP FROM MACAPAL,
AND YOU'RE THROWING PARTIES FOR THE NATIVES!
NOW, WHAT BECAME
OF THAT HEAD MAN?
HE'S, UH...
HUH?!
HE'S RIGHT HERE, SIR.
I WILL BET YOU A FIFTH
OF KENTUCKY BOURBON
THAT THIS MONKEY
KNOWS WHERE THEIR HIDEOUT IS!
CHIEF! ZUÑIGA!
YOU GENTLEMEN KNOW THE DRILL.
GARRISONED IN SOME
LITTLE CORNER OF NOWHERE,
NOTHING MUCH TO DO,
NO ACTION.
ALL YOUR SOLDIERING SKILLS
BEGIN TO SLIP AWAY.
I SAT ON AN INDIAN RESERVATION
FOR FIVE YEARS...
WATCHED MY MEN TURN INTO DRUNKS
AND WHOREMONGERS.
A LITTLE RABBIT HUNT WILL DO
YOUR FELLOWS A WORLD OF GOOD.
ANYTHING TO REPORT?
WHERE IS CREIGHTON?
DAMNIT!
HE SAYS
THE MAN CONFESSES.
HE KNOWS WHERE
THE INSURRECTOS HIDE.
YOU'RE STILL HERE?
I AM.
YOU THINK
HE'S TELLING THE TRUTH?
I HEAR THE CONFESSIONS
OF MANY MEN, COLONEL,
BUT THEY ARE ONLY
TORTURED BY THEIR SINS.
RAFAEL! RAFAEL!
RAFAEL.
THAT'S NOT TORTURE, PADRE.
FIVE MINUTES ON THE TRAIL,
HE'LL BE
AS GOOD AS NEW.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM HERE?
MAYBE HE NEEDS WATER.
HE HAD HIS FILL OF THAT
THIS MORNING.
WHAT THE SON OF A MONKEY NEEDS
IS A DOSE OF LEAD.
CORPUS CHRISTI.
AMEN.
THAT'S GOVERNMENT
PROPERTY, SOLDIER.
WELL, THE GOVERNMENT
CAN COME AND GET IT.
SHOULDN'T NOBODY DO NOTHING
BUT SLEEP IN THIS HEAT.
THAT'S WHAT THEM GOOGOO BANDIDOS ARE DOING RIGHT NOW,
STRETCHED OUT IN HAMMOCKS
NEXT TO A NICE COOL STREAM.
THAT'S WHERE WE'RE GOING?
HELL NO.
WE'RE GOING ON AN ALL-DAY STROLL TO NOWHERE.
YOU THINK SO?
THAT LITTLE AMIGO
UP THERE
COULDN'T WALK A STRAIGHT LINE IN A CATTLE CHUTE.
THEM FELLAS WORKED HIM OVER
PRETTY GOOD.
FIRST CHANCE HE GET,
HE'S GONNA GIVE US THE SLIP.
AND THAT'S THE BEST THING
THAT'S HAPPEN TO US TODAY.
HE SAYS THIS IS IT.
WE'VE BEEN GOING IN CIRCLES,
DAMNIT!
IF ANYBODY CAMPED HERE,
IT WAS A LONG WAY BACK.
AND ANYBODY WHO'S OUT HERE,
UNLESS THEY'RE BLIND,
KNOWS WE'RE COMING BY NOW.
* IN THE LAND OF DOPEY DREAMS
* LOVELY, PEACEFUL PHILIPPINES
* WHERE THE BOLO MAN
IS HIKING NIGHT AND DAY *
* WHERE TAGALOGS
STEAL AND LIE *
* AND AMERICANOS DIE *
* THERE YOU HEAR
THE SOLDIERS SING *
* THIS EVENING LAY
* DAMN, DAMN,
DAMN THE FILIPINOS *
* CROSS-EYED
KHAKIAK LADRONES *
* UNDERNEATH THE STARRY FLAG
* CIVILIZE 'EM WITH A KRAG *
* THEN RETURN US
TO OUR OWN BELOVED HOMES *
I'M TELLING YOU,
IT'S NOT JUST THE BEENO.
I'M GETTIN CHILLS OUT HERE
IN THE BLAZING SUN.
MY KNEES FEEL SHAKY.
YOU GOT THE RUNS?
I HAD THOSE
EVER SINCE MANILA.
THIS HERE IS A WHOLE
DIFFERENT DEAL.
HEY, IF SHANKER
CAN GET SENT HOME--
GET OFF OF THERE!
I CAN'T MOVE!
THEY DON'T HAVE THE AMMO
TO KEEP THIS UP, PEOPLE!
FIX BAYONETS!
GET READY TO CHARGE!
ON THE LIEUTENANT'S ORDERS,
WE GO OVER THE TOP AND FLUSH THEM OUT!
READY!
CHARGE!
AAH!
DUTCH? CAN YOU SEE WHERE I'M HIT?
I CAN'T FEEL NOTHIN'.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT, KID.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
DAMNIT.
LEAVE 'EM THERE.
COLONEL, THE FAMILIES OF THESE MEN ARE IN THIS BARRIO.
THEN LET 'EM GET A GOOD LOOK.
COLONEL?
THAT'LL DO.
GET SOME PEOPLE ON IT.
SIR, HE MAY HAVE RUN US AROUND TODAY,
BUT THE AMBUSH--
WE TOOK THREE CASUALTIES
TODAY, LIEUTENANT.
WE LOST OUR SCOUT,
TWO AMERICAN BOYS.
ONLY KILLED FIVE
OF THE ENEMY.
WE LET THE MONKEYS GET AWAY WITH THOSE NUMBERS,
AND THEY'LL NEVER GIVE UP!
I HAVE TO LIVE
WITH THESE PEOPLE.
NO, LIEUTENANT!
YOU GOTTA MAKE WAR ON THESE PEOPLE!
YOU LET THE BLEEDING HEARTS SORT
OUT THE REST WHEN WE'RE GONE.
NO, NO, NO.
IT IS NO. IT IS NO.
IT SAYS NO,
AND IT IS CONFUSED,
AND IT SAYS NO!
NO, NO, NO, HOBO,
NO, HOBO, HOBO.
I'M THINKING THE SAME THING.
I COULD GET HOME,
BUT YOU HAVE TO GET ME
OUT OF HERE.
I CAN--I CAN MOVE UP,
YOU CAN MOVE ME UP!
HOW YOU DOIN', SON?
I CAN'T FEEL NOTHIN'
BELOW MY BELT.
WELL, YOU TOOK ONE
IN THE HIP.
IT CAME OUT CLEAN,
BUT...
IT MUST HAVE NICKED
YOUR SPINE ON ITS WAY.
TAKE IT ALL THE WAY UP.
TAKE IT ALL THE WAY UP...
WILL YOU MAKE HIM
SHUT UP?
FELLAS SAY THAT YOU'VE BEEN
TO A HANGING, CORPORAL.
BACK HOME.
WE STRUNG UP A NIGGER
THAT STABBED A WHITE MAN.
YOU DO THE HONORS, THEN.
ANYTHING BACK FROM MANILA?
I SENT A LINE-CHECK
TO SANTA ANA FIRST THING.
EVERYTHING'S CLEAR.
STAY WITH IT.
IF COLONEL HARDACRE
FINDS OUT--
HE WON'T FIND OUT, WILL HE?
THE AMIGO DID LEAD US
INTO AN AMBUSH, SIR.
MAYBE.
THEY CAN'T BEAT US.
I DON'T KNOW
WHY THEY EVEN BOTHER.
IT'S THEIR COUNTRY, SIR.
LIEUTENANT, I MUST INFORM YOU
THAT I MUST LEAVE THIS PLACE.
ABOVE ALL THINGS,
I AM A SPANIARD.
LIVING UNDER THE RULE
OF OTHERS--
BEFORE YOU LEAVE,
THROW ON YOUR CEREMONIAL GEAR
AND DO WHAT YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO FOR THE AMIGO.
THIS ONE'S HEAD MAN NOW.
TELL HIM TO WATCH HIS STEP.
I THOUGHT I'D
CATCH YOU SLEEPING.
AND I THOUGHT YOU'D BE BACK
IN THE STATES BY NOW.
OH, THEY SAY I'M CURED.
CURED FROM THE CLAP?
THAT'S A BIGGER LONG SHOT
THAN US CATCHING AGUINALDO.
YOU'RE SHITTIN' ME.
IT JUST CAME IN
ON THE WIRE FROM MANILA.
THEY NAILED AGGY?
HOT DAMN!
HO HO HO!
YEAH, AND HE'S ASKED OUR LITTLE
BROWN BROTHERS TO GIVE UP THE GAME.
MacARTHUR'S ORDERED
GENERAL AMNESTY,
LETTIN' PRISONERS
GO LEFT AND RIGHT.
ANY INSURRECTO THAT WANTS
TO THROW IN THE TOWEL
GETS 30 PESOS MEXICAN
FOR HIS RIFLE.
THEY CAN HAVE MINE.
WE GOTTA CELEBRATE.
HERE WE GO!
CHAMPAGNE GLASS
RIGHT HERE.
OH, YEAH.
I STRETCHED A COUPLE APACHES BACK IN THE TERRITORY.
THEY CONSIDER IT A...
PARTICULARLY
IGNOBLE DEATH.
IT MAKES AN IMPRESSION
ON THE OTHERS.
WITH THIS BUNCH,
WHO KNOWS?
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S GET THIS SHOW ON THE ROAD.
"MILITARY NECESSITY ADMITS
OF ALL DIRECT DESTRUCTION..."
"...OF LIFE OR LIMB
OF ARMED ENEMIES, HOWEVER,
"MEN WHO TAKE UP ARMS
AGAINST ONE ANOTHER
"DO NOT CEASE
TO BE MORAL BEINGS
"RESPONSIBLE TO ONE ANOTHER
AND TO GOD.
"WAR ADMITS OF DECEPTION,
BUT DISCLAIMS ACTS OF PERFIDY,
"AND AS CIVIL OFFICERS OF
THE HOSTILE, OCCUPIED COUNTRY
"OWE STRICT OBEDIENCE
TO THE VICTORIOUS GOVERNMENT,
"AT PERIL OF THEIR LIVES,
IT HAS BEEN JUDGED
THAT RAFAEL DACANAY..."
HEAD MAN OF
THE BARRIO OF SAN ISIDRO
SHALL HANG BY THE NECK
UNTIL HE IS DEAD.
YOU THINK
THIS IS A SHITHOLE,
YOU OUGHT TO SEE
SAN ISIDRO.
THEY HAD A SMOKER
THE OTHER DAY.
WAS ANYONE KILLED?
A COUPLE ON BOTH SIDES.
YOU KNOW WHO GOT IT?
THEY DIDN'T SEND NAMES.
THERE'S SOME GOOGOO
THEY'RE GONNA STRETCH.
COURSE, THEN THIS MESSAGE CAME IN--
DAMN! I'D BETTER SEND
ALONG THE HAPPY NEWS.
WELL, THAT'S WHAT I CALL
CUTTIN' IT CLOSE.
AAH!
I WAS JUST PART
OF THE CROWD, SIR.
I DIDN'T TIE THE ROPE.
SIGN OR MAKE YOUR MARK
RIGHT HERE.
YEAH. ALL RIGHT,
GIVE HIM SOME MONEY.
COME ON.
SIGN OR MAKE YOUR MARK
RIGHT HERE.
THIS THING CAN STILL SHOOT.
WELL, THEN THIS IS
YOUR LUCKY DAY, AMIGO.