♪ Did your daddy ever kill
a man? ♪
♪ I know my daddy did
♪ he didn't use a gun...
Okay. Can you do this?
No....
So what if you try this one?
No.
Okay, remember that Beyoncé
song?
What?
"All the single ladies"?
No!
Come on, Harriet... one song.
It's your party.
♪ You'll only see
the player... ♪
Come on, let's dance!
♪ Did he leave 1,000 women?
♪ Did he lose a million green?
♪ If you ever met my daddy,
you know just what I mean ♪
♪ I still love him
♪ no matter what he's done
♪ and he's my only one
♪ he might be a lying,
stealing cheater ♪
♪ don't slap him...
♪ and if you see my daddy,
don't tell him what I said ♪
♪ if he knows this song's about
him ♪
♪ it might go to his head
Hey!
My god.
I am so proud of you, and if mom
and dad were around, they'd be
so proud of you, too.
Yeah, I wish they were here
to see it.
You know, I was thinking about
dad the other day...
How long will reba be staying
in Austin?
♪ He's as sweet as a...
About a week.
Well, I'm so sorry that I
can't be there for you.
It's okay.
You know, I should get back to
the party.
I love you, sis.
Bye.
♪ He might be a lying,
stealing cheater ♪
♪ don't slap him...
♪ when you're daddy's little
girl ♪
♪ you're daddy's little girl
for good ♪
♪ You always wanted more
♪ and if you could get more,
you would ♪
Um...
Ma.
♪ You've been trying to do
the math ♪
♪ and adding up the clues
for years ♪
♪ it's hard to see the truth
♪ but walking in his shoes...
Hey.
Um, so I know I'm probably not
supposed to be asking you this,
but, um, what was it like in
there... you know, in that
institution or whatever?
♪ I still love him
♪ he might be a lying,
stealing cheater ♪
♪ He might be a lying...
Reba...
Okay.
Harriet, you okay in here?
Yeah.
♪ And if you could get
more... ♪
God.
I have to pee.
Reba, are you in there?
Not her.
Ready?
Yeah.
Shit!
We have John forest here
in the studio who has predicted
that today is the first day
of the apocalypse.
Mr. Forest, for those who
aren't one of your...
Shit, I'm late.
Whoa, wait.
Maybe when you get back, we can
hang out.
Why?
My god.
I am so excited about...
I'm going to open your eyes
to a world of possibilities.
You have no idea.
It's gonna be amazing.
It's gonna be incredible.
Texas has so much to offer.
♪ I talk real fast ♪
♪ I talk real hard ♪
♪ I'm a bad, bad man ♪
♪ and I walk right in ♪
So...
♪ I sat right down... ♪
How are you doing... really?
♪ Mr. Boss man... ♪
My god, I'm fine.
Don't worry about me.
I'm excited to start this new
phase in my life.
I learned the Dewey decimal
system.
Whoa, that's impressive.
I wanted to be prepared.
So, who was the guy?
He's just some guy from
the gallery, and I know you
changed the subject.
Yeah, but what happened to Ian?
Ian and I were never gonna
make it.
He just wanted me to want him
more, you know?
Wanted me to tell him I loved
him all the time, try to chase
him down.
I don't chase.
You don't chase.
You know, I know we got
a late start, but just in case,
I planned a very special trip
for US.
♪ Well, we're never gonna be
the famous ones ♪
♪ that we dreamed about, no,
when we were young ♪
♪ and the Hollywood Superman
pedestal ♪
♪ you're real, real pretty
like a young girl should ♪
♪ we're never gonna be
the famous ones ♪
♪ that we dreamed about, no,
when we were young ♪
Judgment day!
Only you would start a road
trip on the first day of the
apocalypse.
♪ Kicked out the lens... ♪
♪ I said, "you want to be
the king" ♪
♪ well, then all right ♪
Well, I do.
I do.
♪ Well, all right ♪
This is your plan?
I thought it'd be authentic.
I am literally speechless.
Why are you still working?
Aren't you a grad student now?
Just trying to make a little
cash before I start.
It was nice seeing your mom
yesterday at the party.
Yeah.
I don't want her to be alone
when she doesn't have to be,
but, god.
She is nonstop right now.
Your mom's probably just
worried about you.
That's what moms do.
My mom is worried that i'm
gonna end up like her...
Discarded for a better version
and all alone.
I'm never gonna end up like
that.
She's just trying to show you
that she loves you.
Good night.
Okay, if we were Thelma and
Louise, which one would you be?
Thelma, so I could run into
Brad Pitt's penis.
You can have Michael madsen.
He's kind of cute.
No. You thought he's cute?
Pompadours are hot.
No, they're not hot.
Don't be so boring, Harriet.
You used to think pompadours
were hot before you got into
grad school.
Okay, reba, can we just have
fun?
This is your first road trip.
I planned a very special scenic
route.
I haven't been on a road trip
for a reason.
I do not need to see white
america.
♪ My ♪
Hey, I was just teasing.
This will be fun.
♪ And you're mine ♪
♪ Is this a trend, or...? ♪
I can see you.
So?
Anyone coming can see you.
What's your point?
Okay.
You didn't stick it out with
Ian, so have you ever thought
that maybe you do the same thing
with your life?
You know, you never take a stand
or make a strong choice.
You never make a decision,
you know?
You just sort of say "fuck it"
and move on.
It's all arbitrary.
Harriet.
Reba.
Listen, Oprah, I didn't know
we were on girl time.
Besides, I'm not the one with
the problem knowing what I want.
I know what I want.
Really?
You want to be a librarian...
In Texas?
Yeah.
I mean... libraries are important
to me, you know?
I mean, our parents used to take
me and Amanda to the library
when we were kids, and it was
the only place I could really
find...
I love this song!
Harriet!
♪ ...escape your mind ♪
♪ I'll show you to the... ♪
Come on!
♪ ...on the dance floor ♪
I'm not dancing with you.
Come on.
You want to.
I know you do.
Yeah.
Watch me choose to do this.
No, reba! Don't!
Don't!
We're in Texas.
You may get in trouble.
No, reba, don't!
Whoo!
♪ One, two, three, go! ♪
♪ Go! ♪
♪ revolution on the dance
floor ♪
I give that a 5.
Fuck you!
♪ revolution on the dance
floor ♪
Um, could you just, um...?
"You're exactly where you're
supposed to be."
My god.
Don't make fun of me.
Where else would we be
besides exactly where we are?
Have you ever thought about
that?
Hey, can you just...?
I know it's old-fashioned and
doesn't make sense, but i'm
supposed to be a librarian.
I'm supposed to have a life
surrounded by books.
I just know it.
But why?
I don't know.
They have power, and once you
have that power or that
knowledge, no one can take that
away from you.
There's no signal here.
I told my mom I'd call her when
we got halfway.
And on this historic day,
many in the United States are
asking, "what caused this
extreme act of terrorism?"
The president emphasized the
need for calm and assured...
It's still too early to
estimate casualties, but it
could easily total in the
millions in the
immediate aftermath and untold
more in the ensuing weeks from
radiation exposure.
Air's terrible here.
Could be wildfire season.
Do they have that here?
The sky looks a little crazy.
I'm just gonna go look for
a phone.
I'll be right back.
No phone anywhere, but I found
something better.
Hi.
I made friends.
What's this?
Um...
That's my work.
I'm an inker... for comics.
I never understood why all
the female characters in these
things have to dress in such
skimpy outfits to beat up bad
guys.
It's essential.
Can you just give it back to me,
please?
Sure.
Thank you.
It just seems like such a
male-centric view, you know?
I'm Harriet.
Right.
Forgot that part.
I'm reba.
I'm Alex.
I thought I was gonna be
Alex.
We can both be Alex.
I'm kit.
Isn't that a writer?
Yes, I'm a writer.
I'm sorry.
I'm just not feeling great.
Quit being such a
psychosomatic pussy.
I'm not a psychosomatic
pussy, man.
I don't feel good.
So, Harriet, reba says that
you might be able to give US
a ride.
She did?
Just up the road a bit.
We really appreciate your
kindness.
It would, like, totally cement
our faith in humanity.
Reba, can I talk to you for
a minute?
Yeah.
Why did you tell them they
could come with US?
They're a little weird, but
they're musicians, so it's par
for the course.
I do not think this is a good
idea.
Okay, it's been a little
while since you had a date.
You can thank me when it's over.
But only if you come.
That's ridiculous.
I had a date...
Give me the keys.
What is that?
A taser.
A what?
It's a weapon.
Give me the keys.
I'm not giving you the keys.
Dude, what are you doing?
I thought only women carried
tasers.
Shut up!
Come on, man.
What are you doing?
I'm getting US the hell out
of this godforsaken country
if these two bitches would just
shut up and give me the keys!
He's just being real
squirrelly.
You're being
super-squirrelly.
Just shut up, you guys.
In case you haven't noticed,
what we're doing is totally
illegal.
No, man, what you're doing
is totally illegal, all right?
We already agreed that there
is no illegal anymore.
That's what I meant.
All right, man, but that's no
excuse for bad acting to enter
the equation.
No matter the state of
the world.
State of the world?
You two... shut up... keys!
Do you have to yell, man?
Some of US have splitting
headaches.
You're sick, too, aren't you?
I'm not sick, man.
I have a headache.
I'm warning you guys.
She's gonna give you
the keys.
No, I'm not.
I'm not fucking around
anymore!
Give me the fucking keys!!
Totally squirrelly.
It was an accident!
Sorry!
You okay?!
What the hell were you
doing?!
No, no!
Give me the keys! Now!!
Hey, look...
I'm real sorry we're stealing
your car and everything, but
it's pretty much every man...
Every person for himself out
there, so...
Let's move!
Lie on the ground and put your
hands behind your head.
Count to, like, 100?
And don't move until you're done
or we won't be as nice as we've
been.
36, 37, 38...
39, 40, 41, 42...
43, 44, 45...
We need to find a phone.
Damn it.
My phone was in the car.
Yeah, mine too.
Let's go.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I think there was a gas station
back that way.
Yeah, but Austin is that way.
It'd be stupid to go back that
way now.
Stupid?
You know what's stupid?
We just got carjacked, almost
tased, and all your clothes
are probably getting worn by
three skinny guys right now.
Sorry I missed the first class,
professor smarty-pants.
You wouldn't believe what
happened to me this weekend.
I wasn't quite overcocky.
Overcocky?
Yeah.
It means a totally fucked-up
situation.
No, it doesn't.
It means when a bunch of dudes
come all over a girl's face.
My point exactly.
You're weird.
You're gonna miss me...
Bad.
Come on.
I bet the first people who see
US will stop.
Let's go.
♪ The dregs, the dregs
♪ the spider legs like lashes
on my eyes ♪
♪ I thought the drugs would
kill the bugs... ♪
Hey! Hey!
Stop! Stop!
Hey!
Ho ho ho!
Come on!
What's in this?
I don't know...
Clothes and comics or something.
Great.
It will be something for US
to burn later when we freeze
to death.
You're not gonna burn my
books.
♪ It's hard to find
a problem ♪
♪ that I can't dissolve
♪ and the devil in the details
♪ well, he's stepping back
This is ridiculous!
It's freezing out here!
This is by far the darkest dark
I've ever seen, and we're
probably gonna freeze to death
or get bitten by a snake or
a coyote or whatever the hell
else is out here!
Hey.
Things could still turn around.
Jesus!
What are you talking about?
That's crazy.
That's not crazy, actually.
You want to know what's crazy is
picking up three strange hipster
boys at a deserted rest stop.
That's crazy.
You know, whatever.
We wouldn't have been at that
crappy rest stop if you weren't
leaving me.
What are you talking about?
I'm not leaving you, I'm just
moving on with my life.
You didn't even talk to me
about it.
Yeah, I don't have to consult
you.
That's part of making adult
decisions which you know nothing
about.
What?
My god.
Of course we end up here in the
middle of nowhere because i'm
with you and you don't...
You don't think about the
consequences.
You just do shit.
Because thinking has gotten
you so far?
You're just jealous.
Of what?
What... lame grad school?
Fucking Texas?
No, that i'm... I'm moving on
with my life, that I'm actually
doing something with myself.
Is that what the armchair
shits told you in the crazy
place?
Yeah, as a matter of fact,
they did.
I don't even know who you are
anymore... like, with your
stupid post-it notes and your
blind denial and all that weird
psychoanalyzation.
You are not moving on.
You're just moving.
You are not growing up.
All you're doing is turning
your back on what you already
have.
Fuck this.
Hey!
Harriet!
Aah!
Hello?
Are you okay?
Aah!
Are you okay or are you hurt,
or...?
No.
No, i'm... I'm okay.
I just thought... I thought
I was gonna hit you.
No, I'm okay.
You did great.
It's probably both of our lucky
days.
My friend and I lost our car,
and no one stopped for US, so
I-I just had to wave someone
down.
It was pretty stupid.
Yep.
I'm Harriet.
Sean.
Look, I don't want to intrude
or anything, but would you mind
giving US a ride?
Harriet, maybe this isn't
such a good idea.
Where you going?
Somewhere with a phone?
Hello?
Hop in.
Gas station up the road a piece.
Where you from?
Los Angeles.
No, I mean, where are you
really from?
Sean...
Do you live around here?
Where are you girls headed?
Austin.
What's in Austin?
I'm starting graduate school.
In what... your dreams?
No, in information studies.
It's interdisciplinary.
It ain't happening.
We should just get out.
This is not okay.
We could just walk.
We are exactly where we're
supposed to be.
No secrets!
I'm sorry.
I didn't... I didn't mean to be
sharp.
I'm just a little stressed with
everything that's been
happening.
Well, I guess
since we just got carjacked, we
have a little bit of a leg up
on those stress levels.
You making fun of me?
No.
No, no.
Why would I do that?
Yeah, no.
She's totally serious.
You girls think this is
a time for jokes?
A time for fun and games?
No, this... this is a time
for reckoning.
That's what this is.
Why?
Harriet.
Isaiah.
"The earth is polluted because
of its inhabitants who have
transgressed laws, violated
statues, broken the ancient
covenant.
Therefore, a curse devours
the earth."
He knew it.
Forest knew it.
And he was righteous.
I never doubted him.
Never.
Not once.
Why are...
Just nod your head.
Secrets!
Going after the bases, if you
ask me.
Koreans.
North Koreans.
They're the only ones who can
do it.
Hey, asshole.
I'm Chinese.
Don't you have to report in
somewhere?
Yeah, I kept telling everybody
about you people.
No one believed me.
Sean, um...
Do not engage.
I can hear you.
I'm right here!
Hey, Sean, do you think you
could slow down a little bit?
You think you can pull your
sneaky shit on me?
You done fucked with the wrong
country this time.
Now we are gonna bring the pain.
Stop the car, you crazy piece
of shit!
We are gonna nuke your yellow
asses back into judgment day
for what you've done.
You get that right?
You understa that right?
Fuck you!
Aah!
"Therefore a curse consumes
the earth.
Its people must bear the guilt."
Fuck you!
You dickless sack of shit!
We're gonna Bury you!
At the entrance to every...
Forest knew it!
He saw it coming, and you will
pay for your sins!
All of you from the west, they
praise the lord, his majesty!
"Terror and traps..."
Where is everyone?
I'm gonna go out on a limb and
say that this is the worst road
trip ever.
Yeah.
It's... terrible, actually.
It's been a complete and utter
waste of time.
What? No. I...
I didn't mean it that way.
The funny thing is, i'm
exactly where I'm supposed
to be.
Nowhere.
Wait. Harriet.
Open up.
Harrie.
I got something for you.
Come on, harrie.
Got to be better out here
with me than in a gas-station
bathroom.
Okay, let me just say something.
I know how important this is
to you...
And I know that it can feel...
I know that it can feel dark
sometimes.
But I'm your best friend.
And we're gonna get you
to Austin no matter what.
Hey.
Enough of this chicklet talk.
Let's get wasted.
Okay, but we have to leave
them a few bucks for beer.
Please.
This day calls for something
a little bit less pussy.
Ha ha ha!
Go back to the candy pile.
My god!
There you're also a doctor.
I'm so punk rock!
Go back to the chip pile.
My god.
I should really clean that up.
There you're a doctor, but
you're a failure 'cause you're
drunk like your father.
Now, you go back to the candy
'cause that is where you turn
the light on...
Where you turn the light on...
Die...
You're drunk.
And then you join all your
friends in the afterlife because
you were alive on the chip pile
the whole time, and time is
irrelevant.
And that's the plot of loss.
Do you ever wonder why
everyone on TV looks so good
when everything's going to shit?
Like...
Milla jovovich.
She looked hot.
♪ Hold on, dear
♪ like a barnacle on the ship
of fear ♪
♪ I'm out here
♪ like an island on a sea
of tears ♪
Hah.
Kick.
I should probably wear shorts.
What was that?
I don't know.
I'll go this way.
You go around the other side.
Wait. Harriet.
I don't know, Sean.
I don't see nothing.
She was here.
The chink was in my car.
Sean, this don't feel right.
I think we just need to just get
out of here.
I left them.
They... they couldn't...
Got to get the dog out.
Sean, get in the car.
Get the dog.
Hey.
Did you see something?
Is there someone here?
What's wrong?
Okay, basically there are no
working phones in the southwest.
Come on.
I don't really like it out here.
Let's just go inside, okay?
Okay?
Let's go.
Let's just say for a second that
there is a god.
Why would he hate fags?
I mean, why would he hate
anyone?
I thought that was the point
of having a devil.
I just don't get it.
Did I ever tell you about that
friend of mine when I was
little... what was her name?
Lisa something or other.
She was super-religious.
I didn't realize it at the time,
but her parents used to take me
to sunday school and mass every
sunday when we were playing, and
years later I get this Christmas
card, and I swear to god the
only three words they used in
the entire card were "Jesus,"
"savior," and "amen."
How do you make a sentence
with those three words?
How do you send a card to
somebody...
Come with me to Austin.
What?
I am.
No...
Stay with me...
In Austin to live.
Yeah, right.
Harriet...
Look, it's safer there, and
you've always said you wanted to
get out of L.A.
You know, Austin could be
a fresh start.
I don't know, Harriet.
Okay.
I bet Austin has a great art
scene, and it's smaller, so it
would be easier to break your
way into.
And, you always say that
you've slept with everyone in
Los Angeles, so it'd be a whole
new population.
That was a joke.
Los Angeles...
Is a wasteland.
There's nothing there anymore.
It's not fair to say that
there's nothing there.
No, reba, what I'm trying
to tell you is that...
Shh.
What?
It's them!
Who?
The hipsters!
Get down!
We have to hide!
Where?!
We're in the middle of the road!
Wait, I have an idea.
Man, this chick has a ton
of books.
Books are no longer useful
except as fire fuel.
That's ridiculous.
Yeah, it really is, man.
God.
I think that I have the runs
again.
Just 'cause there's a nuclear
war doesn't mean we can't read.
And... we won't.
I mean, what's the point?
I'm sorry.
What's the point... of reading?
I don't know, man.
How about education or
entertainment or just trying
to expand your world view
a little bit?
How about that?
You're never gonna make it.
What if Mexico's just as
fucked?
As long as they didn't
detonate nuclear weapons against
their own people.
You don't know that's what
happened.
It's so obvious.
What about al-qaeda?
What about
al-qaeda?
What kind of fucking moron are
you?
Okay.
What terrorist organization
could detonate four bombs within
the u.S. At the exact same time?
Moron?
What government could do that
without US finding out about it
right away with four cities that
happen to have key military
bases right by?
Just shut up, all right?
You sound like a crazy person.
Right, man.
I don't know!
Hey!
Shut him up!
Stop it!
Aah!
What was that?
I don't know.
He's been a fucking baby
ever since I tased him.
You know what, man?
He's sick. Okay?
And I'm not feeling great
myself.
Didn't any of your crazy comic
books teach you how to do this
stuff?
I got US this far, didn't I?
I'll get US out.
Yeah, you did.
Good for you.
You know, you're not actually
looking 100%, either.
Starting to feel a little sweat?
It's Texas, dickhead.
Sweating's a recreational sport.
That's cute.
You should put that on
a bumper sticker.
Hi.
Remember me?
Yeah.
You haven't seen my friend,
have you?
The blond one... Steve... Alex?
It doesn't matter.
His name's Steve.
I-I misplaced him.
No.
But I lost my friend, too.
And now I'm just out here all
by myself...
All alone, just little old me.
Okay.
Come on.
You don't really think i'm
stupid enough to fall for that,
do you?
Aah!
Jesus Christ!
What the hell is wrong with...
Is he dead?
Hey, kit?
Wait, um, wait.
Can you just wait?
Sorry.
I know the bombs are making
things weird, and I'm still
trying to figure out what to do
about that.
This is gonna sound crazy, but
I feel like you might be the
person who could hear it, so...
Here goes.
Um...
You know, if I was being honest
with myself, I don't have a lot
going right now.
I mean, I'm not a loser, but,
I'm sort of just nothing...
Sort of a walking example
of unfulfilled potential.
So, anyway, I applied to grad
school and didn't get in.
But regardless, i'm... i'm
going, and it's the first time
in my life that...
I haven't just fallen into
whatever's easiest.
And for better or for worse,
I'm dragging my friend along
with me, and... and that may not
mean anything to you, but it
means the world to me, and...
That car right there, that's my
stuff.
And...
Could I just have it back,
please?
I always wanted to do
something like that.
I think that staying motivated
is more important than ever now,
and, and I guess things
kind of gotten out of hand.
Yeah, and, you know, it's no
big deal.
You know, I always like to say
that you're exactly where...
Gotcha!
Took you long enough.
How about we find that friend
of yours and have ourselves
a little fun?
Harriet, get in the car!
Go, reba, go!
Aah!
Why did I do that?
Why?
Hey, just calm down, okay?
It's okay.
It's gonna be okay.
My god.
My mom...
What am I gonna tell my mom?
How am I gonna tell her what
I did?
What am I gonna...?
Hey, hey.
It's okay, all right?
It's okay.
Let's get back to Austin.
We'll just make everything
right, okay?
Okay.
It's gonna be okay.
Stay indoors.
Fires raging throughout Houston
and surrounding areas.
For the unbelievers, they
will never again have conscious
existence.
Reba, I have to tell you
something.
The...
Are you sure this is Amanda's
house?
♪ I gave you half
of everything I own... ♪
Do you want a flyer?
Yeah?
♪ Yeah
♪ come on
♪ This is going...
♪ Quite unplanned
♪ but I'm in too deep now
to fold my hand ♪
♪ I said...
♪ This isn't going...
Baby.
Baby, whoa.
Whoa.
You are just...
You go for it.
Hey, Amanda?
Amanda?
My god.
You made it!
I can't believe you're fucking
here right now.
You made it out of Los Angeles.
I can't believe you're standing
here.
Maybe we should...
I mean, I was so worried.
Everyone's gone crazy.
Everyone went for the water.
I mean, there's, like, no water
left anywhere, and you know that
disaster preparation kit that
I have?
It lasted one day because I only
had five gallons in it, and that
lasts one day, and that's it.
We ran out of water, and so I
thought, "what are we gonna do?
We're gonna drink beer."
Aren't I smart?
Aren't I so smart?
You're smart.
What are you talking about?
I mean, they said like
250,000.
But, baby, that's Houston.
I know!
Those poor fucking
people...
Dying from all the radiation.
We started this fund, you know.
Wait. What... what?
Radiation?
What happened?
Was there an accident?
What...?
You don't know.
My god.
Reba...
There was a bomb.
What?
My heart is just breaking.
Okay, Amanda, stop.
She doesn't know about
the bombs, okay?
Just stop talking.
It is not for you to tell,
okay?!
Will someone please just tell
me what the fuck is going on?
One of the bombs went off
in Los Angeles.
My god.
You knew and you haven't even
told her yet?
Okay, we've been on the road,
and I just haven't had a
chance...
Wait, so you've been on
the road.
Stop it!
Well, how bad is it?
I-I mean, I'm sure it's not
that...
It's a total loss.
Los Angeles is gone.
Hey.
But there has to be survivors.
No, it's pretty grim.
You guys are lucky.
You made it out alive.
Reba...
I'm so, so sorry about your mom.
No.
You knew?
You...
Y-Yeah.
Not really.
I didn't know...
I didn't know everything.
I, um...
I didn't know how to tell you.
I-I didn't want to hurt you.
I just thought we could get here
and everything would just work
out, you know, right?
What is wrong with you?
I'm really sorry.
You're... you're sorry?
About what?
About not telling me that the
world is going crazy, or...
Or... what, or that my...
Or that my... my mom is...?
Hey, it's okay.
No.
We're safe and we're here,
so that's a good thing.
Why are we here?
Amanda, did you know that
Harriet didn't get into grad
school?
She just let everyone think that
she did.
What, you didn't think I knew?
You thought it was a lie that
you could keep from me?
They said I didn't get in
this semester, but they said
that if I reapplied...
Amanda, did you know that
your sister applied to a
make-believe grad school from
a mental institution where she
hung out for the last couple
of months after she tried to
kill herself?
What?
Harriet, I didn't...
You couldn't even get that
right.
Go back to the crazy house
where you fucking belong.
♪ Love of mine
♪ seeing you here will only numb
the pain ♪
♪ there's no real pride
reba
♪ being numb will shield you
from the rain ♪
♪ you owe it to yourself
♪ to let help shine a light
along the road ♪
♪ So lean on me
♪ as we walk into the great
unknown ♪
♪ the world has changed...
Who did it?
Terrorists.
They don't know which group,
but...
Basically they don't know.
Maybe it was god.
♪ ...without you
♪ I'm not alive without you
♪ I would die without you
is there a phone I can use?
♪ ...grown together
♪ side by side, we're better
my mom's just outside of L.A.
If I could just give her a call.
Reba.
You can't.
I mean, the president basically
shut out all communication
because of the terrorists.
Okay.
♪ Love of mine
♪ won't you let yourself
breathe again? ♪
♪ 'Cause it takes time...
I'm sorry.
No, I'm not...
I'm not using it.
Do you need in here?
Um...
It's cool.
You can, um... you can have it.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Look at me.
Do I look okay?
You know, maybe you shouldn't
be, um...
What?
Drinking clear water?
This more than any other
moment is the most important
time to not act without
information, to attack without
certain knowledge.
Are you crazy?
We have been summarily attacked
by the enemy, millions are
dead, many more will die in
the next days, weeks, months.
We are at war.
What's your answer?
Bomb the world until there's
nothing left?
They're scared of terrorists.
They're stopping everyone and
rounding them up.
And I quote the
prophet forest.
The offer of god's love is sent
forth into all the world, but
no man of his own volition will
respond.
Why is this happening?
Do you... do you have, um,
a boyfriend or husband that
maybe I should call?
He's gone.
I haven't talked to him.
I don't know where he is.
Sorry.
I can't go home.
I can't talk to my husband.
I can't call my doctor.
I just want to go home.
I'm sorry.
Hey, slow down.
Do you want to fuck me
or not?
♪ Hey, there, dreamers
♪ I know you feel alone
♪ while you're out there,
out there dreaming ♪
♪ you got no proof to take
back home ♪
♪ you dreamers
♪ dreamers
no.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
No, don't do that.
No, no.
For fuck's sake.
♪ Dreamers
Are you looking for someone?
Whoo!
♪ I've been walking
down the road ♪
♪ I've been asking
who the fuck is this guy?
I'm just talking to him.
Why don't you piss off, man?
This is my girlfriend.
I'm just talking to him.
Yeah.
Now you're just not talking...
Will you just... get off of
me.
Why do you do this to me?
Yeah!
Whoo!
Aah!
My god!
♪ You can feel the rain
coming ♪
♪ it's coming through the
trees ♪
♪ you can feel my life sting
Can you see anything?
Did something happen?
Nothing.
It's just... it's quiet.
Stay indoors until further
notice.
Do not attempt to leave your
homes.
The governor has declared
martial law until further
notice, and all residents are
required to stay indoors.
Police and national guardsmen
will be visiting homes in the
ensuing hours to ensure the
safety of Austin's citizens.
Please make sure you are home.
Anyone found outdoors will be
detained immediately by
uniformed police or a military
officer.
All citizens should be carrying
documentation of citizenship at
all times and will be required
to show them if approached by
authorities.
Anyone without proof of
residency on their person will
be detained immediately.
American passports are
strongly recommended.
I repeat... stay indoors.
Did he just say "passports"?
Reba, reba, you can't go
out...
Harriet?
Copy that.
13, you're out there.
224 on his way out there.
Yes, ma'am, we'll be clear
and...
Harriet?
What you doing out, China?
Don't you know it's dangerous to
be outside right now?
And there's the other one
who's up to no good?
Yeah, China.
Probably not a good idea for a
little communist to be running
freely around after you've
dropped a nuclear bomb on US.
I-I'm an American citizen,
just like you.
No, I don't think so.
I don't think you're anything
like me.
I heard it's not just their
eyes that slant.
All right, listen.
Okay, you guys don't want to do
this.
There's police and
national guard everywhere.
Yeah.
I know.
Aah!
Okay, look... okay, okay.
Just calm down.
What you got for me, China
girl?
Get away from my friend!
Are you crazy?
Why'd you shoot her?
My god, did you see that?
No, don't you see?
I-I'm exactly where I'm supposed
to be.
Harriet.
God, you're bleeding.
You're bleeding.
I don't know what to do.
It's okay.
You need to stop the bleeding,
okay?
No, I can't
you need to stop... you need
to apply pressure.
I think it passed all the way
through.
You need to stop the bleeding.
I can't.
You need to take off your
shirt.
Yes, you can. You can do it.
You can do it.
You just need to stop the
bleeding.
No.
What if I fuck it up?
You're not gonna fuck it up.
No chance.
Aah!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
You were chasing me.
What?
You never chase.
My god.
Okay.
I know exactly what to do.
615 is medical books.
614... that's... that's...
That's... that's first aid.
I'm just trying to round out my
knowledge of bullet wounds
from Sci-Fi shows and comic
books.
You need to keep my torso
elevated.
Okay.
So go get some pillows.
All right. Okay.
Okay. You're all right.
You're okay.
I'm sorry I messed everything
up.
I-i-I'm sorry I made things
harder for you.
Please don't leave me, okay?
Yeah.
I'm not going anywhere.
Harriet?
Harriet?!
Ready?
It's pretty much trashed.
"ledbellies"
♪ When they ask you
♪ well, are you scared now?
♪ where are you scared?
♪ Look them right in the eye
♪ look them right in the eye
♪ in the evening you change
your way ♪
♪ so let the devil inside
♪ let the devil inside
♪ I don't want none of your
grief and crying ♪
♪ it hurts my pride
♪ take these guns and go Bury
in the ground ♪
♪ I don't feel like lying
hey!
♪ Board this train and gonna
take you to Savannah ♪
♪ board this train and gonna
♪ I ain't going home
♪ I ain't going back home
♪ take these tears and go and
drop them in the river ♪
♪ I miss you so
♪ Ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh
♪ ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh,
ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh
♪ ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh,
ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ ooh-ooh-ooh
if you've been kicked in or
abused or mistreated or
misused ♪
♪ you were told there is nowhere
to go but up for you ♪
♪ if you've been hurt or you've
been betrayed or you've been
fucked or you've been
displaced ♪
♪ you were told it was probably
your fault anyway ♪
♪ but when your hustler
subscription and your Xanax
prescriptions ♪
♪ make you feel lonelier
instead ♪
♪ you don't want to hear about
all those starving children ♪
♪ you don't want to be told it's
all in your head ♪
♪ 'cause if it's all in your
head ♪
♪ that's terrible
♪ I saw a junkie lying in a
puddle of his own blood last
week ♪
♪ I saw a cyclist get hit by a
car ♪
♪ I saw a homeless guy chug a
bottle of mouthwash on Christmas
Eve ♪
♪ no, you can never fall too
far ♪
♪ you can buy a salad glove
♪ you can buy an iPod
♪ and you can sell that shit to
bookman's when your wife dies
and you lose your job ♪
♪ you can hope it gets better
♪ you can follow your dreams
♪ but hope is for presidents and
dreams are for people who are
sleeping ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh
♪ ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh,
ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh
♪ ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh,
ooh-ooh-ooh ♪