- HEY, CLETE AND SAM.
- COME OVER HERE.
- SAM, SAM.
- THIS IS SAM.
- A NIGGER HOTSHOT DONE
RIPPED OFF YOUR POKER PALACE.
- SON OF A BITCH.
- OH, YEAH.
YOU KNOW, BOY, CRIME
JUST DON'T PAY IN BUCKTOWN.
- HEY, CLETE,
YOU SURE DO ENJOY YOUR WORK.
- YEAH, YOU GOT THAT RIGHT.
[chuckles]
- HEY, YOU KNOW,
THIS IS A REAL BAD CAT.
HE ALMOST KILLED
A COUPLE OF HIGH ROLLERS.
YOU GONNA BE IN TOWN LONG?
- WHY?
YOU THE WELCOMING COMMITTEE?
- HEY, WELL, YOU HAVE
A GOOD TIME WHILE YOU'RE HERE.
- BETTER GET HIS ASS
TO THE HOSPITAL.
- YOU KNOW
WHERE THE CLUB ALABAM IS?
- YEAH.
SON, DO YOU BELIEVE IN GOD?
- YEAH, SURE.
WHY NOT?
- THEN YOU'RE IN
THE WRONG PLACE.
[laughs]
- WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME
IT WAS CLOSED?
- YOU DIDN'T ASK, DID YOU?
THE PLACE BEEN CLOSED
SINCE BEN DIED.
- WHERE CAN I FIND A GOOD HOTEL?
- WE AIN'T GOT ONE.
- WELL, HOW ABOUT ONE
THAT CHANGES SHEETS
AT LEAST EVERY OTHER NIGHT?
- HMM.
THAT WOULD BE THE OLD DIXIE.
IT'S JUST
A COUPLE OF BLOCKS DOWN.
I'LL TAKE YA.
- NO, THANK YOU.
I'LL WALK.
- BABY, IS THAT REALLY ALL YOU?
- SWEETIE,
WHAT YOU SEE IS WHAT YOU GET.
[laughs]
BUT FIRST, I WANT TO SEE
THE COLOR OF YOUR GREEN.
AND THEN I'LL SHOW BOTH OF YOU
A TIME YOU'LL NEVER FORGET.
[laughs]
- I'LL HELP YOU WITH THAT,
MISTER.
NO CHARGE.
I'M GLAD TO HELP.
BUT IF YOU WANT TO TIP ME
A HALF A BUCK,
I'LL TELL YOU
WHERE TO GET YOUR ACT TOGETHER
AND WHERE TO GET IT ON.
- OH, YEAH?
GET WHAT ON?
- YOU NAME IT, I GOT IT.
- NAH.
NO, THANKS.
- OKAY, HOW ABOUT CARDS?
IF YOU GO TO DOC ANDERSON'S,
CHECK THE DEUCES AND NINES.
THEY'RE MARKED.
- LITTLE MAN,
I AIN'T INTERESTED.
- OKAY, WOMEN.
THE BEST IN TOWN IS SONORA
OVER AT RUBY'S.
BUT DON'T LET HER GET ON TOP,
'CAUSE SHE'LL
BUCK YOUR BRAINS OUT.
- WHERE'D YOU GET ALL THIS
INFORMATION FROM ANYWAY, HUH?
YOU SELL PENICILLIN TOO?
- THANKS, MAN.
SEE ARNETTA.
SHE'LL GET YOU
THE BEST ROOM IN THE HOUSE.
BUT BE SURE AND TELL HER
STEVIE SENT YA.
- IS THAT YOURS?
- YEAH, WHY?
- 'CAUSE YOU'RE THE ONLY PIMP
I EVER SEEN
THAT DRIVES A MOTOR BIKE.
- HEY.
I AIN'T NO PIMP.
I'M WALT DISNEY,
AND THIS IS DISNEYLAND.
- OOH.
- GOT A ROOM?
- HOW MANY NIGHTS, HONEY?
- JUST ONE.
- THAT'LL BE $15 IN ADVANCE.
IT'S ROOM 204,
AND YOU CAN TAKE THE STAIRS.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT QUICKER.
- THANK YOU.
- SAY, BABY, YOU KNOW,
IF YOU'RE INTERESTED,
I COULD TURN YOU ON
TO A WHOLE LOTTA FUN.
- NO, THANKS.
- WELL, YOU KNOW,
IT AIN'T MY BUSINESS,
BUT WHAT'S A FINE BLACK THING
LIKE YOU DOING IN TOWN?
- I'M JUST HERE
TO BURY MY BROTHER.
THAT'S ALL.
- OOH.
- YEAH?
- A FELLA JUST CHECKED IN
BY THE NAME OF JOHNSON,
DUKE JOHNSON.
- DID HE SAY ANYTHING?
- NO, HE DIDN'T TALK TOO MUCH,
BUT HE SAID HE'S HERE
FOR BEN'S FUNERAL.
- I'M GLAD YOU CALLED, ARNETTA.
- WELL, YOU TOLD ME
TO CHECK WITH YOU NOW.
THAT'S WHAT I'M DOING.
- GOOD NIGHT.
- YEAH.
- YOUR DINNER'S READY,
CHIEF PATTERSON.
- ALMIGHTY GOD IN HEAVEN ABOVE,
I THANK THEE
FOR WHAT YOU'VE SET BEFORE ME.
AND I GIVE--
- UNTO YOU, O LORD,
THE SOUL OF THIS GOOD MAN.
THIS HUMBLE MAN, BEN JOHNSON.
A MAN OF THE PEOPLE,
ALL PEOPLES,
WHO ALWAYS HELD HIS HAND OUT
TO HELP OTHERS.
WHO GAVE LIKE YOU,
AND ASKED NOT IN RETURN.
THE LORD IS MY SHEPHERD.
I SHALL NOT WANT.
HE MAKETH ME TO LIE DOWN
IN GREEN PASTURES.
HE RESTORETH MY SOUL.
SO WE KNOW, ALMIGHTY GOD,
THAT YOU WILL CONTINUE TO LOVE
BEN AS WE HAVE LOVED HIM.
TO EMBRACE HIM, TO TAKE HIM
INTO YOUR KINGDOM THIS DAY.
AMEN.
IN THE NAME OF THE FATHER,
THE SON, AND THE HOLY GHOST.
- THOSE ARE GOOD WORDS,
REVEREND.
- THANK YOU.
- EXCUSE ME, SIR.
I'M WALDO HARLEY.
MIGHT YOU BE A FRIEND
OF OUR BELOVED BEN THERE?
- YEAH, I'M DUKE JOHNSON.
- DUKE.
THAT'S JUST WHAT I FIGURED.
ARETHA.
ARETHA, YOU AND STEVIE
SAY HELLO TO THE DUKE.
THAT'S BEN'S BROTHER.
- YOU REALLY DUKE?
- BEN TOLD US ALL ABOUT YA.
SAID YOU'RE THE SMARTEST ONE
IN THE FAMILY.
YOU KNOW, HOW YOU'VE BEEN ALL
OVER THE WORLD AND EVERYTHING.
- SO YOU'RE THE ONE.
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
YOU SAW BEN?
FIVE YEARS AGO?
- NO, IT WAS MORE LIKE SIX.
- SOME HOTSHOT BROTHER.
- ARETHA, PLEASE.
- WHERE WERE YOU
WHEN HE NEEDED YOUR HELP?
- WHAT KINDA HELP?
- THERE'S NOTHING
YOU CAN DO ABOUT IT NOW,
EXCEPT FOR TO FIND THE TIME
TO COME TO BURY HIM
AND COLLECT HIS STUFF
AND SPLIT.
- ARETHA, NOW--
- AREN'T YOU GONNA STAY?
- NO, HE'S NOT GONNA STAY.
HE WOULDN'T DIRTY THAT SHOESHINE
IN THIS COW PASTURE,
WOULD YOU, MR. DUKE JOHNSON?
- ARETHA, PLEASE.
DON'T MIND HER, DUKE.
BEN WAS GOOD TO HER.
HIS DYING KINDA PUT A PAIN
AND GRIEF INTO HER.
DON'T MIND HER.
- NO.
I CAN'T MIND A LADY
THAT SPEAKS HER MIND.
- THAT'S RIGHT, DUKE.
DUKE, YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
- AND ACCORDING TO THIS WILL,
LEFT EVERYTHING TO YOU.
AN ESTATE CONSISTING MAINLY
OF A LOT AND FRAME HOUSE,
A HAND-TOOLED LEATHER WALLET
CONTAINING $39.43,
AND A SAVINGS ACCOUNT PASSBOOK
IN THE NAME
OF BENJAMIN A. JOHNSON.
- OKAY, ALL OF BEN'S THINGS
BELONG TO ME NOW, RIGHT?
TO SELL, USE,
ANYTHING I WANT, RIGHT?
- IN ABOUT 60 DAYS.
- 60 DAYS?
MAN, YOU GOT TO BE KIDDING.
- THAT'S THE STATE LAW.
TAKES THAT LONG
TO CLOSE AN ESTATE.
- WHAT AM I SUPPOSED TO DO?
STICK AROUND THIS RAT TRAP
FOR TWO MONTHS?
- OF COURSE,
WE COULD RELAX THE RULES A BIT,
ALLOW YOU THE USE
OF YOUR BROTHER'S PROPERTIES.
- HUH.
HOW MUCH?
- LET'S SAY YOU SIGN FOR
AN EMPTY HAND-TOOLED
LEATHER WALLET.
- YOU RUN A NICE BUSINESS
AROUND HERE, DON'T YA?
- HI, DUKE.
I'VE BEEN OVER THERE
WAITING FOR YA.
TOLD STEVIE HERE ALL ABOUT IT.
- YEAH, ABOUT WHAT?
- OH, HOW YOU'RE GONNA STAY ON,
OPEN THE CLUB AND EVERYTHING.
MAN, I CAN'T WAIT FOR THEM GOOD
TIMES TO START ROLLING AGAIN.
THE PLACE WAS REALLY LIKE A HOME
TO SOME OF US, YOU KNOW.
ESPECIALLY STEVIE HERE
'CAUSE HE LIVES IN THE BACK.
YOUR BROTHER BEN MADE
A RIGHT SMART LIVING FROM IT.
GONNA DO THE SAME THING FOR YOU,
DUKE.
- I FIGURE LIFE OWES ME MORE
THAN JUST A LIVING.
ALL I WANT FROM THAT BAR
IS FOR SOMEBODY TO BUY IT.
LOOK, I'M GONNA BE STUCK HERE
FOR TWO MONTHS.
YOU REALLY WANT TO HELP ME?
- SURE, DUKE.
- THEN YOU FIND ME THAT BUYER
FOR THE CLUB ALABAM
SO I CAN GET THE HELL
OUT OF HERE.
OKAY?
- SURE, DUKE.
- YOU TAKE CARE.
- MR. DUKE, MR. DUKE, SIR,
IS IT ALL RIGHT
IF WE WALK A PIECE WITH YA?
- WE THOUGHT YOU WERE COOL,
A WISE DUDE LIKE YOU.
SHOWS HOW WRONG WE CAN BE.
- STEVIE,
YOU SPEAK FOR YOURSELF.
- SOMETHIN' BOTHERING YOU TWO?
- OH, NO, DUKE.
EVERYTHING IS EXPOOBIDENT,
EXCEPT THAT IT'S GONNA BE
A LITTLE HARD
TO FIND A BUYER FOR THE CLUB
WITH THAT CLOSED SIGN
ON THE DOOR.
- THAT'S THE WAY IT IS, BRO.
- BUT IT DON'T HAVE TO BE.
- REALLY, DUKE,
IF THE JOINT WAS OPEN,
PEOPLE WOULD BE HAVING FUN
AND PARTYING REAL GOOD
AND CATCHING GOOD.
SOMEONE WILL COME IN THERE THEN,
WANT TO BUY THE JOINT.
AND YOU KNOW
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO GET DOWN
WITH SOME HEAVY BREAD.
- YOU COULD BE PLAYING
SWEET MUSIC
ON THE CASH REGISTER.
- YOU GUYS ARE DREAMIN', MAN.
- HEY, DUKE, WHY DO YOU THINK
THOSE TOURIST DUDES
COME OVER HERE
FROM ACROSS THE RIVER?
IT'S 'CAUSE THEY KNOW THEY CAN
SWING TILL BROAD DAYLIGHT.
SHOOT!
GET FOUR OR FIVE TIMES
WHAT YOU'RE ASKING
IF THE CLUB WAS OPEN.
- AND DON'T FORGET
ALL THOSE ARMY RESERVERS
OVER AT THE ARMORY.
ONE NIGHT A WEEK,
AFTER MARCHING AND DRILLING,
THEY'RE HOT
AND THEY'RE THIRSTY.
AND WHERE DO THEY HEAD FOR?
THE CLUB ALABAM
FOR SOME RELAXATION.
- RELAXATION, HUH?
YOU KNOW SOMETHIN', LITTLE MAN?
YOU REMIND ME OF ME
WHEN I WAS YOUR AGE,
TRYING TO BE SOMEBODY,
ALWAYS JIVING AND HUSTLING.
- I AIN'T HUSTLING.
I'M JUST TRYING TO GROW UP FAST
IN A FAST TOWN.
- AND ME, I AIN'T NOTHIN' BUT
AN OLD FOOTBALL PLAYER, DUKE.
MAYBE DRINK TOO
MUCH EVERY NOW AND THEN.
BUT IF YOU OPEN THAT CLUB,
IT SURE WOULD MAKE ME FEEL LIKE
I WAS SOMEBODY.
- OPENING THE CLUB CAN'T HURT,
CAN IT?
- YOU SAID YOURSELF
YOU'RE STUCK HERE,
SO YOU AIN'T GOT NOTHING
TO LOSE, DO YA?
- DO YA?
- I AIN'T SOME DUMB BROAD.
I GOT RIGHTS.
- HONEY, WE TOLD YOU BEFORE
DON'T RIP OFF THE MARKS.
IT'S BAD FOR BUSINESS.
- MERLE, IT AIN'T FAIR
YOU MAKING ME SPEND TIME
IN THIS GODDAMN HOLE.
- WE GOT TO THINK OF
BUCKTOWN'S REPUTATION, HONEY.
YOU KEEP CLIPPING THE TOURISTS,
AND PRETTY SOON NONE OF 'EM
WILL BE COMING ACROSS THE RIVER
NO MORE.
- BUT THAT FREAKY BASTARD
WANTED TO WEAR MY UNDERWEAR.
- THIS PLACE GOT A CHIEF?
- YOU GOT AN APPOINTMENT?
- NO.
- WHAT'S THE MATTER, BOY?
SOMEBODY PICK YOUR POCKET?
- I'M HERE ABOUT THE CLOSED SIGN
ON THE CLUB ALABAM.
- OH, YOU MUST BE BEN'S BROTHER.
- EVERYBODY LIKED BEN.
HE WAS REAL PEOPLE,
WASN'T HE, MERLE?
- SURE WAS.
GOOD CITIZEN BEN.
- WELL, THAT'S MIGHTY NICE
OF YOU FELLAS TO SAY THAT.
WHAT ABOUT THAT CLOSED SIGN?
- NO PROBLEM.
ALL YOU GOT TO DO
IS TAKE OUT A CITY LICENSE.
- THAT'S RIGHT.
- HOW MUCH IS THAT?
- HOW MUCH WAS THAT, MERLE,
FOR A CITY STICKER?
- IT WAS $400, WASN'T IT?
- MORE LIKE $450,
I THOUGHT.
- DAMNED IF YOU'RE NOT RIGHT.
- I'LL MAKE SURE
THEY GET YOUR MESSAGE.
- DO THAT, DUANE.
YOU JUST DO THAT.
- YOU THE MAIN MAN?
- YEAH.
- NOW, JUST A DAMN MINUTE.
- YOU'RE THE ONE
I WANT TO TALK TO.
- DUKE JOHNSON?
- YEAH.
- COME IN.
YOU'RE NOT MUCH FOR MANNERS,
ARE YA?
- I GIVE WHAT I GET.
- THIS WHAT YOU WANT?
HOWEVER, NOTHING IS FOR NOTHING.
- I GUESS THOSE TWO CRACKERS OUT
FRONT WERE SERIOUS, HUH?
- SAM.
- YES, SIR.
- WHAT'S THE CHARGE
FOR A CITY STICKER?
- $450 GOOD OLD AMERICAN GREEN.
- NOT ONE DROP IS POURED
IN THIS TOWN,
UNLESS EACH BOTTLE
HAS A CITY STICKER.
AND THE STICKER COMES
FROM THIS OFFICE.
NOW, BEN'S RENEWAL FEE
WAS DUE TWO DAYS AFTER HE DIED.
SO NOW IT'S OVERDUE.
- AND WHAT HAPPENS
IF IT ISN'T PAID?
- THE PLACE STAYS PADLOCKED.
- AND IF I DECIDE TO SELL IT?
- WHEN I SEE SOME DOLLARS
ON THIS DESK,
YOU CAN DO WHATEVER YOU LIKE
WITH THAT FLEA TRAP.
GOOD.
I LIKE DEALING
WITH A REASONABLE MAN.
- I'D LIKE TO GET THAT
UPPITY BITCH RUTHIE ALONE.
I'LL TEACH HER SOME MANNERS.
SHE ALWAYS DID THINK
SHE WAS HOT SHIT.
- YOU'VE GOT A BUG UP YOUR ASS.
- YOU GOT IT?
GET IT OUT!
IT'S GONNA BE FIVE NEXT WEEK.
YOU UNDERSTAND THAT, BOY?
SHIT!
COME ON, LOVER BOY.
LET'S GO.
- EVENIN', WOODROW.
WHOO!
HI, SWEETNESS.
CLEO, CLEO, HERE I COME.
OH, GODDAMN.
CLEO,
YOU ALWAYS WAS MY FAVORITE.
- HEY, HEY, HEY!
EVERYBODY HAVE A DRINK
AND BE SOMEBODY.
SAY, BOY, PUT A QUARTER
IN THE JUKEBOX,
AND MAKE GODDAMN SURE
THESE NEGROS DRINK, Y'ALL.
I'M PLEASED
TO MAKE THE ANNOUNCEMENT
THAT THE MAN HAS DONE HIS THING,
AND IT'S GONNA HAPPEN
AS SOON AS HE GETS HERE.
BOOP, BOOP, BOOP, BOOP.
LOOK OUT, GIRL.
WHAT YOU DOING?
- HARLEY, WHAT YOU RUNNING
YOUR MOUTH ABOUT NOW?
- I'M PLEASED
TO MAKE THE ANNOUNCEMENT
THAT THE CLUB ALABAM
IS NOW OPEN.
- NO.
- YEAH, IT IS.
- SO HOW LONG IS HE GONNA STAY?
- WELL, THAT AIN'T IMPORTANT.
- HONEY, THAT'S WHAT YOU THINK.
HE ONLY DID IT SO HE COULD SELL
IT FOR A BETTER PRICE.
- NO.
NO.
HE LISTENED WHEN I TOLD HIM
HOW GOOD BUSINESS WAS GONNA BE
AND EVERYTHING.
- JUST BAIT TO HOOK THE FISH
THAT'S GONNA BUY IT.
- WHY YOU GOT TO BE SO COLD?
EVERY TIME I MENTION DUKE'S
NAME, YOU GOT TO PUT HIM DOWN.
- 'CAUSE HE'S JUST ANOTHER
BIG CITY, JIVE ASS SPOOK.
THAT'S WHY.
FORGET HIM.
- BUT THIS IS BEN'S BROTHER.
HE DESERVES A BREAK.
- HARLEY, LISTEN.
I'VE MET 100 GUYS JUST LIKE HIM.
TAKERS,
EVERY GODDAMN ONE OF 'EM,
AND I GOT THE SCARS TO PROVE IT.
- SHOOT!
YOU DON'T KNOW HIM.
THIS IS A DIFFERENT KINDA MAN.
- HARLEY, THERE AIN'T NO
DIFFERENT KINDA MAN.
- HEY, Y'ALL, CLETE, SAM.
- HEY.
- I'M TELLING YOU
THERE AIN'T NO ONE
LIKE THAT CLEO OF MINE.
MAN, SHE HAS GOT A MOUTH SOFT
AND SWEET AS AN OVERRIPE PLUM.
AND I'LL TELL YA, THAT TONGUE,
SWEET JESUS!
- SHIT.
IF YOU WEREN'T
THE CHIEF'S COUSIN,
SHE WOULDN'T GIVE YOU A SMILE
FOR FREE.
- AIN'T THAT THE TRUTH?
- YOU GO TO HELL.
- HEY, THE DUDE'S
OPENED THE ALABAM.
YOU THINK IT'S TIME MR. JOHNSON
JOINED THE CLUB?
- YEAH, YOU GO ON WITH SAM.
ME AND MERLE GOT SOME BUSINESS.
- AW, COME ON, CLETE.
LET ME GO WITH YA.
I ALWAYS MISS OUT
ON ALL THE FUN.
- UH-UH.
LEAVE THIS ONE FOR THE MEN.
- GET IN THE CAR, WARREN.
- DAMN!
- LET ME HAVE ONE OF THOSE.
THAT TASTES LIKE THAT BEEN
FLUSHED DOWN THE TOILET.
WHAT DO YOU THINK, CLETE?
- WELL, IF YOU SMELL
AND LOOK LIKE A PIG,
I GUESS YOU GOT TO ACT LIKE ONE,
DON'T YA?
ALL RIGHT, FELLAS, GET OUT.
- YOU WANT ME TO TELL HIM,
CLETE?
- NO, I'LL TELL HIM, MERLE.
THE FACT IS I'M GONNA TELL HIM
REAL FRIENDLY.
I'M EVEN GONNA CALL HIM
BY HIS FIRST NAME.
NIGGER.
YOU WANT TO DO BUSINESS
IN BUCKTOWN,
YOU GOT TO PAY
FOR THE PRIVILEGE.
- WELL, YOU SEE,
I'VE ALREADY PAID.
- HEY, THAT WAS JUST
TO TAKE DOWN THE SIGN.
- HEY, HEY, HEY!
EVERYBODY DO THEIR THING.
- EVERY SATURDAY NIGHT,
YOU COME UP WITH 100 BUCKS.
COME SATURDAY YOU DON'T GIVE ME
MY SATURDAY MONEY,
I'M GONNA SLAP A SIGN
ON THAT DOOR.
THAT SIGN GONNA SAY,
"NIGGER, READ AND RUN."
YOU CAN'T READ AND RUN ANYWAY.
FIRST NIGGER TOUCH THAT SIGN,
FIRST NIGGER
TRY TO COME THROUGH THAT DOOR,
I'M GONNA KICK HIS HEAD
TILL HIS EYES POOCH OUT
LIKE AN EAGLE'S ASS
IN A POWER DIVE.
YOU UNDERSTAND
WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT, BOY?
- OH, YEAH, I UNDERSTAND.
IT'S THAT CHEAP, SMELLY,
FUNKY CIGAR YOU'RE SMOKING
THAT'S MAKING YOU TALK SO FUNNY.
- THIS BOY HAS A MOUTH.
- ALLIGATOR MOUTH
AND A HUMMINGBIRD ASS
JUST LIKE HIS OLD BROTHER, BEN.
- HE SURE IS STUBBORN LIKE HIM.
- YEAH, DON'T KICK THIS BOY
IN THE HEAD, MERLE.
YOU KNOW
YOU CAN'T HURT THEM NIGGERS
WHEN YOU KICK THEM IN THE HEAD.
- ALL RIGHT, CLOWNS,
YOU'VE HAD YOUR LAUGHS.
NOW, EITHER GO OUT THE DOOR
OR THROUGH IT.
YOUR CHOICE.
- STEP ASIDE, BOY.
I'M CHECKING THAT CASH REGISTER.
- THE PRICE YOU HAVE TO PAY
TO DO THAT, CRACKER,
AIN'T WORTH IT.
- WHY YOU PALE FACES
ALWAYS TOGETHER?
YOU FAGGOTS?
- OH, YOU LITTLE SHIT.
- STOP!
- DUKE, LOOK OUT!
- WATCH IT, DUKE!
- SUCKER.
- YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
YOU TWO ARE A COUPLE
OF REAL SWEETHEARTS.
- WHAT KINDA JIVE
ARE YOU TALKIN' ABOUT?
- WHY WASN'T I TOLD
ABOUT WHAT'S COMING DOWN HERE?
- OH, DUKE,
I'M SORRY ABOUT THAT.
I DIDN'T SAY NOTHIN' 'CAUSE
I DIDN'T WANT YOU TO LEAVE.
ARETHA HERE, SHE FIGURED
YOU WERE GONNA GO ANYWAY,
SO WHY SHOULD SHE SAY ANYTHING?
THAT'S ALL THAT WENT DOWN, MAN.
- COPS STRONG ARM
THE WHOLE GODDAMN TOWN,
DEALING IN PAYOUTS,
AND YOU DON'T TELL ME
NOTHING ABOUT IT?
- I'M SORRY ABOUT THAT, DUKE.
- NO, YOU'RE NOT SORRY, HARLEY.
WELL, WHAT DO YOU EXPECT US
TO DO?
WE HAVE TO LIVE HERE!
- OKAY, YOU TWO CAN EAT THE CRAP
THAT THEY DISH OUT,
BUT NOT ME, BABY.
NO WAY.
- OH, NOW WAIT A MINUTE, DUKE.
DUKE.
- OH, SHOOT, HARLEY.
- DAMN!
- HEY!
- NOW YOU GET THIS,
AND YOU GET IT STRAIGHT.
I AIN'T PAYING OFF ANYBODY.
NOT YOUR BOOKIES,
NOT YOU, NOBODY!
- NOW, SETTLE DOWN, MR. JOHNSON.
SETTLE DOWN.
NOW, WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
- NOW, YOU JUST CAN THE BULL.
$450 WAS MY FIRST
AND LAST PAYMENT, CHUMP!
- YOU MAY NOT BELIEVE THIS,
BUT WE RUN
A PRETTY BUSY DEPARTMENT HERE.
PUBLIC SERVICE TAKES MONEY,
AND WE DON'T GET IT ALL
FROM WRITING PARKING TICKETS,
YOU KNOW.
NOW, WE'RE NOT A BIG TOWN
LIKE WHERE YOU'RE FROM,
BUT WE HAVE PLENTY OF WORK
TO KEEP US BUSY.
FOR EXAMPLE,
TAKE YOUR BROTHER'S CASE.
WE'RE NOT GIVING UP.
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN
YOU'RE NOT GIVING UP?
- WELL, I THOUGHT YOU KNEW.
SOME UNKNOWN ASSAILANT BEAT HIM,
AND LEFT HIM FOR DEAD.
- I WAS TOLD HE DIED
OF NATURAL CAUSES, PNEUMONIA.
- TRUE.
DUE TO EXPOSURE
AND LOSS OF BLOOD.
NATURALLY,
WE DID WHAT WE COULD, BUT--
MR. JOHNSON, YOU LOOK TO ME
TO BE AN INTELLIGENT MAN.
YOU'VE BEEN AROUND,
YOU KNOW THE ROPES.
AND YOU KNOW A SMART MAN
ALWAYS AVOIDS TROUBLE,
TRIES TO GET ALONG.
DOESN'T HE, MR. JOHNSON?
- IT'S A LITTLE WARMER TONIGHT,
AND I THOUGHT
YOU MIGHT WANT THIS.
- COME ON IN.
- YOU AND I HAVEN'T GONE
OUT OF OUR WAY TO BE FRIENDS.
- IT'S ALL RIGHT.
FORGET IT.
HERE'S LOOKIN' AT YA,
SWEETHEART.
- THIS AIN'T AN EASY TOWN
TO LIVE IN, YOU KNOW.
- YEAH, WHAT TOWN IS?
- WELL,
WHAT I'M TRYING TO SAY IS,
I WAS WRONG.
- EVERYBODY PAYS THE MAN
IN THIS TOWN.
NOBODY TELLS ME.
HONKIES RUN THIS TOWN.
MY BROTHER, BEN,
IS FOUND DEAD IN THE GUTTER.
NOBODY TELLS ME HOW OR WHY.
- WELL, I'M NOT PROUD OF THE
FACT THAT I DIDN'T SAY NOTHIN'.
HOW DO YOU TELL SOMEBODY
THAT THEIR BROTHER WAS BEATEN UP
BY SOME GOONS
AT THE POLICE DEPARTMENT
AND LEFT TO DIE
IN THE FREEZING RAIN?
I'VE WANTED TO TELL YOU, BUT--
- BUT YOU GOT TO HUSTLE
JUST FOR A LIVING, RIGHT?
AND YOU WANT TO PLAY IT SAFE.
- PLAY IT SAFE?
YOU'RE DAMN RIGHT
I PLAY IT SAFE.
I'M TIRED OF LEADING THE CHARGE.
- YOU EVER HEARD OF PRIDE?
YOU WANT TO GO THROUGH LIFE
BEING TRAMPLED, BABY,
THAT'S YOUR BUSINESS.
- WELL, WHAT DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT SCUFFLING AND HUSTLING
AND BREAKING YOUR BACK
FOR PEANUTS, AND TAKING IT ALL,
BUT STILL GOING ON LIVING
AND HOPING AND DREAMIN'?
WHAT THE HELL
DO YOU KNOW ABOUT THAT?
- YOU THINK YOU GOT A MONOPOLY
ON HARD TIMES?
I MEAN,
WHO PROMISED YOU A FREE RIDE?
- YOU THINK YOU'RE REALLY
SOMETHIN', DON'T YOU?
THE SUPER SUCCESSFUL
YOUNG BROTHER,
EVERYONE KOWTOWING TO YOU.
BEN TOLD US ALL ABOUT YOU UNTIL
WE WERE SICK OF HEARING IT!
I MUST BE SOME KINDA
SIMPLE-HEADED FOOL
FOR COMING IN HERE
AND TRYING TO APOLOGIZE TO YOU
FOR MISJUDGING YOU,
THINKING YOU WERE JUST
SOME KIND OF BIG CITY DUDE
COMING DOWN HERE TO PARADE
IN FRONT OF US SMALL-TOWN FOLK.
- NOW YOU THINK DIFFERENT, HUH?
- WELL, I SAW DIFFERENT.
I SAW YOU STAND UP
FOR YOUR RIGHTS
AND SHOW THAT
YOU WERE YOUR OWN MAN.
AND WHAT DO I GET FOR IT?
JUST DUMPED ON.
- WHAT DO YOU WANT FROM ME?
MY BLESSING?
OR THE KEYS TO THE CITY?
- YOU BASTARD!
- GET YOUR BLACK ASS
OUT OF TOWN, NIGGER!
YAHOO!
GO GET 'EM, MERLE!
RIGHT ON.
- HOLD IT, BOYS.
HOLD IT!
HEY, CLETE.
- YO!
- COME ON OVER HERE.
- ALL RIGHT.
- WE DON'T WANT 'EM KILLED,
DO WE?
- WELL, WE MAY HAVE TO,
YOU KNOW.
HE'S PRETTY STUBBORN.
HE'S JUST LIKE HIS OLD BROTHER,
BEN.
- IT'D BE EASY, WOULDN'T IT?
- NOTHIN' TO IT.
- HELL, WHAT'S ONE DEAD NIGGER,
MORE OR LESS?
- NOW, THAT'S JUST THE POINT,
BOYS.
AFTER BEN,
PEOPLE MIGHT GET TOO CURIOUS,
ESPECIALLY UP IN THE CAPITOL.
AND WE DON'T WANT THAT.
I JUST WANTED HIM
TAUGHT A LESSON.
WE'LL SEE HOW WELL
HE'S LEARNED IT.
- RIGHT, CHIEF.
- GET OFF THE CAR.
- YOU ALL RIGHT, BABY?
- YEAH, BUT, DUKE,
YOU GOT TO RUN.
THEY'RE GONNA KILL YOU.
- I NEVER RAN FROM NOBODY,
AND I DON'T INTEND TO START NOW.
- BUT, DUKE,
YOU CAN'T DO IT BY YOURSELF.
PLEASE, DUKE, YOU GOT TO RUN.
PLEASE.
- NO CHANCE, BABY.
- EASE UP, EASE UP.
EXCUSE ME.
YEAH.
- DUKE.
DUKE!
OH, MAN, WHERE YOU BEEN?
LISTEN, MAN.
[chuckles]
EVERYBODY'S BEEN SAYING,
"WHERE'S DUKE?
WHEN'S HE COMIN' HOME?"
YEAH.
[laughs]
LISTEN.
I GOT TWO OR THREE
VERY SWEET PROPOSITIONS
WAITING FOR US WHEN YOU RETURN.
HMM.
LIKE ALWAYS, HUH?
LISTEN TO ONE OF THEM.
[laughs]
- ROY, MAN, I DIDN'T CALL YOU UP
TO JIVE WITH YA, BROTHER.
WE GOT TO TALK SERIOUS BUSINESS,
MAN.
- ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
WHAT'S THE MATTER, MAN?
DON'T YOU LAUGH ANYMORE?
- LOOK, FOCUS IN ON DETROIT.
REMEMBER?
- ARE YOU KIDDIN'?
WE WERE OUTNUMBERED, WHAT,
THREE, FOUR TO ONE.
MAN, YOU WERE SOMETHIN' ELSE.
- WELL, THE ODDS HERE
ARE A LOT LONGER.
MAN, IT'S A JIVE TOWN
WITH A BUNCH OF CRACKERS.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
- YOU REALLY ARE SERIOUS.
EXCUSE ME.
WHEN?
- YESTERDAY, BROTHER.
YESTERDAY.
- WELL, I OWE YOU ONE, BUDDY.
I'M ON MY WAY.
- ROY,
BRING MUSCLE.
- I'M LOOKING AT A DEAD MAN.
- BOY.
WHERE WOULD ONE FIND
THE CLUB ALABAM?
- IT'S RIGHT DOWN THERE IN TOWN.
- WHERE?
- IT'S IN TOWN.
- DO I TAKE A TAXI
OR A STAGECOACH?
- THE CAB'S BROKE DOWN.
- FIGURES.
- HEY.
THAT'S MY HAT.
- KINDA SLOPPY THERE, BOY.
- I'VE SEEN BETTER LOOKIN'
PLACES IN THE SLAMS.
- ROY, WHAT DOES THIS CAT, DUKE,
GOT ON YOU ANYHOW?
- HEY, FRESH MEAT,
WHAT YOU NEED:
GAMBLING,
GIRLS?
- KNOCK OFF, LITTLE KID.
- YOU NAME IT.
POKER?
PINOCHLE?
POON TANG?
- HALF PINT, DIDN'T I TELL YOU
TO HAUL YOUR ASS?
- HEY, HEY, EASE UP, T.J.
THE KID'S JUST TRYING
TO MAKE HIS HUSTLE.
I STARTED LIKE THAT TOO.
- HEY, DUKE,
I THINK YOU GOT SOME COMPANY.
- ROY.
HEY, ROY.
OH, HEY, MAN.
HOW YOU DOIN'?
- HEY, WHAT YOU KNOW, MAN?
- HEY, THANKS FOR COMIN', MAN.
- HEY, WHAT COULD I DO, HUH?
- HEY, HEY, HARLEY,
REMEMBER THE DUDE
I WAS TELLING YOU ABOUT, MAN?
THIS IS HIM: ROY.
- HOW YOU DO, MR. ROY?
- HARLEY.
- OH, THIS IS ARETHA.
ROY.
- ARETHA.
- HI, ROY.
- OH, EXCUSE ME.
THIS IS JOSH, HAMBONE, T.J.
- HOW YA DOIN', FELLAS?
- MAN, I HAVE NEVER SEEN
ANYTHING LIKE THIS AT HOME.
- ME AND THIS CAT,
WE PRACTICALLY GREW UP TOGETHER.
- MM.
WENT THROUGH SOME REAL,
REAL SCENES
FROM THE STREETS
ALL THE WAY UP TO THE TOP, HUH?
[laughs]
- YEAH, RIGHT ON.
RIGHT ON.
BUT GOOD TIMES, RIGHT?
- GOOD TIMES.
YEAH.
COME ON.
LET'S HAVE A DRINK.
- RIGHT.
- MAN, YOU'RE REALLY A SIGHT.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TROUBLE YOU GOT,
BUT WE'RE HERE WITH THE CURE.
- HOW YOU LIKE
THESE LITTLE CUTIE PIES?
- MAN, ARE YOU CRAZY?
GET RID OF THIS JAILBAIT.
- SORRY, GIRLS.
WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO PARTY LATER.
- COME ON, WE GOT TO TAKE CARE
OF SOME BUSINESS.
GET YOUR ACT TOGETHER.
- YEAH.
- OKAY, SO FOUR COPS
AND THE CHIEF.
THAT'S FIVE.
WHAT ABOUT THE GUY WHO HIRED
HIM, HIS HONOR THE MAYOR?
- NO, YOU WON'T HAVE TO WORRY
ABOUT HIM.
HE BROUGHT THE CHIEF IN TO CLEAN
UP THE TOWN FOR THE TOURISTS.
- AFTER HE SAW HE HAD A GOOD
THING GOIN', MOVED RIGHT IN.
- MM.
SO HE'D BE
THE HAPPIEST OF ANYBODY
TO SEE HIM RUN OUT OF TOWN.
- THEN WE DON'T HAVE
ANY PROBLEM, DO WE?
- REMEMBER THAT LITTLE SITUATION
WE HAD A COUPLE YEARS AGO?
- YOU WANT TO WORK IT
THE SAME WAY?
- WHY NOT, MAN?
NO SENSE IN DRAGGING IT OUT.
BESIDES, I WANT TO SEE IF YOU'VE
SLOWED DOWN IN YOUR OLD AGE.
- HUH.
NO WAY.
[laughs]
- HEY, THERE'S ANOTHER ONE
OUT THERE NOW.
MAN, THIS CAT'S GONNA GO BLIND
SQUINTING UP AT ME
WITH HIS BIG BLUE EYES.
- DUKE, WHAT ABOUT THE BOSS
OF THESE TIN SOLDIERS?
- WELL, FAR AS I CAN TELL, MAN,
HE'S ALL SPIT AND POLISHED.
STILL THINK WORLD WAR II
IS GOING ON,
BUT I WOULDN'T PLAY HIM
TOO CHEAP, MAN.
HE DIDN'T GET THIS FAR
BEING DUMB.
- WANT TO KILL HIM FIRST?
- NO, WE'LL HOOK THAT UP
AFTER WE GET THE LOCATIONS.
- YOU SICK ANIMAL!
- WHAT THE HELL
IS WRONG WITH HER?
- THEY HAVEN'T BUDGED
FOR FOUR HOURS.
NOBODY STAYS IN THAT HOTEL
THAT LONG.
- WHERE'S DUANE?
- HE'S OVER THERE.
THEY'RE TROUBLE, BRIAN.
THEY DON'T LOOK RIGHT.
- YOU WORRY TOO MUCH, SAM.
NO COON LOOKS GOOD
TO A DECENT MAN.
JUST REMEMBER, WE'RE THE LAW.
AND GOD IS ON OUR SIDE.
- YES, SIR.
- SEE YA LATER, SAM.
- GETS OFF WORK AFTER MIDNIGHT,
USUALLY MAKES A BEELINE
STRAIGHT FOR THIS PLACE.
THAT'S HIS OLD LADY
DANCING UP THERE.
HE USUALLY TAKES HER HOME
ABOUT 2:00.
- THAT'LL BE A GOOD TIME
TO NAIL HIS ASS,
IN THE SACK.
- MAN, YOU GOT A MEAN STREAK
IN YOU, BROTHER.
- TO THE BONE.
[laughs]
- HEY, YOU BABIES
WANT A LITTLE ACTION?
- WE GOT EACH OTHER, MAMA.
- EXCUSE ME, SIR.
MY NAME IS ROY WAYNE.
THIS IS DUKE JOHNSON.
I'M SURE YOU KNOW HIM.
HE'S A FRIEND OF MINE.
WE WERE JUST TAKING A LITTLE
STROLL DOWN THE STREET HERE.
WE WOULD VERY MUCH LIKE IT
IF YOU WOULD JOIN US, HUH?
- OH.
- LIGHT.
HUH?
- NO THANKS.
I DON'T SMOKE.
- THINK WE SHOULD DITCH HIM?
- NO HE'S FAT ENOUGH.
LET HIM GET SOME EXERCISE.
- THE END OF THE NIGHT HERE.
- SAM LIKES TO SPEND EVENINGS
OVER AT THE HOTEL.
THERE'S ALWAYS A BIG MONEY GAME
GOING ON.
HE GETS A PIECE OF THE TAKE.
- BET FIVE.
YOU WANNA CALL?
- THEN THERE'S MERLE.
LIVES OVER
AT RUBY'S WHORE HOUSE.
OWNS A CHUNK OF IT.
MAN, THAT MOTHER.
I MEAN, THAT MERLE, BOY,
HE GETS HIS KICKS
LEANING HEAVY ON THE LADIES.
- HOW MANY TIMES HAVE I TOLD YOU
NOT TO BE LATE?
- I SWEAR I WASN'T LYING.
- DON'T YOU NEVER LIE TO ME.
YA HEAR?
NEVER!
- USUALLY, THIS TIME OF NIGHT
THERE'S ONLY ONE COP
MANNING THE FORT.
- OH, YEAH?
WELL, IT'S NO SWEAT, HUH?
HE'S PROBABLY
SLEEPING ON THE JOB.
MAYBE WE OUGHT TO TRY
TO MAKE IT PERMANENT.
- PERMANENT?
[both chuckle]
DAMN, BROTHER.
YOU HAVE BECOME
ONE VIOLENT DUDE.
- TRUE.
- LOVER OF ALL MANKIND, RIGHT?
WELL, THE WAY I SEE IT, MAN,
THE FIRST THING WE GOT TO DO
IS TAKE THAT RADIO OUT.
- TRUE.
THE LAST THING WE NEED
IS STATE POLICE SNOOPING AROUND.
SOMEHOW, I DON'T THINK
THEY'D UNDERSTAND.
- WELL, WHAT YOU THINK, HOME?
- IT'S COOL.
LIKE STEALING CANDY FROM A BABY.
- OH, YEAH.
- UH-HUH.
- MERLE!
CLETE!
- NO, NO, NO, NO.
- WAIT, PLEASE.
DON'T HIT ME AGAIN.
PLEASE, I DON'T WANT TO DIE!
PLEASE.
PLEASE, GOD.
I'M JUST LIKE YOU.
- LIKE HELL!
- HONEY,
WHERE ARE THE CIGARETTES?
- THEY'RE ON THE DRESSER, BABY.
- SHH.
SHH, SHH, SHH, SHH, SHH.
- FIRE ESCAPE.
- LISTEN, YOU DUMB SAMBO.
I'M GONNA EXPLAIN IT
JUST ONCE MORE.
I DON'T WANT MY HAMBURGERS
WITHOUT MUSTARD.
I WANT 'EM WITHOUT KETCHUP,
BUT WITH MUSTARD.
NOW, GET IT RIGHT THIS TIME,
OR I'M GONNA KICK YOUR ASS!
- NOT AN INCH.
DON'T MOVE AN INCH.
YOU KNOW ANY PRAYERS, CRACKER?
SHAME ON YOU IF YOU DON'T.
YOU SHOULDA HAD THE KETCHUP.
- I GOT ONE IN.
WHERE'S ANOTHER ONE?
GIVE ME A RAISE.
COME ON.
- KEEP THE MONEY.
I WANT HIM!
- DROP THE GUN DOWN,
OR I'LL BLOW HER HEAD OFF!
DROP IT!
- DUKE.
- I MEAN IT.
NOW, BACK UP.
BACK UP AND LET ME OUT OF HERE.
I'M GOING OUT,
AND I'M TAKING HER WITH ME.
MOVE BACK.
I'LL BLOW HER HEAD OFF.
YOU STAY BACK.
YOU STAY FAR BACK.
YOU HEAR?
- I MUST BE LOSING MY TOUCH.
- GOT TO HIT HIM WHERE IT HURTS,
MY MAN.
- THAT'S A GOOD SHOT.
- [chuckles]
- NO USE WASTING GOOD AMMO.
- RISE AND SHINE, CHIEF.
- THE WAR IS OVER.
- [speaks indistinctly]
- AH, COMPANY.
- WELL, WELL.
BUCKTOWN'S OWN
PRIVATE TIN SOLDIER.
- TEN, HUP!
- WHAT DO YOU THINK, DUKE?
- WELL, HOW ABOUT 10:00
IN THE MORNIN'?
- WHY, THAT'S TOO EARLY.
- WELL, HOW ABOUT HIGH NOON?
- WHAT, AND SPOIL OUR LUNCH?
- DAMN!
LET'S SHOOT HIM AT 1:00 THEN.
- HOW ABOUT RIGHT NOW?
- YOU'RE NOT GONNA KILL ME.
NEWS TRAVELS FAST.
IT'S BOUND TO GET
TO THE STATE TROOPERS.
IF THEY ASK ANY QUESTIONS,
YOU'RE GONNA TELL
YOUR BLACK MAYOR TO TELL THEM
THAT YOU'RE HOLDING
THE CHIEF OF POLICE
FOR BREAKING THE LAW.
NO, YOU'RE GONNA KEEP ME ALIVE
'CAUSE I'M GONNA KEEP YOUR BLACK
ASSES FROM BURNING IN HELL!
- $1,432: PROSTITUTION.
- I CAN'T TELL YA HOW MUCH
WE APPRECIATE WHAT YOU BOYS
HAVE DONE
FOR OUR LITTLE OLD TOWN.
WE WERE ALL BEING, WELL,
YOU KNOW--WE WERE BEING--
- THE WORD'S "SCREWED,"
MR. MAYOR.
- EXACTLY.
JUST THE RIGHT WORD.
- EXCUSE ME, ASSISTANT.
- $2,848: GAMBLING.
- BEFORE I FORGET,
THE BADGES FROM YOUR USED TO BE
POLICE DEPARTMENT.
- WE DO THANK YOU.
IF ONLY THERE WAS SOME WAY
TO THANK YOU.
I MEAN, FOR OUR TOWN
TO EXPRESS OUR APPRECIATION
FOR WHAT YOU'VE DONE
BEFORE YOU LEAVE.
- THINK REAL HARD.
YOU'LL COME UP WITH SOMETHING.
- MR. MAYOR,
LAST NIGHT'S RECEIPTS
COME TO A TOTAL
OF $6,319.
- FINE.
A PARADE.
- WHAT?
- DOWN THE MAIN STREET
WITH THE HIGH SCHOOL
MARCHING BAND
AND OUR POM-POM GIRLS
AND BATON TWIRLERS
AND YOU AND YOUR BOYS
WAVING AND SMILIN'.
AND BRINGING UP THE REAR,
THE BUCHANNAN
VOLUNTEER FIRE DEPARTMENT.
- NO PARADE.
- NO PARADE?
- NO.
NO PARADES.
- I THINK I CAN SUGGEST
A BETTER WAY
FOR YOU TO SHOW YOUR
APPRECIATION, MR. MAYOR.
- DUKE.
DUKE, WAKE UP.
GET YOUR BUNS UP.
DUKE.
- WHAT?
- GET UP.
- COME ON.
ALL RIGHT, COME ON.
ANY TIME'S THE RIGHT TIME.
COME ON.
- DUKE, I DIDN'T COME HERE
TO GET IN YOUR BED.
I CAME TO GET YOU OUT OF IT.
- OUT OF IT?
TOO EARLY.
ROY DON'T LEAVE TILL 12:00.
- BUT, DUKE, THAT'S WHAT
I CAME HERE TO TELL YOU.
THE TRAIN'S LEAVING,
BUT ROY AIN'T.
DUKE.
- WHAT?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKIN' ABOUT?
- THEY'RE ALL STAYIN' HERE.
- NOW, WHAT THEY GONNA DO
IN THIS HICK TOWN?
- THEY'RE GONNA WEAR BADGES
IN THIS HICK TOWN.
- BADGES?
- ROY CONNED THE MAYOR.
NOW HE'S WEARING
THE CHIEF'S BADGE.
JOSH, T.J., AND HAMBONE
ARE POLICEMEN.
- [laughs]
I'LL BE DAMNED.
ALL FOUR OF 'EM, HUH?
AND ALL OF 'EM WITH A RAP SHEET
A YARD LONG.
AND, YOU KNOW, I BET OLD ROY
IS TOTALLY UP TO SOMETHIN'.
- WELL,
THAT'S NOT HARD TO FIGURE OUT.
YOU WANT MY OPINION?
- NO.
- WELL, YOU'RE GONNA GET IT
ANYWAY, DUMMY.
YOUR BUDDY SAW WHAT A GOOD THING
THE CHIEF HAD GOIN' FOR HIM,
AND NOW HE WANTS IT FOR HIMSELF.
- NO, THEY'RE BROTHERS.
THE CHIEF AND HIS BOYS,
THEY WERE--
- HONKIES.
WELL, LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHIN'
ABOUT PEOPLE, BIG SHOT.
WHETHER THEY'RE WHITE, BLACK,
GREEN, YELLOW, OR PURPLE,
WHEN THEY SMELL A FEW DOLLARS,
THEY ALL ACT ALIKE.
- HUH.
- MM.
GET UP!
- I WON'T TELL YOU ANYTHING.
- BUCKTOWN'S PURE GOLD, CHIEF.
AND YOU'VE BEEN SQUEEZING
AND MILKING IT DRY.
SO COME ON.
FOR THE LAST TIME,
WHERE'S THE DOUGH?
- PAYING OFF STREET SCUM
IS EASY.
GIVING INTO 'EM, IMPOSSIBLE.
- A MAN WHO WON'T TALK
DOESN'T NEED HIS TONGUE.
HAMBONE.
- HEY, PARTNER.
[chuckles]
WELCOME TO THE PROMISED LAND,
HUH?
HEY, BABY, WHY DON'T YOU GO
AND PUT SOMETHING ON
A LITTLE SWEETER FOR MY MAN.
- SURE.
- WHAT IS IT WE'RE GONNA BE
PARTNERS IN, BUDDY?
I THOUGHT
YOU WERE GONNA LEAVE TOWN, MAN.
WHAT HAPPENED?
- CONSIDERABLE.
CONSIDERABLE.
MAN, LISTEN.
WHEN I GOT THE TELEPHONE CALL
BACK EAST
SAYING THAT MY PARTNER
NEEDED SOME HELP,
HOW WAS I TO KNOW
THAT HE WAS GONNA CUT ME IN
ON A SOFT TOUCH THAT I'VE BEEN
WAITING FOR ALL MY LIFE?
- TOUCH?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT, MAN?
I JUST CALLED YOU IN THIS TOWN
TO HELP TO GET RID
OF SOME JIVE CRACKERS.
THAT'S ALL.
- ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
SO YOU KNOW
WHAT THE GOOD BOOK SAYS.
"THE LORD HELPS THEM
THAT HELPS THEMSELVES."
AND THAT'S WHAT WE'RE DOING,
MAN.
WE'RE HELPING OURSELVES.
WE OWN THIS TOWN.
AND THANKS TO HIS HONOR,
WE EVEN GOT THE BADGES HERE
TO PROVE IT.
HUH?
HERE'S YOURS.
- NO, MAN.
LISTEN, IT'S NOT MY WAY, ROY.
- WHAT'S THE MATTER, MAN?
HUH?
YOU DON'T LIKE MONEY?
OR ARE YOU BEGINNING TO FALL
FOR THIS SMALL-TOWN JIVE?
I MEAN, HERE WE GOT A POT OF
GOLD AT THE END OF THE RAINBOW,
AND MY HOMEBOY'S
GOING SOFT ON ME.
- OH, COME ON, ROY.
YOU KNOW BETTER THAN THAT.
- WELL, HOW DO I KNOW?
HOW DO I KNOW?
YOU DON'T EVEN ACT LIKE
THE CAT I GREW UP WITH.
- MAN, IT'S JUST THAT
THIS IS MY BROTHER'S TOWN, MAN.
HIS FRIENDS.
I MEAN, I WOULDN'T FEEL RIGHT
LEANING ON HIS PEOPLE, MAN.
- UH-HUH.
YEAH.
OKAY, IF THAT'S THE WAY YOU WANT
IT, THAT'S THE WAY IT'LL BE.
NOW, I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
I WON'T LEAN ON 'EM TOO HARD.
JUST ENOUGH TO PAY THE RENT.
YEAH.
[laughs]
LIKE ROBIN HOOD.
ROB FROM THE RICH.
GIVE TO THE POOR:
ME.
YOU, YOU JUST KEEP RUNNING
THAT LITTLE CLUB OF YOURS
DOWN THERE, SEE.
AND WE'LL TAKE
YOUR SHARE OF THE MONEY,
AND PUT IT IN THE SAFE
DOWN AT CITY HALL.
AND WHEN YOU DECIDE YOU WANT IT,
IT'LL BE THERE WAITING FOR YA.
- YOU'RE SERIOUS, AIN'T YA?
- I'M SERIOUS AS A HEART ATTACK.
OH, MAN.
[chuckles]
I AIN'T GONNA BE NO MORE TROUBLE
THAN THE TAX COLLECTOR.
COME ON, BROTHER.
SHOOT.
WE SUPPOSED TO BE FRIENDS, MAN.
COME ALL THIS WAY
TO HELP YOU OUT.
COME ON.
HEY.
A TOAST, HUH?
[laughs]
TO BEAUTIFUL BUCKTOWN.
- YOU'RE SHORT.
$300 SHORT.
- LAST NIGHT WAS LOUSY!
- AND YOU KNOW WHAT ROY SAID.
- HOW THE HELL CAN I COME UP
WITH AN EXTRA 50%
WHEN THE GIRLS
DIDN'T EVEN MAKE IT?
- WELL, JUST OPEN
YOUR PIGGYBANK, BABY.
EVERYBODY'S GOT TO COME UP WITH
THE NEW DUES FOR A NEW DAY.
OH, MAN, MAN.
THIS TOWN IS SOMETHIN' ELSE.
LIKE EVERY NIGHT
IS A BANK NIGHT, YOU KNOW.
THE TOWN FLIPPING THE TOURISTS,
AND US FLIPPING THE TOWN.
- THERE'S JUST ONE THING WRONG.
ROY'S FRIEND.
- ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT DUKE?
- YEAH.
AND HE'S GOT A BIG HAND
IN THE MONEY.
AND HE DOESN'T DO A DAMN THING
TO HELP US EARN IT.
- NOTHIN' WE CAN DO 'CAUSE
THAT'S THE WAY ROY WANTS IT.
- WELL, MAYBE THERE IS.
I MEAN, THEY'RE GOOD BUDDIES,
RIGHT?
- MM-HMM.
- LET'S SAY
THEY WEREN'T SUCH GOOD BUDDIES.
THEN WE CAN STEP IN AND DO
SOMETHIN'.
- LISTEN, T.J., NO TWO DUDES
EVER BEEN CLOSER.
SO HOW COULD WE CHANGE ANYTHING?
- MAN,
I ALREADY GOT SOMETHIN' GOING.
JOSH IS WORKING IT RIGHT NOW.
BUT, SEE, YOU AND I
GOT TO GIVE HIM A HAND.
THEN I'LL SHOW YA
HOW TO CHANGE THINGS.
ALL RIGHT?
- ALL RIGHT.
- ALL RIGHT,
I'M GONNA TRY AND EXPLAIN IT
TO YOUR SATISFICATION.
NOW, THE QUARTERBACK COME UP TO
THE LINE OF SCRIMMAGE.
HE SEE THE WHOLE COMING
ON THE RIGHT,
SO HE CALLED THE COLOR,
WHICH IS GREEN.
SINGS A STRAIGHT, 45,
AND NUMBER 4
IS THE RIGHT HALFBACK
COMING OVER RIGHT HOLE.
AND NUMBER FIVE IS MINE,
'CAUSE I'M THE ONLY ONE
SOMEBODY COULD TAKE OUT
TWO MENS.
- HARLEY HERE KEEPS TELLING ME
HE THREW THAT KEY BLOCK
IN THE CHAMPIONSHIP GAME.
EXPECTS ME TO BELIEVE HIM.
- BIG LYING NUISANCE.
BIG PHONY.
- YOUR MAMA WAS A NUISANCE.
SHE THE BIGGEST NUISANCE
YOU EVER MET.
- I SAY YOU'RE LYING, BIG MAN.
- I AIN'T LYING, PUNK.
AND YOU, PUNK.
AND YOU, YOU'RE A SISSY.
AND YOU, YOU SON OF A GUN,
YOU'RE A PUNK ASS SISSY.
- LYING LUSH.
I SAY YOU'RE A LYING LUSH.
- BIG STAR FOOTBALL PLAYER.
- I TELL YA,
I WAS THE STAR OF THAT GAME,
MOTHERFUCKER!
- HARLEY.
[crying]
- NO.
- HARLEY.
- STEVIE.
STEVIE, LET GO.
STEVIE, NO.
STEVIE.
WE'RE GONNA GO WITH HIM.
- IF BUSINESS GETS ANY BETTER,
WE'RE GONNA NEED A BIGGER SAFE.
LISTEN.
ADD THIS UP RIGHT HERE.
- NOW, ROY.
- WHAT ARE YOU WAITIN' FOR?
- FOR YOU TO TELL ME
WHY YOU SENT YOUR GOONS
TO BEAT UP ON HARLEY.
- WHY WOULD I DO A THING
LIKE THAT?
- LISTEN, HARLEY
IS IN THE HOSPITAL, MAN.
AND IF HE DON'T MAKE IT--
- OH, COME ON, MAN, COOL IT.
COOL IT.
I MEAN, YOU'RE MAKING A LOT TO
DO OUT OF NOTHIN'.
THE WAY I GET IT, HARLEY
WAS GETTING DRUNK IN THE BAR.
RIGHT?
HE WAS CAUSING A DISTURBANCE.
THERE WAS A COMPLAINT.
LOOK, WHAT ARE MY MEN WEARING
THOSE BADGES FOR
EXCEPT TO KEEP THE PEACE?
- OH, COME ON, ROY.
YOU KNOW THAT'S B.S.
- YOU CALLING ME A LIAR?
- NO, MAN,
I'M NOT CALLING YOU A LIAR.
I'M JUST TRYING
TO FIND OUT THE TRUTH.
- SO AM I.
WHAT'S WRONG, DUKE?
I MEAN, WHAT'S HAPPENING?
I MEAN, AFTER ALL
WE'VE BEEN THROUGH, MAN,
WHY WOULD I WANT TO LAY
OUR FRIENDSHIP ON THE LINE
BEHIND SOME BULLSHIT?
- I'M NOT COMING DOWN ON YOU,
ROY.
I JUST WANT YOU TO CONTROL
YOUR CLOWNS, THAT'S ALL.
BECAUSE IF THEY PUSH MY PEOPLE
AROUND AGAIN,
THEY'RE GONNA HAVE TO TANGLE
WITH ME.
THAT'S ALL I'M SAYING, MAN.
- OKAY.
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT DID HAPPEN TO HARLEY?
- MAN, LIKE I TOLD YOU,
BIG MAN CAN'T HANDLE HIS SAUCE.
WE WENT IN TO MAKE AN ARREST,
AND HE BEGAN
THROWING HIS WEIGHT AROUND.
SO IT TOOK THREE OF US
TO GET HIM OUT.
- THAT'S ALL?
- WOULD I LIE TO YOU?
- OH, HARLEY.
HOW DOES YOUR HEAD FEEL?
- ALL RIGHT, ARETHA.
- WELL, WHAT HAPPENED?
I KNOW YOU DIDN'T START THAT
FIGHT LIKE THEY SAID YOU DID.
- I DON'T RIGHTLY REMEMBER,
ARETHA.
I DO KNOW WE...
WAS ALL
IN THE BAR THERE DRINKIN'.
I WAS TELLIN' 'EM HOW...
I WAS THE STAR OF THAT GAME.
AND THEY SAID I WAS LYING.
- [murmuring indistinctly]
- THE NURSES,
THEY SAY...
IT TOOK 45 STITCHES
TO SEW ME UP.
THAT'S SOME KINDA RECORD,
AIN'T IT?
- YEAH, HARLEY,
THAT'S SOME KINDA RECORD.
- I'M SORRY, ARETHA.
I FEEL LIKE A STOMPED DOWN FOOL.
- OH, HARLEY.
YOU'RE MY NUMBER ONE.
- LOOKS LIKE YOUR FRIEND ROY
IS BUILDING UP AN ARMY.
POOR OLD BUCKTOWN.
THINGS WERE BAD ENOUGH
UNDER THE CHIEF,
BUT NOW THEY'RE TEN TIMES WORSE.
THERE'S NO WAY
THAT WE CAN FIGHT 'EM.
NO WAY.
- CAN I BUY YOU A DRINK, LADY?
- SUIT YOURSELF.
- TWO OF THE SAME.
WHERE'S YOUR MAN?
- NOT HERE.
HE'S AT THE HOSPITAL
LOOKING IN ON HARLEY.
- HOW IS HARLEY?
- HE'S MAKING IT.
NO THANKS TO YOU.
- THANK YOU.
MAYBE YOU COULD DO YOURSELF
AND YOUR MAN A BIG FAVOR,
IF YOU WOULD.
- LIKE HOW?
- GET HIM TO LEAVE TOWN NOW.
- HUH.
WHY SHOULD HE LEAVE TOWN?
- WELL,
THERE ARE A LOT OF BIG REASONS
DOWN IN THAT VAULT AT CITY HALL.
HIS CUT OF THE PIE.
YOU TWO COULD LIVE REAL HIGH
ON HIS SHARE OF THE MONEY.
YEAH.
FINE DIAMONDS, JEWELRY,
HIGH LIVING.
- SUPPOSE I WANT TO STAY.
- WELL, YOU GOT A PRETTY NICE
CHOICE ANY WAY YOU LOOK AT IT.
IF YOU GO, YOU GOT DUKE
AND ALL THAT HEAVY BREAD.
AND IF YOU DECIDE TO STAY ON
HERE IN BUCKTOWN,
I'D BE WILLING TO MAKE YOU
A VERY SWEET PROPOSITION.
SERIOUSLY.
- WHAT IF WE BOTH
DECIDE TO STAY,
ME AND DUKE?
- I DON'T THINK THAT WOULD BE
TOO PLEASANT.
- OH, MAN, I'M GONNA ENJOY THIS.
- NOW, YOU'RE GOING ABOUT IT
THE WRONG WAY, T.J.
- OH, MAN, DUKE WILL THINK
ROY SET IT ALL UP.
YOU WAIT HERE.
- NAH, NAH, NAH, NAH, NAH.
- FIRST,
I'M GONNA BREAK YOUR ARMS.
THEN I'M GONNA BREAK YOUR LEGS.
BUT I'M GONNA START
ON YOUR FACE.
- DUKE, BABY.
I THOUGHT WE YOUR FRIENDS.
NOW, WE COME DOWN HERE
TO HELP YOU OUT.
- YEAH, JOSH, YOU CAN HELP.
YOU GET THIS IDIOT OUT OF HERE
BEFORE I BLOW HIS BRAINS OUT.
THIS IS JUST BETWEEN
ME AND YOU.
- HEY, WAIT A MINUTE, MAN.
WAIT A MINUTE.
WHAT'S WRONG?
- SIT DOWN.
I WANT YOUR FULL ATTENTION!
- ALL RIGHT, MAN, YOU'VE GOT IT.
- NOW, I CALLED YOU HERE
TO DO ME A FAVOR,
AND YOU TAKE OVER
THE WHOLE GODDAMN TOWN!
YOU HAD BRIGHT IDEAS RIGHT FROM
THE START, DIDN'T YA, OLD BUDDY?
AND I FELL FOR ALL THAT CRAP
ABOUT YOU NOT LEANING HARD
ON THE TOWN.
BUT IT'S WORSE NOW
THAN IT EVER WAS, MAN!
BECAUSE NOW
IT'S BROTHERS DOING IT!
SO WHAT GOOD DID IT DO BRINGING
YOU HERE IN THE FIRST PLACE?
- WELL, GO ON, MAN.
DON'T STOP TALKING.
I'M LISTENING.
- YOU SENT YOUR PUNKS
TO BEAT HARLEY UP.
THEN YOU SENT 'EM AFTER ARETHA.
- I DID WHAT?
- NOW, YOU LISTEN.
'CAUSE I'M ONLY
GONNA SAY IT ONCE, ROY.
I WANT YOUR PUNKS GONE.
OUT OF TOWN!
OR I SWEAR, MAN, I'LL PLANT THEM
IN THEIR OWN STINK.
- LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHIN'.
EVER SINCE WE HELPED YOU
GET RID OF THAT CHIEF
AND THEM GODDAMN REDNECKS,
YOU'VE BEEN
ACTING LIKE A GODDAMN FOOL.
YOU WON'T DO THIS,
YOU WON'T DO THAT.
YOU WON'T EVEN TAKE ANY OF THE
MONEY WE'RE TRYING TO GIVE YOU.
AND NOW YOU BUST IN MY PLACE,
AND ACCUSE ME
OF PULLING ALL KINDA WEIRD SHIT!
WELL, I AM TIRED OF IT.
AND I AIN'T GONNA STAND
FOR NO MORE OF IT.
NOW, JUST GET THIS,
GET THIS IN THAT HEAD OF YOURS.
I AM RUNNING THIS TOWN!
I'M RUNNING IT!
AND I GOT THE MAYOR
AND EVERYBODY ELSE
RIGHT BY THE BALLS,
INCLUDING YOU.
AND IF ANYBODY'S GONNA LEAVE,
IT AIN'T GONNA BE OLD ROY.
IT'S GONNA BE YOU.
YOU DIG?
- YEAH.
THAT'S THE WAY IT IS, HUH?
- YOU CALLED IT.
- ALL RIGHT, BUDDY.
ALL BETS ARE OFF.
- GIVE ME THE POLICE DEPARTMENT.
T.J., THIS IS ROY.
YOU WANTED ME TO SET AN EXAMPLE
FOR THIS TOWN.
FROM NOW ON, EVERYBODY PAYS.
SO LEAN ON HIM.
- HEY, HEY, HEY!
EVERYBODY HAVE A DRINK
AND BE SOMEBODY.
MAKE GODDAMN SURE
YOU PAY FOR IT.
LOOKIT, WE GOT SOME WHITE PEOPLE
IN THE JOINT.
YOU GUYS HAVE A GOOD TIME.
ALL RIGHT?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
- I'M REALLY FINE.
- JEFF, IT SURE IS GOOD
TO BE HOME, BOY.
HEY, ARETHA.
HOW YOU DOIN'?
- THE DOCTOR SAID
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO BE RESTING.
- AH, SHIT.
I'M TIRED OF RESTING.
I WANT TO BE HERE
WITH MY FRIENDS.
- RIGHT ON, MAN!
- ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT,
I'M NOT GONNA ARGUE ABOUT IT.
- SAY, WHERE'S THE DUKE?
- HE'S TAKING CARE OF BUSINESS.
- I'M LOOKING FOR THE BIG SHOT.
- HE AIN'T HERE.
- WE CAME EARLY.
T.J.
- YEAH.
- JOSH.
- WE GOT A SPECIAL MESSAGE
FOR HIM.
- GO GET WORD TO DUKE.
- WHERE IS HE?
- SHOW 'EM
WHAT WE'RE TALKING ABOUT, T.J.
- IT ONLY TAKES ONE
LITTLE MATCH.
- YOU BASTARD!
- YOU CRAZY MOTHERFUCKER!
- IMAGINE THAT.
ASSAULTING A LAWMAN.
TAKE HIM IN.
- HARLEY.
- HANG ON, JOSH.
MAN,
YOU'LL GET HER SOON ENOUGH.
- [shouting indistinctly]
- HARLEY!
HARLEY!
- [shouting indistinctly]
- HARLEY!
HARLEY!
- WHAT THE HECK
ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- ARETHA SENT ME.
T.J., HAMBONE, AND JOSH
ARE OVER AT THE CLUB ALABAM.
COME ON.
SHE NEEDS YOU.
- HOW MANY OUT FRONT?
- ONE.
- ALL RIGHT.
- HEY, KID, HOLD IT.
- DUKE, THANK GOD YOU'RE HERE.
- WHAT'S HAPPENED HERE?
- ROY'S THREE HOODS
CAME IN HERE,
AND THEY TRIED
TO BURN THE PLACE DOWN.
HARLEY TRIED TO STOP 'EM,
AND THEY DRAGGED HIM OFF.
- DRUG HIM WHERE?
- TO JAIL!
YOU GOT TO TALK TO ROY.
MAKE HIM LET HARLEY GO.
ROY'S YOUR FRIEND.
- NO, HE'S GONE TOO FAR NOW.
IT'S TOO LATE TO TALK.
- NO.
YOU CAN'T FIGHT HIM ALONE.
THERE'LL BE FIVE OR SIX OF 'EM
AT THE JAIL.
- I GOT A PLAN THAT SHOULD
EVEN UP THE ODDS A LITTLE BIT.
- BUT, DUKE,
WHAT GOOD IS IT GONNA DO HARLEY
GETTING YOURSELF KILLED?
DUKE!
- STEVIE, YOU KNOW THAT ARMORY
YOU WAS TELLING ME ABOUT
ACROSS THE RIVER?
YOU KNOW WHERE IT IS?
- YEAH, I CAN FIND IT.
- COME ON.
LET'S GO.
- ROY, I WANT TO TALK TO YOU.
PLEASE, ROY, IT'S IMPORTANT.
- GO AHEAD.
I'M LISTENING.
- I'M ASKING YOU
TO LET HARLEY GO.
IT WASN'T HIS FAULT.
HE JUST GOT A LITTLE CRAZY
WHEN YOUR BOYS CAME IN THE BAR
AND TRIED TO BURN IT DOWN.
- WELL, MAYBE YOU OUGHT TO BLAME
DUKE FOR THAT, NOT ME.
- WELL, DON'T TAKE IT OUT
ON HARLEY
BECAUSE OF YOUR FEELINGS
FOR DUKE.
- WELL, SINCE YOU'RE POINTING
FINGERS FOR WHAT HAPPENED,
WOMAN, IT WASN'T MY CHOICE;
IT WAS HIS.
I MEAN, DUKE'S GOT HIS HEAD
IN A WEIRD KINDA PLACE.
- NO, NO, HE DOES NOT
WANT TO GO AGAINST YOU.
HE SAYS YOU'RE HIS FRIEND.
- YEAH, WE'VE BEEN TIGHT,
BUT THAT COMES WITH RESPECT.
AND RESPECT COMES FROM KNOWING
HOW IT IS IN THE STREETS.
WHAT YOU HAVE TO DO TO GET BY,
AND DOING IT,
AND DOING IT WELL, DAMN WELL.
THAT'S WHAT IT'S ALL ABOUT.
- BUT IT DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE.
IT'S JUST YOUR DAMN EGO!
- EGO?
NO.
IT'S HOW YOU SURVIVE.
- WELL, I WANT DUKE TO SURVIVE.
I WANT TO LOVE THAT MAN.
I DON'T WANT TO BURY HIM.
YOU JUST DON'T GIVE A DAMN
ABOUT ANYBODY, DO YOU?
- YOU LISTEN, ARETHA.
YOU SHOW ME ANYBODY WHO GIVES
A DAMN ABOUT ANYBODY ELSE,
AND I'LL SHOW YOU A FOOL,
A DAMN FOOL
WHO GO THROUGH LIFE
WITH THEIR HANDS OUT
BEGGING INSTEAD OF GRABBING.
DO YOU THINK ANYBODY
IN THIS TOWN IS ANY DIFFERENT?
THEY DON'T GIVE A DAMN
WHO GETS KILLED,
JUST SO LONG AS
THE DICE KEEP ROLLING,
THE HOS KEEP HOIN',
AND THE MONEY KEEPS FLOWIN'.
IT ALL REVOLVES AROUND
THE BIG "G," BABY,
THE BIG GREEN.
EVERYBODY EVERYWHERE
IS SCRATCHING
FOR WHAT THEY CAN GET.
I'M JUST SCRATCHING
A LITTLE HARDER.
- YOU POOR, SELFISH,
IGNORANT MAN.
HAVEN'T YOU EVER HAD THE GUTS
TO LOVE SOMEBODY ELSE?
- MAYBE.
MAYBE I NEVER HAD A WOMAN
LIKE YOU TO FIGHT FOR ME.
MAYBE I EVEN ENVY DUKE FOR THAT.
I'LL BE SEEING YA.
- ISN'T IT BEAUTIFUL?
- OH, MAN, THAT MONSTER
COULD OPEN UP THE GATES OF HELL.
- WELL, WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
- WHERE'S T.J.?
T.J., I WANT TO TALK TO YOU.
WELL, I HAVEN'T BEEN TOO
FRIENDLY WITH YOU,
AND I THOUGHT I'D COME BY
AND APOLOGIZE.
- IS THAT RIGHT?
- YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
AND I NEED A FAVOR.
- WELL, IT COSTS.
- WELL, YOU DO ME THIS ONE
LITTLE OLD FAVOR,
AND I'LL DO ANYTHING YOU WANT
AND SOME.
- LIKE WHAT?
- HARLEY, HE'S JUST AN OLD DRUNK
THAT I FEEL SORRY FOR.
HE'S NO GOOD TO ANYBODY.
LET HIM GO.
- ALL RIGHT.
HAVE IT YOUR WAY.
AFTER--
- UH-UH.
BEFORE.
YOU LET HIM GO NOW,
AND IT'LL BE GOOD
BETWEEN YOU AND ME ALL THE WAY.
- OKAY, WE'LL DO IT YOUR WAY.
FOLLOW ME.
- HARLEY.
HARLEY.
LOOK AT YOU.
- ARETHA.
WHAT YOU DOIN' HERE?
THIS AIN'T NO PLACE FOR A WOMAN.
- SHH.
I CAME TO KEEP DUKE
FROM GETTING--
- DUKE.
- SHH.
SHH.
WOULD YOU PLEASE LET HIM GO NOW?
I GOT TO GET HIM TO A DOCTOR.
- DUMB BROAD.
YOU COME HERE TRYING TO DEAL.
I DON'T MAKE NO DEALS.
I TAKE WHAT I WANT.
AND THEN I'M GONNA KILL DUKE.
JUST LIKE THIS.
NOW, WHERE'S ALL THAT HONEY
YOU PROMISED ME,
THAT SUGAR AND MILK?
- SAY, BOY--
- BEG!
BEG!
COME ON.
BEG.
- I DON'T BEG FOR NOTHIN'!
- NO, BOY!
- TIGHTEN UP, NIGGER.
NOW BEG!
BEG!
- NO!
- BEG!
- SON OF A BITCH!
- NOW YOU FREEZE, NIGGER.
- HARLEY.
YOU ALL RIGHT, BABY?
- YES.
- WHERE'S THE AMMO?
- IN THE CHARIOT.
- HAMBONE!
- YOU TWO STAY BACK.
- DID YOU GET 'EM ALL?
- ALL EXCEPT ONE.
- I ALWAYS KNEW MY BUDDY
WAS A REAL MAN.
- IF ANYBODY HAD TOLD ME, ROY,
THAT WE WOULD BE
ON OPPOSITE SIDES
FIGHTING EACH OTHER--
- YOU MIGHT NOT BELIEVE THIS,
BUT I NEVER LIED TO YOU.
I NEVER SENT ANYONE
TO HASSLE HARLEY OR ARETHA.
- HOW DID IT HAPPEN THEN, ROY?
- T.J.
HE WANTED US TO TANGLE.
- LOOKS LIKE HE DID A GOOD JOB,
DIDN'T HE?
IT'S DOWN TO ME AND YOU NOW,
RIGHT?
I DON'T WANT TO SHOOT YOU, ROY.
I JUST WANT TO
BEAT THE HELL OUT OF YOU.
- IT'S YOUR DEAL.
- WINNER TAKE ALL.
LOSER, GET OUT OF TOWN,
NEVER LOOK BACK.
DEAL?
- DEAL.
- * YOU'RE MY FRIEND *
* AND I WANT YOU TO KNOW
* I'LL DO MY BEST FOR YOU *
- HEY, HEY, STEVE, COME HERE.
DUKE AND ARETHA WANT TO BE ALONE
FOR A LITTLE BIT.
BESIDES, YOU AND I GOT TO
GO HOME AND GET SOME SLEEP
SO WE CAN GET UP
AND GO TO SCHOOL TOMORROW.
- SCHOOL?
- THAT'S RIGHT.
DON'T YOU WANT TO GROW UP
TO BE SOMEBODY?
- I AM.
- WHAT?
- A MAN.
- OKAY, MAN.
- * THE WOMAN OVER THERE
IS MIGHTY FINE *
* SHE'S ALWAYS ON MY MIND *
* THINGS ARE GETTIN' BETTER
IN BUCKTOWN *
* I SEE THE PEOPLE
LAYIN' THEIR MONEY DOWN *
* THINGS ARE GETTIN' BETTER
IN BUCKTOWN *
* I THINK I'M GONNA
HANG AROUND *
* THINGS ARE GETTIN' BETTER
IN BUCKTOWN *
* I SEE THE PEOPLE
LAYIN' THEIR MONEY DOWN *
[funky music]
*
* WITH NO ONE,
AND I WALK RIGHT IN *
* AND THE SHERIFF
GOT A HOLD ON THE TOWN *
* IT MIGHT TAKE A TANK
TO LOOSEN THE GRIP *
* I MIGHT HAVE TO TEAR IT DOWN
* I DIDN'T COME
FOR A GOOD TIME *
* SINCE I'M HERE,
I'LL GET MINE *
* THE WOMAN OVER THERE
IS MIGHTY FINE *
* SHE'S ALWAYS ON MY MIND *
* THINGS ARE GETTIN' BETTER
IN BUCKTOWN *
* I SEE THE PEOPLE
LAYIN' THEIR MONEY DOWN *
* THINGS ARE GETTIN' BETTER
IN BUCKTOWN *
* I THINK I'M GONNA
HANG AROUND *
* THINGS ARE GETTIN' BETTER
IN BUCKTOWN *
* I SEE THE PEOPLE
LAYIN' THEIR MONEY DOWN *