Brought him back from town with
me, he used to work at the Griffin Bank.
- Well, that ought to be useful.
- Yeah, helped me do a layout of the town.
Well.
Is this the bank?
- Sheriff's office on down the street.
- Over here, eh?
And does this alley go
all the way out of town?
Yeah.
Well, you did a good job
Ira. I feel like I live there.
After we hit that bank,
they'll be glad you don't Sam.
Sam Ward?
Do we need him anymore?
I'll be going then.
All right boys, get your horses.
- Oh Ira, did you find the Keliher place?
- Yeah, it's up at the head of Clear Creek.
- Oh, seven, eight hour ride maybe.
- You sure that Keliher is there?
- Yeah, he's there all right.
- Good.
I'll just pay him a little social
visit when the job is finished.
Meet you back
at the hideout, eh?
- Oh Sam?
- Yeah?
- How long going to be?
- Just long enough to kill Logan Keliher.
- Logan.
- Yes?
- Have you seen Sammy?
- He's helping me.
- I think.
- All right.
Here, let me give you a hand.
You seem awfully
anxious to help.
- We're going to town, aren't we?
- Who said anything about we?
- It's a long trip, I could help you drive.
- Yeah?
Well, you talk your
mother about it?
- She, she doesn't really care.
- But she did say you couldn't go.
- Did she say why?
- She thought I'd be a bother to you.
- But I won't be, I promise I won't.
- Well, I tell you what. You've...
been a big help to me
getting ready and everything.
Maybe I'll just have a
little talk with your mother.
Thanks Dad.
Susan...
you know, I don't know if I'm up to making
this long drive all by myself or not and...
Sammy is offered to go.
- Yes, we discussed before.
- He'd be a lot of help.
Thought you have
enough to worry about.
Town is such a treat for a little kid, even
Griffin after living out here all this time.
Looks like I'm outvoted. All
right Sammy, put your jacket on.
We'll be back sometime tomorrow.
Hope you don't mind both
your men being gone overnight.
Somebody has to
hold down the fort.
I hope everything
goes all right in town.
We don't want move
again, do we Sammy?
Don't worry, we won't.
And what about the money?
- How can you raise...
- I'll manage.
Come on Dad, let's go.
Told you he'd be a lot of help.
Now you be a good boy.
Let's go.
Come on.
- Like to do something for me?
- Yes sir?
You take this list over to
Fishman's store and ask him to fill it.
- You wait for me there.
- All right Dad.
- Sammy?
- Yes sir?
- You like have a licorice stick?
- Sure would.
Tell me Mr. Fishman
I said it'd be all right.
Sorry mister.
- Farmer is in town.
- It's not even Saturday night.
- I'm looking for Goldie.
- Oh, she's upstairs.
Oh, hello Keliher, ain't seen
you in town in some time.
- Hello Diggs.
- Well, now that you're here...
maybe you'd like to
have drink with me.
- You buying?
- Oh well no, I was kind of hoping you would.
I'm sorry old timer.
I'm afraid farming hasn't been much
more profitable than buffalo hunting.
Them two bumming
each other for drinks...
it's a good way for both of
them to stay sober, hey Pink?
Come on farmer, I'll buy you
a drink. Barkeep, set them up..
- There Diggs, you have mine.
- I'm not too proud.
Jeff said he wanted
to buy you a drink.
- I didn't refuse him.
- Then drink it.
Pull in your horns Pink.
Logan is drinking with me.
You will join me?
- As long as you saved my hide Goldie.
- Pink doesn't know you as well as I do.
Joe.
He's the best gun-hand in Griffin,
SO I hire him, doesn't mean I like him.
- Kind of a pushy kid with him.
- Jeff?
When Pink is cold, Jeff sneezes. He'll
learn better, if he lives long enough.
You've been mighty scarce
since you moved here to Griffin.
- Farm keeps a man busy.
- Farming?
Somehow that just
doesn't seem your style.
You changed a lot since the
old days down on the border.
Look different without
that 45 strapped to you.
- Have to admit I miss it now and then.
- Got everybody around here fooled.
Remember the last time
we had a drink together?
Del Rio.
You were with the
Texas Rangers then.
- I thought you'd come in to shut me down.
- No, no.
I had other fish
to fry that night.
- Another one?
- This is not exactly a social call Goldie.
I'm flat broke.
- Oh?
- I owe the bank $500 on that place of mine.
That's a lot of money Logan.
I know that, that's
why I came to you.
Well, I don't carry that
much money with me.
- Wouldn't...
- Goldie...
just tell me, yes or no?
- You wouldn't say it, would you?
- Say what?
I haven't forgotten Logan.
You did me a good turn once but you'd
never mention when you're in trouble.
I expect to get this back.
I expect you will.
You're too late mister.
The bank is closed.
I know they're closed,
but they're still in there.
We're closed.
Come back tomorrow.
I told you, them bankers
sure got it soft, ain't they?
Most of us have
got to work till dark.
- Idiot.
- Somebody looked in the window.
- All right, get going.
- Sheriff, Sheriff Moore.
Let them draw them off.
They're robbing the bank,
help. They're robbing the bank.
Sam.
Who wants to ride in the posse?
Logan?
Logan, is that you?
Sam.
- Where is he?
- He's not here.
Well.
Let me take a good
look at you Susan girl.
Been a long time, hasn't it?
You haven't changed a bit,
you look even better than ever.
- You're wounded.
- Oh, it's nothing, don't worry about it.
- Let me bandage it for you.
- Well, all right.
You always were a
good nurse Susan.
A good wife too,
for that matter.
- Our boy, our son is with Logan?
- Yes.
Six years.
- Guess he's not a baby anymore, is he?
- No, he's a big boy now.
I was hoping to see him.
Sam, he doesn't
know you're his father.
Well, he will, soon enough.
Try to understand Sam.
- Everything is different now.
- Nothing is different Susan, not with me.
SO Logan left you all alone, eh?
Well he, he ought to
know better than that.
A beautiful woman like you shouldn't
be all by herself like that, it's not safe.
- And that's how I lost you, remember?
- You can't really believe that.
Well, it's true, isn't it?
A little sweet talk from Logan
when my back was turned and...
well, you just got a
little mixed up honey.
Sam, you went
away to prison, for life.
You knew they weren't
going to keep me there.
Couple years and I'd had enough,
came out looking for my wife.
Sam, I'm not your wife.
- You knew about the divorce.
- Well now, we won't worry about that.
Look, I understand honey.
This, this thing with Logan
was just a, a handy way out...
for you while I was gone.
Logan had nothing to do with it.
Sam, our marriage was through when you
first started making your way with a gun.
Logan took you when
I was behind bars.
When I couldn't fight for you.
Well, I'm out now and
I'm taking you back.
- It's finished between us.
- Is it Susan?
Let's see if it is.
Well Logan is...
Logan is got a stronger
hold on you than I figured.
- Too bad we don't have more time.
- There'll never be time, not for us.
You'll come around
Susan, when Logan is dead.
I'll be back, you can
count on that, honey.
- He was here.
- Yes.
We drove all night,
I'll put him to bed.
- He came here to kill you.
- Somehow I never really believed he'd try.
He said he'd be back.
We've got to move Logan, we've got to
go some place where he'll never find us.
NO use running.
Besides, I just paid the bank.
We can't stay here now.
He's coming back to kill
you and to take Sammy.
He found us here,
he'd find us anywhere.
Best chance is to see he's
caught and sent back to prison.
Can't they get him without you?
Who knows him as well as I do?
I was praying you'd never
have to use that gun again.
I know.
I hope you don't
have to kill him.
Is the last thing I want to do.
Logan.
Don't take any chances.
I don't want you to kill him,
but if it has to be you or him...
If it comes to that.
I want you to come back.
Oh, I want you to come back.
You fellas shoot, then
ask questions later, en?
- We was certain you was ward.
- I'm sorry to disappoint you.
Say, I've had enough of this
anyway, let's head back for town.
What's the matter Leach?
Beginning to wish you were back
at the saloon, throwing out drunks?
You'd better lay off.
You must be part of Sheriff
Moore's handpicked posse.
Yeah, we are what are
you doing out here all alone?
Where's the rest of
the posse Tucker?
We lost the trail, the sheriff split
us up into bunches to cut sign.
This tracking is supposed to
be your long suit, isn't it Diggs?
I've tracked a sight of them
but this fella ward is might tricky.
- Did you know was Sam Ward we was after?
- Yeah, I knew.
- I'd like to come up against him.
- Maybe you'll get a chance.
Keliher, you never did say
what you was doing way out here.
I was trailing Sam ward.
- That ain't Ward's horse.
- No, I'm riding Ward's horse, he stole mine.
Funny thing he just
happened to stop by your place.
Isn't funny to me.
Good way to get a
bullet in you Lottie.
Something went wrong.
Well, not altogether.
- What happened to the others?
- They won't be back.
My man, Ira...
- What about him?
- He got killed in the getaway.
I want his share of that money.
You sure do come right to
the point, don't you baby eh?
Well? How about it?
- About what?
- About the money.
I want Ira's share,
it's mine now.
Well, you might be selling
out too cheap, Lottie girl.
On?
You got something else in mind?
Ah, maybe.
Just how much did you get?
Enough for you and me to blow
the town of El Paso wide open.
El Paso?
El Paso.
Yeah, I think I'd
like that just fine.
- Won't take me any time to get ready.
- No, no, no, hold on, hold on.
Let's spend a couple of
days getting acquainted, eh?
Yeah, you're not a bad
looking woman Lottie.
Doll you up a little bit there, why you
could hold your own with most any company.
Oh, I bet you know how
to spend money Sam.
Well, now I'll tell you.
- I never been able to save any.
- You know something?
Ira told me I was going to like you
when he talked me into coming up here.
Was he right?-
Well, you didn't grieve
very long, did you?
About as long as he
would've grieved for me.
Yeah, I like that.
You know, a man will always know
where he stands with you Lottie.
Couldn't trail a herd of buffaloes
through this kind of going.
You think there's any
point in looking further?
As long we've gone this far.
I say we're wasting
our time, let's turn back.
How about you and Jeff Pink?
Well, town would look pretty
good to me right about now.
Me too, I've had a
bellyful of this riding blind.
I'm afraid I'll have to agree,
we might as well call it quits.
Diggs...
you know this country
real well, don't you?
Better than most.
All right, let's say you're
an outlaw on the run.
Where's the one place
you wouldn't go from here?
Right up there.
Why not?
Because nothing there
but rocks and rattlesnakes.
Unless maybe you want to
count them murdering Apaches.
They hole up back
in there after a raid.
Sounds like just the kind
of a place Ward would pick.
- That be just a wild goose chase.
- Then why don't you go back?
Because you're too anxious, think
I'll just string along, just in case.
I wish they had gone back.
If they have left, there have
been fewer of us to split the money.
Worry about the reward
after we catch him.
I wasn't thinking
about the reward.
I think I'll wear
my hair piled high.
Maybe an ostrich plume.
And a red satin dress.
Oh yeah, I look good in
red, you like red Sam, eh?
- Sam.
- Yeah.
Oh, you'll be proud of me.
Red satin, hair up and silk.
Nothing but silk
next to my body.
- Oh, I love the feel of silk.
- Yeah, so do I.
Hold it Sam.
Hey, you took me...
by surprise Logan, I didn't have that
much luck when I came looking for you.
About the unluckiest
thing you ever did.
- Now stay over there.
- It's all right Lottie, it's me he wants.
I'll make a deal with you Logan.
You're not exactly in a
position to make a deal.
Give me my gun.
We'll settle this between
us right here and now.
- No.
- You owe me that much.
- I don't owe you anything Sam.
- Give me my gun.
Look, one of us will walk out of
here and that'll be the end of it.
That be easy for you, you
don't have anything to lose. I do.
Turn around.
Lean your head against the wall.
Let's see them.
What about me?
For now you might
stir up a pot of coffee.
Look, I didn't do anything.
I was just waiting here for them
to come back, now that's no crime.
We'll let the law decide that.
- Watch that arm, I took a slug in it.
- I know, I put it there.
You were in Griffin?
I wish I had seen you.
I saw you plain enough after my
first bullet dropped you, now sit down.
Why didn't you shoot me again?
Ah, you felt guilty.
Sure, you felt guilty about
stealing my wife and kid.
No.
We were friends once Sam.
- It's not easy to shoot an old friend.
- Friends?
That's a long way back Logan, and
I've got one big advantage over you.
You won't kill me
unless you have to.
I won't hesitate one
second about killing you.
- So you got him all by yourself.
- Good going Keliher.
- Man can't have no privacy anywhere.
- Hey Pink, look what we got here.
Turn around honey,
let's have a look at you.
I said turn around.
Say, you're a looker, eh?
You can keep my share of the
reward fellas, I'll take this instead.
- Take your hands off of me.
- Leave her alone.
- What is to you?
- I said leave her alone.
You giving the orders
from now on Keliher?
I'm giving the orders.
- How come?
- After all, he took ward.
Yeah, that's right, he did.
All right Jeff, leave her alone.
Did you find the money?
I didn't even look for it,
figured I have plenty of help.
You found ward easy enough.
- I'll make him tell where it is.
- You make me tell?
- You won't get it out of him like that.
- I'll bet she knows where is hid.
- No.
- She knows, all right.
Just give me a minute with her.
What's the matter with you fellas
anyway, talking about torturing people?
The money can't
be that hard to find.
- Well, ain't back there.
- Maybe hid it outside.
Let's start looking for it then.
Hey old timer, come here.
You better protect
your interest, eh?
They're sure anxious
about that bank money.
Yeah, too anxious.
I'm sure glad
you're along Tucker.
I'll do what I can.
You got enough
to feed this bunch?
Then start fixing.
I have to get wood.
Go ahead.
- You wasting time Sam.
- Oh, I'm in no hurry.
My chances are looking
better by the minute.
I'd say your chances are mighty slim
unless you say where the money is.
- You want them to beat it out of you?
- I'm not worried Logan.
As long I got you here to protect
me, from those honest citizens.
It's in the fireplace,
the fireplace.
- I said I could make her talk.
- Leach...
- I see you found it.
- He almost got away.
- How much you get?
- I don't know yet.
Come on, we'll give
you a hand with it.
I was hoping that fight out there
would've lasted a little longer.
- So I noticed.
- That's sweet bunch you got there.
- I didn't pick them.
- Well, maybe you should've boy.
More than 20,000.
I don't think I've ever seen
that much in one pile before.
This would buy a high
old time back in Griffin.
Boys, boys...
There's no reason you
shouldn't keep that money.
Why sure, let, let me go...
and nobody back in Griffin ever need
know that you found me or the money.
That's kind of an
interesting thought.
Yeah, it's worth
considering all right.
There's only one thing wrong
with it, we can't trust you.
Now if you were dead,
we'd be home free.
We could tell them back in
Griffin that we had to Kill...
ward and that we
couldn't find the money.
- What about her?
- She'd tell the whole thing.
We'll get rid of her too.
Hold on, killing ward is one thing
but I ain't for murdering no woman.
You don't have to
do it, I'll take care of it.
I killed many a squaw Indian
fighting, 'Tain't no different.
That money is going back to
Griffin, these two are going with it.
I don't think you can
stop us, we've got Diggs.
Now Jeff here is a little squeamish but when
it comes right down to it, he'll back me.
- You might have Tucker on your side.
- Of course I stand behind Keliher.
That's cold blooded
murder you're talking about.
Well, I kind of figured
you'd see it that way.
Leach, I don't imagine
you're quite so high minded.
Sure ain't.
You like the odds?
We got callers, Apaches.
Most likely scouts
for a raiding party.
We can make a mighty
tempting target there.
- Let's get them before they get away.
- No.
You shoot and be a war
party down here no time.
We can't just
wait till they hit.
Afraid you're right, turn
this place into a graveyard.
I think we better start act like
we don't know they're out there.
And after dark
can try slip away.
You think he's right about
that Apache war party?
When you go, leave me here.
I'd as soon take my chances with
those Apaches as with this bunch.
Not a very good
bet either way Sam.
Tie my hands in front here,
will you? I can ride a lot better.
Yeah and you can grab a gun
a lot better too, couldn't you?
Why Logan, you know
me better than that.
- I'll take my own horse back.
- Oh, I thought was a fair trade.
I didn't, Leach,
give him a hand.
Stick with me, I'll
look out for you.
Over against that ledge, quick.
- What did you see?
- Nothing.
The best thing
you could've seen.
They're probably hitting
the cabin about now.
I wouldn't have given a plugged
nickel for our chances last night.
How much you think they'll be worth after
them Indians find out they've been tricked?
I'm plumb wore out, when
you figuring on stopping?
- Well, not here.
- That girl needs some rest.
Those Apaches catch up with
us, she'll get a good long rest.
This will have to do.
That Keliher,
that Keliher, he...
- sure pushes hard, doesn't he?
- Yeah, too hard.
You want me to help you
find a place to bed down?
No, thanks. I'll...
All right.
All right Sam, bail off.
You better post a lookout, I know
them Apaches, they ain't give up.
I'll take the first watch, whoever
is on guard keeps an eye on Ward.
You and ward seem
uncommon friendly.
In case you get any ideas, remember
I sleep lighter than a night owl.
Stay awake all night if you
want to, tie these horses off.
NO, no, no, not now. Later.
I'll come to you.
You get a strange sense of humor
Sam, then you always did have.
NO, no, I was just remembering
that night on the Concho...
when we were in the Rangers
together, remember that night?
- Yeah, I remember it.
- Yeah, was Comanche country.
Just the two of us
on guard that night.
All those shadows out there.
Yeah, we were a little edgy.
Oh Captain
Roberts, he, he said...
he said, the Comanches never,
never strike at night, remember?
Yeah, yeah well, just when we getting
a little comfort from that thought...
those Comanches hit us, boy they came
hollering and veiling in out of the night.
Scared us half to death.
Yeah, we had quite a
fight on our hands that night.
Oh Logan, Logan...
in those days I thought more of
you than anybody in the whole world.
I would've put my
life in your hands.
Matter of fact, I did.
Well, it just goes to show you
how wrong you can be about people.
First time I get in a little trouble, first
time I get on the wrong side of the law...
you turn against me.
Well, I haven't trust
in anybody since.
I didn't turn on you Sam.
I even quit the Rangers so
wouldn't have to go after you.
You quit the Rangers so you
could go after my wife and kid.
That's not true.
Sam, you left that girl broke
and homeless with a baby to raise.
Well, that don't give you no
license to go out, stealing them.
We didn't even think about
getting married the first I...
felt the responsibility
because you were my friend.
A responsibility I
don't think you ever felt.
Logan, everything
that I ever did...
I did for them and their sake.
Shooting a man and...
going to prison for life is not
exactly the right way to raise a family.
Well, I didn't mean to shoot that
man, I mean, not the first one anyway.
And then, after I, I broke out well, I had
no choice but to go on making it with my gun.
You didn't have to
come looking for me.
Oh yes, I did Logan.
That's the one
thing I did have to do.
There's something you
better get straight Sam.
Susan is my wife
now and I love her.
And Sammy is my son, not yours,
was only a baby when you left.
All these years, he's had
my love and I've had his.
It's not enough just
to plant the seed Sam.
The real father is the man who
gives his whole life to a child.
I'm the father, Sammy is
my flesh, he's my blood.
And I'm going to kill you
for taking him away from me.
No, not here, over there
where they can't see us.
Come on.
All right, let's
get ready to ride.
On Ward jumping you like that kind of sets
my mind at ease about a couple of things.
Well, now you know.
This yours?
- You tricked me, you dirty little...
- No, I didn't, let me got.
- You were supposed to be guarding him.
- Stop crowding me or I'll make you wish...
- Turned west here.
- He's heading right back the way he came.
Not anymore.
Hi boys.
You must be getting to
like that horse of mine Sam.
Nice of you to bring
him back this time.
Yeah, well I figured you'd
appreciate that, ain't it?
Brought back a mess
of Apaches to boot.
- Thought you preferred those Indians to us.
- No, I changed my mind.
There's a place to
stand them off up ahead.
Rifle Sam.
What's the matter boy? Don't
like the way I shoot Apaches?
Yeah, you shoot Apaches fine.
- We did it.
- We whipped them.
- You don't know much about Indians, do you?
- Think they'll be back?
They'll be back all right, it's
a matter of when and how.
Keep an eye on him.
Why don't we try and get out
of here while we got the chance?
Yeah sure, those Apaches
would like that just fine.
I'll take my chances right here.
Everything all right back here?
- Yeah, I guess so, are they gone?
- For now.
- Look, I can use a gun if I have to.
- We may need you.
- Do we have much chance?
- We'll give them a fight.
- Guess you're safe enough here.
- Logan...
I'm sorry about the knife.
- That was last night.
- No.
I didn't know Sam was
going to try to kill you.
You know Sam very well, do you?
I do now.
He's just like all
other men, using me.
Sure made it sound good though.
Promised he'd take me to
El Paso, dress me in silk...
stay at the best hotel.
Oh yeah, we had
a lot of fine plans.
Now, if I even get out of this alive,
probably wind up going to prison.
Maybe not, no one needs
to know about that knife.
Thanks Logan.
You know, I've always thought
that all men were the same.
But if I get out of this alive
and get another chance, I...
Diggs, stay there.
Watch that ledge,
I'll try to draw him out.
Lottie.
I, I feel, I feel sort of
naked without my gun.
It won't take long to dress
you when those Apaches hit.
You know Logan, I get the
feeling that you don't trust me.
Should 1?
We ought to get out of here
while we still got the time.
Well, we ought to.
We won't stand a chance in
here when they come back.
How much of a chance you
think we'll stand out there?
Leach getting a little edgy?
Man ought to learn to face
death without whimpering.
Maybe is the waiting
that's getting to him.
Well, that's the
hard part all right.
But when they do come,
then a man is really alive.
Diggs, you know I get the
feeling you kind of like this.
'Tain't that so much, but
life sort of pass this by.
Now fighting Indians, well, that
makes us of some use again.
It's good to know that
old gun is on my side.
Well, you're not a bad fella Keliher,
the way they come nowadays anyway.
Just a mite of education
would straighten you right out.
Nobody's gun is ever on anybody's
side out of plain kindness of heart.
Man's nature is too
pure cursed for that.
I can't give you an
argument about that just now.
Way I see it, everybody is out after
everybody else hide, one way or another.
- Who are you looking to skin out Diggs?
- Nobody, unless he stands in my way.
Sort of what I figured.
Tucker.
- Now, about that bank money.
- Hey Diggs, I'm glad you brought that up.
You know, it's funny I'd all
most forgotten about the money.
You know, you didn't have
quite the right attitude when we...
talked about it
back at the cabin.
But then, your objection
is been taken care of.
Tucker of course, he
was against killing ward.
He won't care now.
Hey Leach, you haven't
changed your mind, have you?
No.
That's it, then. we'll shoot
Ward and split the money.
Let's see, there's
five of us left.
- Comes to $4,000 a piece.
- Aren't you hurrying things a little bit?
Keliher hasn't agreed
to come in with us.
Oh, he'll come along
with it, won't you Keliher?
There's four of us against you.
You're damned if you do
and damned if you don't.
All right, 4,000 dollars looks
pretty big to me right now.
But we better hang onto ward for a
while longer, came in handy this morning.
Oh, we'll leave him here with
them, he'd just be dead weight for us.
Not if we run into
those Apaches again.
He's right, we'll keep Ward
until we get out of Indian country.
- So now the Indians are saving my life, eh?
- In front.
All right, get down.
Without the rifle.
Carrying the two of us this horse
will never make it in to Griffin.
Griffin? We'd be better off if we
headed in the opposite direction.
With that old fox Diggs on our trail,
doesn't matter which direction we hit.
- If we make it to Griffin, we'll be safe.
- Safe?
Well, that don't
exactly fit into my plan.
You know Logan, you're such a good friend,
aren't you? That you're going to save me...
- for a hanging, eh?
- You made your own bed Sam.
- Well, what you going to do? Lynch me?
- No, less you try to get away.
I'm to let you lynch yourself.
Now move out.
Go on.
Hold up Sam.
You ought to be played
out enough by now.
- The rope is sawing my head Off.
- Turn around.
Well, it looks like we're
on the same side again.
The first things
first, for both of us.
We'll never be able
to stand them off here.
Work higher.
Sam?
I was going to kill you.
You make up your mind to do
something, you sure are bullheaded.
How bad is it?
Probably live to get
another chance at me.
I'll get the horse.
- Leave me here.
- No.
- You'd be taking a corpse back.
- You can make it as far as my place.
I'll fix up the wagon and
take you in from there.
Talk about being bullheaded.
Logan.
I've got Sam out there.
- He's alive?
- Just barely.
I didn't shoot him.
- Dad, Dad.
- Boy.
Come here.
- Come on boy.
- Sam might tell him.
Let me take a look at you son.
You don't know me, do you son?
Are you the man Dad
was after, Sam ward?
- My name is Sam too.
- I know.
Is it true you killed 20
men? A kid in town said so.
How many then?
Too many.
You bad hurt mister?
- Yeah, I'm bad hurt all right?
- Could I help you?
- Could you get me some water?
- Sure.
Thank you Sam.
Dad, Dad.
- He's hurt Dad.
- Yeah, I know.
Fix a bed in the wagon.
Sammy, you help your mother.
- You ready to travel? Come on.
- I'll do it.
You're...
You're doing a good job...
Logan with my...
with your son.
Yeah...
with our son.