Hey, Mom?
What's up, I'm working.
Get out. Art!
You just won five bucks!
You finally got a real job?
Sound design is a real job.
You re actually a
professional sound designer?
Not exactly, I'm still
doing foley. But I'm
getting paid this time!
I'm so proud of you!
It's going in the church
bulletin. What's it called?
It's an indie movie, it probably
won't come to theatres near you.
You probably won't see it.
You know what, I've actually
really gotta finish this. So I'll call
you back later okay love you, bye!
JUNE, ADRIFT
Subrip: Pix
Hurry Barkley.
You will be late for class.
Thanks, Babcia.
You want me to clock
you in, it's gonna cost ya!
Rachel, you
didn't have to do that!
It wasn't any trouble.
To pack up my classroom?
You already had to pack up yours!
I wanted to make sure
you didn't have any excuses
not to go on
your date with Mark.
You set me up
on a date with Mark?
No, I can't, I couldn't,
he's so cute!
It'll be great.
I still have to find a
summer home for that'stupid turtle.
I sent your class turtle
home with Benny Schwartzman.
And there's this
UPS package on my desk
that I still need to mail.
I saw it! Already mailed it.
My god. Really?
That is amazing. Rach,
st... I mean, but wait, don't... I
ught that you liked Mark?
I couldn't possibly date
anyone ht now. I'm way too busy.
I don't know what my mom is
elling people, but I have a job!
Have you eaten yet today?
and I don't need her friends
to me up on pity dates, you know?
Do you have something
I can put water in?
On top of the fridge.
Contrary to popular belief,
am not the ideal match for all
sement-dwelling mouth-breathers.
Do you ever open your mail?
Yeah, I've been busy this week.
This is from December.
From your parents?
I'm getting to it,
it's on my to-do list.
She was trying to hook me up
with an unemployed
thirty six year old who still
hasn't finished undergrad.
Em, sorry about your day.
Merry Christmas
friends and family!
This year has brought us many
blessings. Arthur and I are
nning for our 60 day summer
ise to Australia. Anchors away!
Hannah and her wonderful
husband Brandon
have secured political asylum
for 112 more Sudanese refugees.
So proud of you two.
A little birdy told us
Kent and Amy are
expecting some good news!
Congratulations you guys.
Meanwhile, Emma is still
trying to do the LA thing!
We re all pullin for ya, but
remember, we still haven't
packed up your bedroom.
You have options. They included
you in the letter this year.
You suck.
This is Kasia, I call
your mother five times.
I cannot stay open for this.
Come pick up her order now.
Shit.
So hot right now.
What did I say?
No talking.
So hot! So hot!
Shut the door!
Get the keys!
They re not here! Help me look!
Dude, I'm looking for my pants!
Fuuu...
Hey, so, what
are you up to tomorrow?
I'm totally free;
tomorrow's my only day off.
Sweet, I need
you to cover my shift.
Wait, I ve never
worked in lumber before!
That's fine, you're mexican,
you can do it, right? Lo siento.
You missed dinner.
You are better than this.
I'm sorry.
Hey, mom, you know it is
three in the morning here, right?
I know you weren't sleeping.
True.
Well, I hate to lose
it because it's the'source
of some of my best material,
but it's time.
Time for what, mom?
It's time to throw out the boat.
What?
We re leaving tomorrow for
our trip so I'm clearing out the
garage for the July renters.
Plus. You promised me
if you didn't fix it by the time
you were twenty five
I could get rid of it.
Wait... I really want
to finish it though.
You re never
gonna get around to it.
Seriously, I will finish it
the next time I am out there.
Emma, I don't want to have
that boat in my garage for another
eight years. It's going out by
the bins for next Tuesday's
trash pickup. End of story.
Okay.
Love you!
Love you too, mom.
Where is my shirt?
Where is the shirt? Every time,
I cannot find it.
I am looking for it,
it was here, now it's not here!
In the kitchen.
Looking for... Thank you!
You could have said...
you did it for me! Love you!
English! In this house!
She is graduating!
Glue it!
I'm taking the flag!
I am taking the flag!
I made this for you. For today.
Babcia!
Barkley, hurry up in there,
your mother needs to get ready.
We leave for commencement
in thirty minutes!
I dropped out.
What? I cannot hear you,
your mother needs to peepee.
Tata, I dropped out.
What? What.
Barkley, open the door.
Barkley, you're
trying my patience!
Okay, I'm not angry,
I just want to talk,
okay, okay, okay, just
open the damn door!
What is going on,
Barkley, we are leaving soon.
She's not graduating!
She's not graduating?
I left school, Mama.
What?
She is graduating!
That's not how it works!
I left three months ago!
Where have you been going
every day for that time!
Ace hardware?
Open the goddamn door, come
out here and tell it to my face!
How could you do it to us?
I'm not happy!
Who gives shit! You
don't work to be happy,
you work to feed your family,
to put roof over your head!
Jesus, you love engineering,
you were on the top in your class!
Just because you
re good at something
doesn't mean you
like it, I hated it!
Okay, so just tell me,
what are you going to do?
I don't know!
She doesn't know.
What a beautiful plan!
Sleep with strange men,
don't worry about it,
just have fun, that's all
that's important!
I'm getting the'screwdriver!
Open... open it!
I didn't know you
made the decision to sell.
Yeah, it
seemed like the right time.
With you and Chris outta the
house it's time to downsize.
Okay, well, I can get
a plane ticket right away,
so I can come help you
fix up the place for buyers.
Honey, I ve been working
on the place for months. It's all done.
Okay, well, I
can help you pack up.
I got it.
How about I...
Honey, it is under
control. Do not rearrange your plans
on my account. You do you
this summer. Okay? I love you.
Love you.
Bye sweetie.
Hey, why so tense, doll?
Loved that last cut.
Really, thanks
for all the great work
you're doin on
Take It In The Aft.
No problem, happy
to have the work.
Great, cuz we got more for ya,
Freckles. Listen, as you know,
everyone at Beat Around
The Bush Productions
is really hopin to
hit it outta the park on this
one, we really wanna take it to
the next tier of the adult film
industry and we need
this to be a masterpiece.
Got it. Well, I