Have a shot, kid.
A little nerve tonic.
I'm not nervous, Cragie.
I just gotta take a leak.
- Then do it now.
- On some poor bastard's grave?
What do you give a shit?
If someone was smart, they'd rip out
these graves and plant tomatoes.
These people are no good.
They're dead.
Say, hey, Cub fans.
Baby, I sure hope
you all are down there...
'cause we got the big game today.
Today is our day, baby.
Dig this, man.
All you cats on the home team,
listen up.
Spider's getting ready
to make the big play.
If you mothers drop that ball,
the Spider's--
- What's happening, Doc?
- There you are.
You take too fucking long.
Every day you're late.
- Get your ass in the car.
-  I got everything we need.
- Got a million places to go.
-  Let's get out of here.
- They'll be waiting.
- Okay, home team, ready in the bullpen.
Covering you, shortstop.
Double play. We'll get the nut.
- Center's in.
- Where's Cragie?
- Talk to me, left field.
- Damn it. Left field is in position.
Okay, guys,
run around first base.
- Double play, you got them in sight?
-  Yeah, we got the eyes on them.
- He's heading for the alley.
-  What the fuck is this?
I get up early. This guy has my nose
in his pocket at 6:30 in the morning.
I come around these funky
neighborhoods. I'm sick of it.
I've been on the phone three days.
I'm glad to get out, though.
You can't tell nobody
about this kind of stress.
How's somebody gonna relate?
All right, boys, here we go.
Nice and easy.
Leave a space
for the good guys.
I ain't ever letting her
out of my sight.
This is lovely. Look at this.
The other guys went to Brazil.
Took 12 people for a party.
This is my vacation. Ain't this nice?
- Spider, this ain't my style.
-  I can dig it, baby.
It's too much like real work
even for me.
You'll have everything you want
in two hours. All the action you need.
Trick or treat, smell my feet.
Come on, baby.
- Back off.
- Come on, baby.
- Do your thing, Pancho.
- Hey, man, we're clean.
- You think we're goddamn fools?
- Watch it.
- Don't you know these guys, Spider?
- We ought to get married.
We just want to do a little business.
Does this guy speak English?
-  Fuck, this is routine.
-  I can't believe this.
- Do this every fucking time.
- I should have taken a Valium.
Found you a present.
These things will test your head.
- I know these people, trust me.
I like the way it sounds.
Where's that money?
That's mine until it's yours.
I don't like people
that don't want to shake my hand.
I don't care where they come from.
I don't give a fuck what they represent.
I don't dig motherfuckers
that don't shake my hand.
- Come on, Eenie. Move your ass.
- What are those guys up to?
They're going to work.
What do you think?
- Let's go.
-  At this hour?
Don't worry about it.
Let it roll.
They got a hard-ass for a boss,
like us.
I just want to get out of here
real quick with my deal...
and I want to find out
what's going on here today.
Holy Christ.
Told you this was
the right place.
Scares me shitless.
- Tell him that's a nice decoration.
- Watch it.
Cool it, man.
Forget about that man's old lady.
Give me a break, man.
- Victor's got the best.
- The best.
You Comacho dudes are too much.
I can't believe you guys.
This really looks all right.
I feel some rocks up in here.
- Gonna make a lot of people very happy.
-  Damn right it's good.
By the numbers.
I know they got a good reputation.
I'm just doing this because...
my people expect me to do this.
I'm not trying to insult the guy.
He said you got
diarrhea of the mouth, baby.
Tell him that's too bad.
I thought he had more class than that.
That's the color I need.
Let's go.
How's that?
Everybody, get ready.
Right field is clear
if those painters are out of the way.
What are you talking about?
A crew of painters
went into the building next door.
- They're gonna wreck that building.
- Call them in.
- Let's move! Move!
Like I told you, Vic,
you can always depend on the Spider.
Go!
Get the door, Cragie.
Move it!
The plank! Let's go! Out!
Sh.
In the bag!
Get it in there!
Get the girl!
Let's get going! Come on!
Forget him!
We're out of here!
-  Got one in the hallway!
-  Up against the wall. Let's go.
They're going out the front!
Come on! Come on!
- Shit!
- Just get in here!
- Go, go, go!
Motherfucking son of a bitch!
Damn it!
Cragie! Cragie?
It's okay. I got the son of a bitch.
Cover the stairs.
Jesus.
Citywide units,
we have an officer shot.
Request for additional ambulances.
Several gunshot victims.
Use caution.
There are plainclothes units
on the scene. Zone-free radio.
- Damn.
I told you to stay in there.
- Take it easy, Kopalas.
- Sarge--
The kid didn't dust him.
I did. Him or me, Sarge.
The kid saw the whole thing.
Tell him, Nick.
Yeah, that's what happened.
Stay here, Cragie.
Keep this clear.
Did you Miranda that guy?
Come on, don't do that.
Do you know how much these things cost?
Eddie, listen to this.
A bait shop.
We get some worms, some minnows.
We don't even have to get real worms.
We'll get those rubber ones.
You goddamn Dr. Jekyl!
He's a butcher.
You know, Sarge, I don't think
these guys know who their friends are.
I'm tired of this shit.
Efren, what's gonna happen to you
when Luis comes up from Bogota, huh?
I'll tell you what will happen.
Your asses will be freeze-dried
and fried. Your goose is cooked.
You must know who did it!
Who'd you fuck over lately?
- Luis ain't gonna like it--
You want a tune-up, fuckface?
Sarge, you know why a Comacho
is like a cue ball?
The harder you hit them, the better
the English gets. You want to play pool?
Save it, Brennan.
Book them.
Come on, talk to me.
What do you know?
- What about Vito and Eenie?
-  Keep your eyes closed.
- Come on.
Come on.
-  Yeah. All right.
- Ready?
Now open.
Oh!
- Happy birthday, Mom.
- I'm so glad you're here.
- Happy birthday, Molly.
- Molly.
Molly, come here. Come on.
Pack me a bag for the lake.
Come on, I'm in a hurry!
- But why?
- Business.
Move. Do what I tell you.
Papa.
- Don't do it, Mama.
- Hey, none of your lip today!
I cannot believe you.
Nothing's changed.
Today is Mom's birthday.
She deserves better than this,
- and so do we.
Tony, sorry I'm late.
Got stuck in traffic.
Picked up something nice.
Fucking Victor Comacho's alive.
Vito and Eenie are dead.
Jesus Christ.
You pulled that hit?
-  Don't go, Diana.
- I can't stay here, Grandma.
You put somebody on the house,
and you look after her.
You gone fucking crazy?
You're starting a war.
You're putting the whole outfit
on the line.
They're probably out looking
to start your uncle right now.
Keep your mouth shut! What Mr. Scalese
don't know, won't hurt him!
Happy birthday.
Cragie, you're assigned to headquarters
until the hearing.
Hearing?
Who called for a hearing?
That goddamn little punk tried
to shoot me in the back!
Sit down.
-  Lucy Partida.
- That Commie piece of shit?
Shut up! Partida demanded
a formal hearing. You'll be under oath.
The department will provide you
with a lawyer unless you got one.
A Citizens Review Board member
is waiting to talk to you.
Doesn't sound like
you've got anything to worry about.
Kopalas, you work with Cusack
until this is over.
Yes, sir.
All right, that will be all.
Thank you, sir.
- Where did they take Dorato?
- County. He'll be okay.
Listen, I don't have time
to nursemaid a rookie.
- I don't need a partner.
- That's right.
You don't need a partner.
You need a goddamn keeper!
Jesus Christ, how do I explain
this one downtown?
We gave you 600 man-hours.
You took a month to plan the thing,
and what do you have to show for it?
Eight bodies, one dead informant,
one of my best men shot!
You'll have me back on the beat,
busting perverts in the park.
We've got a bigger problem.
This Luis Comacho is crazy.
He won't take this lying down.
That's all I need:
a goddamn war.
What about this business
with Cragie?
You know what I think of Cragie.
All right,
I'll deal with downtown.
You find out who burned
the Comachos before they do.
Kates.
Eddie, you had a good setup.
Too bad it went to hell.
Yeah.
Luis, the war does no good
for any of us.
It can only make what's bad
worse.
Get them out of here,
and fix them up.
I want them beautiful
for their mother.
My brothers,
I promise you blood for blood.
How you doing, Sarge?
I really appreciate your help.
It's quite all right.
It's so overwhelming.
Hey, I'd like to talk to you.
One day I would like
to give you a gift...
of a Colombian necktie.
Very special.
You slit the throat,
pull out the tongue.
And on you,
it would look beautiful.
Why don't you give it to me
right now?
Come. We're running late.
Eddie, you better grow eyes
in the back of your head.
Come on! Good shot again.
That's it.
Keep going. Keep it up.
- Come on. Good combination.
Come on, Eddie.
Look out.
Come on. Again.
He's running.
- Shit! Ah, man.
- You okay?
Out of my way, you side of beef.
Hey, partner.
I'm all right, man.
- How's the foot?
-  Swinging. Listen to this.
Two g's, we open up a beef
and sausage stand outside Wrigley Field.
You dish out the beef.
I take in the cash.
Free games.
I have a contact downtown.
How can we watch the games
if we're hawking hot dogs?
I never thought of that.
Davis, I want
to have a word with you, man.
Amano, when you're through playing
with that, I want to talk to you.
Joey, I want you to
help me get some signatures
- on this petition for Cragie.
-  Yeah, no problem.
I figured
on the 14th at lunchtime.
Sure.
Beautiful.
Gus, put that thing down
and sit up for a minute.
I want you to sign this.
It's for Cragie. All right?
Attention all senior personnel.
There will be a demonstration
of the Prowler tactical assist robot...
at 1600 hours.
- Your attendance is required.
- Good shot, Eddie.
Cusack, how about taking the gloves off
long enough to sign this for Cragie?
- Is it about the hearing?
-  You bet.
- I pass.
- What the fuck's the matter with you?
He's burned out, Brennan.
You know it.
Get off your high horse.
He made a couple mistakes.
The man was a hero.
What do a bunch of civilians know...
about coming up some shithouse staircase
scared out of your shorts?
They only know
we're supposed to protect them.
If Cragie doesn't get off the streets,
he'll kill somebody else...
or he'll get somebody killed.
Maybe even you, Brennan.
Thanks a lot, Sarge.
You're a real prince.
Here we go.
Come on, good shot.
Come on, one more time,
Eddie.
The Prowler's
standard weapons complement...
includes one recoilless rifle...
two Mark-19 grenade launchers...
and twin 50-caliber machine guns.
I have sufficient firepower
to neutralize...
a wide variety
of security threats.
As you can see, this lightweight
handheld control unit enables you...
to direct my movements...
while simultaneously operating
the various weapons systems...
in manual or full-automatic mode.
In full-automatic mode, my infrared
heat sensors and Doppler radar...
mean that I am able to acquire
moving targets at night...
without assistance
from the operator.
That concludes
the program demonstration.
Now our factory representative
will discuss the features...
of the simplified Mark-2
handheld control system.
After the gyros are locked...
any movement of the hand controller
is duplicated by the Prowler.
The simple control system means even
semiskilled employees can operate--
He's talking about you, Cusack,
so pay attention.
You've all got to qualify on this.
It's the future.
As they say,
even a child can operate it.
You're looking at the perfect cop.
The damn thing follows orders.
Another gun without a brain.
The machine guns can be linked to
the laser range and guidance system...
for target orientation.
If the commander would like
to pick someone to elude Prowler...
I'll show you
our target acquisition system.
Halt. Police.
Throw down your weapon.
We will not harm you. Please place
your hands above your head.
- Drop it.
- You are under arrest.
Please do not resist.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Eenie Verona
is the gentleman's name.
Looks like you did
a hell of a job on him.
- Know him?
- Yeah, he's just a punk thief.
- Looks like he graduated.
- He sure flunked house painting.
He had an uncle.
Served time together.
What the hell's his name?
- Gagleoni?
- Gamiani.
Gamiani. I think we should
get to know him better.
This Gamiani
is a real swinger, huh?
- Good-bye.
- Take it easy, baby.
I'll be back real quick.
Here we go.
He's the most active one.
He's got great eyes, doesn't he?
- What about the lion over there?
- Yeah.
Look at that one
standing up by the cage.
He's trying to figure out
what we're doing.
- Yeah.
His pretty white breast.
Isn't that pretty?
Is that a leopard?
- I'll be back in a second, okay?
- Okay.
Kind of young for that old guy,
don't you think?
What's going on?
Eddie, this isn't panning out.
Why don't you watch, kid?
Learn something.
- What are you doing here?
- Your papa worries.
Get out of here, Lou,
and leave me alone.
Come on.
Let's go see the ducks.
I don't want to see the ducks.
What's wrong with ducks?
Yeah, come on.
-  Hey!
- Hi!
Hey, guys!
Diana, thanks again!
-  What's so funny?
Enough already.
We're following them,
they're following her...
and nobody knows nothing.
-  Come on.
Let's find out something.
Stay here.
God.
- How are you?
- Congratulations.
I'm glad you made it.
Excuse me, this is Mrs. Wilson.
- This is my friend, Diana.
- Nice to meet you.
- This must be a lucky break then.
-  It is.
I just sold my first piece
to Mrs. Wilson here.
Terrific.
I like your new stuff.
Especially the dead dog series.
When did you do that? It's great.
Hello. Would you like
some hors d'oeuvres?
- Bye-bye.
- Thanks for stopping by.
I'll see you downstairs later.
He is really a character.
She's a great girl.
I'd love to help.
We should set up a date,
and I'll help you hang it.
I'd be delighted.
Excuse me.
Who was that girl you were talking to
in the black slacks?
- I think I know her.
- Diana Luna.
- You understand it?
- Sure. Don't you?
Mm-mm.
I'm Eddie Cusack.
- I'd make it Eddie the cop.
- That obvious, huh?
Listen, I don't know where my father is,
and I don't give a damn.
I have nothing to do
with my father's business...
Uncle Scalese's business
or any of it.
So why don't you leave me alone?
It was nice meeting you.
I thought I was feeling good,
but--
Happy? Whoo!
You bet!
- Can I use your phone?
- Yeah. Right over there.
Whoo!
Kobas, this is Sergeant Cusack.
I want a team to cover a house
on the southwest side.
Luna. L-u-n-a. Anthony.
Yeah, Crazy Tony Luna.
I don't know if he's around,
but if he shows up bring him in.
Thanks.
Catch you later.
That's a very nice choice.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, you comfortable?
They're wasting the show.
- Tony's not even in town.
- They'll get the word.
Mrs. Luna,
come away from the window.
- How about yourself?
- Don't worry about me.
- I'll take care of him.
- Take care.
Wait here.
- I can back you up.
- Stay by the radio.
-  Felix, you all right?
- Yeah, yeah.
Get me yesterday's numbers
on Phoenix, huh?
What are you doing here?
Off, asshole.
Cusack.
The modern age's answer
to the crystal ball.
Marvelous,
if you know how to read it.
If you've got some extra cash,
buy oranges.
The price is low, and I can promise you
there will be a trucking strike.
Is that a bribe, Mr. Scalese?
It's a prediction.
Nah.
I wouldn't try
to bribe Eddie Cusack.
They tell me you're incorruptible,
untarnished.
I hear they call you Stainless Steel
on the street.
Me? I think you're
a pain in the ass.
I'm looking for one
of your nephews.
Tony Luna.
Good-bye, Mr. Cusack.
There's a shitstorm coming, old man,
and you can stop it.
Good-bye, Mr. Cusack.
- Nobody talks, right?
- That's right, Sergeant.
Just like the cops.
Just like the Comachos.
Nobody talks.
I'll find Tony Luna...
and I'll nail his ass
and anyone else connected to him.
- You got that?
- You punk!
Nobody threatens me.
It's not a threat.
Ohh!
It's a prediction.
Roger, Homicide.
We're at Lincoln Park Conservatory.
Victim is a male Caucasian.
Multiple knife wounds.
Coroner's on the scene.
Request for laboratory backup.
Tony Luna's bagman.
They call that a Colombian necktie.
They found Tony's restaurant manager
hanging from a meat hook in the kitchen.
Looked like someone tried
to carve a canoe out of him.
Tony's used car lot on Ashland
is burning as we speak.
- Head salesman is fried zucchini.
-  Jesus.
It's starting.
- Let's go.
-  Good morning, Mrs. Luna.
- Good morning.
Don't the eggplants
look wonderful?
They're all over
the place;
in the house and out in the street.
Looks like a war zone.
-  How many victims, 10-21?
- Five so far.
Four adult females, one adult male;
all Caucasian.
This is Cusack. Was there a girl,
late teens, brownish hair?
Negative. We got four adult
females pretty chewed up.
The youngest looks about 40.
What kind of people
are these guys?
What's it about?
I'm not going.
I don't have to go.
Your mother got killed.
Take it easy.
Just put your jacket on.
Let's get out of here.
Stick with me.
Run.
Stay here.
Cut the chica.
Angel!
Let her go.
Take out your weapons.
Left hand.
Up against the wall.
Move it!
You heard me, Angel.
Diana, come here.
- Back!
Let her go.
Eddie!
Come on!
Wait.
Whoa.
-  Angel!
One more step,
I'll cut her head off!
Give it up.
Get your ass up.
Shit!
No! No!
Is it true?
Yeah.
Keep your goddamn pants on.
Eddie, what the hell is going on?
Come on in.
Fred Pirelli, Diana Luna.
Hi, kid.
She won't go into protective custody,
and I couldn't leave her alone.
I hate putting you on the spot
like this.
I spent 30 years "on the spot."
Can you put her up
until I find her old man?
Whatever you need.
Brennan, I heard you're
gonna retire when you sober up.
In that case, I'll never retire.
Dorato, you only have to buy one boot.
You're getting off cheap.
Are you serious?
I'm sick about it.
These boots were handmade in Italy.
They cost me 17.50...
- with the police discount.
Hey, Eddie.
Yeah, it's me.
Yeah.
Why don't you come by
and tip a few?
Come on. Come on.
Have a few beers with me.
It will do you good.
- Aw, come--
Do I know--?
I know it's late.
Hey, Eddie,
I have to talk to you.
Yeah, at Mike's.
All right, great.
Thanks, pal.
What the fuck
are you doing?
Try and relax, Flash.
This will be a slide, man.
Easy in, easy out.
Piece of cake, man.
Nothing to it.
German fucking chocolate.
You got it.
- Sure you checked it out?
- Trust me.
- Are you sure?
- You know the drill.
- I go to the back, you go to the bar.
- Right.
You order a drink.
What will you order?
- What's the difference?
- You have to know what you're ordering.
You're making me nervous.
- Relax. Have a toothpick.
- Fuck a toothpick.
Let's go get some money.
You ought to crash, babe.
You had a heck of a day.
- How you doing?
-  How are you?
Hurry up. I got a lot of women
who want to sign it.
- It's a piece of art.
- It's a piece of shit.
- Just don't become a ballerina.
- Yeah.
What's up?
- How you doing?
- Open house tonight.
Give me a Black Russian
and a Courvoisier.
Straight up.
Where's all the dancing girls,
shaving their legs?
All right, get your hands up,
motherfuckers!
Which of you two guys
is the brains of the outfit?
You stupid motherfucker.
Dumb cocksucker.
Bring that piece of shit over here.
- Come here.
- Worm brain motherfucker!
Spread them.
Kiss the bar.
Old lady told me he was fucked-up
in the head. Do I listen?
"Gonna be a piece of cake, man.
Nothing to it. Gonna be a slide, man."
- Should have listened to my old lady.
- Screw her. Everybody else has.
- Cuff them and get them out of here.
- Give me your paw.
They get dumber every day.
Just let her get some sleep.
That's what I need too.
-  Get some and take care.
-  I'll call you tomorrow.
- Here's some tea.
- Thanks.
What do you do
if you don't have someone?
You find someone.
Will you hold me?
You'll be fine.
I'll see you tomorrow.
You're lucky my hands are cuffed.
I'll kick your ass,
handcuffed or not.
- You'd be black and blue.
- You can't, man.
Shoot me, so I don't have to listen
to him anymore.
- Hey, man--
- Shut up.
- You think you're John Wayne?
- I'll make you Jane Wayne.
-  Who ordered the Courvoisier?
- Hi, Sarge.
Hey, Sarge.
- What's this?
- These morons tried to rob us.
We called the station
45 minutes ago for a wagon.
They didn't believe us.
They thought we were kidding.
Eddie, partner, come here.
How you doing?
I want you to meet two friends of mine.
This is Ruby, a dental hygienist.
Very oral.
Marlene here works for a proctologist.
Don't turn your back on her.
Have a drink.
I have a proposition for you.
Later.
Let me plant two words
in your brain:
alligator farming.
- "Alligator farming"?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
It'll work.
Thanks.
- How's the girl?
- She's fine.
That fucker.
Why is he down here?
- Want a beer?
- Nah.
Val, give me
another Southern Comfort.
I really want to be a good cop.
Sometimes I get so scared, you know?
- Only a fool doesn't get scared.
- It's so easy for you.
You got all the answers.
For me, I don't know.
Cragie planted the gun
on that kid.
He just wasted him,
blew him away...
and I went
right along with it.
My partner.
I don't know what I'm gonna do
about that hearing tomorrow.
Tell the truth.
See? You make it sound so easy.
I got a wife and a kid...
and you're telling me
to commit suicide.
How am I supposed to live with these
guys if I sell out my own partner?
And if you don't?
- Cragie gets away with it.
- And the chance to do it again.
It was a mistake.
It was an accident.
- That kid was killed because of it.
- Don't you think I know it?
I see that boy's face
every time I close my eyes.
Tell it like it is, Nick.
I'll back you up.
- See you guys later.
-  Yeah, Eddie.
Look what's here.
Nice to see you out with the boys
for a change.
Cragie.
They tell me my sergeant
wouldn't sign for me.
- Want to tell me why?
- You know why.
No, tell me.
Mister, you don't belong
on the streets anymore.
Fuck you.
Where do you get off?
Right about here.
Good night, Sarge.
If it was dark, Officer...
how were you sure Vega had a gun?
We got lucky. There was a glint of light
reflecting off the weapon's barrel.
Officer Cragie,
you have heard Mrs. Munoz's testimony.
Yes, ma'am.
You heard her tell this panel
that she saw you...
lay the gun
in her grandson's hand.
I'm not saying
the woman made this up...
but there's no way she could see
anything from where she was standing...
in a hallway that dark.
Like you said,
she's the boy's grandmother.
Young lady, you are about
to have the house specialty:
Eggs Pirelli.
You got your protein,
carbohydrates...
vitamin D, vitamin C.
Good for you. Strength.
Eat now.
- Eat.
Right after you heard
Officer Cragie's gun discharge,
what did you do then?
I immediately advanced
down the hall.
What did you see?
The deceased, Vega...
lying on the floor.
Officer Cragie
was checking his vital signs.
What happened then?
We recovered a .25-caliber automatic
from the teenager's right hand.
Did you see that weapon in Vega's hand
before Officer Cragie fired?
Yes, ma'am.
No more questions.
You made that uniform look good.
That guy next to me--
Handsome devil, huh?
That's Eddie's dad.
Better than a good cop.
He was killed
in the line of duty, '71.
- An accident.
- What do you want?
- Gas company.
-  How you doing?
I can't comment on that.
It was over before I got there.
Aren't you his superior officer?
Cragie's in my unit, yes.
Did you request that Officer Cragie
be on your team?
- I did not.
-  Sergeant...
I have here a department document
dated 24 September of last year.
It is a request by you to have Officer
Cragie transferred to another unit.
- Are you familiar with this document?
- I am.
Why did you request this transfer?
Thirty years is too long for anyone to
look at the city's guts, Mrs. Partida.
Are you saying Officer Cragie
is not fit...
to work the streets of Chicago?
That's what I'm saying.
Come on, lady.
Give the guy a break.
- Fuck me? No, fuck you.
- Why are you arguing with him?
He didn't want me on tactical.
Operator, please check 555-6610 for me.
Seems to me the man
has his tongue stuck to his asshole.
That don't bother him.
He's the fucking white knight.
Sorry, the number is out of
service. I'll report it if you want.
You want to take on the world
by yourself?
Now you'll get your chance.
We just got here, Sarge.
- Wasn't he a friend of yours?
- More than a friend.
- Where's the girl?
- There was nobody else.
Squad, this is 1462.
I need backup.
Have 64 and 63 meet me at the billiard
parlor on 18th near Halsted.
Ten-four, 1462.
-  1463, come in.
-  Brennan, chow time.
1463, you've got
1462 requesting backup.
Meet him at the pool hall,
18th and Halsted.
Unit 1463 here. We can't respond.
We have a drug purchase in progress.
You want to reassign that?
Can anybody assist
for 18th and Halsted?
Got a one-man TAC team
going into a pool hall.
5447, we have a call from zone
10 for a backup.
Tactical Sergeant 1462
needs assistance...
at the pool hall
at 18th and Halsted.
Can you help him out?
He's a one-man unit.
We got a dead dog here
blocking traffic on Washington.
We're waiting
for animal control.
We're tailing a
suspicious vehicle southbound on Wells.
Jack, do you have a backup
for 18th and Halsted?
You heard what happened.
Who the hell will back him up?
- You're playing fucking games.
- If you want to respond, take a cab.
This car ain't going no place
for that son of a bitch!
Zone 10, we're not
getting any help for car 62.
Can somebody assist car 62?
He's alone.
- Zone 20?
-  You're breaking up here.
We're going in
for a radio check.
You don't want to be in here.
If I want your opinion,
I'll beat it out of you.
Where is he?
I don't know what
you're talking about!
I want Luis, you fucking punk.
Get out of here.
Talk, asshole.
He's on his way.
Who wants the first one? Hm?
You, amigo?
How about you, huh?
Gun, cabron.
Take him apart.
Grab his legs!
Grab his legs.
- Victor!
Save him.
When the sun comes up,
you give me Luna...
or the girl dies...
slowly.
You don't understand, huh, Eddie?
I told you, man,
don't fuck with the Comachos.
Eddie?
Eddie!
Where the fuck is he?
Cusack?!
Hey, Eddie?
- Jesus Christ, are you all right?
-  I'll live.
I'd have been here,
but those guys kept it from me.
I've been talking
to my friend, Maggie...
who works on a computer
at the Federal building.
- You're going to die.
- They have Diana Luna.
I'm trying to tell you...
she got a wire that Tony Luna's
been laying down in Wisconsin...
and he's coming in town tonight
at the Union Station at 10:00.
Hey, Eddie.
Hey, Eddie!
Hello, Uncle Felix.
You're a bad boy, Tony.
I told you leave it alone,
but, no, you had to start this.
You were always that way.
You're like a kid.
You see something, you grab it.
- Give it to me.
- For what?
I'm only here to cooperate.
There's someone with us, boss.
Move it.
This bitch is crazy!
Get rid of him!
- Don't fuck with me, old man!
- Tony, we won't hurt you!
You tell Luis,
I've got Tony Luna.
I want a time and a place.
Got it.
Cusack, where are you going
with my car?
Hello, my angel.
Have you had a nice night?
I have wonderful news for you.
- Look at me.
- Look at the man, huh?
Daddy's on his way.
He's dead.
Beautiful job.
Look at the way it came across.
Watch. It will be a screen pass
to the right.
Eddie, how are you?
Eddie's a good guy.
You're learning about football.
To learn about me,
you'll have to learn about football.
I want two guys up there.
- How many are up front?
- I got two up there.
Make it four.
We'll be prepared for anything.
I don't trust this son of a bitch.
Victor, take the girl back.
- I have a present for Luna.
- I have two guys up the middle.
That's great.
Efren, come with me.
Victor, when this is over,
Luna goes back to Bogota with me.
I don't know.
I was watching films with my girl,
and the next thing I know...
he locked the door
and took the truck.
I don't know what happened.
What's going on?
Cusack took off
with a truckload of armor.
- He's a one-man army now.
- The son of a bitch is crazy.
Okay, no more games.
Where's Cusack?
He's saving the world.
Eddie's out there alone, and you're
going to let him die? Fuck all of you.
- Cool it, kid.
- "Cool it"? No.
No, no, no. You fucking cool it.
I won't lie for you anymore.
I saw him lay a gun on that kid.
He blew him away, and I saw it.
- You fucking little bastard.
- Goddamn you!
What's this for, partner,
your next fuckup?
You better be straight.
Your badge is on the line.
If I can't do this right,
you can have it.
Get someone in the air.
We have to find Cusack.
- Get out there.
This is Kates. Listen to me.
We have a sergeant in a green truck.
We're looking for him.
Who do you have in the air?
City wide--
- Go get him!
- Come on! Let's go!
Get the girl!
- Hold on! Ahh!
Ahh!
This concludes
our demonstration.
If you have further questions...
our factory representative
will be happy to answer them.
Get up, you son of a bitch!
Get the fuck up!
Come on, Eddie!
We told you we'd get you!
Come on, asshole!
We got him, Pompas!
Come out, you chickenshit!
Ahh!
Come out, you bastard!
Come on, Luis, we got him! Pompas!
Efren!
Ahh!
Cusack!
You just killed that girl!
You know where to find me.
Hey, Eddie.
Partner, I got a great idea.
Mail-order Christmas trees.
Think about it.
See you tomorrow?
Yeah.
English - US - PSDH