Drop your rifle.
Get your hands up over your head.
Well, so you've come
to thank me, stranger?
That's one way of putting it,
but I'm a curious man, mister.
Before I thank you, I'd like to know
what you got against me.
Why nothing, son,
nothing at all.
Then why did you shoot at me
instead of the Comanches?
I'd call that a mighty fair question.
You mind if I put my arm down, son?
I got a bad shoulder.
Just don't go reaching
for any iron, huh.
Well, you might put it onto the head
in the military strategy, son.
You see Comanches sometimes
get queer notions.
They figure that land back there
is kind of sacred.
As long as you was trespassing,
you were safe.
I was just trying to coax you
back onto sacred territory.
So that's why they kept
changing their minds.
I'm afraid I owe you
my sincere apology, sir,
and my thanks.
Ah, there was no real danger.
There's only ten of them
and I still got one good arm left.
Mind if I have a look at this one?
Yeah.
This is right friendly
of you, stranger.
Looks as though
the Comanches got to you
before they got to me.
There was no Comanches.
Comanches is real friendly people,
if you don't rub them the wrong way.
Let's just say it's a snake bite.
Seems as though the snake
left a little bit of lead in there.
Only one kind of snake
around these parts.
I'll get it out
as quick and easy as I can.
There's no hurry, son.
Only don't throw it away,
I like to save
the lead folks take out of me.
I got me three pounds of it.
I reckon that there is supposed to be
one of them Bowie knives.
That's exactly what it is.
That is exactly what it ain't.
That's the poorest imitation
of the genuine article as ever I seen.
- It is.
- Yessiree.
That one is the same
as thousands of others
folks are selling back east.
A real Bowie knife,
that's something else again.
I'd ought to know,
I gave Jim Bowie the idea
for that weapon myself.
That's mighty interesting.
Yessiree, it was back in Louisiana.
Me and Jim were sitting
on the front porch whipping.
Jim was a rich man in them days.
It was on account that I'd given him
the idea there's plenty
of money in sugar.
No time at all, Jim had cleaned up
three million dollars.
Two million.
You a friend of Jim Bowie's?
- Not particularly.
- Hmm.
Well, anyways, Jim,
I says, 'Someday I'm gonna fashion me
a hunting knife, 16 inches long,
and curved in the end
like a heathen...'
Scimitar.
That's right, scimitar.
'So as my hand won't slip,' I says,
'aimed to put cross guard on the hilt,
and I'm going to put a double edge
on the last three inches.'
Four inches.
Next thing I knowed,
Jim Bowie had beat me to it
and made the knife his self.
I don't think I quite
got your name, son.
James Bowie of Louisiana.
Oh, while you was talking
I was beginning to think--
James Bowie?
Why, I'll be hog swallowed.
And whom do I have
the pleasure of digging into?
Dan'I Seeger,
Dan'I Gideon Seeger,
ex-hunter, ex-Indian fighter,
ex-congressman, and as you have
probably figured out,
the biggest hogtied, jugheaded,
turnip sucking liar in the whole world.
Steady now, Dan'I.
I think I got it.
I find this mighty interesting, Jim.
Them bucks out there,
come galloping by,
and see how close they can come to us
with their arrows
and they try again 10 paces further on,
and so on.
It's that so on that bothers me.
Well, I wish you were still
a member of congress, Dan'I.
This seems the most appropriate time
to register a complaint.
I call that mighty fair shooting.
You take Shoshones, Jim,
they're a bit nearsighted for Indians.
Now, if them were Shoshones
instead of Comanches,
I'd be getting a little nervous.
How many rounds do these
games usually run?
Three is about average,
four rounds is extra good.
If it should happen to run up to five,
well, them bucks would be
talking about nothing else
for weeks to come.
That's nice to know.
Well, in case they're only
playing a three rounder,
it was mighty nice meeting up
with you, Jim Bowie.
Excuse the left hand, Dan'I.
It's been a nice friendship,
if a short one.
Yeah, me unconscious
most of the time.
Look yonder, Jim.
It's Quisima, the number one chief.
I'd seen him once in Washington.
He's the one I came out here to see.
Does he understand English?
I don't know.
So this is the mighty Quisima,
who sat in the Council of the White Man
in Washington.
This is Quisima,
who gave one hand in friendship
to his white brothers,
while the other hand held a knife.
This is Quisima
whose word is shifting as the wind,
whose tongue twists like a river
of many branches.
This is Quisima, breaker of treaties.
Today, the Comanche
is held in honor and respect,
like the mountain that never yields
or the sun that never changes.
Tomorrow you will be
driven off like a dog
that wanders close to a campfire
to take his place among men.
White men broke treaty,
went where forbidden to go.
He's a stranger in these parts.
Your men should've come
to him friendly-like
and told him he was trespassing
on sacred ground
instead of swooping down on him
like chicken hawks trying to kill him.
I come from the Land of the Naches,
in the Muscogeean, to sit in council
with the mighty Quisima.
If I did not come in friendship,
your three braves would now lie dead.
Comanche honors his treaties.
Hope my white brothers do same
when time comes.
One white brother hurt,
Comanche medicine man
make him well again.
Meantime, white man,
whose tongue is as sharp as his blade,
will teach Quisima
more about his knife.
James Bowie,
if I had your gift of speeching
I'd still be in congress.
It's all right, Jim.
My arm being as good as new,
we are pulling out tomorrow.
Well, Quisima, I've kept
my part of the bargain.
In the two weeks we've
been here, I've taught your men
how to make and fight
with my kind of knife.
A blade that cuts two ways
has kept his word.
Quisima will keep his
when treaty with white man is renewed,
Bowie, brother of Quisima,
may dig silver ore
that lies beneath land of Comanches.
And the Comanches will get
a good price for it.
As long as campfires burn
before the tents of Comanches,
the blade that cuts two ways
and his friends will be welcome.
I ain't aiming to pry
into your private affairs, Jim,
but that silver deal
you made with Quisima...
You're not prying, Dan'l,
since the war of 1812,
the country's been trying
to get back on its feet.
We need that silver to help us do it.
That's why I came out here.
I hate to disappoint you, Jim,
but that treaty ain't
being renewed next week.
You're mistaken.
The renewal was drawn up
when I left the east.
Oh, it was drawn up all right.
But Andy Jackson gave it
to a dimwit named Dan'I Seeger
to give to the Comanches
for ratification.
Well, then, what's wrong?
Remember that bullet
you took out of my shoulder?
Well, a short while
before I run into you,
I was dragged and thieved.
The ornery skunks
took the treaty renewal.
But the president can always
send the Comanches another copy.
Yeah, but it'll be
weeks before they get here.
Meanwhile, folks are pouring
into the territory
by the dozens, just waiting
for the treaty to expire.
Comes the deadline,
they all will be staking claim.
Once they get in here,
it ain't gonna be as easy
to get out of here.
Any idea who might have done it?
Nope, but I'm hoping
I might find out something
when we get to Crooked Tongue.
Don't your remember anything?
As a matter of fact,
there was something, Jim.
Just before I passed out,
I got a whiff of fancy perfume.
- Perfume?
- Perfume.
Smelled real good, too.
For a minute,
I thought I was getting mighty
too close to the pearly gates.
Do you know what kind it was?
No, but I'd recollect it
if I ever ran cross it again.
I may not have good brains,
but I sure got a good smeller.
Dan'I and I have been
doing some tall thinking
along the way.
Whoever took that treaty
knows for certain
there'll be no renewal next week.
- That follows.
- So naturally, you'll expect
to have a lot of silver
to sell in the near future.
- Well, seems logical.
- Well, I'm gonna spread it
around town
I came out here to buy silver,
all I can lay my hands on.
Now, why couldn't I have thunk of that?
The best way to get polecats
is to smoke them out.
Anybody who's ready
to make a deal with you
knows more than he had ought to.
Precisely.
And since you're
evidently known by sight,
I suggest we ride into town alone, hmm?
As we used to say in congress,
'The motion is seconded and passed
and the meeting is adjourned.'
Come on, you cow-heels.
Now, put your money down.
Boozer here will take all bets.
Your money or your livestock.
But just see that you make it big.
With our luck,
I'm not gonna make this ride
unless you fellas
make it worth my while.
Now let me get this straight, Katie.
You're betting you can
take that tray in one hand
and ride full gallop
to the end of town...
Stop dead, ride back at full speed,
return the tray,
and if one of the glasses is spilled,
- I've lost my bet.
- Katie, you've just made
yourself a wager.
Do you call that a wager?
Take that trash out of my sight.
I don't aim to be insulted
by small bets like that.
Well, come on some man-sized bets
or I'm not going to trouble myself.
All right.
There you are.
That's more I like it.
- Come on, now. Come on.
- $14, keep going.
Come on now, come on.
All right.
Come on now. Let him do it. Come on.
Come on, put your hands over here.
Come on, Katie. Come on, Katie.
Get away, folks.
Go on, hanging right on to it.
There.
- Now, y'all set, Katie?
- All set.
Good lord, there we go.
Now, easy does it.
Easy does it.
Don't spill it, I got my money on it.
You clumsy ox.
I'm terribly sorry.
Blundering fool.
Now, now, miss. I said I was sorry.
It's not nice for a lady
not to be a lady.
Sorry?
He said he's sorry.
You blundering tinhorn,
- you made me lose all my bets.
- Bets?
I didn't know ladies made bets.
You call me a lady once more
and I'll fill you full of lead.
Easy now, miss. The mood you're in,
you're liable to pull that trigger
thereby causing
a most embarrassing situation
for both of us.
You did that on purpose.
Look, mister. If the lady wants
to pull a gun on me,
that's quite all right.
Where I come from,
we usually let the ladies
have their way.
But I don't like a man doing it.
Oh, you don't? Now I'm gonna shoot...
- You get out of this.
- But Miss Katie,
- I bet my whole bankroll on you.
- I can take care of this,
this tinhorn without your help.
I've got an idea.
Why don't you two toss a coin
to see who shoots me, huh?
You talk too much.
All right, mister.
Draw.
I said draw.
Sorry, ma'am. Back in Louisiana,
when we meet any pretty ladies,
we make love to them,
we kiss them,
spank them on occasion,
but we never go around shooting them.
Are you going to draw or aren't you?
Of all the yellow, spineless,
cowardly coyotes I...
Pay off all bets.
Another thing I forgot to mention,
I dislike the sound of someone
cocking a pistol behind my back.
Hello.
Howdy?
I'd like to deposit this bank draft
and draw some cash against it.
Oh, sure, sure.
Hmm, $5,000?
You have to take this up with the boss,
in there.
It's all right. Go right in.
Well?
Look, miss, I'm liable
to run out of apologies
if you're following me around
to start trouble again.
What do you want to see me about?
I can assure you, miss,
seeing you was the least
of my intentions.
I'm waiting to see
the president of the bank.
All right,
start talking.
You're not the bank president.
Mister, I am the bank and I'm busy.
Now, what do you want?
I'd like to deposit this draft
and draw some cash against it.
James Bowie, Louisiana.
And now you got the better of me.
I usually like to know
the names of people
- I do business with.
- The name's Kathryn Howard,
and we're not doing any business.
Do you mean you're not going
to honor this draft?
That's exactly what I do mean.
I don't like the look of it.
Meaning, you don't like me?
Suit yourself.
I don't like you, mister,
or your bank draft.
But there isn't another bank
within 200 miles.
I'm considered a fairly
wealthy man back east,
but if you refuse to cash this draft,
I might as well be broke.
Now, it does seem to work out
that way, doesn't it?
Thanks for dropping in, Mr. Bowie.
But this is ridiculous.
This is a perfectly legal bank draft.
You can't refuse to recognize
- The Bank of Louisiana.
- I refuse to recognize
the whole State of Louisiana.
Ms. Howard, I've done
a lot of things in my life,
but I've never had
a bank president across my knee
for a good spanking.
That's a pleasure
I shall look forward to.
If you refuse to accept this draft,
I'm sure the gambling casino next door
will be very glad to.
Mr. Bowie.
Let me give you
some friendly advice.
Get out of town. You've already
been here too long.
Very kind of you
to want to be my friend.
Thank you.
We must have dinner together sometime.
Jack. Good
How about you?
- Eight.
- Seven.
- Four.
- Who's in charge around here?
Stacey.
That's him at the end of the bar.
- How about you?
- Yeah.
Excuse me. They tell me
you're in charge around here.
- That's right.
- I'd like to cash a draft
drawn on the Bank of Louisiana.
Certainly. How large?
- Five thousand.
- You know, that size,
you have to take it up
with the big boss.
And where do I find the big boss?
In the office.
Oh, no.
- It's you again.
- Get to the point, Mister.
This happens to be one of my busy days.
Now, what can I do for you?
Oh, I've seen everything.
I have no time for small talk,
Mr. Bowie.
But if this is a social call, I--
No, not at all.
Ms. Howard, I have in my possession
a draft drawn on the bank--
oh, what's the use?
Look, I need cash.
I'll make you a sporting proposition.
I'm not a gambler,
but evidently you are.
One cut of the cards for five thousand.
You've made yourself a bet, Mr. Bowie.
Come on.
We're breaking in for one hand
of high card, Slim.
That's all, boys. Pick up your chips.
Give me 5,000.
Five thousand one hand?
You ask too many questions.
Cash if you don't mind.
Mind if I have a look at those cards?
- Why you little...
- That's all right, Slim.
Mr. Bowie has a peculiar
sense of humor.
Why don't you shuffle them, too?
Well, it's not necessary.
After all, we do trust
each other, don't we?
Ladies first.
Oh, I forgot, you don't like
to be called a lady
or dress like one either.
An eight.
Four.
Your money, Mr. Bowie.
I believe I mentioned before,
I don't gamble, Ms. Howard.
You can have the draft.
That'll keep it from being gambling.
Now, look, Mr. Bowie, if that's a bet,
I don't think you meant that
to be an insult or did you?
I never insult anyone with $5,000,
especially a lady.
What'll it be?
That'll be all right.
Any kind of will do.
Jim, I've have smelled
half the people in town,
and believe me, there are no lilies.
I've smelled polecat and sheepherder
and about a dozen assorted smells
I haven't classified as yet.
Any trace of that perfume?
Not a whiff, but I'll keep on smelling
until my smeller gives up.
I'm sorry you had trouble
with the boss.
If she'd known who Jim Bowie was,
I'm sure she would have been
more courteous.
I can't imagine that female tiger,
if she is a female,
being courteous
under any circumstances.
Oh, Katie's really
a nice person, Mr. Bowie,
when you get to know her better.
Getting to know her better
is one ordeal
I'm hoping to spare myself.
Can I buy you a drink?
- Thanks.
- Boozer.
So far, all the friends
I've made in this town
- add up to zero.
- Well, your entrance into town
wasn't exactly conducive
to making friends.
You know, I spent most
of my life in the east.
That's where I first heard of Jim Bowie
and his fabulous knife.
I hear tell it's a deadly man killer.
It's a hunting knife.
Sorry.
You're in sugar, aren't you?
Used to be.
We don't grow much sugar
in these parts.
No, but I understand
you're expecting a fine
crop of silver very soon.
Thinking of staking your claim
in Comanche Territory?
I'm leaving the claim taking to others.
I'm buying silver. All I can get.
That's very interesting, Mr. Bowie.
If I hear of anyone
with silver to sell,
I'll pass the word along.
Well, if it ain't Ms. Katie Howard.
Lucky for you, Lem,
I can't tote any guns in this outfit.
What are you rigged up for, Katie,
a wedding or a funeral?
Wait until you see the dress
I wear the day we bury you.
All right, boys.
When Katie goes feminine,
somebody better watch out.
Still wondering if the tiger is female?
Not anymore.
I'm raising 10 more.
No bet.
What's the idea?
I thought I told you card sharks
to keep out of my place.
- Now get.
- But I--
Go on.
Mighty affectionate for a man your age.
It ain't affection. It's that perfume.
Well, if it's going
to affect people like that,
I better not use it anymore.
All right, miss, where is the treaty?
- Treaty?
- The treaty with the Comanches.
The one you took from me.
What have you done with it?
I don't know what you're talking about.
That treaty was a property
of the federal government
and I aim to get it back.
I'm sorry, Ms. Katie.
Why you clumsy mutt.
Hey, someone get me out of here.
Someone get me out of here.
I promised myself this
pleasure, Ms. Bank President.
- Ow.
- That's for not cashing
my draft.
I'll kill you when I get out of here.
Ow.
That's for giving me so much trouble.
Throw these two gentlemen out of here.
Well, I hope you know
what you're doing.
You bet I do.
You know, people don't toss
Jim Bowie around like that
- and get away with it.
- I'll take my chances
whoever he is.
For your information,
he's a very wealthy man.
- He's in town to buy silver.
- So what?
A Comanche silver is no good
to us if we don't get someone
- to take it off our hands.
- There'll be other buyers.
Sure, maybe in a few months?
But we can use Jim Bowie now.
If you don't want all our plans
to fall through,
you'd better go after him.
See if you can repair
the damage you've done.
Me go crawling to him?
I'd rather die first.
I'm not asking you, Katie.
I'm telling you.
Eh, it's no use, Jim.
I'll never learn to keep my mouth shut.
If I had, I'd still be in Congress.
You never struck me as the kind of man
that goes around kissing strange girls
in the shoulder
and in one drink, too.
I wasn't kissing, I was whiffing.
And I got me a nose
full of that perfume.
- Ms. Howard?
- Uh-hmm.
Instead of saying nothing,
playing possum,
I had to raise a fuss
and get us thrown out.
Now, we can't get back in there
to snoop around.
I'm not so sure of that, Dan'l.
I came out to tell you
that I was sorry.
I want to apologize.
Well, this is a surprise.
It is to me, too.
I mean, we try to run
a respectable place
and if your friend here
hadn't started all the trouble--
He's no friend of mine.
I never saw him before.
Well, you were trying to help him.
Just a case of helping the underdog,
too many against one.
I reckon I could take the blame
for that little fracas, miss.
You see, I met up with
an accident awhile back
and I've been kind of
getting funny spells ever since,
you know, imagining
all sorts of funny things.
I'm sorry if I caused you
any trouble, stranger.
Um, I hope we can consider all this
a misunderstanding, Mr. Bowie.
I'm sure that's all it was, Ms. Howard.
Oh, that's very kind of you to say so.
If you're not holding any grudges,
I--I'd like to offer you a drink.
Well, the offer is gratefully accepted.
Providing of course
I'm still welcome inside.
Oh, of course, Mr. Bowie.
And again,
my deepest apologies.
Not at all, Ms. Howard.
My apologies to you.
Oh.
Well, I'll be...
hogswalled.
How about this table, Mr. Bowie.
Splendid.
You can see everything from here.
And nobody can get behind me.
Oh, now, Mr. Bowie.
Boozer,
see that Mr. Bowie
has anything he wants.
But, Ms. Katie, I think he's just a--
You're not paid to think.
Mr. Bowie is a guest of mine.
Give him the best in the house.
Oh, by the way,
have you made any arrangements
- for your lodgings?
- No, not yet.
Well, then it's all settled.
You'll stay at my ranch.
That's very gracious of you,
Ms. Howard.
Oh, not at all, Mr. Bowie.
You know, I had no idea
Stacey was your brother.
You didn't?
He told me when I got to
know you better,
I'd get to like you,
and I believe he was right.
Oh?
So, in two days, you think
you're beginning to know me?
At least I'm beginning to like you.
Oh.
Come.
I thought the Comanche
had a peace treaty
with his white brothers.
Come.
It seems that's his entire vocabulary.
I think we better go with him.
Why are we brought here like this?
Quisima breaks his word
to keep the peace
with the white man.
Quisima keeps his word.
Want to know if white men
will keep theirs.
A blade that cuts two ways
will sit in council
of Comanches.
Pakanah.
This is Pakanah,
my son.
He lived with white man.
He tell you when your tongue message
is given to us.
White man like bird
that makes sweet music
but rob nest of others.
He promised Comanche peace
while hand reaches for a gun
to slay him.
Every day,
we see white man
come across plain
from direction of morning sun.
He bring tools with him,
not for planting of corn,
but for digging of silver.
White man
plan to betray Comanche.
He will take his land.
There will be no new treaty.
Each day Comanche wait,
white man becomes stronger.
Comanche must strike
at once tonight.
Council agrees with Pakanah.
But I told them,
'My brother, Bowie,
man of honor.
He not lie.'
If he tell me
white man renew treaty,
Quisima believe him.
What do you think, Ms. Howard?
I...
I don't know.
I pledge my word of honor, Quisima,
that the treaty
has already been renewed
and has been sent on its way here
from Washington.
White man has false tongue.
I don't blame you
for being angry, Pakanah,
but I don't like to be called a liar.
White man lie.
I make him admit.
If that's the way you want it.
Not with your weapons,
with ours.
Each to his own.
Please don't.
You won't stand a chance.
Then why don't you stop it?
You know there's a new treaty
and you know who took it.
I can't.
Then I've got to fight him
or every Comanche in the territory
will be on the warpath before morning.
I wish you'd change your mind, Pakanah.
I don't wanna kill you.
I want kill you.
I told the truth.
White man tell truth.
You think I want that silver
for myself, don't you?
Well, you're wrong.
I have my reasons, good reasons,
but they wouldn't mean anything to you.
Maybe they would.
Not to an Easterner.
You would have to be a part of that
to understand
and that would have to be
a part of you.
My father and grandfather
came out here to try
and make something
out of that wilderness
and they died trying.
They brought
all their friends with them
and everyone who'd listen.
Go on.
But things didn't work out
the way they expected them.
They raised cattle,
but there was no way to get them
to the eastern markets.
People began to get discouraged.
Lately things have been getting worse.
A lot of families have left
the territory and gone back.
And you think that Comanche silver
will keep them from leaving,
is that it?
Yes, that's it.
Once they stake claims,
they'd have to stay here.
And no one, the Indians
and the federal government included,
is going to stop us.
That's mighty big talk, Ms. Howard.
Well, that's the way
we feel about it, all of us,
even my brother Stacey.
Of all the upside down,
back into,
mule-headed, illogical,
irrational feminine reasoning.
You saw the mood
those Comanches are in.
Do you think for one moment
the shooting stop
with that one rifle ball I took out
of Dan'I Seeger's shoulder?
I'm sorry about that.
There wasn't supposed to be a shooting
but the men with me
were pretty desperate.
- Somebody slipped up.
- And they'll slip up again
if they try to jump Indian land.
Quisima has already given
the government permission
to dig for their silver.
That's mighty fine for the government,
but it doesn't do us any good.
Listen, Ms. Howard,
your desire to improve this territory
is most commendable,
but you're going about it
in the wrong way.
Don't you understand?
The country needs this silver.
They'll make a road out here.
Wagon trains will be rolling
in and out of here.
People who left will be coming back
and hundreds more.
Besides, this territory
will be bigger than anything
your father or grandfather
ever dreamed of.
You really believe that?
Believe that? I know it.
So you're calling off the deal, Katie?
All our plans,
everything we've worked for?
Not unless you agree, Stacey,
after all, that's your problem
as much as mine.
Oh, anything you say
is all right with me,
you know that.
Since we only have three days left,
I suggest we get the treaty to Quisima
as quickly as possible.
I didn't know there'd would be
a change in plans.
I destroyed it.
I'm sorry.
Well, no harm done.
You two confess the word out
that there is a new treaty
and nobody is to try moving in
on the Comanches.
That'll protect us till Andy Jackson
can send along a new copy.
Yeah, I'm afraid that won't work, Jim.
A lot of newcomers pulled up stakes
and came out here just to get in
on the silver rush.
They're not gonna be
in a listening mood.
I found out when I was in
business back East
that usually the best way
to handle a stubborn customer
was to get a couple of drinks
and a good meal under his belt,
then he'd usually listen to reason.
We're gonna throw the biggest shindig
this territory's ever known.
We'd throw the cafe wide open
and wine them and dine them
until they're ready to listen.
And just in case a few of them
don't see the light,
I suggest we take their guns away
before they come in.
What's the matter, Tom?
Comanches making trouble?
Heck no, get down
to Crooked Tongue today.
Free fills and plenty of liquor.
Katie Howard's throwing a shindig,
- you better hurry.
- Yeah?
I guess I better get home
and change my duds.
Come on.
Hey, stop everything.
Katie Howard's throwing a party.
Free fills and liquor for everybody.
Are you sure there ain't no
charge for this?
Everything is free.
Well, in that case, thanks.
Here now.
We don't have none of that.
I like your neighbors, Katie.
They're nice, friendly people.
I sure hope they stay that way
after we bust the news to them.
Well, I don't expect any trouble
with the old timers,
but there's a lot of newcomers
around here
that I've never seen before.
Hello. Jed.
Oh, excuse me.
- Hello, Sue, hello, Jed.
- Hello.
I'm sure glad you could make it.
I wouldn't miss this on a bet, Katie.
- What's all this all here?
- Oh, sorry, Jed,
everyone is checking their guns.
Fair enough.
Sure is a pretty girl.
Sure is.
Too bad she's always wearing buckskin,
keeping her figure covered.
At your age, Dan'I,
you shouldn't be looking.
I ain't seen much else to do.
Uh-oh.
We're just talking about you,
Ms. Katie.
Jim here was saying
if I'd help keep an eye
on the weapons,
he'd sure like to ask you
for a dance.
And what did you say, Mr. Seeger?
I said I'd be delighted.
On the contrary, Mr. Seeger,
I'd be delighted.
♪ Follow me, my bonny lad ♪
♪ For I'll not follow you ♪
Come on, Katie, don't be bashful.
Sing it out loud for all of us.
♪ My father bought ♪
♪ At great expense ♪
♪ A grand high stepping grey ♪
♪ But when he puts her out a fence ♪
♪ She backs and backs away ♪
♪ Hey ho, the morning dew ♪
♪ Hey ho, the rose and rue ♪
♪ Follow me, my bonny lad ♪
♪ For I'll not follow you ♪
♪ My mother bought ♪
♪ A likely hen ♪
♪ On last St. Martin's day ♪
♪ She clucks and clucks ♪
♪ And clucks again ♪
♪ But never yet will lay ♪
♪ Hey ho, the morning dew ♪
♪ Hey ho the rose and rue ♪
♪ Follow me ♪
♪ My bonny lad ♪
♪ For I'll not follow you ♪
♪ Now, Mustard is my brother's dog ♪
♪ Who whines and barks all day ♪
♪ But take him with you all to hunt ♪
♪ And he'll get in the way ♪
♪ Hey ho, the morning dew ♪
♪ Hey ho, the rose and rue ♪
♪ Follow me ♪
♪ My bonny lad ♪
♪ For I'll not follow you ♪
♪ When walls lie down ♪
♪ For steeds to step ♪
♪ When eggs themselves go lay ♪
♪ And the ducks jump ♪
♪ Into Mustard's jaw ♪
♪ To you my court ♪
♪ I'll pay ♪
♪ Hey ho, the morning dew ♪
♪ Hey ho, the rose and rue ♪
♪ Follow me ♪
♪ My bonny lad ♪
♪ For I'll not follow you ♪
Uh-oh. I'm sorry, boys,
but you have to leave
your shooting guns here.
Who said so?
Ms. Howard.
Yeah? Well, nobody's taking my gun.
Well, then, you can't go in.
Well, why don't you try to stop us?
I got that one from the Iroquois.
The Iroquois taught me that one.
I better tell them now.
I'll take a couple of these.
This is as good a time as any
to make a little announcement.
There's a new treaty with the Comanches
and it'll be here from Washington
in a few days.
That means that you can all forget
that midnight deadline tomorrow.
Nobody is moving in
on Comanche territory, nobody.
You can do whatever you like, lady,
but I'm moving in.
If any of you newcomers feel
like arguing,
I've got a couple of good
arguments right here.
You old timers
know how my folks felt
about this territory
and how I feel about it,
and I'm not going to let it break up.
That silver is going to be mined,
but it'll be done legally
and there'll be plenty of work
for everybody
and a chance to live right
and bring your kids up in the same way.
This territory is going to grow faster
and bigger than we ever dreamed.
Those that feel like I do
will do well to stay.
And as for the others, well,
we'll stake them to the expenses
of their trip back home.
I'm staying, Katie.
- You can count on me, too.
- yeah.
What about the rest of you?
Katie, I'm afraid
I've got some bad news.
I was up on the north range
checking the cattle
and I found a couple of fresh carcasses
and some wolf tracks.
- Wolves?
- Yeah, traveling in a pack,
about a dozen of them
as near as I can make out.
I've never heard of wolves
traveling in packs
this far South.
They're heading towards Timberline.
Oh, I got my stock grazing up there.
I better get my rifle and get going.
- I'll go with you.
- Just a minute, boys,
you'll need help.
Folks, as part of these festivities,
I'm organizing a wolf hunt.
I'll pay $20 in gold
for every pelt you bring back.
Well, Jim, you sure you won't
change your mind
- and come with us?
- No, I better stay
and keep an eye on the party.
Hmm, it's quite a pretty party
to keep an eye on.
- What about you, Stacey?
- Oh, I'd have trouble
getting on a horse,
let alone, riding one.
Well, I'm thinking on four pelts,
- one for each of us.
- Let's go.
Well, I guess everybody's here
except the boss.
It's only a wild turkey.
We got a long day ahead of us.
They make mighty good eating.
Here he comes.
You all know what we're here for.
I had you men picked because I think
you all feel the way I do.
We didn't come out here
for the good of the glorious West,
but for our own good.
Now, that being so, we are moving in
on Comanche territory tonight.
Are there any questions?
Yeah.
Suppose the federal government
brings troops in here to throw us out.
There won't be any law
in this territory
for 25 years.
By that time, we'll all be rich enough
not to have to worry.
You've been talking mighty big
about how we're all gonna get rich,
but you ain't never mentioned
how we're gonna split up the silver.
I'll let you know that
after we take over
and start digging it.
I'd like to know right now.
Are there any other troublemakers
hankering to know how we split up?
This ain't no argument, Stacey,
But what are the Comanches
gonna be doing
while we're digging the silver?
That's all taken care off.
Comanches without rifles
shouldn't present much of a problem.
I've got the original treaty right here
with, shall we say,
a little added clause.
Clause 10,
this treaty of peace to take effect
only on the condition that said
Comanche Indians
shall immediately as a token
of their intention
of keeping said peace,
surrender all guns, rifles,
and powder in their possessions.
Well, there it is, Quisima,
all signed and sealed.
This trick of white man,
Comanche must not give up gun.
Long before white man came,
Comanche hunted with bow
and knife was happy.
White man's gun
has brought them only sorrow
and bloodshed.
Since we will now live in peace
with white brothers,
we not need these guns.
It shall be as white brother's wish.
Sorry you had to leave so soon.
Got to get the youngsters home
and straightened out,
they act too much.
Sure was a swell shindig, Ms. Howard.
That cake was every bit
as good as mom's.
Mmm, almost.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye. Bye.
Well, it looks like your party
is a success in more ways than one.
Thanks to you.
It was really your idea.
Folks took the change in plans
very nicely.
I'm sure you won't have any trouble.
And someday soon,
I'll be coming through
this way again
and this territory will be booming.
You're not leaving.
In a couple of days.
I want to get down there
and find out what it's all about.
When do you expect to get back?
I'd be more up to hurry
if I knew I was being missed.
In that case, Jim Bowie,
you'd better hurry.
I'm going to miss you, too.
Oh, what's the matter, Dan'l?
Didn't you get any wolves?
I found plenty of wolves,
two-legged wolves.
Jim Bowie, you and me have been took in
like a couple of first-class
greenhorns.
- Meaning, what?
- Meaning if there's a wolf pack
in them hills, I'll eat my saddle.
Looks like Ms. Howard and her brother
dealt it to us right off
the bottom of the deck.
I hope you know what you're
talking about, Mr. Seeger
because I don't.
No, I suppose you don't know
where your brother is
or what he is up to.
Of course I do.
He took the buckboard back
to the ranch.
And you can just stop
your playacting, young woman.
Stacey and most of those men
are up in the hills
in that supposed-to-be wolf hunt
and they are aiming to move in
on the Comanches.
Well, that's not true.
Naturally, she don't know
nothing about it.
Just like she don't know
her brother rides
like a
and he's mighty handy
in a lot of other ways.
Jim, I don't know anything about this.
- I swear it.
- I've got to hand it to you,
Ms. Howard, that wolf hunt
was a stroke of genius.
- You've got to believe me, Jim.
- You picked a clever way
of getting the guns back
to the men and sneaking them out
without arousing suspicion.
Jim, you've got to listen to me.
I've listened enough.
Let's go.
Boozer, I want to see you
in the office.
I'm kind of busy out there, Ms. Katie.
Get over there.
Where's Stacey?
I don't know.
I guess he went home.
You know where he is
and what he's up to.
No, ma'am.
I don't know nothing.
Then, you'd better start guessing.
- No.
- Stay right where you are
and don't move.
What is this, a joke?
Listen, Boozer,
I've talked big and tough
all of my life,
but I've never shot anyone.
You'd better start talking.
But if I talk,
Stacey will kill me.
You can worry about that later.
If you don't talk,
I'll kill you.
We got here as fast as we could.
We do not want Quisima to think
it is the white man's government
that betrays The Comanche.
Our brother, Bowie has spoken well.
Quisima understand
there's great problem.
The boys still got a few hours
before sundown,
plenty of time to get ready
for that pack of human hyenas.
The Comanches have given up their guns.
They have only arrows and lances
and few knives
my brother, Bowie made for them.
They'll never let you get
close enough to use them.
Well, they'd pick you off
like a herd of buffalo.
If Comanches must die,
they will die like men,
but never gave up
sacred soil of their fathers.
Listen, Quisima,
dying may be all right for your men,
but you've got to get your women
and children out of here.
Let them take what they can carry
and hide out in the hills,
then spread your men out.
Let them fight
from behind rocks and trees.
Caution your braves again.
We'll wait beyond the village
until Stacey's men come close
on this mountain then we'll attack.
Well, Stacey,
the men are rested and fed
and raring to go.
Well, you can pass out some whiskey,
no more than two drinks per man.
You're quite a ways from home,
aren't you, sis?
I had to see for myself.
Well, now you know.
You're not thinking of whipping
your naughty brother.
Quite an arsenal you've got over there.
You're not taking any chances.
I can't afford to.
The Comanches are most cooperative.
They gave up their guns
without a struggle.
You've been planning this
for a long time.
Even before I come out here.
I suppose I'd be wasting my breath
if I tried to talk you out of it.
Just as much as if I tried to talk you
into coming in with me,
and giving up that nonsense
about building up the West.
Very well, Stacey.
Now we know where we stand.
From now on, I'm on the other
side of the fence.
Fortunes of war, Katie.
Where are you going?
Out of here if I don't get
a bullet in my back.
Take some men and go after her.
We're not waiting any longer.
We're moving in on
the Comanches right now.
Ha, ha.
I don't know how I'm gonna make out
with your kind of knife, Jim.
I was practically weaned
on this Arkansas toothpick.
Remember, it cuts up as well as down.
This not white man's fight.
You go.
We like it here, Pakanah.
Besides, we've gotta make
things right on account
of what Stacey's doing.
It's fellers like him
that gives a white man a bad name.
Once, in anger,
I want kill my brother, Bowie.
Now, if you let me,
I want fight beside him.
Glad to have you.
Well, wouldn't have to wait long
to get his wish.
Here they come.
They won't get their guns back.
Tell them to save their arrows.
Well, you know what
it feels like to be a turkey
in a turkey shoot.
Well, they can't hold that much longer.
Maybe if I try to ration them.
You think so, huh?
Look.
They won't get their guns back, eh?
Quick, rifles.
Don't get them tied along.
Let's go.
I ought to turn you over
to The Comanches,
but you'll be a lot safer
with the federal government.
As soon as I finish my business
with Mr. Houston,
I'll be back.
Hurry, Jim,
I'll need a lot more help now.
Looking like that,
you'll do all right.
Well, goodbye, Kate.
Bye, Jim.
Good luck.
That ain't no way
to say goodbye to a gal,
you big galoot.
Go ahead and kiss her.