December, 1983.
The Nereid,
a British atomic submarine
Tokyo Bay, Japan
I'm pregnant.
But it's of no matter to you.
Farewell.
In the fall of 1982,
mankind died out...
Leaving only 863 people
alive on Antarctica.
How could this have happened?
Virus - Resurrection Day
In 1981...
All genetic engineering
experiments...
...to create new viruses...
...were banned internationally.
However, one year later...
February, 1982
Leipzig - East Germany
Military Biological
Research Center
Herr professor!
Close that or the coffee gets cold.
I've got to drive 60 kilometers today.
I'm sorry, professor.
It's pretty bad weather.
I have no choice.
My sister is sick.
I am sorry. Please drive carefully.
Thank you.
March, 1982
University of Maryland,
United States
Biological Research Center
April, 1982
Soviet Union -
Republic of Kazakhstan
Italy - Milan
Italian flu rages
through the country
government authorities
are concerned
Italian flu - is it a new virus?
May, 1982
South Pole - Showa Station
Leader, it's a message
from the capital.
"We hope to have the Italian flu
under control soon.
Please calm down
and continue your observations.”
A superficial response,
as usual.
Doesn't calm me down.
Let's pin it up
in the cafeteria.
It should make
everyone feel better.
Yes, sir.
It's that Australian group
from next door.
Let me speak.
Can an unknown disease
like that...
Really exist?
How should I know?
All I know is that
the whole world's in a panic.
Matsuo! Connect the electricity!
Roger!
You amaze me.
Doesn't it bother you at all?
Hey.
He's got a girlfriend.
She's my wife's friend.
She's really beautiful.
What do you think?
Huh?
I won't say anything bad.
Why don't you ask about her
by telegraph sometime?
We broke up.
Broke up?
She probably couldn't
put up with me.
- But you...
- Matsuo!
- Let's do this.
- Hey!
I'm pregnant.
The child will be born
while you're at the South Pole.
I'm lying.
But even if it were true...
It's of no importance to you.
No matter what happened to me...
You'd still go, right?
That's right.
Earthquakes
and the South Pole...
Are all you care about, right?
Let's break up...
After all.
You and I.
Banzai!
I didn't think you'd come.
As far as the child goes...
I told you it was a lie.
Either way...
it doesn't matter to you.
I'm sorry.
I hadn't planned
to say something like this.
In truth...
I wanted to see you off
with a smile.
Go in good health.
Farewell.
June, 1982 - Tokyo
- Move aside!
- It's an emergency!
- Out of our way!
- Let us through!
- It's an emergency!
Excuse Me!
Miss Noriko?
Miss Yoshiko.
What's wrong?
You're so pale!
Nothing's wrong.
I'm just a little tired.
Akira, what's wrong?
Do you have a cold?
Vaccinations.
It was hard...
So early in the morning.
Miss Noriko!
You're awake.
You stayed with me?
What are you saying?
More importantly, are you okay?
Yes.
They couldn't save it?
The baby.
Recently, I've been so busy...
I overexerted myself.
Did Mr. Yoshizumi...
...know about it?
I did something cruel.
I thought I could
raise her myself.
White House - the Oval Office
July, 1982
Martial law is instituted
in all of Japan
When did this start?
He was coughing last night...
But he suddenly
went limp this morning.
You, take him to a room quickly!
We have to examine him now.
Take a lung biopsy.
His heart is weak, too.
Will he be okay?!
We must take him now!
But doctor, my husband
is in the hospital...
And I have a 101 degree fever.
All the hospitals are full,
and I've been waiting!
Please calm down.
After the flu test,
he'll get better.
- Come on.
- This way.
Okay, next patient.
Doctor!
I'm fine.
I'm okay.
Please rest a bit.
I'll take over for you.
- Okay, please take over.
- Yes, sir.
Doctor.
Please hang in there!
Thank you.
Shall I get you some tea?
I'm fine.
You've got to have something!
We have milk, too.
- Get me some water.
- Yes, sir.
Did you hear today's news?
The death toll
has passed 30 million.
That many?
The mortality rate...
Is 459%!
They say it may keep growing!
Doctor...
How long will this continue?
I don't know.
But we must do
everything we can.
Everything must end sometime.
The question is,
how will it end?
August, 1982
It's no use!
How many days
since we lost contact?
This is the eighth day.
It seems to be
a terrible situation.
I don't believe it!
How could Japan be ruined...
...in just three months?!
How could that be?!
Tatsuno, that voice!
Are you calling us?
It's no use, he's pushing
down the Mike button!
He doesn't know how to use it.
He must have...
...gone on to heaven.
You asshole!
Mr. Tatsuno!
Asshole!
September, 1982
New York - 7.4 million dead
London - 6.9 million dead
Paris - 2.3 million dead
Rome - 2.9 million dead
Moscow - 7.8 million dead
Tokyo, 10 million dead
Miss Yoshiko.
Akira!
You're here!
You're alive.
I'm sorry.
You were lonely, right?
Akira...
Do you want to come with me
to where Papa is?
What about Mama?
Your Mama...
Can't come with us.
That's why
I'll take you to Papa.
Papa will be happy!
Are you cold?
Please...
...drink this.
What is it?
It will stop you
from being cold.
What's wrong?
It's nothing.
Akira...
Try calling your Papa.
Papa.
Louder.
Papa!
One more time.
Is that you, Tatsuno?
Tatsuno!
Hey!
Tatsuno's gone somewhere.
- What?!
- Stay here.
Tatsuno!
Yoshizumi!
Hey!
You can't go any further!
Let's search again
once the blizzard has ended!
Let me go!
Yoshizumi!
Tatsuno has gone to join
his wife and child.
If I could,
I'd do the same thing!
Tatsuno!
Yoshizumi!
Soviet Union's Mirny Station
Chile's Frei Montalva Station
Frances D'Urville Station
November, 1982
Dawn already?
Want me to drive?
I'm alright. Please sleep.
I can't.
Only five days left
until the Antarctic conference.
Until we reach Palmer station...
...we'll have to keep this pace.
Will all 11 countries...
...be at the antarctic conference?
They should be.
It's a meeting
to decide the fate...
...of the survivors, after all.
We can't be late.
Wait a second.
Hit it again!
It's no use!
I'm sorry.
It's not your fault.
What should we do?
There's no time!
Shall we walk?
Walk?
We're still 620 miles
away from Palmer station!
Even I couldn't be so reckless.
But since we've come this far...
...Norway's station
should be close.
We should be fine
if we go there.
She's pregnant!
Yoshizumi...
Yes?
Can you stay here
with that woman?
Huh?
I have to get
to the conference on time.
So there's no way...
I can take a woman
about to give birth along with me.
Since you're single,
please take care of her.
I understand.
I'll figure something out.
To give birth at the South Pole
in such times as these.
I hope she's born alright.
One year later, virus MM-88
continued to occupy Earth.
Mankind remained holed up
on the icy continent.
United States - Potomac River
Life is wonderful.
Life is...
...wonderful.
Wonderful.
The world died again.
Several years later...
What are you doing...
...alone in a place like that?
You won't answer me?
Then, keep sleeping
there forever.
Where are you going?
My friends and child
are south of here.
Child? Is it yours?
No, but I love him very much.
It's no use.
There's no one left.
But I'm heading south anyway.