( blowtorch sizzling )
Man: control, rescue team is
in the main service corridor.
control:
Affirmative, colonel.
- What's it look like in there?
- The main power is out.
- Switching to night vision.
- Man #2: Oh my dear God.
- Man #3: What the hell?
- control, we have massive
casualties over here.
control: confirmed. We expected
that when we saw the hull damage.
- Was it decompression?
- Negative on that, control.
lt almost looks like a wild animal
tore through the crew.
- Man #2: What the hell happened here?
- ( rapid beeping )
- Sir, l'm showing four live ones.
- Four?
There's supposed
to be 137 crewmen.
Raiders never hit a ship
this big before.
- We should call in reinforcements.
- cut the chatter, marines.
Locate those life signs, Private.
They're in engineering.
Near the shock point core.
That's it then.
Lock and load, marines.
- ( explosion )
- Hey, look out!
- What's happening?
- The engines are firing.
How is that possible?
( whispering voices )
lt's over.
They're dead. Finally.
( sobbing )
lt's finished.
lt's not finished.
This is too big to end here.
We've been in contact
with a higher power.
God damn it! l've had enough
of your crazy shit, Stross.
You can't see because
you're not a true vessel.
Will you two shut the hell up?!
We still need to work
together, all right?
- We've got to get--
- Quiet.
- Listen. Do you hear that?
- ( banging )
Woman: Oh my God.
They've come for us.
lt can't be more of them.
We destroyed that damn thing.
l won't let them hurt her.
This is Abraxis Rescue Team.
ldentify yourselves.
- Thank God you're here.
- l knew they'd come.
l'm Dr. lsabel cho, chief medical officer of the USG
O'Bannon.
You just get away now. Nobody's taking my baby
away from me again.
Drop the weapon now!
- Nickolas, it's all right.
- Kuttner, don't do it.
- Put 'em down.
- No, please, you have no idea
- what we've been through.
- ( grunting )
They sent you, didn't they?
They think that they
can control this.
They are all fools. can't you see?
lt's already happening.
convergence is here.
We shall all be made whole!
Aggh!
Fools.
control, we've got one blue casualty
and four survivors in custody.
Bringing 'em in.
( mechanical whirring )
Man #1 : What the fuck do you think
really happened over there?
The bodies had these looks
on their faces like whatever
killed those people
drove 'em crazy first.
Man #2:
What's command saying?
Man #1 : command's treating the whole thing as a
navigational accident.
Accident my ass.
Man #3: lt almost looked like
they killed each other.
Man #1 : lf you ask me, something
went seriously fubar out there
and the big guys back home
are trying to cover their big fat ass--
Oh, excuse us.
We didn't see you.
They sent an interrogation unit
all the way out here?
Man #3: What kind of shit
did those bastards
from the O'Bannon get into?
l don't know,
but they are righteously fucked now.
Scans confirm the target
has been destroyed.
lt's unrecoverable.
Unfortunate,
but not a complete loss.
- What of the survivors?
- Only four, l'm afraid.
l'm informed our specialist
is among them.
Luckily, yes. We're prepping
for debriefing now, sir.
l am authorizing
enhanced interrogation techniques.
l see. Do you think that
will be necessary?
We don't have time for subtlety.
There have been questions raised
about what happened at Aegis 7.
When word of the O'Bannon gets out, people will
demand answers.
lf you can't provide them,
l shall be forced
to re-evaluate
my confidence in your abilities.
Of course, sir.
You have seven hours
before your ship docks at the Sprawl.
This situation needs
to be resolved by then.
Yes, sir, l understand perfectly.
What are you standing
around for?
Have the first subject
brought in.
lt's time to go to work.
lt's everywhere,
all around us,
- inside us-- the patterns.
- Hey!
- Guards!
- l see it all now.
- Will somebody talk to me?
- Human life is only a passing phase.
l'm not supposed to be here.
Hey, is anybody out there?
God damn it,
somebody open this door.
lt's okay, Vivian.
Don't worry, pumpkin, we're safe now.
Everything's gonna be just fine.
Soon we'll be back with Mommy
and then we'll all be together.
Man: This is fucking crazy.
l mean, it just doesn't make
any goddamn sense.
We survived that horror show
back on the O'Bannon
just to be locked up here?
You know the reason we're in here
is because that fucking lunatic
shot a marine.
lf anybody should be
in here, it's him.
lt's okay, baby girl.
He's just a little scared.
Don't pay any mind.
l don't have anything to do
with this crazy bastard.
- l don't even know these people.
- Borges, will you calm down?
You're not helping matters.
They have deeper reasons
for detaining us
than Mr. Kuttner's outburst,
Mr. Borges.
There's a great design
behind everything that's happened.
And we're each a part of it now.
Seriously, am l the only one
who didn't go batshit crazy
back on that damn planet?
Stross is right about one thing.
We might have a problem.
l did a tour on one of these
with a med unit a few years ago.
We're on board
a government interceptor ship
in a holding cell
where they detain terrorists.
So what does that mean?
lt means the government
might want someone to blame
for what happened
on the O'Bannon.
And that will most certainly
be us, Alejandro.
This may well be the last time
we see each other.
Don't touch me!
lsabel, what's the matter?
Well, it's about fucking time.
What's going on?
- Why are you holding us here?
- Step back.
Hey hey hey,
take it easy.
- No problem here.
- Nickolas Kuttner,
- you will come with us.
- Huh-uh.
l'm not leaving my little girl.
Don't do that.
Let me talk to him, okay?
Get your hands off me!
l'm not letting you
take me away from her.
- ( electricity crackles )
- ( screams )
Stop. Stop it!
He's had enough.
You'll kill him.
- What the hell is going on?
- l don't know.
( whispering voices )
Let me go, God damn it.
She needs me.
You bastards, can't you see her?
- ln the chair, if you please.
- She's right there.
- ( electricity crackles )
- ( screams )
No no, she needs me.
l have to protect her.
She needs her father.
No no, Vivian, Vivian!
Let me go!
Mr. Kuttner, please calm yourself.
We have some questions.
l'm not telling you shit
until l see my daughter.
Mr. Kuttner,
the mind holds
countless rational
and irrational fears.
For you, the fear
is being burned alive.
- ( beeps )
- ( gasps )
No! No!
( screaming )
( panting )
That was simply an electronically induced
hallucination,
created in the brain,
but the mind is reality,
is it not?
State your name and occupation.
Nickolas Kuttner, ex-marine,
security officer
on the cDc O'Bannon.
What the hell do you want
from me?
You are not here
to ask questions, Mr. Kuttner.
We are going to ask the questions.
You are going to answer them
honestly and completely.
Do you understand?
Yeah, l understand.
We want you to start
from the beginning.
We want you tell us
about the mission to Aegis 7.
Aegis 7.
The O'Bannon got word
to ship out about a week ago.
We were ordered to Titan, where we picked up a
team of civilian tech heads.
Mission specs were sealed
so nobody knew where we were headed.
After we were underway
a few days,
the captain called a briefing.
Stross:
ls that your daughter, Mr. Kuttner?
She's beautiful. My son has
the exact same color eyes.
Mind your business, Stross.
He doesn't wanna talk
about it, Nolan.
His little girl died in an accident
back home a few weeks ago.
Oh God, that's terrible.
l don't know what l'd do
if anything happened to my little boy.
Dr. cho, how's it going, girl?
Hey, Stross, l saw your wife earlier.
She seemed a little stressed.
Alexis is always stressed.
So, lsabel, wanna go grab a drink
at the Hole after this?
They got 12-credit specials
after 0500.
l'm sorry. l can't.
l've got two rookies
with artificial gravity sickness
to deal with.
Ugh! Boring, Doc.
You stay locked in med bay
all the time,
you'll never get a man
interested in you.
Have some fun.
Personally, l think starting any mission
without a drink or six is a bad idea.
l'll grab a beer with you
if the offer's open.
Oh, l don't usually drink
with tech heads,
but sure, why not?
l'm no lowly tech head,
thank you very much.
l'm gravimetric
control engineer, first class.
So what do you guys know
about this mission l don't?
That is what we called you
here to tell you, Mr. Nayim.
commander Sergenko,
l didn't realize you were on this ship.
Excuse me, sir.
l'm Alejandro Borges with
the engineering team from Titan Station.
l understood this was just
a routine gravimetric stabilization gig.
What's with all the secrecy?
This isn't your standard
asteroid patch-up job, son.
This is big time.
lt must be. Dragging our sorry asses
all the way to the edge of the galaxy--
Sergenko:
Eyes up and mouth shut, people.
Good morning, captain.
Good morning.
This is why we're here.
- l'm here 'cause it's double wages.
- ( chuckles )
The planet is Aegis 7.
lt was virtually destroyed
in a mining accident three weeks ago.
As you can see,
the impact has made
the planet unstable.
- Unstable?
- Damn!
That's where we come in.
Ourjob is to hold Aegis 7 together.
Borges: You've got to be kidding!
There is no way--
The captain is not
yet finished speaking.
After we achieve orbit,
eight drop ships will deliver
gravity stabilizers
to these key points.
The artificial gravity web
generated should be enough
to stabilize the planet.
Are you serious?
With only eight units?
That planet is practically
one huge bomb ready to explode.
How long do you think
a few gravity stabilizers
will hold something
like that together?
This is what you
signed on for, Mr. Borges.
lt's too late for you
to back out now.
Any other questions?
When do we drop, captain?
0500. Dismissed.
Stross, cho, Kuttner, Rin,
we would like to speak with you.
l understand some of you
have heard rumors
about what happened
on Aegis 7.
You can speak freely.
Rin: l've heard
they found something on
the planet surface so terrible
a guy called clarke
dropped a whole continent on it.
Something-- something alien.
- Bullshit.
- captain: The rumors are true.
They discovered an alien artifact
65 million years old.
cho:
My God! lt's actually real?
Kuttner:
What the hell is it?
Sergenko:
No one knows for sure.
lt's supposed
to contain certain properties.
What kind of properties?
That's classified, Dr. cho,
even to me.
And l assume the artifact
was destroyed upon impact.
correct,
but satellite imaging
reveals fragments have survived.
Your team's mission is
to locate and secure
whatever can be salvaged
of the artifact.
On a planet that could
explode any minute?
lt will be well worth the risk,
Mr. Kuttner.
Let's cut to the chase, captain.
Just how much
are these fragments worth?
Two million credits a kilo.
You know,
l hear Aegis 7 is beautiful
this time of year.
Man:
Shuttle 1 , prepare for launch.
- Nayim: We're dropping in three.
- You're playing hologames
- three minutes before a drop, Pawling?
- Yeah, l can't pause it right now.
Aren't you a little young
to be on this operation anyway?
- ( laughs )
- My cousin's a genius at two things:
hologames and gravity stabilizers.
We'd be screwed without him.
The real question is,
what are you guys doing here?
You're not engineers.
We're surveying
for gravity fluctuations.
Fluctuations?
The whole planet's one big
goddamn fluctuation.
What the hell
are you surveying?
Locking onto gravity stabilizer.
Releasing docking clamps.
Ready to drop.
Hold onto your breakfast, kiddies.
Man:
Shuttle 1 , drop in five, four,
three, two, drop.
Nayim:
Entering lower atmosphere.
Here's where the ride
gets fun, folks.
Yee-haw!
- l always hate this part.
- crazy bastard, level us out!
( explosion )
Kuttner:
Will you look at that?
Borges: God damn!
cho:
Holy shit!
This isn't a planet.
lt's a freakin' disaster in process.
Borges: This is nearly total gravimetric
and geothermal disruption.
lt seems impossible
the planet's held together this long.
Almost as if--
- As if what?
- Nothing. Nothing at all.
l need more data.
Okay, Noah, Omar,
ourjob is to keep that stabilizer
from overloading.
Let these guys go do
whatever the fuck it is
they're really doing here.
The scanners are calibrated to
the frequency of the mortar fragments.
Sweep out in branching formation.
Maintain radio contact at all times.
Any questions?
Back here at 0900.
- ( explosion )
- Ho!
This is bullshit.
Rin, come in.
This rock is getting
more unstable by the minute
and l haven't found a damn thing.
Kuttner, l've lost track
of your signal.
- Rin.
- come in, do you read me?
- come in.
- Rin, you copy?
- ( beeping )
- Holy shit. Rin, come in.
l've got something.
( panting )
This way, l think.
l gotta be right on top of it.
Will you look at this?
( whispering voices )
( screaming )
Oh God! This is--
( wailing )
What is it?
l don't--
l don't understand.
Ahhhh!
Vivian: ♪ Twinkle twinkle ♪
♪ Little star ♪
- ♪ How l wonder what you are. ♪
- lt can't be.
Papa, what are we, Papa?
What are human beings?
Vivian, no, wait!
Where did you go?
"Daddy will always keep you safe."
- That's what you said to me.
- ( whooshes )
( woman screams )
( screams )
No, not again!
This isn't possible.
come in, do you read me?
come in, Kuttner.
- Rin.
- Where the hell are you?
Sergenko wants us back at the ship.
This place is coming apart.
- Something just happened.
- Kutt, do you copy?
Yeah.
- Yeah, l copy.
- Rin out.
- Papa?
- Vivian.
l miss you so much, Papa.
Oh, baby, l miss you too.
- Why didn't you take care of me?
- ( growling )
l tried to take-- no!
Get away from her.
- ( roars )
- Get away from her, no!
No! Vivian.
What's happening?
( screams )
Get away from me.
Get away from me!
Kutt, what's with you?
You look like you've seen a ghost.
Kuttner, all l got from you was static.
What happened?
l'm not sure.
l saw--
- l saw--
- Nickolas, what's wrong?
Are you in pain?
He's been acting weird
since l found him.
- ( screeching )
- lt could be his suit pressure.
What do you want?
Keep away from me.
Take it easy, Kutt.
Everything's cool.
Kuttner, what is that
in your hand?
- Borges: lt looks like a fragment.
- Vivian: Papa!
Vivian!
- They've got me, Papa.
- No! Vivian!
- Kuttner, stand down.
- Leave me alone.
They've got my daughter
and l'm gonna save her.
- Vivian!
- cho: Someone stop him.
- Kutt, where are you going?
- Vivian!
Stross: He's got a piece of
the artifact. lt's affecting his mind.
Sergenko:
Get after him.
Kuttner, what are
you doing here?
You're gonna have to wait, man.
We got a problem with the power flow.
- Papa!
- Vivian?
Papa, help me.
Keep away from my daughter.
- ( grunting )
- What's he doing? He's gone nuts!
- What the hell is your problem, man?
- l won't let them hurt you, Vivian.
l won't let you have her.
Leave her alone!
- ( growling )
- Get away
from my--
Papa! Papa!
Help me, Papa!
Leave her alone!
( groaning )
My head.
What happened?
Viv, where are you, honey?
Noah, no! Shh!
Don't speak.
You'll be okay.
l need help here!
Borges, Pawling.
What happened?
- Did the monsters get him?
- You bastard!
( grunts )
Oh, Nick.
What have you done?
Rin, Stross,
lock Kuttner in the ship now.
The stabilizer's overloading.
Noah, can you hear me?
Noah!
- Let me see him.
- Noah!
Alejandro, you have
to let me see him.
( groaning )
Stross: Make sure
those bonds are secure.
The artifact's influence
can cause homicidal outbursts.
And how do you know that, huh?
What's really going on here?
Rin, Rin, where's Vivian?
We can't leave without my daughter.
What the hell happened
to him out there?
Papa.
Goodbye, Papa.
Vivian! Vivian!
No! No!
Let me go! Let me go. No!
No! Let me go!
- Let me go. She needs me. Let me go!
- ( beeps )
- ( electricity crackles )
- ( screams )
( Vivian laughing )
There you are.
There you are, baby girl.
- Prep the subject for cryosleep.
- Wait.
Woman:
Yes sir.
Mr. Kuttner will be
of great use to us.
Guards, restrain the subject.
Guard: Hold it right there!
What do you think
you're doing?
Don't hurt me, please.
l was ordered to do it.
You won't take me away from her.
She needs her father.
l have to find her.
l have to keep her safe.
Hurry, you fool.
Alert security.
Tell them he must not be harmed.
Vivian!
Where are you, Vivian?
lt's Daddy, baby.
Don't be afraid.
- ( groaning )
- ( Vivian humming )
Vivian.
Wait.
Don't go, Vivian.
come back.
Daddy's hurt, baby girl.
Just please.
Please wait for me.
Where did you go?
- Papa.
- Viv.
No!
Don't-- don't leave me.
Don't leave me again.
( beeps )
Papa, get up.
You have to get up, Papa.
- Vivian.
- l'm here, Daddy.
Pumpkin.
You have to hurry, Papa.
They're coming.
They wanna take you away
from me.
l'm here, Daddy.
come to me.
We can be together.
Together.
Always.
Always and forever, Papa.
Always and forever.
- There he is.
- What's he doing?
- He's opening the airlock!
- He's gone crazy.
Stop him! No!
Vivian: ♪ Twinkle twinkle ♪
♪ Little star ♪
♪ How l wonder what you are ♪
♪ Up above the world so high ♪
- ♪ Like a diamond in the sky. ♪
- Always and forever.
He came into direct contact
with a shard.
The Overseer will
not be pleased.
But we still have the others.
Bring in Alejandro Borges.
Stross:
Humanity is just the beginning,
the chrysalis
for something greater,
something older, wiser.
We will become.
We must become.
Stross, l'm serious, man.
l will pay you real money
to just shut the fuck up.
What do you think
those alarms were all about?
Oh, uh, Kuttner's dead.
Stop it.
You don't know that.
But l do.
l can sense it.
We are all one.
This separate limited existence
of living matter is just an illusion,
a passing dream.
Great. Thanks for creeping
me out yet again, Doc.
( panting )
( whimpering )
( screams )
Woman: Are you ready
to cooperate, Mr. Borges?
Okay, all right, anything.
Just no more spiders.
Man: Tell us about the disaster
on Aegis 7.
Tell us about the shard.
l... didn't even know
about the damn shard.
l was just there to do a job.
Okay, Noah, Omar,
ourjob is to keep that stabilizer
from overloading.
Let these guys go do
whatever the fuck it is
they're really doing here.
Something's up
with their little expedition.
Suspicious as hell.
Nayim:
What do you mean?
They're here to measure
gravity fluctuations?
- l don't buy it for a second.
- ( loud rumbling )
The planet's breaking up.
Move your asses.
We got work to do.
Pawling: Looks like l'm gonna have
an interesting first day on the job.
Nayim: l knew six stabilizers
couldn't hold it.
Borges: We've got to hold her.
There are still teams on the ground.
Pawling:
The power flow's out of balance.
Gravity fluctuating. Go to manual.
Noah, do you have it?
- Just a second. Almost there.
- Noah!
- Got it! Yes!
- Nayim: Good work, kid. l'm impressed.
- That's my coz.
- Whoa! Whoa there!
Shh. Settle down, big boy.
That's it.
Pawling:
Sliced, diced, dead.
God, come on, there's gotta be
a harder setting than impossible.
Eh, the movie was better.
Hey, l never asked you, Borges,
how did you end up with that arm?
Not much to tell, really.
Mining accident. l lost it when
a grav stabilizer l was working blew.
My coz is being
humble again, Nayim.
Alejandro there saved
five guys off that rig. He's a hero.
We lost 15 men that day.
l'm no hero.
l'm sorry.
Life takes us strange places.
l was going to be a priest
when l was young.
You're a Unitologist, Omar?
You really believe aliens
- created the human race?
- Look at us.
We have perfect symmetry
and a brain as powerful
as the most advanced computer.
And this came out of nothing?
( coughs ) Bullshit.
Laugh if you wish, my friend,
but human life was created
by alien beings.
And when we die, we return to them.
- Grav flux is starting up again.
- We've got an overload.
Nayim:
Gravity web is destabilizing.
She won't hold.
We could drop a dozen stabilizers
on this planet and it still wouldn't keep what's left
from blowing.
Borges: We need to hold it
until the teams get back.
Noah, can you balance the flow?
- Kuttner, what are you doing here?
- ( Kuttner muttering )
- What's he doing?
- l won't let you!
- ( grunting )
- Omar.
- Wait wait.
- What the hell is your problem, man?
- We don't have time for this shit.
- l won't let them hurt you, Vivian.
- Run, baby, run!
- Who's Vivian?
What the hell
are you talking about?
Monster!
Get away from her!
- Almost got it. There!
- Noah.
Yes, we're stable.
l'll kill you. l'll kill you all.
No!
Noah!
Oh my God.
Oh my God. Noah.
- Stabilize.
- Don't speak.
You'll be okay.
l need help here!
What happened?
Did the monsters get him?
You bastard!
- cho: Let me see him.
- Noah, can you hear me? Noah!
Alejandro,
you have to let me see him.
He's bleeding out.
We have to get him back to the ship.
Doc, is he gonna be okay?
- l'm so sorry.
- ( explosion )
Nayim: The stabilizer
is overloading. l can't hold it.
Alejandro, Alejandro,
they need you.
Nayim:
The whole power grid is failing.
Alejandro, l'm sorry, my friend.
Automatic systems are a total loss.
lt's a cascade failure.
There's nothing we can do.
- We have to get out of here.
- This is Sergenko. All units evacuate.
Get back
to the shuttles, everyone.
Move! Go go, move it!
Run, get to the ship now!
The lava is flowing this way.
That's Nolan and Rin up ahead.
There's a chasm ahead.
Don't stop.
Jump it, come on! Jump!
( screaming )
- This way.
- l can't run anymore.
- ( screams )
- Gotcha!
Thank you. Rin.
- Rin! Rin!
- ( screams )
Nolan.
- l'm okay.
- Don't stop. Get to the ship.
Sergenko:
Rin, l'm sorry.
You were a good soldier.
- Oh my God.
- Go around, hurry!
- commander Sergenko.
- Too late.
Borges, take this.
lt's more important
than you know. Protect it.
Get out of here,
all of you.
That's an order.
Get on the ship.
( screams )
Sergenko!
- What is happening?
- Gravity increasing.
( screaming )
- Nayim: ls everyone all right?
- Omar! Omar, above you. Look out!
- Omar! Omar!
- Borges, we can't help him.
- We have to go.
- We must get to the ship.
( grunts )
What the fuck is happening?
- Get me out of this.
- Shut the fuck up,
you crazy motherfucker!
Buckle up, guys.
We have to get off the planet.
Someone cut me loose,
God damn it.
Hold on.
Stross:
The planet's going.
Why is the engineer
flying the goddamn ship?
- Borges!
- l'm barely a pilot, okay?
- l think l'm gonna throw up.
- Aim for Kuttner.
Shit!
We've lost Shuttle 4.
We must get the shard back
to the O'Bannon.
What are they doing?
The ship is too close to the planet.
They need to clear the gravity well
before they shock point out.
That bastard's not
leaving us behind. Hold on!
Borges, we have to go faster.
lt's tearing apart now.
The engines--
look out for the engines.
Hold on!
- cho: Borges!
- This is bullshit.
We're coming in too fast.
l told you we shouldn't
have let him drive.
Shit shit shit!
Get those fires out now,
move it! come on! come on!
Are you all right?
Someone call medical.
That son of a bitch!
Man:
Full power to the engines.
- Woman: No contact with survey teams.
- ( crew chattering )
Are we far enough
to shock point?
- You! You knew!
- Hold on, son.
- We've got a situation here.
- She's going.
Emergency power
to shock point drive.
- Shocking out, in eight...
- collision alert.
seven, six, five...
four, three...
- We're not gonna make it.
- two...
( screaming )
- Look out!
- ( explosions )
Emergency thrusters.
Fly with the blast.
Ride it, ride it, God damn it!
Firing thrusters.
Damage report.
Damage report!
Hull breach
in section B.
Shock point drive is down. We have
heavy casualties in engineering, sir.
Weapons control,
vaporize any planetary debris
that gets too close.
Lieutenant Marcus,
send out a distress signal.
Sir, those rocks
will tear us to pieces.
We won't survive very long
without the shock point drive.
l understand
the situation, Ensign Voigt.
Borges, get your team down
to the engine room
and repair that drive.
Mr. Borges,
l gave you an order.
l'm not fixing shit
until you explain
why this fucking rock
was worth my cousin's life, sir.
What are you talking about?
captain, Kuttner had some
sort of psychotic breakdown.
Engineer Pawling
was killed, as were most
of the engineering teams.
Follow me, all of you.
First Officer, l want a full
damage report in five minutes.
Yes sir.
Okay, ladies, man your stations.
The bodies have been
taken to cold storage.
Kuttner is under observation
in sick bay.
captain, perhaps it would be
best to keep the shard
under quarantine until we know
more about its properties.
Mmm, of course.
l was hoping for more, but--
You were hoping for more?
You sent us
on a suicide mission
for a lump of rock?
This is much more
than just a lump of rock, son.
The high l.Q. boys back home
say this will change
the face of science itself--
And that's worth all the people
who died back there?
Easy, Alejandro. l'm sure
the captain couldn't predict
the shard's influence on Kuttner.
Look, son, the shard--
it's worth a lot of money.
Enough for you to take care
of Engineer Pawling's family
for the rest of their lives.
You son of a bitch!
- Borges!
- Take it easy, Alejandro.
- ( loud bang )
- What the fuck was that?
Pieces of the planet
are still impacting the ship.
We need to get clear
of the debris field.
Mr. Borges, if l didn't need you
to save the ship,
you would be
in the brig for that.
Now get your ass down
to the engine room
and repair
the shock point drive,
or we're all dead!
Alejandro?
How old was Pawling?
cho: About 19.
l'm sorry, Noah,
l got you this job.
lt's all my fault.
And you never came into direct
contact with the fragment?
No, l swear. l never
touched the damn thing.
Lie detection states
99.9% truth.
He never touched it.
Thank you, Mr. Borges.
You've been most cooperative.
What's happening?
We'll have you escorted
to guest quarters
for the remainder
of your trip to the Sprawl.
You mean l can go?
Seriously?
You'll have to go through
med scans of course,
but you'll be back home
to your family as soon as we dock.
Oh, thank God.
Thank you. Thank you.
- Right this way, Mr. Borges.
- l can't believe it.
l'm actually going home.
l gotta tell you guys,
a couple times back on
the O'Bannon, l honestly thought
l was a dead man.
Have them remains taken
to cold storage
- and bring in Nolan Stross.
- Yes sir.
( panting )
No no,
what are you doing?
Please don't.
Don't do this!
No! Stop! Let me out! No!
l'll be good. Let me out.
Oh God, please let me out!
claustrophobia.
Most horrible.
Now l take it
you're ready to talk sense.
We're on a bit of a deadline.
l'm sure you understand.
Yes yes, l understand--
better than you
could possibly comprehend.
Dr. Stross, you have been
chief research scientist
on the O'Bannon
for a little over a year now.
One year, two months
and nine days.
And all that while
you've also been clandestinely
a part of our government's
secret investigation
into the alien marker.
ls that correct?
That's correct.
Since l was already a part
of the O'Bannon's crew,
they decided to send us in
after the lshimura incident.
l was to examine
any fragments in the marker
and make a thorough report.
l see.
Now why don't you share with me
the results of your investigation?
After we returned
to the O'Bannon,
l went to check on my family.
My family means
a great deal to me.
The shock point drive
is down?
But how are we gonna get
home without it?
An engineering team is working
around the clock to fix it, Alexis.
Don't worry.
Everything's gonna be fine.
- Won't it, little fella?
- Nolan, level with me.
Does all this have anything to do
with that other research you're doing?
- The government stuff?
- Alexis,
can you please not grill me
during the few moments a day
l get with my son?
l need to go. The captain wants me
to examine the artifact
- we found on the planet.
- What kind of artifact?
- The classified kind.
- What about that doctor
you're always with?
ls she classified too?
Alexis.
You spend more time
with her than with us.
She's a colleague. Why would
l have brought you on this trip
if there was anything going on?
Because you're the senior science
officer and l pestered to come along.
- l've gotta get to the lab.
- You can't keep running there
every time l wanna
have a discussion
about our relationship.
Don't wait up.
- ( baby crying )
- Oh, sweetie.
( shushing )
l'm here.
Mommy's here.
- ( knock on door )
- come in.
caleb, l really should be
starting the analysis of the shard.
captain?
l want some answers,
Mr. Stross.
l nearly lost my ship
recovering that damn thing.
l know l'm just supposed
to turn it over to you.
You'll have to take that up
with home base.
l have.
They tell me all matters
connected with the shard
are need-to-know only.
My goddamn ship's scientist
needs to know more about this
mission than l do apparently.
Excuse me for saying so, sir,
but you don't look well.
lt's the shard.
l can hear it talking to me.
caleb, have you discussed this
with Dr. cho?
( loud rumbling )
Just get the damn thing
out of my sight,
but l'm warning you, Stross,
whatever the hell is going on,
you keep it in your lab.
We're in deep enough
shit here as it is.
lt's even more astonishing than
l could have possibly imagined.
What is, Doctor?
The structure is similar
to a hologram.
Every particle contains all
the information of the whole.
What made this
cuneiform-like symbol?
There's no scratching
or sign of cutting--
as if the crystal itself
gave birth to it.
What?
- What's happening?
- ( voices whispering )
The shard, it's--
Oh, my head.
Some form
of telepathic encoding?
Dr. Stross,
are you feeling well?
l'm fine.
My God, it's a form of DNA,
a blueprint.
Nolan, what are you doing?
lsabel, you won't believe it.
Sandra, that will be all.
- Thank you.
- But, Doctor, we need to run
- a spectral analysis--
- That will be all, Miss Burns.
lsabel, it's amazing.
The shard, it's the key
to an alien language,
a guide to DNA chains
l've never seen before.
This may contain the secret
to the future of human evolution.
Nolan, are you okay?
You seem a little hyperactive.
Try and understand,
this is the finding of a lifetime.
( kissing )
Well, don't let it
go to your head, hmm?
But this could alter
the very destiny of humanity,
- change everything.
- Shh! We'll talk about that later.
But right now...
( laughs )
The shard seems to generate
some sort of carrier wave
so advanced my instruments
can barely detect it.
Though l have a theory
that when it comes into contact
with dead human tissue,
it reanimates the cells,
possibly into a new
and more evolved form.
can you explain what happened
to Kuttner on the planet?
Well, it seems most humans
when influenced
by the marker
become hyperpsychotic.
Only a very small percent
are resilient to its effects.
Kuttner was already on the edge--
his grief over his daughter.
The shard pushed him over
into a delusional state.
And you believe the shard was
originally created by aliens?
A higher intelligence
most definitely,
what a primitive mind
would call God. ( gasps )
God, he says.
Stross, maybe you
should get some sleep.
Stross, Stross?
can you hear me?
( voices whispering )
( screams )
The shard somehow
transmits nightmares,
dreams and visions,
but the knowledge, it emanates.
l need a test subject.
( distant explosion )
Already the signal from the shard
permeates the dead flesh
of the subject.
l've never seen
anything transform
an entire host cell so quickly.
lt's-- it's beautiful.
Damn it!
How can l be expected
to complete my experiments
under these conditions?
What?
That's not possible.
( whispering voices )
- ( growls )
- ( screams ) Oh no!
lt's all your fault, Doctor.
They will all suffer
because of you.
( panting )
H-hallucination.
lt was just a hallucination.
The door-- l broke the seal.
l wasn't thinking. ( gasps )
Good Lord,
what have l done?
- Dr. Stross, l've got the analysis--
- Sandra, get out!
( Sandra screams )
Oh no.
No, get away.
lt's not my fault.
The shard-- it tricked me.
Leave me alone!
Hold the light steady, will ya?
- ( growling )
- lt's still after me.
Here, it won't find me in here.
No!
- Oh my God, no! Oh God.
- ( men screaming )
( panting )
Oh God. Oh God,
l need help.
The captain.
captain, l have to tell you.
lt's about the shard.
Not right now, Stross.
l've got the engine room on the horn.
l need that shock point
back online now, Borges.
Thanks to that class-A
clusterfuck down on the planet,
captain, l barely
have any engineers left.
lt'll be a miracle
if we can pull this thing off.
- Mister, l have taken all the shit--
- ( screaming )
- What the hell is going on?
- We're under attack.
Borges. Borges!
God damn it.
Lieutenant Marcus,
take a security team down there.
- captain, please, listen to me.
- Not now, Stross!
Woman: We have a code 3
emergency in the engine room.
All personnel report
to their stations.
This is not a drill.
Repeat, this is not a drill.
- ( alarm blaring )
- Alexis, the baby.
Emergency stations, move it.
Move it!
Oh oh God.
( screaming )
Alexis.
Lex, are you here?
Alexis, l made
a horrible mistake.
The shard.
l'm not thinking clearly.
- ( baby cooing )
- Alexis?
Son, son, is that you?
- ( screeching )
- Get off of me!
( grunting )
- Where's my son?
- Alexis: Nolan!
That's my baby! No!
You monster!
Get away from my family.
( screams )
( panting ) Nolan.
( shouts )
( panting )
Nolan? Nolan, something's happening.
The bodies--
they're turning into creatures.
lt has to be the shard.
Oh God.
Oh my God.
Seeing those dead creatures
must have truly affected her.
lsabel changed after that,
but l had to do it.
Those things were
threatening my family.
Dr. Stross,
where is your family now?
l-- l locked them
in their quarters.
Did your men find them?
Are they safe? What about the baby?
- His heart rate is 160.
- l need to see them.
convergence is coming.
We have to be together
- when the change arrives.
- Dr. Stross, where is your family?
ln my quarters, l told you.
- Yes, you did.
- ( beeps )
- ( electricity crackles )
- Where is your family?
Safe in quarters.
Saved them-- l saved them.
lnteresting.
l've never seen
such a complete block before.
- lncrease the voltage.
- ( screaming )
l won't!
l won't remember.
- You can't make me remember.
- Really quite extraordinary.
( beeps )
You're just doing what it
wants you to do, all of you.
You're gonna kill me now,
aren't you?
Like you did Kuttner
and Borges.
We don't want
to kill you, Dr. Stross.
- You don't?
- Of course not.
You came into direct contact
with the marker.
lt actually communicated
with you.
Your mind holds the key
to its language.
You're exactly
what we've been looking for.
What is that?
What are you doing?
Please stop.
l did everything l was asked to do.
Why are you doing this
to me? Stop.
Stop it.
Please stop.
Not this, please.
Please please!
lnterrogator: Unfortunate...
about the claustrophobia.
Woman: They will be pleased,
won't they, sir?
Stross is everything
they wanted.
Not quite everything.
Bring in lsabel cho.
Woman:
Sprawl, this is Abraxis.
- Requesting permission to dock.
- Man: Permission granted, Abraxis.
- Welcome home.
- ( lsabel screaming, crying )
You are making this
unnecessarily difficult, Doctor.
We merely wish to know
about the shard's full effects
upon the O'Bannon's crew.
You're talking
to the wrong person.
Nolan studied the artifact.
And we want to know more
about Nolan Stross.
Did he reveal the details
of his investigation to you?
- You were having an affair.
- Why is that relevant?
Dr. cho, l have no wish
to cause you further discomfort,
but if you do not
answer my question,
l shall be forced
to intensify my methods.
Do you understand me?
Yes.
Tell me about your affair
with Dr. Stross.
l-- the affair lasted
several months.
We'd been working together
for a year.
l didn't plan it.
lt was just something
that happened.
He told me he was
going to leave his wife,
but l didn't want him to.
l tried to stay away,
but l couldn't.
For the first time in my life
l was in love.
After we found
the shard on Aegis 7,
Nolan started acting
strange, erratic.
Do you know what's
the most fascinating thing
- about the crystal structure, lsabel?
- Hmm?
The patterns there
are almost familiar,
like a dream
l've nearly forgotten.
l think you've lost me.
l only speak English
and Korean.
This is going to shape
reality itself, lsabel.
Nolan, l want you
to come to sick bay.
Let me run some
psych scans.
Remember what that thing
did to Kuttner?
l don't need psych scans.
You have no comprehension
of what l'm doing here.
l've nearly grasped
its sacred language--
the ultimate source
of human life itself.
Nolan, you're starting
to scare me.
l think it's time
for you to leave.
l have work to do.
All right.
l need to check
on Kuttner anyway.
So how's our patient today?
Resting comfortably, Doctor.
Are you feeling better,
Nickolas?
Head hurts,
still can't remember much.
Do you remember seeing
your daughter?
Of course.
She's out playing right now.
- She'll be back soon.
- Of course she will.
Those engineers better
get the drive working.
l need to get Vivian home
to her mother.
l'm sure they're doing
their best. l have to go.
Try and get some rest, okay?
Whenever l close my eyes,
all l see are monsters.
All right, Doctors. We have
a dozen DOAs to process.
Ripley and Wells should have
finished the prep by now.
The captain
wants a full report by--
( gasps )
oh my God.
- Man: Good Lord.
- The bodies are gone.
What could have done this?
By the Great Marker.
ls that Dr. Ripley?
call the captain.
- We've got to--
- ( growling )
( snarling )
Get out! Get out!
Shut the door!
Run! Get out of there!
- Shut the door!
- ls that door gonna hold?
- Did everyone get out?
- What is it?
- ( alarm blaring )
- Emergency stations.
Everyone get
to your posts now!
- Move it!
- ( screaming )
- Kuttner: Doc, what's going on?
- My God, this can't be happening.
- Doc!
- lt can't be.
- Am l going crazy?
- ( crashing )
What the fuck is that?
- Oh no.
- Get me out of here.
Get me off off this table now.
lt's the monsters, isn't it?
l knew they'd be back.
- ( screaming )
- ( snarling )
come on!
come on, you bastard.
Here l am,
right here.
What the hell is it?
The shard's behind this.
l can feel it.
( explosion )
- Where's the rest of the crew?
- l don't know.
- We have to find Vivian.
- l'm sure she's safe.
Look, if the shard's doing this,
then we need to find Nolan.
come on.
All this blood--
what happened
to all the bodies?
Man: They changed.
They became one.
l saw it.
l saw it happen.
Kuttner:
chief, is that you?
They want you too.
They want you both dead!
- Oh shit!
- chief, what are you doing?
- ( screaming )
- Let's go. This way.
Right behind you.
- Where are we now?
- This is Nolan--
l mean, Dr. Stross' quarters.
Wait here.
- Keep your eyes open.
- No shit. You think?
Nolan?
Nolan, something's happening.
The bodies,
they're turning into creatures.
Nolan, is that your wife?
The baby.
Nolan, what have you done?
lsabel, we have to
warn the others.
- l accidentally released the infection.
- Keep away from me.
Keep away from me!
- You monster!
- Doc?
- Stross: lsabel.
- You monster!
What is it?
What's the matter with you?
- ( gunfire )
- Look out. There's another one.
- How many of these things are there?
- On your left.
- Aim for its eyes.
- lt's still coming!
- Get out of the halls.
- Get to safety.
- Look out!
- ( screaming )
- lt's still coming!
- Stross, what the hell is going on?
- What are these things?
- They are the future, captain.
They're what we were always
meant to become,
- glorious and immortal.
- God damn it, Nolan. Get it together.
What's wrong with you, man?
captain,
we've got more company.
Too many to fight.
We need a way out.
Vivian. Baby, is that you?
Vivian, wait.
- come back. lt's not safe down there.
- Kuttner.
- Where the hell's he going?
- No, he's right.
- They can't follow us through there.
- Then hurry. Move your ass.
- He went into the vent.
- Get moving!
- l'll cover you.
- Keep going all of you.
- Hustle it up, Pallas.
- Right behind you, captain.
No!
Let go, you son of a bitch.
- Ow!
- Officer Pallas.
caleb, get them out of here!
- Officer Pallas. Leslie. Leslie!
- There's nothing you can do.
She's gone. She's gone!
She--
she was a good officer,
a good shipmate.
We need to keep going, captain.
Those things may find a way
into the vent.
come on, Vivian went this way.
By all means, let's follow the ghost
of his dead daughter.
l'm not entirely comfortable
depending on someone
who has obviously lost his mind.
Yeah, l know exactly
what you mean.
Vivian says we should
go down there.
cho: l think we're over
the science section.
captain: This is your lab,
right, Stross?
Sounds quiet enough.
lt's all clear.
- come on.
- Something's got him.
No! Borges, it's us.
- lt's Kuttner.
- l know who it is.
- ( gun cocks )
- Take you with me.
Stop it. Stop it!
We don't have time for this shite!
calm down, Alejandro.
l only want safety
for my daughter.
Your daughter's dead, asshole.
Just like my cousin you killed.
No, Vivian, don't listen.
He's confused. He's just scared.
Borges, what's the situation
with the shock point drive?
Did you get it operational?
Fuck no. The engine room
is totally fucked!
We barely got out.
- We?
- Sorry, captain. We were overrun.
captain:
They got the bridge as well.
Let me take a look at that arm.
Pretty rough laceration,
but you'll be okay.
- l'll need some help here.
- l'll help, love.
lsabel, what is wrong with you?
Keep away from me,
you sick bastard,
or l swear l'll throw you out there
with the rest of the monsters.
Stross, we could
use you over here.
- Yes, captain.
- What the hell is going on?
Why is my crew turning
into goddamn monsters?
Homo sapiens
are the true monster.
These are higher forms of life.
We're becoming them,
and soon we will all become one.
- What did you say?
- lgnore him. He's not well.
No no, there's an old
Unitologist proverb:
all forms of life will unite
in convergence
and we shall be one.
My mom said that we were living
in the end of days.
- convergence is coming soon.
- ( loud bang )
By the look of things,
it seems like your mom was right.
So how the hell do we stop it?
Stross, you're the only one
who understands those things.
How can we stop them?
Nolan, look, we need you, okay?
The necromorphs are animated
by the signal from the shard.
We have to stop the carrier wave.
Then give me that goddamn thing.
l'll stop it.
Didn't even scratch it.
There's no way you can
destroy it, only shatter it.
And every piece will retain
the properties of the original,
like a hologram.
There's got to be a way.
No no.
lt was designed by an intelligence
we can't begin to comprehend.
You would have to cast it
into the heart of a star.
Or a reactor core?
Yes.
Yes, that might do it.
Then we take this thing
to the engine room and we destroy it.
Are you serious? The engine room
is fucking crawling
- with those things.
- Then we fight our way through them.
We don't have a lot of choice.
The ship can't take much more.
What do we have for weapons?
Just your gun and these bone saws
we grabbed in medical.
l was working on those things
until you guys showed up.
captain: Are you actually building
something out of all this junk?
Flamethrower,
a few incendiary grenades.
Found some plasma cutters--
charges are pretty low.
Okay then.
can you travel, Lieutenant Marcus?
- Yes sir.
- Then everybody arm yourselves.
Let's go.
Kuttner:
God damn, it's quiet.
cho: Those things couldn't have
gotten the whole crew, could they?
- captain: Everybody stay together.
- Borges: Wait. What was that?
l thought l heard something.
- lt's clear. This way.
- ( metal rattles )
l know l heard something.
- Look out!
- Marcus, get out of here!
Aw shit!
cho: Move it.
lt's right behind you.
- l think we're just pissing it off.
- Got any better ideas?
- Yeah, run!
- cho: This way!
Hurry! Down here.
- Jenny?
- Lana, don't get too close to it.
lt's all right.
lt's my roommate Jenny.
Praise the Marker.
Jenny, are you okay?
Lana, no. Get away from it.
- Lana!
- ( screaming )
- captain: They're right behind us.
- Borges: come on, Doc, we gotta go.
Let's see if this
bad boy works.
( explosion )
Finally. The engine room's
through that door.
We're not too far
from the reactor core.
We're not there yet. Look!
( snarling )
Let's go! Move it!
We've got a hull breach!
Hold on to something.
( alarm blaring )
We're losing oxygen.
Get to the engine room.
We can seal the airlock there.
- Help me! Oh God, help me!
- Hold on.
- captain: Hang on, son.
- l'm coming for you.
Almost got you.
A little closer.
No!
- No!
- cho: Nickolas, look out!
Kuttner!
( grunting )
Got you.
Thanks.
come on, move it.
Get your asses up here.
- We have a problem.
- What now?
The power is out
to the airlock door.
lt's damaged on our side.
lt has to be closed
from out there.
Kuttner: Anyone out there
will be torn to pieces.
- l'll do it.
- No, you'll be trapped.
- cho: captain, we'll find another way.
- You will do as you're ordered, Doctor.
You too, Mr. Borges.
Send this thing back to hell
where it belongs.
And tell my wife she was right.
l should have retired
before this trip.
All right, you bastards!
come and get me!
My God. He's gone.
The captain's gone.
- Now what?
- l'll tell you what.
We throw that damn thing
into the core like he told us.
This way.
There it is.
The shock point drive.
The most powerful machine
mankind has ever created.
cho:
How do we do it?
We throw it into the core
over the edge
of the platform. There.
( screaming )
cho:
No, the shard!
l've got it.
Oh shit.
( low roaring )
l am so fucking sick
of these fucking things.
You and me both.
Oh shit!
There's too many!
- cho: No!
- Borges: Get off,
you son of a bitch!
( whispering voices )
Get away from him!
What is Stross waiting for?
Throw it into the core!
Destroy it.
Kuttner:
Stross. Stross!
( voices whispering )
Nolan, what the hell
are you doing?
Destroy that thing now!
- God damn it, Stross. Gimme that!
- Don't you see, lsabel?
- lt's too important to destroy--
- Oh shut up! ( grunts )
Throw it!
Throw it now!
( explosion )
- lt's over.
- They're dead.
Finally.
lt's finished.
( gasps )
You know the rest.
lt's a pity you didn't come
into direct contact
with the shard.
You have a fine mind
and a strong will.
l'm sure it would have...
resonated with you,
as it did with Stross.
Oh my God.
You knew what would happen if we
found the fragments, didn't you?
We are not ignorant
of the marker's capabilities.
You didn't just want the fragments.
You wanted us exposed to that thing!
All that horror,
all those deaths--
you did it on purpose.
You have nothing to fear.
ln the end, you won't suffer.
- l promise.
- l don't understand.
During our session
we docked at the Sprawl.
There is someone here
who would like to speak to you.
Ah, my dear Dr. cho.
lt's a pleasure
to finally meet you.
l'm so sorry
about any discomfort
this process may
have caused you,
but you must understand
how important this project is.
Project?
What project? Who are you?
l? l am a simple Overseer
to a greater purpose.
We are working to change
the face of humanity, my dear.
come with me and l'll explain.
Doctor, you and your team
did a fine job.
- My compliments.
- Yes sir.
Thank you, sir.
l'm very happy
that you're pleased.
Very pleased indeed.
Good day.
Praise the Great Marker.
l thought ourjobs
might be in jeopardy.
Do you think
we might be promoted?
l'm sure the Overseer will see
that we are appropriately rewarded.
( gun cocks )
Overseer: As a doctor,
you must see that the marker
is the greatest discovery
in the history of humanity.
lt has the potential
to alter human DNA,
to save our flawed dying species.
lt turns people
into mindless monsters.
ls that the kind of nightmare
you want to unleash?
lts power is controllable
under the right circumstances.
We just need some more time
to continue our research
into the marker.
Regrettably, these recent events
have become too public.
We need an airtight cover story
and we'd like you
to help us with that.
You want me to just forget
everything that's happened?
To my shipmates on the O'Bannon
and all those colonists on Aegis 7?
We have significant resources
dedicated to this project, Dr. cho.
You'd be an important part
of the team.
ln a few years, you could be heading
the whole medical sciences division.
Please consider helping us
with this great work.
l won't do it.
You're playing God
with human life.
People deserve to know the truth.
( sighs ) lsabel,
l'm truly sorry you feel that way.
What-- ( grunting )
Secure the patient.
What are you doing? Stop it.
Get your hands off of me.
Stop! Let me go!
Everything is ready.
You may proceed.
- What are you going to do to me?
- Someone has to be held responsible.
- ( whirring )
- No! Please don't do this.
Please, oh God! No!
No!
Woman: Authorities today announced
the arrest of a suspect connected
to a recent series of terrorist attacks
on the USG lshimura, the USG O'Bannon
and a mining colony on Aegis 7.
lsabel cho, a former medical officer
assigned to the O'Bannon,
was rescued from a lifepod
recovered after the O'Bannon's
engines were sabotaged
and the ship destroyed.
lnterrogators have received
a full confession from Miss cho,
and sentencing is scheduled
for next week...
The cover story is working well.
People believe what
they wish to believe, Dr. Edgars.
- Yes.
- ( door opens )
Ah, it appears
Dr. Stross has arrived.
Excellent. That makes two
who have come into contact
- with the marker.
- Two? Who is the second?
The engineer
who destroyed Aegis 7.
We found him half crazed
in an escape shuttle.
lmagine our luck.
Synchronicity reveals the will
of the cosmos, Dr. Edgars.
Of course, Overseer.
Be gentle with the patient.
His mind is the key
to the secrets of the marker.
Yes sir.
Welcome to your new home, Nolan.
Welcome to the Sprawl.
♪ Twinkle twinkle, little star ♪
♪ How l wonder what you are ♪
♪ Up above the world so high ♪
♪ Like a diamond in the sky ♪
♪ Twinkle twinkle, little star ♪
♪ How l wonder what you are. ♪
( instrumental music playing )