Ahhh.
Mr. Martin.
Mr. Martin, come quick.
There's a man
up at my place.
Take it easy.
No time to take it easy.
You've got to come right away.
You know, Eli, in all the months
I've been on this job,
there hasn't been one week
you haven't had three
or four people
skulking around your place.
But listen...
You got money
in your mattress or something?
This man wasn't skulking.
He was, I don't know what,
staggering around like
he was lost.
Maybe it was just
his weekend that get lost.
Mr. Martin,
this man ain't drunk.
If he's not.
She sure is.
Deputy, I'm telling you,
this fellow's different.
Well, you keep him
that way, Eli.
I'll drop in on you
on my way back.
Hello there.
You could have
ended up like that.
Officer,
I know
there's no excuse.
I agree with you.
May I have your...
I was going pretty fast,
wasn't I?
You were going
pretty reckless too.
You know,
this is an old road.
It's tricky and dangerous,
it's lined with signs
that say 25 miles an hour,
15 miles an hour,
"Winding road."
Now, those signs
can be quite interesting
if you're going slow enough
to read them.
I've read them
all before.
What do you think
we put them up for, pedestrians?
Can you give me one good reason
why any sane person would drive
the way you were driving?
No.
You surprise me.
I was sure you would.
Well, actually, Officer,
I'm maladjusted.
I come from
a broken home.
Want me to write
that down for the judge?
You're not going to
throw the book at me,
are you?
Well, here's what
I'm going to do.
I'm going to reach into
the hat and pull out just
one of your violations.
Forty-five miles
an hour in a 25 zone.
Sign there, please?
Here's your copy.
I'll save the reckless
driving charge for next time.
Operator! Operator!
The sheriff's office, quick!
Sure looks like he put up
quite a struggle.
Yeah.
Be sure and don't touch
any of this stuff, Eli.
Don't worry. I know
all about these things.
No identification
of any kind.
No wallet.
Labels all cut out
of the clothing.
All we have for sure is
that he wasn't a suicide.
Ah.
Not with his hands tied
behind his back.
You should have listened to me.
I told you to come up right away.
Now, Eli.
Remember the story
about the boy who cried wolf.
Don't you go trying
to put the blame on me, Sheriff.
Nobody's blaming anybody, Eli.
If we followed up all your stories,
we'd have to put on two extra men.
Which, by the way,
you taxpayers won't let us have.
You know, it's no wonder
old Eli lives alone.
No woman could stand
to listen to him all the time.
I wish I'd listened
to him this once.
There's not enough time in the day
to stop and measure all the ifs.
You made the same choice I would
and went after what you saw
instead of what you didn't see.
That's what you're paid to do.
I know that.
It doesn't make me
feel any better.
If I'd gone with Eli,
that man might still be alive.
Now, look, boy.
When I hired you,
I hired myself a good lawman.
I didn't think about
what happened in Denver then.
You stop thinking about it now.
You shout your mouth
and solve this case.
- Morning, Deputy.
- Morning.
Rising with the sun,
or just going to bed?
Hoping to catch some worms.
I'm trying to get a line on a fellow.
Thought maybe you could help me.
I'll do my best.
Fellow about 55,
60 years old, tall,
grayish hair,
distinguished-looking.
When last seen,
wearing a suit of thin,
dark gray shiny material.
Doesn't sound like
anybody I've seen.
Thanks anyway.
Oh, if he turns up, do you want me
to tell him you're looking for him?
No, thanks.
He's turned up already.
Oh, yeah, here it is.
R.E. Wallace,
El Trovatore Motel.
That's all?
Well, that's all you asked me.
Well, that's all you've got?
No permanent address or anything?
Nope.
Well, you must have asked
to see his driver's license.
Why?
Well, most people do
when they rent an automobile
to a perfect stranger.
Oh, he didn't rent the heap.
He bought it for a 150 bucks.
C.O.L. Cash on the line.
Well, registration?
Oh, he hasn't gotten around
to fill that out yet.
Hey, look. You're the law.
What do you think? Should I
send it to him at the motel?
No, send it to the county morgue.
Good morning.
Morning.
Looks like it's going to be
another scorcher, don't it?
Yes, ma'am.
Are you selling tickets
for the sheriff's rodeo,
or are you
just raiding the place?
I wouldn't think of it.
Just trying to track down
some information
on a Mr. R.E. Wallace.
Oh, yeah. Number 8.
I don't think
he's here now, though.
I don't see his old yellow car.
You mind if I take a look
in his room?
Why should I mind?
Can you tell me anything
about this Mr. Wallace?
Well, not an awful lot,
I'm afraid.
He's been here
four or five days,
but he's not gabby
like most of us.
Very quiet,
fine-looking gentleman.
I'd say a businessman of some sort,
probably from the east.
Has that funny way of talking.
This is 8.
What?
What in the world
could have happened?
This is just awful.
Why everything's ruined !
I'll certainly have plenty
to say to that Mr. Wallace.
I don't think he did it, ma'am.
How can I ever
get it cleaned up?
Don't touch a thing, please,
as a favor to the state of Arizona.
No label on this clothing either.
Not even any laundry marks.
All this expensive luggage.
But no initials on it.
Nothing.
What does that mean to you?
First I thought the killer
was trying to cover up
the identity of the victim.
Now I think the victim
destroyed his own identification.
How do you figure that?
Any man who buys luggage
as expensive as this
usually has his initials put on it.
Could be.
Could be, brother bloodhound.
Don't just stand there.
He ain't treed yet.
Get out and see
if you can pick up his track.
It's sure funny how now,
when I got nothing to say to you,
you keep wanting me to talk.
You've got to keep talking,
Eli, till I can make
some sense out of it.
I can't remember crazy talk
when it don't make sense.
Well, try. Think.
What else?
Over.
He did say something
about over the rim.
Over the rim.
That must mean the Grand Canyon.
Well, that narrows it down
to Arizona anyway.
Come on, Eli.
Did he say anything else
that you haven't told me?
Well, but I'm not sure
I heard it right.
Come on.
It sounded like
"dancing in the bucket."
Dancing in the bucket?
Uh-huh.
At least that's what it sounded like.
Got any idea what it could be?
Over the rim.
Dancing in the bucket.
Bucket.
Hey, wait a minute.
You just keep your mouth shut.
Hey, Jack! Over here!
Mr. Ward?
Yeah. Oh, hi, Deputy.
Say, what do you call
that contraption out there?
Tramcar.
You see anything of him?
Around here we call it
the dancing bucket.
Who's he looking for?
Charlie Piper.
Old Charlie's one of the guys
that works here. He's missing.
What's he look like?
He's about 30, maybe 35.
You seen anything
of a man about 60,
grayish hair, 5'11", well built?
No. Nothing around here
but us chickens.
You know what happened?
One time a guy did end up
down there.
Can you imagine? He got so busy trying
to get his ladder working, he just...
walked right over the edge.
How do you figure that?
How long has old Charlie Piper
been missing?
I don't know for sure.
He's a watchman around here
on the weekends.
When we come on today,
he wasn't around.
And you didn't think of
reporting this to the sheriff's office?
Hold on.
Don't take me in yet.
We don't think nothing
of it around here,
when a guy's missing.
What do you mean?
The work. Gets them.
See the bucket out there?
Well, that thing travels 9,000 feet
across that canyon
to that cave on the other side.
Inside that cave,
there's about 500,000 tons
of prehistoric bat guano.
Man, that's a lot of fertilizer.
The only way
to get the stuff out's
in that bucket.
I figure old Charlie
probably got tired
of shoveling the stuff
and riding the bucket,
so he lit out.
Next thing you know,
he'll be sending us postcards
from Las Vegas or somewhere.
Hey, Jack!
What about it?
Bill, not a thing.
All right, bring it on in.
It's time we got back over
at the other side
and start hauling guano.
I'll ride back over with you.
Have you searched
the other side yet?
Nothing over there
but that cave and the cliff
and a lot of tired, worn-out bats.
Well, if you find anything,
notify us, will you?
All right.
Want to ride over
and take a look for yourself?
No, thanks.
Howdy, Deputy.
Hi.
Hi, Harry.
Hi, Joe.
Scotty?
Les, what can I do
for the long arm of the law?
Well, I could use
a double shot of bourbon,
but I'm on duty.
Coffee.
Say, you know Charlie Piper?
One of my regulars.
Did he ever say anything to you
about leaving his job?
Well, he had dreams,
just like everybody else.
What about you? You want to wear
that green uniform the rest of your life?
I used to have other ideas.
I got a terrific notion.
Yeah? What?
Well, here we are,
two healthy boys,
you with the good looks,
me with the baby fat,
hanging around a ghost town,
waiting for the dry rot to set in.
Now, ain't that
a kick in the head?
I won't argue.
That ain't normal
for two boys like us.
I got an idea. Why don't you
go out and disconnect
the radio in your car?
Sheriff won't like it,
but that I can do.
Good.
Then we'll
get rid of this thing.
I'll take this packed house,
the whole three of them,
throw them out, lock the door,
and (WHISTLES) we're off for Las Vegas.
Scotty, I like you.
And I like your notion.
Tell you what.
I'll donate my car.
The siren will speed things along.
Ah, we'll go for two,
three days.
Maybe the whole week.
We'll do nothing
but a lot of drinking
and gambling,
carousing and disturbing the peace.
Building mind and body.
Only one thing.
I work for the county. I'm poor.
Friend, money can't buy
happiness.
All the money we need
is for that first drink.
Then along comes
this doddering, wealthy widow,
somebody about 22
and eager to buy the next round.
Keep dreaming, Scotty.
We're one girl short.
Tell you what. I'll drop in later,
and we'll make more definite plans.
Thanks for including me.
Well, don't dawdle, boy,
because youth is fading fast
over the horizon.
None for me, thanks.
I have to drive.
Bobby, why don't you go
inside in the back room,
lay down for a while,
and then drive?
Did you snitch my keys
out of my car again?
No.
You did, didn't you?
Steady now. Steady.
Oh, he'll be all right.
Marshal.
How's law and order
in the Old West?
Could be better.
Could be worse.
May I see
your driver's license?
Of course you can.
No, just the license, please.
Thank you.
You connected
with the Kendon gold mines?
I'm not bragging.
Any relation to Janice Kendon?
Marshal, we don't bandy
the names of womenfolk
in our saloon.
Scotty, can you keep an eye
on his car?
Maybe he'll be in shape
to pick it up in the morning.
Wait a minute, Sheriff.
You're not going to lock him up for this?
Nah, he can afford
to feed himself.
I'm going to take him home.
Come on, boy.
Here we go, friend.
What did you
bring me here for?
Well, isn't this
where you live?
I just exist here, man.
If I want to live,
I gotta go someplace else.
Hey, Jan!
I'm back here.
Come out!
Come out wherever you are!
Hi.
Where did you find him?
Well, your husband seemed to need
a little help getting home.
What shall I do
with him, ma'am?
Oh, he's no trouble.
You just back him up
like this and press firmly.
Aaah!
It's all right.
He's only my brother.
Oh.
He always responds
beautifully to cold water.
Wish I knew why he had
to drink so much.
That step's a tricky one.
If you'll excuse me,
I think I'll slip into
something more comfortable.
If anyone asks for me. . .
We will.
Hi, Dad.
If it were anybody but you,
I'd say you needed a drink.
So I drink. So what?
Better get in
and change your clothes.
That's what I call a brilliant idea.
Good afternoon.
How are you, sir?
Hotter the weather,
hotter his temper.
Sure.
I haven't seen you
around the place before.
Oh, I'm sorry, Dad.
This is Deputy...
Les Martin, sir.
Jim Kendon.
Scotch, rye or bourbon?
Well, do you have
any beer around?
We'd be dead if we didn't.
Can all right?
Yes, sir. Fine.
What have you been doing
these days
besides chasing girls
and giving them tickets?
They letting you in
on the murder case?
You know, that was my old office
where they found that man.
Yes, we know.
Thank you.
When was the last time
you were there, sir?
I haven't used it since
the Battle of Gettysburg.
The only time I go over there
is when I get lonesome
for the old days.
Well, pleased to have met you,
Mr. Martin.
I'd better be getting back
to my fossils.
What kind of fossils?
Dad likes to wander up
and down the canyon
picking up rocks.
He's pretty much
retired these days.
I think it makes him
a little sad to see the mines now.
The way it does me.
I go and wander around
the place sometimes.
Watch it fall apart.
I'm sorry.
Do you want to sit down?
Oh, no thanks, Miss Kendon.
I've got to get back to work.
You're a real dedicated
public servant, aren't you?
Not dedicated enough,
I'm afraid.
Why do you always look as though
you have something on your mind?
Well, because I have.
One thing I'll regret
the rest of my life is
chasing you the other day
to give you that ticket.
Why, Officer Martin,
that's the most gallant thing
I've ever heard.
Yup, that's me.
Gallant but stupid.
While I was handing out
speeding tickets,
that's when the man
was being killed.
Well, thanks for the drink,
Miss Kendon.
I didn't know.
I'm sorry.
Ward, hi.
You got something?
Remember that fellow I said
had taken off for Las Vegas?
Yeah.
Not so sure about him now.
That's his watch.
One of my boys found it
up the canyon.
At the rim?
Close to it.
It was over by a boulder.
Well, you know,
even a dollar watch
wears out sometime.
Maybe he just
threw this away.
Not Charlie Piper.
Like a kid about that watch.
Sort of a lucky piece, you know?
You don't think
he'd have gone to Vegas
without this, huh?
I don't think
he'd go anywhere without it.
I can't hear them.
That's because you never knew Kendon
the way it used to be.
You know, there were
10,000 people living here
when the mines
were going full steam.
Oh, it was
a wonderfully noisy place.
The clatter of the big mills
and the whine of the conveyor belts.
And every now and then,
a great big, beautiful explosion.
And all day long,
kids laughing
and playing and howling
at each other.
It was a rip-roaring town too.
You know, Scotty's saloon
was just one of seven.
Dance hall girls.
Say, Methuselah,
how old are you?
It was less than 20 years ago.
Look at it now.
Yeah.
You know, for a few moments there,
I thought I could hear it too.
Welcome to the club.
Let me ask you something.
Is it possible
there could still be
a lot of gold here
without you people
knowing about it?
Are you kidding?
You're sitting on $20 million
worth of gold
and practically everybody
knows about it.
During the war, the government had to
close down all the gold mines
because they needed
the manpower.
Well, the war's over.
What are they waiting for?
For the price of gold to go up.
I don't see anything wrong
with $35 an ounce.
Nothing wrong with it?
In other countries,
where there's a free market,
it averages about $50 an ounce.
Oh, well, that is a difference.
$24,000 a hundred pounds.
Darn right it's a difference.
Mm-hmm.
My father spent a fortune
sending me to college in New York
to make me ladylike and dainty.
You come along, and in five minutes,
I'm just a miner's brat again.
I think you still look
ladylike and dainty.
I'll slug anyone who says I don't.
With all this gold here, how come
they have only one man guarding it?
Oh, Eli's not here to guard it.
He just keeps the fences in repair
so that the tourists
won't fall down the mine shafts.
And that concludes
the lesson for today.
All right, teacher.
Here we go!
Oh!
Tell me, Les, what do you do
when you finish a day's work?
Go home,
get your notes in order?
Oh, I generally
hang around the pool hall.
Sometimes I get in with a group
to go stealing hubcaps.
You need some recreation.
You mean like a hobby,
like stamp collecting?
Why don't you find yourself a nice,
intelligent, well-rounded girl,
take her out
for dinner and dancing?
I think you're well-rounded.
You might try my house,
say, 7:00 tomorrow evening?
That sounds like a dare.
Oh, it is.
All right, you're on.
Tomorrow at 7:00.
Lightweight gloves.
Keep an eye out for cops.
Hey, what are you
doing down there?
What the hell business
is it of yours?
Get up out of there.
What's your name?
Suds Reese.
What are you doing here?
Minding my own business,
that's what.
I'm hitchhiking my way
out of this lousy state,
so I stopped for a couple of beers
and I'm sleeping them off.
In a gold mine?
I just wanted a cool place to sleep.
You county cops got nothing to do
but give me a hard time?
Wait a minute.
Where did you get those?
They're a graduation present
from me mother.
Yeah?
You must have skipped
a couple of grades
you shouldn't...
Get your hands up.
Keep 'em up.
Now turn around.
Spread your feet. Come on!
I ought to break your neck.
What are you trying to pull, huh?
No wonder you didn't want me
to look at these. R.E.W.
Mr. Reese, if you want
to leave this state, ever,
you better have a real good story
about where you found those.
What kind of a way
is that to talk?
I found them
laying back down there.
And you had no idea
who to give them back to, right?
I don't know any R.E.W.
Reese, you're coming down
to Kingman with me
just to make sure you don't.
All right, get going.
You heard me.
Come on now.
What's going on out here?
I've had
enough trouble out of you.
Book him for assault and battery
and suspicion of murder.
Murder?
Suspicion of murder, huh?
This guy sure gets around
considering he just got out of jail
in Prescott late yesterday.
Late yesterday in Prescott?
You know this guy?
He's one of my star boarders.
Suds Reese.
He likes it,
don't you, Sudsie?
Sure, you got the best
county jail in the county.
Then why did he slug me
when I started to look
at these binoculars?
Old Sudsie's like that.
Look at the initials. R.E.W.
That certainly could be R.E. Wallace.
Where did you get them?
Like I told this joker,
I found them.
Sorry, Les. Probably true.
Anyway, we can book him
for assault and battery.
Sheriff, the county attorney's
on the telephone again.
I'll take it in my office.
Lock him up.
Come on, Les.
You might as well
be in on this too.
I've met
County Attorney Houghton.
He doesn't think very much
of the sheriff's department.
The feeling's mutual.
Mr. Houghton,
Sheriff Edwards.
Oh, that's very reassuring,
Mr. Edwards.
People around town
are beginning to wonder
if we still have a sheriff.
I have in my office
the mayor and Mr. Sanford
of the Kingman Dispatch.
They have the feeling that,
though you may be on the case,
you're not doing anything about it.
Well, we are. Matter of fact,
I got something on it this morning.
Communication on Charlie Piper.
Los Angeles Police Department.
The old goat's just bluffing.
Shuffling papers.
If we don't win the election,
it won't be his fault.
Here it is.
Arrested for hijacking a truck.
Beat the rap.
Apparently, the county attorney
down there wasn't doing his job.
July 6, 1953, was tried and convicted
for the burglary of a warehouse.
Yeah, yeah. Must have been
a different county attorney.
Edwards, I'll tell you one thing.
Neither one of those county attorneys
would have gotten a conviction
if you'd been sheriff.
Because your Mr. Piper
would never have been arrested
in the first place.
Look, Sam, why don't you take care
of your department
and let me take care of mine?
Sam Houghton backed my opponent
the last time I ran for sheriff.
It would make him very happy
if we don't solve this case.
Matter of fact, it might lose me
the next election.
You mean, for both our sakes,
I'd better make some progress, huh?
You got the message.
What are you
all dressed up for?
I'm not all dressed up.
You've got shoes on.
It gets cold
around here at night.
If you must know, I have
a young man calling for me.
Obviously, you can't think
too much of him
if you're not even going
to keep him waiting.
Hi.
Hi!
How are you, sir?
Fine, thanks.
How about a drink?
I'll intoxicate him.
Come on, Les.
Let's live dangerously
and take my car, huh?
Not that dangerously.
You can drive.
Well, in that case...
Good night, sir.
Good night.
I keep coming back
to one theory.
Could somebody be sneaking gold
out of your father's mine?
Your somebody would have
to sneak it out by the truckload
to make it worthwhile.
Well, if you had a big truck
and taking ways,
where would you take the gold?
I've been accused of having
fetching ways,
but this is the first.
This is hardly a big girl's idea
of a gay night out.
Can't we talk about us?
I'm just trying to protect you.
Somewhere in these hills,
there's a murderer on the loose.
You frighten me.
If you don't answer my question,
I'm really going to frighten you.
Yes, sir.
Well, if I were stealing gold,
we miners call it high-grading,
I'd take it down to Mexico.
Fifty dollars an ounce, remember?
Would you have to know
a lot about mining
to discover a rich vein?
Yes, and that's the last
of your questions.
Where are you taking me, Mr. Deputy?
To Scotty's.
I want to ask him some questions.
This is turning out to be
a fabulous evening.
I was hoping to combine
business with pleasure.
Then let's get down to business.
Ah, here we are.
Thanks.
Looks like
your brother's here.
He's always here.
What else does Bob do?
He's supposed to be
a geologist.
Supposed to.
How's that?
Well, he just does it
to keep peace in the family.
I wouldn't say he worked at it.
Or at anything else,
for that matter.
Except flying maybe.
Mademoiselle Kendon.
Reserved table, up front,
not too near the music.
Inspector,
champagne, of course.
Hi, Scotty.
Hi.
I'll join you in a minute.
All right.
Come on.
Drinks are on me.
Hi, Sis.
Stud or draw, deuces wild.
You name it.
Why didn't you come home
last night?
Why should I?
Well, Dad and I
were worried about you.
I'm sorry that you were worried,
but I don't give a damn about him.
Look, Bobby.
No one wants to interfere with you.
Boy, when I think of you
driving those turns at night,
absolutely pie-eyed.
I drive better drunk.
That's because
you've had more practice at it.
How's the new fellow?
And this is
the specialty of the house
for the carriage trade.
Ha! Speaking of
the carriage trade,
have you seen
any strangers around?
In a ghost town?
What would they be doing here?
Well, just in case, if you do,
anyone, anyone at all,
get in touch with me
right away, will you?
If I see any strangers here,
I'm going to grab them,
pull them in here, then roll them.
Then I'll call you.
You have my blessing.
You're a little premature.
You usually get
what you're after.
I can't get you to stop drinking.
You've got to lose sometime.
You've got to stop sometime.
Tell you what I'll do.
I'll cut for it.
See? It's impossible.
Okay, but take it easy, huh?
You too, Sis.
Hey, Scotty,
how about another drink?
For an arm of the law,
you're very light on your feet.
And on yours.
You're a lot younger
than your jokes.
Where did you learn to cha-cha?
I sent away
for a mail-order course.
But the left foot never arrived.
Are you tired?
Uncle.
I'm glad you said it first.
When you're not
drag racing with policemen
or rinsing out your brother,
what do you do to keep busy?
I'm a domestic.
When summer comes,
Dad pretends the housekeeper
needs a long vacation.
So I keep house
for him and Bobby.
Uh-huh. What do you do
in the winter?
Now I know
why you became a policeman.
You just like to sit around
asking questions.
It's my turn now.
All right.
What did you do
before speeding tickets
and the cha-cha?
Well, actually,
I started out to be a lawyer.
Mail-order?
University of Colorado.
I passed my bar exams.
I practiced for two years
in Boulder City.
But I . . .
It just didn't get me.
Not enough excitement?
Not enough fresh air,
I guess.
Then what?
On one of the cases
I was handling,
I met a police sergeant
from Denver. Homicide.
And his job seemed much
more interesting than mine,
so I became a policeman,
homicide.
A detective.
Mm-hmm.
That's interesting.
Were you a good detective?
They seemed to think so.
There was even talk of running me
for district attorney.
I'd have voted for you.
Another round, please.
Well, you can't finish
the chapter there.
No personal life?
No policewomen?
Well, I did meet a girl.
We fell in love, got married.
Had three wonderful years.
Then she became ill.
Everyone was
very understanding.
I couldn't keep my mind
on what I was doing,
and. . . I messed up
a terribly important case.
The department
was kind of glad to see me go.
And when she died,
I just couldn't stay in the same town.
We don't have to talk about it
if you'd rather not.
Oh, it's finished now, I think.
I became somewhat of
a drifter for a while.
I had nowhere to go,
nothing to do.
Until I ran into Sheriff Edwards
here in Kingman.
He knew about me
and practically bullied me
into becoming a deputy,
bless his overweight old heart.
I'll go along with that.
And what about the future?
You could still run
for district attorney.
Well, the main thing at the moment
is to do a good job right where I am.
There's nothing to stop you.
Hello, Deputy.
Good evening, Mr. Houghton.
Miss Kendon, do you know
Mr. Houghton, our county attorney?
Yes, we've met.
I'm glad to see
you're relaxing.
Someone ought to tell him
that all work and no play
makes Jack a dull boy.
Yeah, well, I think
I'd better start getting real dull.
Check, please.
I don't know about you,
but Mr. Houghton just lost a vote.
Mine.
(ON RADIO)
I'm sorry, Mad Dog,
you wouldn't have it
any other way.
Well, Lieutenant,
I guess that closes the books
on Mad Dog Cooley.
Should've listened to 'em, Mad Dog.
Well, you couldn't have picked yourself
a better time to have dropped in.
I just made a discovery.
That fellow who was murdered
is sitting right here next to Mr. Kendon.
Look.
Oh. Here, have yourself an apple
while I phone the sheriff.
Oh, peel it?
Is this the coroner's inquest?
Yes, Miss Kendon.
According to
your previous testimony,
before coming here,
you were a lieutenant
in the homicide division
of the Denver Police Force.
Yes, sir.
You're experienced
in homicide cases therefore.
Well, yes, sir.
I've had some experience, yes, sir.
Perhaps you can explain
why you seem to have
no leads at all
as to the murderer's identity.
As I explained
in my previous testimony...
Is this your testimony
about your discovering this body
or the body earlier this week?
Or the body last week?
When you have
as many murder cases as we have,
you have to be
a little more specific.
I'm sorry.
We're talking about
three unsolved murder cases.
We have three bodies.
It could be we have
only one murder case.
While the manner of these three deaths
shows no similarity,
we believe there's
a strong connection between them.
Would you mind defining
that connection?
When I can define it,
that will close the case.
We know generally
that John Doe and Eli Jones
had met shortly before
John Doe was hanged.
Both men died
in the same place,
a place that's visited by probably
not more than a dozen people a year.
The office of the inactive
gold mine at Kendon.
Mm-hmm.
And the third man?
Charles Piper.
We know that Charles Piper
leaped or fell
or was pushed over
the rim of the Grand Canyon
at Granite Gorge.
Yes, but we don't know why.
When we know why,
we'll probably know who.
Well, that's a well-made phrase.
Mr. Deputy.
Let's go back to Denver.
Thank you.
The last case
that you handled there...
involved the murder
of a 16-year old boy,
one Harris Knight.
Now, according to
my investigation.
Now, wait a minute, Sam.
This has nothing to do with this inquest,
and you know it.
I know nothing of the kind.
But I do know this.
I'm the county attorney,
responsible to the good citizens
of Mohave County,
and they're very upset,
with good reason,
over these three
unsolved murders.
Mr. Coroner, it's up to you
to see that he sticks to the inquest.
I'd like to answer him, Sheriff.
Might as well
have everything out.
You may continue the questioning.
Mr. Martin,
according to my investigation,
you had the police department in Denver
holding the wrong man for trial.
It wasn't until
you were relieved of your job
and another officer replaced you
that the true murderer
was found and convicted.
Yes, sir.
In other words, you were guilty
of several mistakes
and some carelessness
in the matter of Harris Knight.
Yes, sir.
And then again,
according to your testimony,
the deceased, Eli Jones,
intercepted you
on the morning of the 16th
of this month
and he begged you
to come with him
to interview a John Doe,
a man known as
R.E. Wallace,
who was killed later the same day
in the Kendon Mine office.
Now, have I made
any misstatements of fact
up to this point?
No, sir.
According to your own report,
you disregarded Eli Jones's request
and went chasing after a girl.
I wasn't chasing after any girl.
I was taking care
of a traffic violation.
You gave her a ticket?
Yes, I did.
What was the ticket for?
Forty-five miles an hour
in a 25-mile zone.
Well, that doesn't sound
so serious to me.
Certainly not as serious
as murder.
Or even a request
for help from Eli Jones.
When Eli Jones asked for help,
I didn't know of any murder.
And I did see somebody
breaking the law.
You can call it a mistake
only now, after the fact.
You made a mistake
in the case of Eli Jones
and John Doe.
You made a mistake in Denver
in the matter of Harris Knight.
Now, why should we have
any reason to assume
that there won't be further mistakes?
I can't give you any guarantee.
Nobody can.
Mr. County Attorney,
our sole purpose here is to establish
the identity of the deceased
and to determine the cause of his death.
Mr. Coroner,
I'm just trying to do my job.
And I assume that all of us
are trying to do the same.
It seems clear to me
that those of us
who haven't met with
violent death so far
might be reassured
if there were fewer mistakes
and more progress.
Perhaps this entire community
would all feel a little more secure
if someone with a different record
was handling this case.
You seen the morning paper?
You want my resignation?
No, I don't want your resignation.
But if this sort of thing keeps up,
I'm going to have to accept it.
Hey, Martin, you've got
a stack of unanswered
phone calls out here.
Janice Kendon called.
Miss Kendon called to report
she's a missing person.
Janice Kendon would like...
Would like to send you
a food package. Where?
I see at least you
got the messages.
He's been working
like a dog, Miss Kendon.
He is a dog.
Not being a girl,
you can't imagine
how embarrassing it is
if you keep chasing a man
and he keeps hiding from you.
I'm sorry.
All right, Deputy,
put your hat back on
and take the silly look off.
You're gonna buy me
a hamburger.
All right, you're on.
I'll just put these things away.
Oh, I had a professor
of medieval history
had a jacket almost like this.
Yeah? In New York?
Of course.
That's where Norman James is.
Who's Norman James?
Your history professor?
He is the man who makes these jackets
with the funny little round lapels.
Oh, Les, you are a country boy.
Back in the effete east,
you could be ostracized
for asking a question like that.
What are you talking about?
Norman James is the most exclusive
gentlemen's tailor in New York,
and this jazzy lapel
and these crazy pockets
are his trademark.
Where could I find
this Norman James?
Would he be in
the New York telephone book?
You don't think he'd have
an unlisted business number?
He's not all that exclusive.
What's that for?
For being the best girl
a deputy ever had.
Well, hey,
how about my hamburger?
Stay right there.
I'll get you a truck
full of hamburgers.
Rush this out, will you?
To New York Police Department.
Contact immediately,
Norman James.
"Norman James made suit
as described for only one customer,
"Randall E. Whittemore,
"Claiborne Towers, New York.
"Whittemore, Executive Vice President
of Kendon Mining Corporation,
"currently on extended business trip."
Pretty smart of you
to recognize that jacket.
We hicks out here probably
never would have known about it.
Janice recognized it.
Do you think Mr. Kendon
is connected with this somehow?
Well, let's face it.
He and Whittemore belonged
to the same company.
Daughter recognized the jacket.
What if you go out
and have a little talk with Kendon?
Yeah.
On second thought,
it'd probably take
half the time if I went out there.
Well, if you want.
No, no.
You know your way around.
Besides, why send
an old man to do a boy's job?
Hi.
I'd like to see
your father.
My father?
Isn't this rather sudden?
It's line of duty.
Oh. Well, he and Bob
are fighting again.
They're in the den.
Did you find out
about the jacket?
Yeah.
Well, that's good.
You're getting somewhere.
I don't know.
This case is better in some ways,
worse in others.
We'll not discuss
it any further.
That's fine with me,
because I'm sick of it.
Dad?
Mr. Martin is paying us
an official visit.
Howdy.
Hi.
Well, which one of you
two's in trouble this time?
Oh, they're not in
any trouble, sir. I am.
Oh?
Uh, Mr. Kendon,
when was the last time
you saw Mr. R.E. Whittemore?
Randall Whittemore?
Yes, sir.
Let's see.
Last May at the stockholder's
meeting in New York.
You haven't seen him since?
No. Why?
Well, the man
who was found dead
at the Kendon mine office
was Mr. R.E. Whittemore.
What?
Yes, sir.
Oh, no!
I'm afraid I'll have to ask you
to come down
and identify him
at the morgue.
Of course.
This is shocking.
You didn't even know
he was coming out here?
I had no idea.
Hello? Yes, he's here.
Just a minute.
Bob, it's for you.
Who is it?
I don't know. A man.
Mr. Kendon,
isn't it kind of strange,
Hello? Oh.
his not getting in
touch with you?
Yes. It is strange.
Why don't you sit down?
I'll be there right away.
I wonder...
I wonder
what he was here for?
My guess is he found
someone was taking ore
out of the Kendon Mine.
I think you're on the wrong track.
First place,
you don't just walk into a mine
and fall over
a high-grade pocket.
You have to know
something about gold mining.
A lot of people around
here know about that.
Yes.
But even after you
discover the ore,
you still have to
blast it out.
Now, that's hard to do.
Quietly.
Do you have to blast?
I suppose under
some circumstances
you could get it out
with jackhammer and pick.
But you still
have to get it out
and sell it somewhere.
Taking a few hundred pounds
of gold ore at a time, say,
six or seven
thousand dollars' worth,
you could load it onto a truck
or even a small plane.
Yes, I suppose so.
Excuse me.
I think I'll make
some coffee.
None for me. Thanks.
Mr. Kendon,
have you told me
everything you know
about this case?
What do you mean?
I don't have to steal
from my own mine.
I'm sorry
I have to ask you
these questions.
Where's she going?
I have no idea.
You have any idea
where Bob went?
Well, if he's not in a bar,
where he probably is,
he might be out
at the crop duster's strip
where we keep
the old company plane.
I'll be back.
That will be a pleasure
I can forego.
You know you're not
supposed to call me
at home.
Well, merciful heavens,
look who got out of the wrong side
of the bed this morning.
You know who was there
when you called?
The deputy sheriff.
No!
Let's finish loading the plane.
I dug it all myself.
And then we're off to Rio.
Rio? Are you crazy?
Why the sudden change
in our plans?
We sell the stuff in Mexico
and then we head south.
Kid, I know places in Rio
that make Las Vegas
look like a Sunday afternoon
in Philadelphia.
You know, you remind me
of Charlie Piper.
I had him figured
for a lazy loafer
from the start too.
I'm glad I got rid of him.
I got news for you.
If I could fly this crate,
I wouldn't need you either.
You mean you killed
Charlie Piper?
Oh, I should have, but I didn't.
What a character. Just like you.
Never did anything right.
I give him a job,
busting up some rocks.
He lets an old geezer
with a trick suit
catch him at it.
So I said to him, "All right,
Charlie, let him follow you
up to the canyon.
"Then you shove him over the edge."
Gets into a fight
and he can't even lick
an old man.
Who's going to take care of him?
Good old Scotty.
That's cold-blooded murder!
Oh, come off it, kid.
This might have been
a cut caper of yours
to get back at your old man
for being twice the man you are.
Me? I went along for the loot.
That's worth the lives
of two men?
Two? (CHUCKLES)
I forgot to tell you about Eli.
You murdered Eli!
What do you want from me?
He sees a picture of the old snooper
up on the office wall in Kendon.
If I don't get rid of him
and the picture,
everybody in the
whole county would know
who the guy was.
They already know!
Know who?
The headman of the whole
mining combine, that's all.
Well, now, don't that
take the cake?
Before the day's over,
they're going to know who we are.
Here we are all wrapped up
snug as a bug in a rug
and ready to roll.
Now you go to work,
daddy-o.
We put on the lap strap,
turn on the no smoking sign...
and away we go.
No!
Oh, kid, come on.
Don't be that way.
If I said anything
about your old man
you didn't like,
I'll apologize
all along the way.
Come on.
I'm not going.
Oh, kid, don't be a drag.
You know I can't fly this thing.
Kid.
I'm going to have to knock you
off the company payroll.
Bobby!
Bobby! (CRYING)
Bobby.
Doll baby,
I didn't mean to knock him off,
but you're going to be
my ticket out of here.
Now come on.
Your car, let's drive.
Nobody's going to dare
to throw a rap at me
for fear of hitting you,
how's that for a hot flash?
Back it up.
I kid you not.
Car 3 calling KOA 776.
Come in Car 3.
George, let me talk
to the sheriff
Les.
Yeah, Scotty O'Brien's our man.
He's killed Bob Kendon,
taken off in Janice's car
with her as hostage.
Where are you?
Crop duster's strip.
With a flat tire
and a broken radiator.
Now, he's heading north.
Better notify Buzz
to warm up the planes.
We're going to need them.
Okay. I'll pick you up.
George, get the emergency band.
Attention, all units.
Faster, hon, faster.
I said faster!
That's better.
(ON RADIO)
We interrupt this broadcast
for a special news bulletin.
Mohave County's multiple
murder case came to
a violent climax today
with the fatal shooting of Robert Kendon
and the kidnapping
of his sister, Janice,
by a Mohave County innkeeper,
Scotty O'Brien.
O'Brien and his captive
are apparently headed for
Pierce Ferry on Lake Mead
where O'Brien possibly hopes
to pick up a boat
and lose himself
in the vast reaches of the lake
and its 550 miles of shoreline.
And now we return
to Don Hale's musical favorites.
Stop the car.
Stop it!
Back it up.
Now hold it.
To the right.
Let's go.
(ON RADIO)
No sign of them
at Pierce Ferry.
Check the other road. Out.
Let's get out, doll baby.
Come on.
Billy Boy!
Where are you, Billy Boy?
Scotty, you lost your marbles?
Look, Billy Boy,
I've got a boat waiting
for me on the other side
and I need a ride,
and you're gonna
give me one.
Now, this thing is loaded.
How do you like those apples?
Let's move.
Do as he says.
He killed Bob.
Move! Move!
I see her Thunderbird
outside the tram shed.
Seen any sign of them?
No, they must be inside.
We're landing now.
We'll be right there.
Get going.
Billy Boy, let's go.
If you don't pull that switch,
I'll have to pull this trigger.
That's going to make
hard feelings all the way around.
Now, do you get the message,
or does she?
Stop the bucket!
Help me!
Somebody, help me!
Save me!
Oh, my God !
Somebody, help me!
I can't make it!
Oh, Les.
Darling, don't let me go.
Don't you worry about that.
I've no intention of it, ever.
Hey, Ward, take us back.
And be careful.