Brooke...
Whoa,
another terrific half-time show.
Ladies, thank you so much.
They always put on a great one.
Don't they, fellas?
All right,
our Jackson high hornets
are gonna be back on the court in just a few
more minutes. Good job. Nice, ladies. Nice.
And remember, guys, we have
our big championship right here,
home court, next Saturday.
And if I were you,
I would get your...
Brooke, why did you
deliberately block her?
You knew Megan was supposed
to have the last tumble.
Look, I'm really sorry,
coach hanley.
I just didn't want her
to mess it up.
And how many times
have I told you
not to primp
in front of the crowd?
Hand it over.
I'm sorry.
You know what? You're right.
I don't need it.
But, I mean, you could
really use some help.
So, here, take this.
And this.
Do you see how the lip color
matches my nail Polish?
So, how did they do?
Lorene, enough's enough.
I quit.
Here they are,
back again on the court,
our mighty hornets.
Come on.
Let's hear it for them.
Welcome to Jackson high.
Hi.
Your college professors
have given you glowing praises.
I have to give you a hug.
You are my fairy godmother.
To teach and coach...
This is a dream job.
Jumping in in the middle of the
semester's gonna be a challenge.
I'm up for it.
The squad is practicing
right now.
Shall we meet them?
I'd love to.
Okay.
come on, girls! Nice!
Good work.
These girls are really talented.
They can fling themselves around
all right.
Nice!
Hey, b.L.T.!
Hey. "B.L.T."...
That's my nickname.
Blazin' lorene tippit.
We're all about girl power,
aren't we, ladies?
So, let's see, this is Brooke,
jeri, Lisa, Tabitha, Ashley...
Wait, you'll never remember
all these names.
Let me just introduce you.
This is Emma carr.
She's taking over miss hanley's
world geography class.
She's also
your new cheerleading coach.
Hi, I'm Megan Harper.
It's nice to meet you.
You ladies will be happy to know
that coach carr has extensive
cheerleading experience.
Our last coach
didn't know the difference
between a herkie and a hurdler.
Well, I do.
And that was a difficult reload
you guys pulled off.
Who choreographed that?
That'd be be.
I'm impressed.
Well, I see that you all
are in good hands.
I've got a meeting
with the superintendent.
Mom?
Say "hi" to
superintendent tompkins for US.
Okay.
Principal tippit
is your mom?
Yeah. It's a cross
I've learned to bear.
Can I see
what you guys were doing?
Sure.
Hi, I'm Emma carr.
I'm taking over
miss hanley's class.
Nice to meet you.
Hi.
Hey.
Adam reeve, tennis coach,
little u.S. History on the side.
Tennis coach.
I'm the new cheerleading coach.
So, lorene hired herself
another sacrifice.
Have you had
a "fab five" encounter yet?
A "fab five"?
Yeah, fab five,
Satan's cheerleaders.
You think I'm kidding.
This is Helen durant,
the other
world-geography teacher.
Emma... I'm sorry...
Carr.
Nice to meet you.
New cheerleading coach.
Wow, look how young she is.
Are you going to start a pool?
I think it's a must.
Put me down for four weeks.
I'm gonna give her five.
You guys are betting
on how long I'm gonna last?
Nothing personal, honey,
but those cheerleaders
have been through four coaches
already this year.
Yeah, and that last one lasted,
what, three weeks?
So, actually,
we're being very generous
in our expectations of you.
Why don't I get in on that pool?
Hey, how'd it go?
Well, I only saw them
for a couple minutes,
but what I did see, Tim...
They were good.
They were really sloppy,
and they had no Polish.
But I have some incredible
athletes to work with.
That's great.
So, no regrets moving here?
Well, I miss my mom.
I miss my morning runs
with Heather.
I miss US going to church
with John and Anita.
You want to head back home?
No.
I want to see my husband
get his master's degree.
Then what did you have planned?
Maybe making my mama
a grandmama.
Why don't you
take that coat off?
Why don't you?
You know what?
I am totally spanked.
I do not want to deal
with reeve's class today.
Let's just ditch.
I'm down.
I didn't finish my stupid paper
on stupid mccarthyism.
I'm not ditching.
I can deal with coach reeve
any time, any day.
Look, I took this picture of him
yesterday.
Lisa, what are you,
his stalker now?
Shut up.
He's hot.
Um, even if his junk
was on fire,
he still wouldn't be hot.
You're just jealous.
You know what?
Please, stop drooling.
You're gonna get my shoes wet.
Let's go.
Let's go, dude.
Bye.
Bye, guys.
Hold up.
I thought we were ditching.
I turning my paper in first.
It's perfect, and I'm not gonna
let him take any points off.
Are you serious?
I'm serious.
Hey, coach reeve.
Here's my paper... on time.
You know, again, I'm really
sorry I can't stay for class.
I'm certain you can, Brooke.
Go sit down.
Wait, I thought you knew.
Cheerleading tryouts
are next week,
and coach carr asked me to help
her put together a schedule.
She told me this morning
she was on her way
to put a note in your box.
Well, there was no note
in my box, so go sit down.
You know what?
It's probably there right now.
I'll go get it.
And, you know, jeri's
supposed to come with me, too.
Well, aren't you
going with them?
No.
I'm staying here...
with you.
That'd be so cool.
Brooke, thank you.
So, we saw in one
of your magazines
you can apply
to be cheerleader of the month
and actually get on the cover
and everything.
Yeah, you can.
You get more than that, though.
You get scholarship money.
You girls should apply.
I'll write you a letter
of recommendation.
You know what?
I'll bet if I was on the cover
of cheerleading today,
the usc song girls
would totally take me.
You want to be a song girl?
That's great.
I mean, I've seen them perform.
They're amazing. I
know. And you know what?
They also live in L.A.,
which is where my dad lives.
She keeps begging him
to let her go live with him,
but he doesn't have room,
'cause he's got this new kid... excuse me.
My dad cannot wait
for me to get out there.
You know, he said
if I get into usc,
he's gonna add a room
onto his house just for me.
Wait, why aren't you girls
in your third period?
Coach reeve let US go early.
We just wanted to come here
and help you schedule practice
for tryouts.
I mean, you said you wanted
to give US
some individual help, so...
Yeah, I did. I just thought
maybe after school.
Let me look.
What about today?
I can work with you guys today.
What do you need help with?
Choreography? Tumbling?
What?
Well, forget tumbling.
I'm not gonna tumble anyway.
I don't think you have
a choice, though, jeri.
The constitution says
you have to do a back handspring
to get on the squad.
I'm sorry.
I guess you don't know.
I was in a horrible car accident
in October,
and I have a doctor's note
that says
I'm not supposed to tumble.
You know,
plus it messes up her hair.
Shut up.
Well, I will talk
to principal tippit about it
and see
if we can make an exception.
But I can't make any promises.
Hi.
Is principal tippit available?
Yeah, she is.
Great, thanks.
Hey, Mr. Spretnik.
So, what'd you do
this time, reeve?
Just trying to get Brooke
and her gang
transferred
out of my class again.
You really have it in
for my cheerleaders.
No, only five of them.
Emma carr.
Come on in.
Great.
I have been hearing
incredible things
about how you're doing.
Really?
You're a natural teacher.
You have an air of confidence.
And that's what these kids
really respond to. Thank you.
Excuse.
Pamela Blackburn to see you.
Is that
jeri Blackburn's mother?
'Cause that's why
I actually came in here,
to talk to you about jeri.
Lorene.
Excuse me.
I've got a bone to pick with you
over your new
cheerleading coach.
Um, I'm coach carr.
Did you tell my daughter
she's not gonna
make the squad next year
because her doctor
won't let her tumble?
N-No.
That's not what I said.
I did, however, explain to her
the constitutional...
I don't care about that.
You're not gonna keep jeri
off the squad
for something
that isn't even her fault.
I'll take you and this school
to court if I have to.
Now, Pam, no need to put
the fear of god into my staff.
Coach carr was just telling me
about jeri's predicament.
We will get a committee together
with our n.C.A. Rep
and ray studdard
at central office,
and we'll come up... lorene,
I need to know what...
I need to let coach carr
get back to class,
and then I'll answer any
of the questions that you have.
I'll calm her down.
Our girls have been friends
for years.
You just keep up the good work.
Okay.
Thank you.
1, 2...
whoo!
Thank you, Megan.
I'm never gonna live up to that.
Yes, you can, Cindy.
You need to stop biting
your nails and relax.
You're not competing
with your sister.
They want to see your best.
Tabitha doering!
Whoo!
Yay, Tabitha!
Go, girl!
Hey! Yeah!
Honey, please tell me
I didn't miss your tryout
or Megan's?
Janice,
you just missed Megan,
but Cindy hasn't gone yet.
I have to apologize
to Megan.
What kind
of booster president am I,
missing
my own daughter's tryout?
Mwah!
Me and daddy
are so proud of you.
Love you, mom.
Hey, Brooke, I know
your mom isn't here yet,
but she said she promised
to come watch you.
That's funny. She's never came
to see me before.
Jeri Blackburn!
Yeah, jeri!
Whoo!
Jeri! Jeri! Jeri!
Jeri!
Wait, hold on.
Mrs. Blackburn,
what's going on?
We already took this up in
committee, and it was decided...
What makes you think
it's only up to you
and your little committee?
Go ahead, baby.
My gosh.
"Cindy Harper"! I'm in!
"Dakota lumley," you're in!
"Summer Samuelson" in!
Wait, where's Megan?
My gosh!
We all got in!
My gosh, I don't know
how we all did this!
Golly gee,
we get to be cheerleaders.
Isn't that the most exciting
thing in our pathetic lives?
My god.
Jeri, you're not on here.
What? No way.
Coach carr made you co-captain?
Well, I feel like
we could do a really good job
if we work together.
It's okay.
They're jerks.
For a second, I thought
she was gonna run her over.
You know she wants to.
You knew coach carr was planning
to make Megan co-captain
and you said "okay"
when I've always been
the only captain?
Brooke, I can't tell coach carr
that a girl
who's perfectly qualified...
Did it occur to you that
I'm the best one for the job?
Or that Megan has never
choreographed a single routine
because she sucks at it?
You are like everyone else.
You think everything I get
is because I'm your daughter.
I hate you being principal.
I don't even have a mom anymore.
Brooke, I wish
you wouldn't say that.
Well, the truth hurts,
doesn't it, principal tippit?
So, is Megan still gonna be
our captain?
Megan's not our problem.
Our problem is a coach
who thinks she can do whatever
she wants with our squad.
Like hell.
O0 c1oh, my gosh, look at
what Paris Hilton is wearing.
Yo, look at this.
What?
Look.
That's hideous!
Don't worry about it.
Hey, Mr. Spretnik.
Hey, Mr. Spretnik. Hey,
Mr. Spretnik. Hey, Mr. Spretnik.
Now, you girls are gonna behave
this summer, right?
How do you want US to behave?
Gets him every time.
I think he was getting hot
right there.
Ha ha!
My god.
What are you doing?
What's up, baby?
My god, get a room.
Wait, how did you
sneak on campus?
It's the last day of school.
What are they gonna do to me?
Arrest you?
Arrest me? Again?
What's up, ash?
Jeri, better tighten
your animal's leash.
Animal?
Down, boy.
You're such a dog.
Yo, what's up?
I just texted you.
I'm gonna score some bud
for Tabitha's kickback.
You down? Let the girls get
it. He gives it to them for free.
You know what?
Forget weed.
Coach carr will probably make US
pee in a cup at cheer camp.
No, she won't.
Yes, she will,
because that's the kind
of Nazi bitch she is. Bye.
You guys will get it? Will you get
it for me? Shh. Here she comes.
I don't care.
Let her hear me.
Bye, girls. I'll see you
on Wednesday for cheer camp.
Have a good summer.
I wonder what's going on
with Brooke.
She's being so cold.
Well, you don't want my opinion.
Here.
By the way, here's your $200.
We never should have let you in
on that pool.
Well, here you go,
you sore loser.
Buy your wife some flowers.
No, no, no, you won that money
fair and square.
And, besides, I'm not buying
my wife anything right now.
And why not?
'Cause our 10-year anniversary
is coming up in a few weeks,
and I want her to think
that I forgot.
You better remember.
It's a setup.
I've already booked
a romantic weekend.
Looks like coach carr's
moving in on your territory.
I guess you won't be giving him
your little gift now.
Watch this.
I'll let my mother take the kids
for a couple of days.
We get ourselves
a second honeymoon.
And you don't think your wife
is gonna suspect something?
God, I hope not.
Excuse me, coach reeve?
Hey.
I just wanted to give you this.
It's all chill songs
I thought you'd love.
Thank you.
It's very thoughtful of you.
No problem.
Very sweet of you.
So, I will see you
in a couple days, okay?
Bye.
Have a good summer, kiddo.
Thanks.
You, too.
Bye, lise.
He's totally mine.
That was so stupid.
All right, ladies.
Get together.
Okay, beautiful.
Nice. Nice.
Nice. Come on.
Beautiful.
Okay.
Turn around.
Let me see your legs. Okay.
Make out.
Tabitha, kiss her.
Brooke.
Look, you guys.
Beautiful. Beautiful.
Jeri and Trevor
are fighting again.
Beautiful. Brooke.
Brooke?
Who cares? They
should just break up already.
Make out.
Hey, make out.
Gross.
Kiss her.
Hey, want some?
Drink, drink, drink, drink,
drink, drink, drink!
Tabitha?
What do you think you're doing?
Mom, it's the last day
of school.
You said I could have a party.
I said you could have
a few friends over.
I did not say you could pass out
booze to the entire school.
There had better be some Tequila
left in that bottle
for my margaritas
or you are in big trouble.
I love your mom!
My god!
Jeri is such a bitch.
I should totally
break up with her.
No, she should break up
with you.
Why?
'Cause you're a jerk,
that's why.
Come on, you know I'm solid.
Right?
I don't think so.
You don't think so, what?
I don't think you're a good guy.
Why am I not a good guy?
I don't think so.
Whoops.
If daddy calls while I'm gone,
tell him to try my cellphone.
Brooke, I don't know
why you get your hopes up
with that man.
He's obviously
too self-absorbed to...
Geez, the way you rag on him,
no wonder he left.
Brooke, I want you
to have a good time.
I don't want to fight.
All right, whatever.
Bye.
Hey, cheer camp's only a week,
and New Orleans
is only a few hours away.
Okay.
There's Jackson high's
shiny new star.
Lorene, this is my husband, Tim.
Very nice to meet you.
Emma has told me
such nice things about you.
Nice to meet you.
Whoo!
Wow. The girls are going to camp
in a limo.
Yeah, when Brooke and Ashley
asked me, I thought, "why not?
It might be a good bonding
experience for the squad."
Well, you should go, baby.
I'll see you soon.
I'll call you tonight,
okay? You better.
I love you.
I love you, too.
It was very nice
to have met you,
and I'd love to have you over for
dinner sometime. Absolutely. Thanks.
Jeri! Jeri! Jeri! Jeri!
Whoo!
What's jeri doing here?
She was added back to the squad
by superintendent tompkins.
Coach carr is freaking.
I know. I love it.
Do you have the central office's
phone number?
No, no, no, you're not
gonna call central office,
not without my permission ever.
But three other girls
didn't make the squad
'cause they couldn't do
a back handspring.
How is that fair that jeri is
and they're not?
The decision's
already been made.
I know that you want to do
the right thing for the squad,
but the right thing
to do right now
is to welcome jeri back
and go on to camp.
Please.
Come on, you guys!
Let's go!
Let's go! Defense!
All right, you guys.
Let's hear it!
Pump! Pump! Pump it up!
Pump that spirit!
Keep it up!
Pump! Pump! Pump it up!
Pump that spirit!
Keep it up!
You guys are embarrassing
yourselves.
Megan?
Pump! Pump! Pump it up!
Pump that spirit!
Keep it up!
Pump! Pump! Pump it up!
Pump that spirit!
Keep it up!
Pump! Pump! Pump it up!
Pump that spirit!
Keep it up!
Pump! Pump! Pump it up!
Pump that spirit!
Keep it up!
Pump! Pump! Pump it up!
Pump that spirit!
Keep it up!
I don't have it.
I know you stole
Cindy's tape, Brooke.
I saw you!
Now, give it back.
Chill, bitch.
I don't have it.
Yes, you do, Brooke!
Search me.
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
What's going on?
I brought a roll of duct tape
so we could play a joke
on the captains,
tape them up in their rooms
like they did last year.
But Brooke and Lisa took it.
She's lying.
Come on, you guys.
Look, I don't want
to ruin your fun,
but you can't just
steal someone's stuff.
So, why don't you give it back,
and I'll take you someplace
to get your own roll, okay?
Let's go. Come on.
Let's get our stuff.
You know,
I'm gonna go ask coach Wilson
if I can borrow her car
'cause it's late.
You know what?
I can hold your stuff for you,
if you want.
Okay. Um,
two seconds. Thank you. Okay.
Right back.
That was too damn easy.
Seriously.
What are you doing?
Well, coach carr said she
doesn't want to ruin our fun,
so we're gonna have some fun.
Look who we have here.
You guys are crazy.
Do it.
Hey, there.
What the hell are
you trying to do, carr?
Was that message supposed
to be some kind of joke?
What are you talking about?
That text message
you just sent me.
What if my wife had read it?
I don't think she's gonna
find that too funny.
What text?
I didn't send you a text.
Well, I sure as hell got
a text message from your phone!
Saying what?
"I think we should hot box."
I don't even know
what a "hot box" means.
Neither do I.
But it sounds like, you know...
Well, if you didn't send it,
who the hell did?
This is not funny.
Okay.
I really would love
to have a bra like that.
That is hot.
You girls sent coach reeve
a dirty text from my phone?!
I told you she'd think
hot boxing was something
about sex.
Chill out.
It's not about sex.
It means smoking weed
in your car, windows up.
Get it?
"Hot box"?
And you think that's better?
What is wrong with you girls?
I am married!
Coach reeve is married!
Do you have any idea
how ugly this could have gotten?
We're sorry, okay?
We thought
we were doing you a favor.
We all know
you like coach reeve.
Yeah.
Never touch my phone again.
No problem, coach carr.
I don't even know what to think
about you girls anymore.
What are we supposed to think
of you?
You're having
a fricking heart attack
over a stupid, little joke.
We really did think
you'd laugh about it.
So laugh.
It's late. Y'all need
to get back to your own rooms.
Now!
You know what?
Just go.
See ya.
Wouldn't want to be ya.
Nighty night.
Why are you here, Brooke?
Why are you a cheerleader?
Because I'm good at it.
You're good
at the physical part.
But there's more to it
than that.
It's about being
a certain kind of person...
A person who cares,
cares about her squad,
her fellow students, her school.
You know what?
Save the lecture.
The school is all
my mother ever talks about.
I'm a cheerleader for me.
That's who people notice... me.
Look at your uniform.
Your name isn't on the back
of this.
You don't have a number.
This uniform
isn't about you, Brooke.
It's about being a part
of something bigger than you.
Anyone can get noticed.
There's nothing special
about that.
But it takes someone special
to inspire others.
Do you want to know
why I made Megan co-captain
of this squad?
Because she knows
how to inspire people.
And you, Brooke?
You don't.
All right, you guys, let's go.
Come on.
Pump! Pump! Pump it up!
Pump that spirit!
Keep it up!
Fire! Fire! Fire it up!
Fire that hornet spirit up!
Pump! Pump! Pump it up!
Pump that spirit!
Keep it up!
Fire! Fire! Fire it up!
Fire that hornet spirit up!
5, 6, 7, 8.
Here we go, hornets!
Here we go!
Come on, you guys.
Here we go, hornets!
Here we go!
Louder!
Here we go, hornets!
Here we go!
O0 c1 Jackson high,
I give you your varsity cheerleaders!
Yeah! Whoo!
Give it up
for your Jackson hornets.
Whoo!
Whoa!
Hey, that was really great.
I am so proud of you guys.
You guys were amazing today.
I need to thank our captains.
You guys both stepped up
and ran the practices.
You figured out the lighting,
the effects,
and raised the money
to pay for it.
Awesome job, you guys.
And, Brooke,
this was especially your show.
The choreography,
the presentation
was beyond amazing.
I'm so proud of you!
Brooke! Brooke! Brooke! Brooke!
That was the best pep rally
in Jackson history!
And I think we all know
who we have to thank for that.
Give it up for coach carr,
you guys.
You were great!
It wasn't me.
You guys,
go home and get some rest.
I'll see you tomorrow.
I'mproud of you.
No practice tonight?
Finally.
Brooke? Brooke?
Brooke?
Brooke, you were
so wonderful out there.
How about
we go to dinner tonight,
just you and me?
You know, I'm sorry.
I can't.
Coach carr invited me
and Megan over
to help pick out music
for crosstown showdown.
Right, coach?
What?
The mix for crosstown showdown?
Tonight, yeah.
Sure.
Hey. Hey.
Yo, come here.
No, you don't touch me.
Why?
Do you have any idea
how stupid I felt
when you showed up
at that party with jeri?
You told me
you broke up with her.
You lied to me.
We are broke up.
Look, calm down, okay?
She was needing a ride.
She called me, and she just...
You are such a... okay,
look, look, listen, listen.
I wasn't... I'm not with her.
I came here to see you.
That's why I'm here, okay?
Lunch money.
Thank you, daddy.
Wait, where's Ashley?
Not my day to babysit her.
I'm not with her.
Okay?
No, I can't!
You can't what?
I can't do this.
I mean...
Just stop it.
Fight! Fight!
If you would
just let me explain...
You're sleeping with
my boyfriend, aren't you?
You fugly slut.
Slut?!
You're calling me a slut?!
Yes, I'm calling you a slut!
Yes, I am!
You bitch!
Hey!
Did you think
I would not find out?!
Bitch!
Jeri, stop!
Die!
No! No, you're supposed
to be my friend!
Come on.
Move it. Move it. Move it.
Out of the way. Out of the way.
What's going on?
Jesus, Ashley.
Ashley, are you all right?
What happened here?
Ashley, are you okay?
Did somebody hit you?
No.
I just have a bad stomach cramp,
that's all.
Well, if she or anybody else
gets any more stomach cramps,
the repercussions
will be expulsion.
Is that understood?
Come on.
Yeah, jeri.
Where's Lisa?
Whose phone is that?
Talk to me.
My god, she did what?
Lisa, off the phone now!
No way.
My gosh, give me details.
My god,
you must be kidding me.
Lisa, off the phone now!
This is important.
Do you mind?
You better give me the phone.
No way.
My gosh.
Girl, give me the phone.
Okay.
Meet me at the quad at break.
Okay, okay.
There. I'm done.
Happy?
I can't believe she did that!
Or that Brooke would call her
in the middle of class!
What's the big shock here?
The fab five run this school...
Brooke, Lisa, Ashley,
all of them.
They've been doing exactly
as they please for years.
But since the pep rally,
I thought that...
Did you really think a pep rally
was gonna make a big difference
with those girls?
Brooke, Brooke,
I need to talk to you.
Look, mom, not right now.
Look, I have to go to practice.
I need to talk to you now.
Tabitha, run on ahead.
Just go.
Yes, ma'am.
Miss durant just dropped off
a disciplinary-action referral.
For what?
For phone use in class
for you and Lisa.
So?
Look, you know
how intense she is,
always getting uptight
over nothing.
Coach carr came in with her,
and she wants to give you and
Lisa demerits for the offense.
Are you kidding me?
I cannot tell you
how royally pissed I am.
Yeah, at me.
No!
At coach carr.
I didn't hire her to go
on a witch hunt for demerits.
Now, why don't you tell me
your version of what happened?
You don't have a choice.
You are getting 10 demerits.
No, I'm not.
Not unless Mr. Spretnik says so.
And he won't.
How could you do that?
Write me up without even
asking me what happened?
Okay, first of all,
I didn't write you up.
Mrs. Durant did.
Second of all,
it doesn't matter what happened.
You girls did what you did,
and you have to face
the consequences.
So, if you're not
gonna sign this,
I'm gonna be talking
to Mr. Spretnik
at the end of the day.
What is your malfunction, Emma?
Well, at the moment,
it's your tone,
so, please,
watch how you talk to me.
Brooke.
Brooke!
Do you really think
I want to give you demerits
after all the hard work
you've done?
I was crushed
when miss durant told me
you called Lisa
in the middle of class.
I thought
you were better than that.
Yeah, that's what I thought
about you, too.
And, believe me, I won't ever
make that mistake again.
And, by the way, um,
my mom wants to see you
in her office.
Now.
O0 c1 so, you're saying we
can't for phone use in class. Ts
no, jeri had just found out
that her boyfriend
was cheating on her...
With Ashley, of all people.
Apparently,
jeri said she felt suicidal.
And Lisa was worried about her,
which is why
she picked up the phone.
If that was why
she answered the phone.
You know these girls...
How they play with the truth
to avoid consequences.
Look, whether it's true or not,
I think it's wrong
to let this slide.
I really want to instill
a sense of accountability
in those girls.
It's not your job
to hold them accountable.
It's my job,
and it's Mr. Spretnik's job.
I would appreciate it
if you'd do your job
and get the squad ready
for the game tonight.
I know it seems
I'm being argumentative.
I just...
I want to do a good job here.
I want to do a good job for you.
You're new at this.
And you haven't learned yet
that the people above you
with years of experience
have good reasons
for their decisions.
I need you to start
figuring that out.
You should be warming up
for tonight's game.
Well, we just wanted to know
if we had to sign
the demerit book.
I think you already know
the answer to that.
We need at least two
six-packs, so, jeri, you go in.
No, Brooke, I don't have my...
I don't have my fake I.D.
I don't have mine.
I thought I told you that.
Hey, y'all, to the left.
Ooh.
Ladies.
Well, well,
well. Make it happen, Brooke.
Hey, give me that.
Unh-unh, unh-unh, unh-unh.
Hey!
Easy.
Wait, no, come on!
Come on. Come on.
You got it!
Whoa!
Y'all riding dirty?
Yeah, I wish.
Got a beer for a lady?
Make that two.
You guys, look.
Thanks, dude.
Look over there.
Anyone want to go?
My god.
It's getting bad.
It's terrible.
What do you think about this?
R-r-r!
No, you should wear them.
Hey! Hey!
Y'all are all 18, right?
Just barely.
You really think we should
be in here in our uniforms?
Look, just relax, okay?
I mean, look at all
these dirty old men in here.
I bet they love
naughty cheerleaders.
Mr. Spretnik!
Ooh, "heat wave lubricant."
How about some
of this bondage tape?
Flexy dong.
Now, that's hot.
That's great.
Yeah.
That's really hot, Brooke.
What do you think?
She is not a real cheerleader. I bet
she can't do this. What can't she do?
Bad Tabitha.
Wait, you guys, come here.
Come on.
You have to see this.
Hey, um,
why don't you hold this?
Okay.
This is good.
Be bad.
That is so sick.
My.
Hello?
Janice, what's wrong?
Pump! Pump! Pump it up!
Pump that spirit!
Keep it up!
They're in their uniforms.
I'm getting a little...
I know.
It's Ashley.
Who did you say brought this
to your attention?
Janice Harper.
Her daughter Cindy
showed it to her.
I'm just not sure
how to handle this.
Emma, that's all right.
We'll handle it.
That was awesome.
All right!
We love you.
No, no, Janice Harper's
probably shown this
to the entire booster club
by now.
I can't be involved in this.
This is gonna have to be handled
by central office.
Miss Anderson?
Bathroom?
Hey.
Heard about the video.
Say it.
Get it over with.
Say what?
"I told you so."
Not what I want to say.
What do you want to say?
That if anyone can turn
the situation around
for these girls, it's you.
Thanks.
You're the best.
You know, I really hate it
when you pull me out of class.
If you have to talk to me,
just wait till lunch.
Pump! Pump! Pump it up!
Pump that spirit!
Keep it up!
Whoo!
That was awesome.
Wait, how did you find this?
Do you know how difficult
damage control is gonna be
for this?
"Damage"?
What damage?
Hey, coach carr,
will you take a video of US?
Please?
You guys really don't care
about what you do
or how it affects other people,
do you?
Look, all we did
was make a stupid video.
It was supposed to be funny.
The jocks around here
make sex jokes
and act obscene all the time.
No one throws a fit about that.
I guarantee you if they were
in their uniform and off campus,
they'd be in big trouble.
So, then it's okay
as long as we're on campus.
Jeri, when you're
in your uniform,
you represent this whole school.
You represent everyone else
on your squad.
Do you realize that anyone
who watches this video
is going to think Jackson
cheerleaders are a bunch of...
Trashy sluts?
I am so disappointed in you.
Coach carr's disappointed in US.
Well, I guess I shouldn't be.
I mean, you did warn me
that all you care about
is getting noticed.
So, congratulations, Brooke.
You're finally getting noticed.
You four are gonna sit out
until the district decides
what your punishment will be.
We'll see what my mom says
about that.
You do realize that in college
you won't be able
to run to your mother every time
you don't like something?
Here. It's obviously
your time of the month.
All right, you guys,
crosstown showdown
is in a couple weeks,
so let's go
and start stretching.
Look who it is.
The little narc.
You think we wouldn't find out
you showed your mom the video?
I'm sorry.
No, but you will be.
I'm sorr... I'm sorry!
I'm sorry.
Aw.
Stop it, you guys!
Yeah. You're sorry? Yes.
Really?
Are you sorry?!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Brooke! Brooke!
Seriously, wait.
You're sorry?!
I'm sorry!
What are you sorry for?!
Brooke! Brooke! Brooke!
Brooke, stop! Brooke!
Brooke, what are you doing?!
Are you crazy?!
You know what?
Try and hit me!
You want to hit me?!
Come on! Hit me!
You know, if you tell anybody
about this,
I swear to god,
you'll get worse.
And I kind of hope you do tell,
'cause it'd make me so happy
to smash your face in.
Let's go.
Come on.
Are you okay?
It's okay.
I'm calling mom right now.
No, you heard them.
You can't tell.
You have to promise me.
Promise me.
O0 c1 Pamela, the video
showed the girls drinking alcohol.D.
According to the cheerleading
constitution,
they should actually be removed
from the squad. Please.
I just read that 80%
of all high-school students
drink on occasion.
It's ridiculous
to expect our girls
to behave like it's 1950.
Look, I don't
want Lisa drinking,
but I should be the one
to handle it,
not our little
cheerleading coach.
We pay what, 1,500 bucks so our
girls can be cheerleaders? Try $1,800.
$1,800. Okay.
We paid our money.
Let's let 'em cheer.
You know I'm not gonna appeal.
I'm trying to keep myself
out of this.
Lorene, come on.
You could at least back US up.
Or get your
little miss sunshine coach here
to back off.
If coach carr thinks
we're trashy sluts,
she's gonna get trashy sluts.
Lord!
The sun just came out!
Whoo!
Almighty, that is sexy.
Unh-unh. No way.
I've let a lot slide
with you girls,
but this...
The way you're dressed, unh-unh.
What's wrong with the way
we're dressed?
You know exactly
what I'm talking about, Brooke.
Are you looking at her boobs?
You perv.
I want you...
I want all of you right now
to get down to the office,
get permission to go home
and change.
Go.
I don't think so.
Excuse me?
You get out of my classroom
right now, Brooke.
You know what?
You might as well get
your panties out of a wad,
because we're not
going anywhere.
So, what should we talk about
today, class?
Miss Brooke.
Yes, jeri?
Um, let's talk about
how Trevor called me last night
and said that Ashley
is so crap in bed
and that she makes sounds
like a monkey.
Really?
Aw, poor little baby!
I got a banana for you.
Run, slut! Run!
What are you looking at?!
Nothing.
It's just...
Doesn't feel so good
to be on the other side
of it all, does it?
I was never as mean as Brooke
and jeri are being to me.
I was never that cruel!
Yes, you were.
You were exactly like them.
So, I went
to Mr. Spretnik yesterday
about Brooke
already having nine absences
in my class this year.
And this morning I see this.
Wait, that says
she's been absent three times.
Exactly.
It's been changed.
Yesterday, it says nine,
this morning, it says three,
and I didn't change it.
Could one of the girls
have accessed the server?
Yeah, it's possible.
But it's also possible
they didn't have to
because someone in that office
did it for them.
You know, I tried to avoid
doing what everybody else here
does,
and that's just hunker down,
watch the calendar,
and wait for those little
monsters to graduate.
But if it's gonna be like this?
Screw it.
I'm done fighting.
I don't care anymore.
Jeri's mom appealed,
Tabitha's mom, Lisa's dad.
Brooke, do you have any idea
how hard this is for me?
Look, this isn't fair!
No one would care
about that video
If you weren't my mom.
You're probably right,
which is why I don't know
whether to ground you
or feel sorry for you.
Why don't you just bite me?
Okay, you know what, Brooke?
You're grounded.
Go ahead.
Try it, lorene.
I'm gonna call daddy.
I'll tell him
if I can't live with him,
then I'll disappear,
and this time,
neither of you will ever
see me again.
And that's a promise.
It's central office.
That was unnecessary.
Lorene tippit.
Hello, Mr. Tompkins.
Yeah, fine, thank you.
I could not agree with you more.
Yes.
Thank you so much for calling.
I will,
That was vern tompkins,
and he has decided
to reduce the suspension
to 15 days plus probation.
Yeah, well, no thanks to you.
The parents don't want the girls
to have consequences,
the school doesn't want 'em
and now even the district
is backing off.
So, if no one else cares,
why should I be the one
beating my head
against the wall?
Because it's not like you
to back down
from fighting
for what you think is right.
Well, maybe I should start doing
what people with more experience
are doing,
and all they're doing
is watching the calendar
until the fab five are gone,
so, fine, I can do that, too.
What do you want me to say?
That it's okay
not to rock the boat?
'Cause it is. I mean, I've been
in the corporate world.
I know how futile it is.
Why do you think I went back
to get my degree?
Hon, I know you think
cheerleading is
some high, holy mission,
but it's not like
there are lives at stake here.
Maybe you're right.
I'm just not feeling that good.
I'm gonna make some tea.
Do you want some?
No, I'm fine.
Thanks.
Okay.
Okay, so, we're gonna go
low "v," high "v,"
touchdown, tabletop, "t,"
okay? Three claps.
Great, all right, now,
you guys...
Yeah, legs a little
closer together.
Hey, guys?
Sorry to interrupt.
Coach carr just called,
and, unfortunately, she's home
sick today with the flu.
What are you?
Her errand boy now?
So, she asked me
to put Megan in charge.
Try to remember that
you're still on probation, okay?
All right, you guys,
let's bring it together.
Let's try this again.
Ready?
What a total jackass.
I can't believe you actually
worshipped his junk.
Temporary insanity.
Look what I jacked.
I love your mom.
Let's bounce.
Very good.
Okay, lock out.
Hey, Megan,
we're gonna leave, all right?
I don't care
what you do, Brooke.
No!
You suck so bad,
you make this whole squad...
Leave her alone.
Do you really want
to do this again?
Okay, chill, badass.
We're out. Let's go.
Let's go.
Take this.
Get it.
Here.
Here. Here. Here.
Let's go to the mall.
I don't want to go to the mall.
It's old and stupid.
Well, then let's go to Harris'
or something.
Maybe he'll get US high.
We can't go to Harris'.
He's not off work yet.
Let's just go somewhere,
all right?
It's so stupid to waste
a buzz here. Fine.
Here.
Come on.
Some adventure.
Getting frisky.
I'm fricking hungry.
Tab, kill this.
Go! Go! Go!
Um...
He's hot.
You pulled this car out
way too fast, young lady.
You have an off-campus pass?
No, but we have permission
to leave.
If you don't have a pass,
then you need to park your car.
Do you know who I am?
Yes, I do.
Now park the car.
Look, okay,
you can go call Mr. Spretnik
on your little radio,
and he'll tell you
we're allowed to leave.
Hey, Joe.
What's going on?
Hey, there, b.L.T.
You girls need to get
out of this car right now.
O0 c1
Could we be any more fascinating
to these losers?
The curmudgeons are on time.
You know,
it's really funny to me.
This is actually a prop
for a health-class project.
You know, I found it
in the trash can
by the science lab.
Why don't... why don't you girls
just tell me what happened?
Well, now,
we just took a huge test,
and we were all tired,
and we needed some fresh air.
I was running, and it was really
stupid of me, but I fell.
Go figure.
She scraped her knee.
Em.
You got to hear this.
Everyone is saying
you were the one
that caught them
in the parking lot.
You didn't write them up?
No, I didn't.
But they were drinking
on school grounds!
There was no alcohol
in the bottle,
no proof they were drinking.
And as for this skipping thing,
I think there's a lot
of gray area there.
I mean, the other squad captain
gave them permission to go home.
Who? Megan?
Since when can a student
give another student
permission to leave school?!
Lorene,
you have to write them up!
Keep pushing me,
and I will dissolve this program
altogether.
There will be
no more cheerleaders,
and I will let everyone know
that you're responsible.
Now, I have an appointment.
Lorene, before you go...
Those girls have violated
their probation.
They need to be removed
from the squad.
I am not about to deliver
permanent consequences
for an offense
I'm not sure they committed.
This isn't
about embarrassing stuff
on the Internet anymore.
They are becoming a danger
to themselves and others.
This conversation is over.
Why do you help these girls
get away
with whatever they want?
I know why lorene does it.
She thinks
it'll convince her daughter
that she loves her.
But what's in it for you?
All right,
you are becoming irrational.
Maybe you need
to take another day off
until you're feeling...
wasn't it you that altered
Brooke tippit's attendance
record in coach reeve's class?
All right,
you're completely out of line.
This whole school
is out of line!
And if you're not gonna
hold these girls accountable
for their actions,
I will hold them accountable
as a squad.
I will cancel all activities
outside the classroom.
I will see them at practices,
and that's it.
If you're refusing
to perform your duties
as cheerleading coach,
then I'll just accept that
as your resignation.
No, I am not resigning!
You are gonna be dealing with me
until you handle this
the right way.
Why are you making US pay
for what they did?
I know this is hard
to understand,
but if rules are broken,
there have to be consequences.
And these are
the only consequences
I have in my power to deliver.
You said you would never quit
on US.
I'm not quitting.
I'm trying to force a change
in discipline policy.
Can you understand that?
Yeah, but I'm tired of them
getting away with everything
and making US all look bad.
You're not hurting US,
you know?
You're just gonna make everyone
else hate you as much as we do.
Leave.
Make me.
Practice is canceled today.
You can all go home early.
I'll let the office know.
What are you still doing here?
Waiting for Mr. Studdard.
He said he'd be here at 3:15.
You went to central office
with your cheerleader problems?
Well, I think he should know
what's going on here, don't you?
Do you know
what lorene's gonna do to you
when she finds out
you went over her head?
She left me no choice.
She won't even talk to me
about it.
Now, obviously,
Mr. Studdard won't either.
What is wrong
with this district?!
Everyone is just burying
their heads in the sand.
Hi.
The girls were just telling me
about what happened today,
and they're pretty upset
about it.
Janice, I need your help.
Come on in.
Wait.
What's going on here?
After meeting with coach carr
and a number
of the booster parents,
Mr. Spretnik and I
have decided
that you girls
will be written up
for skipping class on Tuesday.
And this is because
of what she wants?
Most of the girls will receive
10 to 12 demerits total.
But jeri already has 10,
so 20 is now her total.
And 20 means removal
from the squad.
That's it, jeri.
You're off the squad.
Really?
I mean, really?
Because my mom is gonna be very
interested to hear about this.
This is twice now that you've
gotten me kicked off the squad.
For what?!
What did I ever do to you?
Jeri, this isn't about
what you've done to me.
She is totally manipulating you,
and you're letting her,
aren't you?
Aren't you?!
Answer me!
So, if you're wondering
why I'm giving you erasers,
well, we've had
a pretty rough time.
And I know this is cheesy,
but this is what
my high-school coach used to do
when she wanted US
to start fresh.
And that's what
this squad needs...
A fresh start.
Would you like me to tell you
where you can put that eraser?
Disrespect to a teacher
is 10 demerits.
So, go ahead, tell me.
Sorry, coach.
But I'm respectfully declining
your eraser.
Hey.
Did she say anything about me?
No,
she just gave US these. You took it?
Why didn't you tell her
to stick it up her ass?
Why didn't you?
You know what?
This is our squad, our school.
We were here before that bitch.
And you know what?
We're gonna be here
after she's gone.
Someone should know about it. And
you say this, um, this affair has been going on
since before last semester?
Yes, sir.
I definitely
heard coach carr say to him,
"what if your wife
finds out?"
All right, well, just keep this
to yourselves, all right?
I'll take care of it.
I need you to come with me
and sit through the first round
of Pamela Blackburn's appeal
over jeri being removed
from your squad.
At camp this summer,
did you or did you not
encourage the girls
to break curfew
and go with you to buy tape
for the purpose of playing
pranks on the other girls?
Yes, but I didn't
consider it breaking curfew,
because they were with me.
And did you let them get away
with sending
a sexually explicit message
to coach reeve
from your cellphone?
No, I didn't let them
get away with it!
But you didn't give them
any formal punishment.
So, if you let them
break some rules and not others,
how are they supposed to know
where you draw the line?
The line at school
is very clear.
Drinking is not allowed.
Neither is skipping class.
Did you frequently flirt
with coach reeve, a married man,
in front of the girls?
Lorene, why am I the one
on trial here?
We're supposed to be discussing
jeri's behavior issues.
Emma, you can't kick a girl
off the squad
and not have questions raised
about how that came about.
I'm curious
to hear your answers.
1, 2...
Wait.
Come on, you guys.
You haven't hit this
once yet today.
Let's try it again.
Come on.
1, 2...
Come on. Stay.
Stay. Stay. Stay straight.
No, no, no!
No, wait.
Get up.
Cindy, get up!
I can't do it.
Yes, you can.
Get up.
Okay.
I'm not helping much, am I?
You're straightening your arms
too early,
so it's throwing
your balance off.
So, I want you to stay up
straight until you're up
and then extend your arms.
Can we do that?
Can we all try this again? Yeah.
Okay.
Ready, 1, 2.
Down... straight.
Cindy, Cindy, squeeze!
Squeeze, squeeze.
You got it?
Yes, yes! Whoo!
Good job, Cindy!
See, I told you.
Good job.
I had a makeup test.
Hey, red, how'd you do?
I nailed it.
Okay.
Lisa, what's that on your leg?
Nothing.
I didn't cheat.
Okay, fine.
I wrote the test answers
on my leg.
Big whoop.
All right.
I'm gonna have to write you up
for academic dishonesty.
You're gonna be benched
for another two weeks.
You're just trying to keep me
out of the crosstown showdown,
just like you're doing to jeri.
You guys need to start thinking
of consequences
before you break the rules.
Let's do it again.
Cindy, okay, remember,
not straightened too soon.
I hate you!
Everyone hates you!
Why don't you just quit?!
Let's start with the dance,
okay?
Come on.
Let's go from the top.
5, 6, 7, 8.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
Hi, daddy?
I'm so sorry
to bother you at work,
but remember
you said to call you
if coach carr starts
picking on me again?
1, look, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
My dad wants to talk to you.
He spoke
to Mr. Resinbrink,
and Mr. Resinbrink says
that you can't stop me
from performing
at the crosstown showdown,
that if you give me demerits,
you have to let me
work them off.
Go ahead.
Talk to him.
How can I coach
with no authority whatsoever?
You either need to make sure
I have some control
over this squad
or you tell supervisor tompkins
I'll resign
as cheerleading coach.
Hi, miss tippit.
Hi.
I need to see that in writing.
Okay.
Thank you.
You think I quit?
That's usually
what "I resign" means, yeah.
Lorene's not gonna accept
that resignation.
She knows I'm a good coach.
She just wanted me
to write it down
so she can take it to district
and show them,
"look,
we have a problem."
Did she tell you that?
God, these girls
are gonna think I quit on them.
I need to write them an e-mail.
"This has been the most
meaningful time in my life.
You girls mean more to me
than you will ever know."
Blah!
Mom!
You know what to say, right?
I'm not an idiot.
Mom, come in here.
Mom, coach carr
sent US an e-mail.
You should read it.
I've been trying to tell you,
she's psycho.
My mom says coach carr's
an embarrassment.
She said she's mostly
embarrassed for you.
Superintendent tompkins
told my mother
he doesn't know
why you ever hired her.
So, I read your e-mail
to the girls several times,
and I do have one question.
You wrote "whether or not I
continue this journey with you."
You do realize that your journey
here at Jackson is over, right?
May I tell the girls
before I go?
No, you may not.
You're to leave campus
immediately.
What do you want?
We just heard
you're not our coach anymore.
I guess someone
didn't want you here?
You girls always get
what you want, don't you?
Yeah, you could say that.
You know, for a while there,
I thought you girls
were actually on your way
to becoming...
Shut up.
Get out of our school.
I feel the most sorry
for you, Brooke.
You have so much potential,
and you just drove away the one
person willing to help you.
The meeting was a joke.
22 parents signed a letter
demanding your reinstatement,
and Mr. Studdard tried
to stop US from reading it.
Why did they bother
to hold the meeting
if they had no intention
of listening to US?
How are the girls doing?
They feel abandoned.
Lorene told them
you quit on them.
I know.
It's only going to get worse.
TV reporter called me.
She's doing a story
about the video on the Internet.
And the questions she asked?
It's gonna be
a "cheerleaders gone wild."
What is this reporter's name?
You're not thinking
of talking to her.
Maybe I can talk her
out of doing the story.
I doubt that.
It's airing tonight.
Well, then I better go.
What's the station name?
What if she asks you
for an interview?
Then I'll do an interview.
Coach Emma carr said she tried
to bring order to the team,
leveling punishments
for offenses
ranging from skipping classes
to posting a sexually
suggestive video
on the Internet.
The Jackson high school
administration
declined our request
for an interview.
Carr said that her attempts
to... Why they'd blur our faces?
Shh. Shh. Shh.
By the high-school principal
lorene tippit,
who has a daughter on the squad.
Yes, I mean, some of the girls
behaved badly.
But the real problem
were the adults.
The school administration
enabled them,
the school district
refused to take interest,
and the girls' parents
did everything they could
to help them avoid consequences.
You know,
we are totally famous.
Feeling Paris Hilton?
More of a "Lindsay Lohan" vibe.
With a touch of Britney.
And her sister.
Girls, it's good to be bad.
The school board is very unhappy
about the publicity...
Very unhappy.
Once I realized
how unstable coach carr was,
I asked for her resignation.
Well, the board has asked me
to hire
an independent investigator
to look into discipline issues
at Jackson.
But there are no discipline
issues at Jackson.
The problem here
was an immature teacher
who wasn't up to the job
and is now using the media
to spread lies.
Yeah, I know,
and we're releasing a statement
to that effect.
Now, we expect the investigator
to tell US the same thing.
Can you assure me
his investigation
will tell US the same thing?
I promise you, vern,
I will make sure
that everyone at Jackson
cooperates
with your investigator.
Okay.
It's not true that I get
special treatment here.
If anything,
people are even harder on me
because my mom's the principal.
I would agree.
It's not easy being
the principal's daughter.
People watch her.
They hold her
to a different standard.
I work 40 hours a week,
so I can't watch Tabitha
every moment.
Yet, she motivates herself
to get good grades,
do volunteer work,
and work her ass off
as a cheerleader.
She was so hot for coach reeve,
she'd ignore US
to flirt with him.
Here, I took this picture
of them on my phone.
I know a few parents
are asking
for her reinstatement.
And I hope
they do bring her back.
Then I can sue this school
for my daughter's
emotional suffering.
Mom, mom, if you would just
let me... please, stop.
Mother, just let me explain!
I'm trying to... mom!
I'll take Cindy in first.
She's the most nervous.
So, was it weird?
If you're wondering whether
I told the truth or not, I did,
even though certain people
are gonna hate me
the rest of my life.
Yeah, but other people
are gonna respect you
for telling the truth.
Yeah, like who?
I mean, if you haven't noticed,
I don't have friends anymore.
Well, you could.
You could have
a whole squad full of them.
If you wanted them.
Hello?
Emma, it's Helen and Adam.
God, it's so good
to hear from you guys.
Lorene forbid everybody on staff
to speak to you.
You're kidding me.
Well, then why are you calling?
So I could tell you
how pissed I am
that you're dragging US
into this investigation thing.
Stop it.
He's not mad at you.
It's just... the investigator
was grilling him
about the two of you,
asking if there was
a sexual relationship,
if you had every acted
inappropriately with him.
Yeah, my wife wants to know
why they're asking
that question.
God, I am so sorry.
I don't see the point
of all this, Emma.
It's not like you're gonna
be able to take lorene down.
I'm not trying to take her down.
I'm just trying
to change things for the girls.
You should be trying
to get your job back.
I just hope this investigator's
gonna find out the truth.
They didn't hire him
to find the truth, em.
You look
a little... Uncomfortable.
That's because
I am uncomfortable.
With the process or with me?
I welcome the process.
I just don't trust you.
From what I hear,
you've been paid
to hang me out to dry.
This isn't
a very auspicious start.
Well, you did say
you wanted me to be honest.
Yes, I did.
What are you doing here?
Talking to the investigator.
He's not gonna believe
a word you said.
Do you know what
all this means for you?
My life is exactly the way
I want it to be.
Is that right?
With this video of you
on the Internet
and the stories in the media,
do you really think
that usc's gonna accept you
as a student,
let alone a song girl?
After conducting
over 70 interviews,
I believe I've identified
the source of the problems
with the cheerleading program.
As you know, the most recent
coach, Emma carr, quit
in an untimely fashion,
then unwisely took her accounts
to the media.
However...
I find her actions
understandable
given the problems
she encountered at Jackson,
problems centered on a popular
group of cheerleaders
who were highly resistant
to authority.
These girls were literally given
carte blanche
to behave as they pleased
by their parents
and by the school
administration.
Regrettably, I found
that Jackson's principal,
lorene tippit, failed to juggle
two of the most important
responsibilities in her life...
Principal and mother.
And it is she who is accountable
for this situation
we find ourselves in today.
Entertain me.
Why aren't the four of you
in class?
We're just waiting for my mom
to get out of her meeting.
And, of course,
this takes all four of you.
That's the "fab four"
to you, reeve.
I have been placed
on suspension,
and so has Mr. Spretnik.
The report faulted me
when all I've ever tried to do
is keep you out of this mess.
Okay, you know what?
Don't blame US
because your investigator
turned out to be a stupid moron!
You know what, Brooke?
You will never talk to me
like that again.
Now, go clean out your locker.
For what? 'Cause I'm
pulling you out of this school.
Like hell you are!
This is my school
and my senior year!
Not anymore it's not.
Go clean out your locker.
Or what?
Or your mother is gonna drag you
to it by your hair!
Excuse me, miss tippit?
What about US?
I don't know what your parents
are gonna do with you.
You're definitely gonna be
removed from the squad.
Your cheerleading days
in this district are over.
Let me get that for you.
There you go. Watch the...
Miss tippit!
Brooke!
Miss tippet,
I'd like to have a word...
Do you have any comment?
Please, give US a comment.
Any comment, Brooke?
Please, people are asking.
Go away!
Brooke, anything
that you'd like to say?
Anything you would like to say?
Any comments?
Miss tippit, any comments?
Do you have any comments?
Miss tippit, please? Comments?
Any comments, miss tippet?
Tell US about what's going on
in the school.
Coach carr!
Coach!
Please, can we get a comment?
Anything, please.
Of course, I'm disappointed
superintendent tompkins decided
not to let me have my job back.
I loved being a coach.
I loved being a teacher.
But this whole thing...
It's not about me.
And I know you guys
are gonna continue
to call this a "real life
'mean girls' story."
But it's not even
about what the girls did.
It's about
how they felt entitled
to the way
they were being treated
by the lack of boundaries.
And I think all of US,
we have an obligation
to set boundaries
and stick by them.
Thought you'd be happier.
The report vindicated you.
Yeah, but jobs were lost,
reputations were ruined.
And for what?
What difference
did I really make?
Maybe I shouldn't be here.
You were invited.
Yeah, by Janice.
But what if the girls
don't want me to be here?
Well, if you don't want
to say hi to the girls
because you think it's gonna
make them uncomfortable,
we can just watch them perform
and then go.
Okay.
Emma.
Emma, over here.
How are you?
You got here just in time.
Janice.
Franklin Madison high school.
My gosh!
You guys!
I missed you.
Hi! Guys!
We're so glad to have you here,
but we're on next. Okay.
We'll see you after, okay?
Okay.
Okay, good luck, you guys.
Bye!
Jackson high school
may now take the floor.
Mom, mom!
Yeah. Yeah.
Tell her about my essay!
Bye!
In Cindy's English class,
she was given an assignment
to write an essay
about the person
she most admired
for overcoming adversity,
and she picked you.
She wrote
about how brave you were
for standing up
to the school district.
If you like,
I'll print you out a copy.
And now, entering
our southwest regionals
for the very first time,
let's give it up
for Jackson high!
Whoo!
Number one!
O0 c... captions by vitac...
www.Vitac.Com