Yeah. Yeah.
-Um...
- Jesus! My god.
- Hey, Sophie.
Pete.
My god. We must've
gotten the wrong apartment.
- I'm... um...
- I-it happens.
-I just, well...
This is my friend.
- Julian.
This is Pete, my neighbor.
- Hey, man.
-This is where he lives.
Sorry. I guess we'll...
-Is that your bathroom?
-Yep.
Dude. My god.
You're not gonna believe
where I am.
This chick is all...
-So, um, how... how are you?
-I know. Yeah, dude.
Come on, tell me what you mean.
She's cute, right?
She's cute?
Alonzo said they finally
caught the guy that was...
Pooping in the bushes,
and I guess it turned out
that it was just, um, a dog.
- No, dude. Dude.
- I...
-I'll be there
in like an hour...
Less than an hour, Max.
I got to go. This...
I'm pissing
all over this dude's wall.
Okay.
Hi.
Hey, there.
So, you want to go next door?
-Yeah, um...
You know what?
I'm actually gonna go to bed.
-What?
-Um... you know, I have
a really big day tomorrow,
just this thing
in the morning, and...
You guys are weird.
-Do you want... some pizza?
-Yeah.
Thanks, Pete.
Yep.
Whoop!
-See you.
- Sophie?
- Hi.
-Okay, so, do you have
any questions about this?
Yes, I... there wasn't
anything to prepare,
so I was just wondering
what I'd be doing.
-Sure. Yeah, we... we're
basically just looking
for somebody who can
really sell this hot dog.
You know?
You eat meat, right?
- Yes.
- Great.
-I don't normally,
but I-I would.
-Okay. Um, if you could just
grab a hot dog bun over there...
-Yep.
-Okay.
You're just gonna eat it
like it is the best hot dog
you've ever had
in your entire life.
-Great.
Do I say anything?
-No. No.
I mean, you can vocalize
if you want to.
-Great.
What's my frame for this?
It's an extreme close-up.
-Of my face?
-Of your mouth.
-Great.
-And speak.
-Hi, I'm Sophie potts
with dreemz talent agency...
That's the dreemz with two e's
and a "z" at the end.
-Great. Go ahead.
-All right.
-Cut.
And you can just spit out
in the bin over there.
-I'm literally getting
chills right now.
Live mermaids.
Man!
You guys...
Y'all know how to do it up, man.
That's great, though.
Well, how long
have they been together?
Sure, so it was time.
Bachelor party with the boys!
You guys are gonna have
a blast, seriously.
Vegas... blowin' it up!
I've been... once,
had too many margaritas,
got a little sick,
but it didn't...
It didn't ruin the trip.
Yeah, I was with
my parents and my sister.
We did the whole
"siegfried & Roy" thing.
The tigers...
I mean, the tigers.
I don't know if you've ever...
Okay, cool.
You're rebooted.
Okay, that's it.
Yeah. All right, under
"protocol," select r-s-m-4.
All right!
Nice, man. Um...
Cool.
Where... and you guys all...
Y'all all went to
high school together?
That's cool.
Okay, well, is there anything
else I can help you with today?
You may receive a survey
through your e-mail.
Again, my name is Pete.
And I'd ask that you rank me
a 9 or a 10 if you are happy
with the troubleshooting
that I've given you.
Cool.
Thanks, man,
and, dude, have fun, obviously,
and call back anytime,
seriously.
Okay.
Yeah, good meeting you.
All right. Bye.
Hey, Pete.
-Hey. Hey, I got to leave
in like a few minutes,
but...
You should come in.
Hey, look, um...
Don't worry about last night
or anything.
There's...
You know, it's...
There's nothing to be...
Embarrassed about.
-Last night?
God. Last night.
-Well...
You know,
I mean, those things...
You've got,
bread crumbs in your hair.
-Do you have anything to drink?
God, Pete. It was this
stupid local commercial, but...
I'm never getting up
off this floor.
I hope that's okay.
-No, yeah, that's...
That's totally cool.
I really do
have to go soon, though.
-That's fine.
I'll just stay right here.
-On the floor?
Forever?
Yep. Forever.
We should probably just
get married, then
I mean, if you're gonna
be here anyway.
-Okay.
- Cool.
- Perfect.
-Great.
-Sweet.
-I... I was just kidding.
-I know.
-So, I've got to go.
Really?
Yeah, yeah.
You want some company?
-My car's just, like,
right up there.
-You know, I don't think
I've ever seen you
outside
of our apartment complex.
-No. Yeah, we have,
that one time at 7-Eleven.
Yeah.
So, where are we going?
-Phoenix, just super quickly.
-Quickly?
-Yeah, we're gonna pick up
my sister from college.
Her semester is over,
and my parents are out of town.
-Isn't that like six hours away?
-Six hours there,
six hours back.
-This is great.
You'll get to meet my sister.
She's awesome.
You're gonna love Jess.
-Ex-excuse me, sir.
I must say...
This is a lovely lady
you have here.
-You're a lucky guy.
- Thank you.
- Do you love him?
-No, come on, now. Do you tell
him you love him every night?
-Yeah, I do.
Every night.
-She does constantly,
all the time.
Wow.
You guys... look at you.
You guys are dressed alike.
You like a bunch of easter eggs.
My god. You make me
want to just peel you off.
You guys watch
a bunch of movies together?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. It is,
like, our favorite thing to do.
- It's our thing.
- You know what?
I got just the thing
for you guys.
- Yeah.
- It's red.
-Red. Cool. Mine's blue.
Um, where are you from?
-San Antonio, but...
-San Antonio, city of missions.
Okay, do you have a dog?
-Hey, Pete.
- Obviously, duh... no.
Stupid question.
If you did have a dog,
what kind would you get, though?
-Pete, I don't think this is...
Do you know how to play
20 questions?
-No, this is... this is...
This is, like,
me and Jess' family version.
It's a lot...
It's more fun, I think.
- Okay.
-Okay.
Here's where it gets hard.
What's the saddest thing
that's ever happened to you?
-The saddest thing
that's ever happened to me?
-Yeah.
-You know what?
I'd probably rather
not talk about it.
-No? Not gonna go for it?
-Nah, I don't feel like
answering that one.
- You're not gonna do it?
- No.
-I just won. Pete wins.
I'm the winner.
- You can win this game?
- Yep. I just did.
You gave up.
- No. Okay. Okay.
-I mean,
you should pretty much know
that I'm basically undefeated.
When we used to play on road
trips, Jess would give up
after like five questions, too,
so don't feel bad or anything.
Actually, the only person
that's ever beat is bradman.
-Who's bradman?
- Is that your first question?
- Sure.
-Bradman is Jess' boyfriend.
He is awesome.
And he's probably gonna get
drafted by the Dodgers.
Is bradman, like,
your role model or something?
-Question number two,
cutting deep.
You learn fast.
I would say, yeah,
bradman is definitely
a good role model, for sure.
-Do I just ask another question?
-You keep it coming
till I give up, yeah.
-Okay. Um... Pete.
What's your last name?
-You don't know my last name?
-Why would I know
your last name?
It's not like we hang out
outside of our apartment
or anything.
-It's on my mailbox.
What am I? Like a stalker?
-Avery.
Peter Stephen Avery, actually.
-Well, Peter Stephen Avery,
it's nice to formally make
your acquaintance.
-Yeah.
You too.
Okay, um, Peter,
do you know my last name?
-Sophie potts, apartment 209.
You're sort of creepy!
-No. I-I get your...
Your bead catalogues.
-Sure, sure.
- I I do.
- Okay.
Hey, Peter, here's a good one.
Do you a crush on me?
What? No.
Do I have a crush on you?
No.
- I don't know.
I mean, first you ask me
to marry you,
and then you know my last name.
- That doesn't mean...
I know lots of
people's last names,
and I don't have
crushes on them.
I don't have a crush on you.
-That's... that's fine.
I was just wondering.
-Why?
-'Cause I kind of have
a crush on you.
-Do you think it's,
like, a... a turtle?
-I don't know.
Jesus.
It looks like it's part snake.
Poor thing.
It's disgusting.
-We can't just, like,
leave it here, though.
-Do you want to Bury it?
-Aah!
I'm sorry.
My god.
-You did good.
We'll Bury it in Phoenix.
-Shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot!
-Hey, Pete.
You left it in drive.
Yeah.
Right.
Sorry I freaked out.
- No, it's... it's fine.
All right.
-You know,
I got hit by a car once.
-Are... are you okay?
-Yeah. Yeah, it was just...
I was carrying this box of,
plates across the street,
and I-I guess I wasn't really
looking where I was going,
and...
But, the... the person that
hit me was in a convertible,
so all the plates...
You know.
She had insurance,
so she's fine now, too.
-Okay.
Cool.
-She was really pretty.
Hey, I know you were
joking before,
but, um, you know,
I was just wondering...
Would you... would you marry me?
I...
I mean, I was just... playing.
Yeah, I know.
I just don't feel like anybody
would ever want to marry me.
Like, I'd marry you, you know?
- Really?
- Yeah.
You're a catch.
- Okay. So, like... so...
So, if right now I was like,
"let's get married,"
you'd... you'd say yes?
Yeah.
-Let's get married.
-You're kidding.
-No, i'm... I'm not,
but y-you are.
-No, I'm not. I'm not.
-Me neither.
-What, so is this...
For real?
-I don't know.
Think about it.
-I'm thinking about it.
- So, we'd split rent.
- We can get tax breaks.
- There are tax breaks?
- Yeah, there must be.
- That's an amazing call.
- I'll look into it.
I can buy milk
by the gallon now.
I can get a bunch of cats,
and I wouldn't even be
a pathetic cat lady.
-Sophie...
This is, like,
a really good idea.
-It's your idea, too.
-Yeah, I know.
It's both of our ideas.
Whoa, does this mean
that I'm like...
The one?
-Well, I've never been
married before.
So, yeah, I guess it's...
So, you're the one.
Awesome.
You're the one, too.
-Aww!
-High five.
Soft mattress or firm mattress?
-I sleep on a futon mattress.
- So, firm.
- Yeah.
-Three, two, one...
I think we should...
Get couple's stationary.
- Yes.
- Yeah?
- And robes.
- Monogrammed, matching.
- Hey, we should sign a prenup.
- Totally.
My parents always said,
"do whatever you want,
but make sure you get a prenup."
Wait. Really?
-Yeah.
"Pete keeps his...
All of his lots of money.
Sophie keeps her kitchenaid."
Seems fair to me.
I should take you on a date.
We're getting married,
and we haven't been
on a date yet, so...
Pete.
What do you think this was?
-How'd it go?
-I had a lovely time.
-Very good.
- Wait!
- What?
-I know exactly what we need.
Hi.
- Hi.
Can I take this off?
- Yep.
-Okay.
What's this about?
- I got you something.
- You didn't.
I did.
I got one, too.
Aah.
-They're perfect.
-Good.
It's...
Scoop, scoop, scoop it.
- Scoop.
-Swimming.
- Swimming?
- Swimming, swimming, swimming.
Then scoop it, scoop it,
scoop it, scoop it.
-Scoop it, scoop it.
Swim and swim and swim.
Scoop it, scoop it
-all right.
Scoop it, scoop it,
scoop it, scoop it.
Swimming, swimming, swimming,
swimming, swimming, swimming.
-Jess!
Je-e-e-e-e-ss!
-Pete, what the fuck?
Hi.
-Hey.
It's good to see you.
-You too.
-Come here.
Spin cycle!
Spin cycle! Spin cycle!
- Peter, Jesus Christ!
Yes!
Man.
-Fucking asshole.
You walked right into that.
Aaah!
Jesus Christ!
Why are you keeping
a dead armadillo back here?
So, that must be its
Do you want to do the honors?
-Our father, who art in heaven,
hallowed...
I guess that's good.
-I think we should tell her.
- I don't know, Pete.
- I think we should do it.
Come on, we have to
eventually, right?
- Yeah, but...
- Let's do it. Let's tell her.
-Tell me what?
-It's nothing.
- Big news, Jess!
- Watch the road.
-No. Yeah, sorry.
Big... but big news.
-Don't you think it's
a little early?
-Shh. Sophie, this is gonna be
great, trust me.
She's gonna love this.
She's gonna be so pumped.
Jess.
- Watch the road!
-Yeah, I know.
-Okay, let's just wait
until a better time.
- What is it, Pete?
- Okay...
- Okay, watch the road.
-Sophie and I
are engaged to be married.
There it is!
There it is, big "j"!
Right?
-You guys are idiots.
-Well, Jess,
I'm genuinely hurt right now.
Come on.
-I'm serious.
That really hurts my feelings.
-Okay, I know it's
sort of sudden.
- What did you expect me to say?
- I don't know.
"Congratulations, guys, that's
really... I'm happy for you."
- Guys, let's just drop it.
- I mean
How long have you guys
been engaged?
-A while, Jess.
A couple hours.
- Great. Wow.
Congratulations.
-Okay, look, I know
it's a little bit... crazy.
-Yeah.
-I mean, we're not
even really dating.
- Sorry. What?
- Well, it was just started out
as a joke, but I think...
- Have you even told mom and dad?
-Have I...
No. Not yet.
Okay. Well...
-Well, he wanted
to tell you first.
-Yeah, Jess, I'm sorry.
I kind of thought you would be
really happy for US.
There's tax breaks.
- Yeah, there are.
-You know what?
I don't even care, Jess.
Sophie and I
are getting married,
and it is gonna be awesome.
- Watch the road!
- No!
-I am marrying
your brother so hard.
-Yeah, you are.
Whoo!
- God damn it, Pete!
- Watch it, okay?
- I've... I've got it.
And I had it on my knee.
- Okay.
-I like your chin.
I like your teeth...
Your eyelashes and how blond
and sparse your eyelashes are.
And look at these hands.
I think our hands
are the same size.
- I've got small hands.
- Yeah.
That's okay.
Okay, your turn.
- I don't...
-Just one thing
that you like about me.
My god. Are you blushing?
- I don't know.
- Your ears are turning pink.
Eeeeek!
- No.
- Is this our anniversary?
- My god. It is.
-Yeah.
-So, what should our song be?
Hey, Jess, what do you
think our song should be?
- Maybe, like, a slow jam?
- You know what?
What if we just turn on
the radio right now?
Whatever's playing...
- Is gonna be...
- That's gonna be our song.
- Totally.
-This is a test of the...
- Shit.
Shit. No.
- I'm okay with it.
- Hey, what's wrong?
- During emergencies is being...
- Pete, it's your sister.
- Official messages would
have followed the alert tone.
This concludes this test
of the emergency...
-Jess.
Jess.
Okay, I'll call bradman.
-You can't. No.
- This is a test of the...
- Can we just
Turn off the freaking radio?
Yeah, sorry.
-If this had been an actual
emergency, official messages
would've followed...
Okay.
-Hey, Jess, what's wrong?
- I don't want to talk about it.
- Okay.
-Um, no, you have to talk
about it. What are you...
-I don't have to talk
about anything!
-Yes, you do.
You're crying. You're upset.
- Okay, Pete, leave her alone.
- What?
-She doesn't want to
talk about it.
-I-I'm just saying...
Jess, tell US what is wrong!
-Bard broke up with me!
He...
What did you do?
- What the fuck, Pete?!
-What?! I ju... but it...
Bradman!
-Just shut up, Pete! I don't
want to hear it! Shut up!
I'm sorry. It's just...
We were gonna go
to bonnaroo together.
-Hey, guys. Hey.
Hey. It's okay.
It's gonna be okay.
Guys.
God damn it.
Pull over. Just pull over.
I don't like it when people cry.
-Bonnaroo is ruined.
Okay. I deleted his number.
It's done.
-Thanks.
This is perfect.
-Did you leave it in drive?
-Check, um... check if...
Check. Is it in drive?
-No, I know how to
drive a car, you guys!
- Sorry.
-Hey, is it okay
if I wear these glasses?
I'm sorry. I didn't ask.
-It's fine.
-Thanks.
-So, do you guys
want to call AAA?
I can call. That's fine.
Cool.
-You guys know
you can't do this, right?
-Do what?
-Get married.
- How old are you?
- 24.
-Yeah, no, that's legal, Jess.
No, I mean
You can't just decide
to get married.
It doesn't work like that.
- Yeah, it does.
- Yeah, of course you can.
That's what everybody
does, Jess.
Name one person that's married
that didn't decide
to get married.
- Arranged marriages.
- No, it's like...
What you guys are doing
is basically an insult
to the whole concept
of marriage.
-You seem like you're
getting upset.
I'm not getting upset.
I just want you to understand
that this is insane.
Wow, yeah, you're, like,
definitely getting
upset right now.
- I'm not!
- Please don't cry again,
'cause that was
really rough on me earlier.
-Shh! Pete. If your sister wants
to cry, you got to let her cry.
- I'm not gonna cry.
- Okay, but if you want to,
you can cry.
- I'm not gonna cry.
- Okay.
- Well, then come down here
and play bottle wars with US.
It's soothing.
-I would, but you guys
are just too good at it.
Y'all need some help?
No, man, we're good.
We got a mechanic coming.
Yeah, this is...
This is no problem.
Look, I'll have you guys up and
running by, by morning.
- Morning?
- Yeah, no problem.
Look you guys
must've hit something,
'cause there's all kinds of like
gristle, like, caught in there,
And the oil pan's like...
Anyway, I'll...
I'll figure it out, so... ohp.
Don't worry about a thing.
Um...
I'll wait here
for the tow truck,
and I'll get somebody to drive
you guys out to the motel.
Motel.
-Okay!
Thanks.
Yeah, no problem.
I'll...
I'll just call the shop, so...
He said a motel?
-Mom?
Hi.
-I got y'all a pizza.
Pepperoni.
Yum.
-Lucky number 208.
Hey, it might be fun, right?
I don't want to blow
your guys' minds or anything...
But there's
a free breakfast buffet.
Great.
Wah!
-Whee!
Aah! Aah!
- Am I doing it?
- Please kick harder. God.
-Can you lift your arms?
-Hey! Aah!
Aah!
My girls!
-You know,
I lived in a motel once.
I mean, not in a room...
In the basement.
But it was nice.
The dryers were down there,
so it was warm.
But that was only
for like a year.
-Cool.
-Hey.
Hey, girl, hey.
Brad's an idiot.
-No, he's actually really smart.
-Really?
Well, you know what I think?
Right, you probably do not
want me giving you advice.
Sorry. No, I...
I could actually handle
some advice.
-Okay, well,
before Pete and I got engaged...
-You mean...
Before this morning?
-Yeah. Before this morning.
Yeah, I just used to think
that all guys were just...
What would
you do with a drunken sailor?
What would you do
with a drunken sailor?
-You were happy
with Brad, right?
-I guess so, yeah.
-Okay, but were you happy
because of Brad,
or because you told
yourself you were happy?
I'm sorry.
I do not know what I am saying.
I am not very good
at this sort of stuff.
-No, no, it's... it's fine.
-Okay, so, things didn't
work out with you and Brad.
You need to find something
that makes you happy,
and then just go for it.
You know, you need to chase it
like a leopard, right?
And, you know,
fuck everyone else.
Fuck what they think.
You are an adult
with really pretty skin
and a fantastic body image,
as evidenced by these...
Wonderfully exotic and bold
choice of bathing suits.
- Thanks.
- Dick-bags like Brad
are just gonna bring you down,
so you know what? Fuck Brad.
Fuck... fuck him.
And don't... don't fuck him,
don't go back to him,
but fuck what he thinks.
You know, pretty soon, you're
gonna not even know who Brad is.
You're... you're not even gonna
be thinking about Brad.
You're gonna be living your life
and being like, "Brad who?"
And then people
are gonna be like,
"hey, Jess, where'd Brad go?"
And you're gonna be like,
"I don't know who's Brad.
And Brad? My god.
Do you know what
he's gonna be like?"
- Sophie.
- Yeah?
-Could you just
stop saying Brad?
-Yes. There it is right there.
That's the first step.
Trust me.
Jessica Stephen Avery...
- That's Pete's middle name.
- What is
the one thing you want...
One thing
that you want right now
more than anything
in the entire world?
-I just want to be drunk.
-Girl, you are already
on your way.
Pete!
Peter!
-What?
-Hey, come on, let's go.
We're getting
your sister trashed.
-Whoo!
- Yeah!
- Okay.
I'll rinse off and over.
- My god.
It is loud in there.
-Dude, what are you doing?
That guy was hitting on me!
-What? No way. Are you serious?
Clearly! And you're all like,
"Hi, how are you?"
You got to look out for me, man!
- You're my...
- Fiancé.
I got this.
Pete.
Hey, Pete. Wait.
-You want some ice?
-No. No, I'm good. I'm good.
Let's just go.
-What?
No. Hey, we're having fun.
This is fun.
Jess.
-I'm having fun.
-See?
-Guys, this is ridiculous.
Let's just go.
- Yeah, okay.
- Okay.
- Quitter.
- Shut up.
- Fucking make me.
- God damn it, Jess.
Fine. You know what?
I'm ready. Let's go.
-Okay.
-You guys can go,
but I'm staying.
- Nope, nope.
We're all going together.
-Nope, nope, I'm staying.
-Quit being such a whiner, Jess.
Bradman broke up with you.
Wah! Big freakin' whoop!
- Pete.
- Pete, that is majorly rude.
Yeah, majorly.
Look, just...
Aah! You know what?
Just do what you want, okay?
- Fine. I will.
- Great.
-Great. Cool.
You guys better not be
having sex when I get back.
Dude, it's weird.
They gave US
these little travel toothpastes
but no little toothbrushes.
That's crazy.
-I guess I'll just
use my finger.
- Hey.
Is this seat taken?
Nope.
-I'm naked.
I...
I'm sorry.
I'm gonna put my...
My boxers back on,
but I just...
Wanted to tell you that.
I don't know what I was...
- No, no.
- Hey, hey.
- Sorry.
-Oop. Um, how about I just meet
you in the middle?
-Okay.
All right.
Um, I'm kind of nervous.
-It's okay.
I was thinking that we can wait
till marriage anyway.
Yeah.
-I'm nervous, too.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
Do you mind?
No.
You're... invited.
-Are you... are you comfortable?
-Yeah.
-Cool.
Hey. Come back.
Hey, guys, it's Jessica.
If you're hearing this, you're
not with me, so that sucks.
-Babe, check this out.
-Anyways, leave a message,
and I'll try to call you back.
-Jess, it's me. Where are you?
Call me back. Bye.
It's me, Pete.
I'm... I'm in the room.
Actually, I'm outside.
Now i'm...
I'm back in the room now.
I'm sorry.
Okay, call me back. Bye.
What?
Your sister's super tidy.
Okay.
-Her phone's off. Her phone's
off, which is typical Jess.
You know, that's,
like, so standard.
That's exactly what she does.
-She... her phone probably just
died, and she just lost her key
- and couldn't get into the room.
- Mnh-mnh.
She would've knocked.
-Hey, hey.
Pete, I'm sure nothing happened.
-She probably just went home
with someone.
-No. What?
No! She... that's not...
She wouldn't... she doesn't...
- What if she was murdered?
- No.
-We should turn on the news.
-This is a test
of the broadcast stations...
Our song.
I don't understand.
You said by morning.
Well, we ran
into a couple of problems.
-Dude, you said "no problem"
like five times!
Totally my bad.
Tomorrow morning definitely,
and I think,
I'm pretty confident I have
this one figured out, so, yeah.
By the way, I...
I borrowed that.
Really good movie.
-Are you sure
she did not come by?
-Yes.
Hey.
Hey, it's gonna be okay.
We're gonna find her.
-Okay?
Hey.
- No.
- Okay?
Just stop!
Just quit it!
If you want to help,
then help, but you're not.
We have to find Jess, okay?
-Hey, maybe she went home
with someone from the bar.
I hate this bar.
-Hey, Timmy!
Great.
-How's your mom?
-He used to be to be my stepdad.
I'm just gonna hang out
back here by the car.
-Okay. Bye, Timmy.
- Hi. We were here last night.
- Inside of the bar.
-And we lost our friend
that we were with.
-My sister, actually.
She never came home.
-Maybe you've seen her?
-She looks like me,
but she's shorter and a girl,
so I guess, in that sense,
she looks kind of like her.
-So like a cross
between him and me.
- But more blonde.
- Right.
-She... she highlights.
-I see a lot of blondes...
Natural blondes, too.
-Okay, give me your phone.
Her.
Okay. I remember her.
Yes!
-Yeah, she went home
with someone.
- You're a fucking liar, man!
- Okay, Pete, slow down.
Slow down.
It's okay, really.
- I'm sorry. I know.
- Okay, she'll probably call.
We'll just hang around and wait.
It's not a big deal.
-No, I think maybe you're
thinking of someone else.
So, if you could just look at...
Just look.
She's not that type of girl.
-Okay, you know what?
Let's go back to that frosty
shop that we saw on the way in.
-No. It was definitely her.
She left, like, in a big Van
with... with a man.
6'2", beard down to here.
- Ungh!
- Pete!
Pete! How is she supposed to
call if you break your phone?
-Is there anything else
that we should know?
-He wore a necklace....
Made of animal bones.
-Okay, yeah,
we need to find your sister.
-Hey, Timmy!
Tell your mom I'll call her!
-She doesn't want to
talk to you, man!
God!
-Did I break it?
Hey.
-Hey.
How's the tea?
Not very good.
Well, that's why
I'm drinking the coffee.
-So, you live out here?
I live where I want.
I'm a wanderer.
-Must be nice.
-It is what it is.
We're all wanderers
in our own way.
You're going to L.A.?
- Yeah.
Could you tell?
No, you just said it
like 300 times last night.
Sorry. Sometimes I just...
I feel like people
can tell a lot about me
just by looking at me, you know?
-I've been looking
at you this whole time,
and I don't know
anything about you.
You, um...
You still need a ride?
-You going to California?
-I'm a wanderer.
-Right.
-Do you feel like, um...
Do you feel like something...
Something brought US together?
Something...
You know,
something bigger than US?
-Yeah.
Tanqueray.
-We all got
different names for it.
-So, beard and a necklace.
Yeah, I know
where that guy lives.
Whoo!
-Whoa!
-6'2" with a beard down to here
and a necklace made of...
Animal bones.
I think you guys
are looking for Chuck.
-Yeah.
Okay, I mean,
I don't know. Maybe.
-We're...
We're looking for his sister.
-Yeah, she's blonde,
kind of hot.
Yeah.
-You saw her?
- Yeah, we...
We heard her.
Loud.
-Do you know where they went?
-Where?
No.
We don't really know where.
Maybe the highway?
Where do you think they went?
-Yeah. Could've been...
Could've been the highway.
-Yeah, I think the highway's
a pretty good place to start.
-Or maybe the frosty shop,
actually.
-No. Remember?
The frosty shop's still closed.
That's right.
Prostitution thing.
-Maybe... home depot.
Or maybe just the highway.
-Okay, so, you think they
went maybe that direction?
- Yeah.
- Okay, great.
-Great.
-Really appreciate it, guys.
Thank you so much.
-You're welcome.
Kind of nice.
-Yeah. I like them.
So...
Where'd y'all meet?
Internet?
What's your sister's number?
I'll call it from my phone.
Yeah. Sure,
1-800-i-don't-know-it.
You don't know
your sister's number?
-No.
I'm sorry, Sophie.
I'm sorry for being
such an idiot.
-Where are we even going, guys?
What, are we just gonna drive
around forever here?
Cool.
Great. This is effective.
Hello?
Yeah, this is her.
Which one is this?
Um...
Okay.
Yeah, I got that.
Yeah, I can do that.
I can do that.
I'll be... I'll be there.
Thank you.
I appreciate it.
Um... all right.
I'll see you then. Bye.
I, booked the commercial.
-The hot-dog thing?
- Yeah, it shoots tomorrow.
- Wow. Okay.
Um... we'll...
We'll find Jess.
The car will be ready
tomorrow morning.
We'll leave really early.
I can run lines with you
in the car on the way back.
Or are there lines, or is it
just the... like, the eating?
-No, I...
I think I should go home.
I need to go home.
Like now.
-Hey. Congratulations.
-I mean, guys, we could drive
around all day and night
looking for her
and not find her.
I really... I really need to go.
-Okay, so, we just give up?
-Yeah, I'm sorry.
I will take a bus.
-I thought this was just
some stupid, local commercial.
-Yeah, it is... it's just
a stupid, local commercial
that I need to pay my rent.
-My sister could be dead,
you know.
Pete, she's not dead.
She went home
with somebody from a bar.
It's not that big of a deal.
That's what people do.
-That's what you do.
Then I should know.
And you know what?
I know why she hasn't called.
She hasn't called because she is
with some weird, tall guy,
and they are busy,
probably, fucking.
He's fucking her.
You know what? There might be
more than one guy.
There might be multiple guys
and there are all sorts of dicks
up in her mouth,
just fucking her mouth,
and then there are dicks
just all up in her ass,
just fucking...
Just fucking her ass.
-She's your family, too, Sophie.
No, Pete, she's not.
-Well, not technically yet.
-Pete, it's a joke.
-There's nothing funny
about your sister-in-law
in some group,
gang-bang sex party.
It's not funny.
-No, you and I are a joke.
US.
We're not fiancés.
We were never gonna be some
happy married couple, okay?
It's just a stupid idea.
We're neighbors.
I use your Wi-Fi.
-You can pull over
wherever, man. We're good.
-What were you thinking?
-How could you do this
to your brother?
to Sophie?
-You know, we've been
driving around all day.
-You could've...
You could've called.
You could've picked up the
phone. You could've called.
-Pete thought you were dead!
-I could only assume
at some point! What else...
- And who the fuck is this guy?!
- Seriously.
He... he looks like uncle Craig.
You know what?
I'm gonna go talk to him.
- Yeah, I think you should.
I think I will.
-I'm gonna go see what this...
Jerk is all about.
-Look, Jess. I get it, okay?
I mean,
I personally have hitchhiked
across several states,
but you know what?
Did you even stop for one second
to think about
how irresponsible this was?
No. What...
What, am I gonna through every
decision like, "I wonder
what this means for my brother
and his fake girlfriend"?
-Yes. Yes, that is exactly
what you should be doing.
You should be thinking
about other people.
You know,
you're not the only person
in this world that counts.
-You told me to have fun.
-I didn't tell you to go run off
and disappear with some man
that has animal bones
around his neck.
-They're puka shells!
Jesus Christ!
-That is...
I make some necklaces and some,
turquoise jewelry.
-I don't even know
why I was freaking out earlier,
'cause you are...
You're cool, man. You're great.
-You're cool.
What, and you two
are such mature adults?
-Yes... yes!
And compared to you, yes!
-You know what?
Perfect. This is great.
I have a great idea for you.
Why are you wearing
turquoise bracelets?
-Shh!
No, this is gonna be great.
- Pete, Sophie...
- What?
- I have a surprise for you.
Chuck, here, happens to be
an ordained minister.
-Congrats, man. Very cool.
-I officiated
at my friend bleslie's ceremony
at lake havasu.
-So, what do you say guys?
You wanted to get married.
Yeah I don't...
-It would be an honor.
-We would love to,
but I actually have to be
getting back to L.A.
-Yeah, I think it's just bad
timing to do it right now.
-And then,
aside from the timing,
I mean, there's,
you know, also the things.
- It's mostly bad timing.
- Really, Pete?
What's going on here?
-You want to know
what's going on here?
Here's what I see.
I see two kids who are scared.
They're in love,
but they're scared.
Of what?
Of each other.
Of their love for each other...
Your beautiful love
for each other.
Now, listen, you two.
This is a tough world,
but you've found something here.
You can choose to ignore it
and go home,
or you can choose
to be happy together
in this life,
maybe even the next.
-So, you gonna chase it
like a leopard?
-Hey, guys.
What's happening? Hey.
-We're getting married.
- Right now?
- Right now.
- Right fucking now.
- No.
Tomorrow.
Tomorrow morning.
Tonight is the wedding feast.
-What about the hot dogs?
-I don't need those dick-bags.
Cool.
Cool!
Hey, man,
got you a wedding present.
I fixed your car.
- Thanks, man.
- Definitely, definitely.
You can just, get me
a check or whatever tomorrow.
Yeah, my mom's
bringing it by later.
You know how mom's are.
- For sure.
- Yeah.
Hot dog?
- I'm okay.
- Cool.
So, there's this one.
I wore it
to the spring semi-formal.
And there's that one.
- Whoop.
- Um...
- Just look at that one.
-Yeah, I guess any dress
is fine, then,
as long as I don't look
like an idiot.
-Sophie, this is...
This is Marc by Marc Jacobs.
So...
- No, the dress is nice.
Yeah, I... maybe I should try
and be hot for once.
-You're gonna look great.
I'm serious.
Sorry for making you guys
drive around all day.
I probably
should've just called.
-It's fine.
I wasn't really worried
about you.
I mean, I was worried about you,
but I was 19 once, too.
-I'm 21.
I had fun, though.
But then it got kind of weird.
-Yeah, that's the thing.
It always gets weird.
-It's so funny.
Pete's in love.
-Yeah.
I guess he is.
-Well, the dresses...
Yeah.
-And bestow upon him
the blessing of fruitful loins.
This one's pretty great.
Right?
Sophie.
Sophie, this is it.
This is... this is totally
your wedding dress.
I mean, okay, I...
Know it's kind of short,
but try it on. I think that
you're really gonna like it.
Thanks.
- Sure.
Hi, guys.
- Jess.
Hey, come here.
- Okay.
- Here, put on this head lamp.
- All right.
-It's cool, right?
So, your guy is... cool.
-Yeah.
-He taught me a lot
about eagles.
Really?
-Which was pretty cool.
-You know we're not a...
A thing, right?
-I mean, I don't know.
I know you're still...
Upset about Brad.
-I'm not upset
about Brad anymore.
I mean, I... I am,
but not really, you know?
Yeah.
I honestly never
thought you'd get married.
-Really?
-Yeah. I mean, I never really
gave it too much thought, but...
I guess I never
pictured it happening.
-I don't know. I guess I never
pictured it happening like this.
-It makes sense, though.
I mean, and Sophie...
I like her.
Hey, I wanted to ask
if you would...
Be my best man.
-Yeah. Yeah. Um...
Yeah, of course.
- Yes!
- Here, um...
Now you have a ring.
Actually, Jess, I...
-Jesus Christ.
- Fumble it around.
- Wow.
- Yeah?
- Good work, petey.
- It's good?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Pillsbury!
No! You are done!
- Aah!
You can't catch me!
Aah!
- Hi.
- Sophie.
Guess what.
-What?
-Jess is gonna be my best man.
Ha!
Hey.
-Hey.
-Don't worry. Jess can be
your maid of honor, too.
Are you sure that this
is really a good decision?
You kidding?
This is, like,
the best decision.
-Okay, yeah. I know it...
Seems a little crazy.
-Yeah.
-But that's what makes it
so great, you know?
Sophie.
Come on. It's gonna be fun.
-Yeah.
We always have
a lot of fun together.
-Yeah, we do.
-It's just...
Do you think that we should be
doing this because it's fun?
I mean, do we seriously think
that this is going to last...
You know, forever?
-If we get married,
it will, yeah.
Sophie, it...
It's gonna be great.
I promise you.
You're gonna love it,
seriously.
Honk, honk.
And...
Don't worry about earlier.
We were both upset.
You just...
You need a little rest.
I'll even sleep in the Jeep
tonight, give you some space.
-Okay.
I'll miss you.
But I'll see you in the morning.
-Yeah, see you then.
-All right.
-Hey, by the way,
that dress looks "f" -ing sexy.
-Thanks.
Okay. Bye.
-Goodnight, beautiful.
-Now can we go?
-No.
I'm an idiot.
I asked her to marry me.
Who else would do that
but a complete idiot?
I'd have been better off
just hooking up
with some dude at a bar.
... hey, Pete.
Yeah, sorry, but...
We're gonna...
We're actually gonna take off.
But, um...
Stay strong, my brother.
Stay strong, Jessica.
Come on, bleslie.
Hey, man,
about that check...
Yeah.
No. Forget about it.
Seriously, it's on the house.
And, thanks for letting me
hang out with you guys.
It really means a lot to me.
So...
Yeah, man. Of course.
-Yeah.
Maybe you two should just date.
Just kidding. Just kidding.
Okay. See you, dudes.
Sorry you got dumped again.
You can go after him
if you want.
I'll be fine.
Me and Sophie, we just...
We weren't meant to be,
you know?
-God damn it.
God damn it, Pete!
I don't give a shit
about that guy.
I don't think that I even gave
a shit about Brad.
But I do give a shit about you,
and you're not fine,
because Sophie fucking left you!
-Gee, thanks, Jess.
I almost completely forgot.
-You've got to...
You've got to fucking try, Pete!
What are you doing?
Jess, what are you doing?
Jess?
-I'm driving home. You can
stay up there if you want.
-No, you're not.
Don't start the car.
Hey, turn the car off.
Do not put that car in dri...
No! No! No!
-You're not an idiot, Pete.
You're a little bitch.
It's completely over
unless you try to fix it.
-Fix what, Jess?
You can't just choose someone.
That's not how it works.
You were right.
What? You can?
I choose that rock.
I choose this car, Jess.
I'm gonna marry this car.
We're in love. We're gonna
live happily ever after.
-Do you really want to
marry the car?
-No.
It actually breaks down a lot.
-Do you really want to
marry Sophie?
Get in the car.
- Right away.
-They're...
I mean, they're okay.
They're workable.
Yeah.
I like what you're doing.
Keep up the good work.
-Hey, Terry,
can I come show you something?
-Yeah, sure.
Wow! These are great!
-Yeah, I thought
you'd like that.
-I do.
Let's get back to work.
- Ooh!
- That was a great one.
One more.
I love it.
Try a little bit more chewing.
- You sure about this?
Sophie.
Don't marry me.
If... if you don't want to,
I don't want to, either.
I'm sorry I just didn't
say this from the start,
but...
I-I really like you.
I've liked you since the minute
that I met you.
And now what's...
Really weird is,
I think...
I love you.
-Keep eating it.
-I just want to be around you.
I don't know why I thought
it was easier to...
Propose than to just...
Anyway, um...
I'm really sorry
for interrupting.
I'm really...
I'm really sorry.
But I needed to tell you that.
It's okay if you don't...
Like me back...
Or love me back.
I just wanted you to know.
-Fantastic. And one more time.
Yah, that is good.
-she's amazing.
-Looks great.
She sounds German.
-this is a test
of the broadcast stations
of your area. Equipment
that can quickly warn you
during emergencies
is being tested.
If this had been
an actual emergency,
official messages would have
followed the alert tone.