Captain Blood!
Captain Blood, there's a prize off
our larboard bow flying Spanish colors.
Come on!
- Boatswain.
- Aye, sir.
Man the guns. Cram on more sail.
Man the guns!
- Larboard helm.
- Larboard helm!
Uncover the guns.
Run out the guns!
Put a shot across their bow.
Number one gun,
fire!
Fire again.
Number two gun,
fire!
You may show them our true colors,
Mr. Mannering.
Break out the Jolly Roger.
Will we never hear the end
of this Captain Blood,
this pirate who captures our treasure
and our ships?
You, my dear Marquis de Riconete.
You. Why haven't you
hanged the scoundrel?
Your Majesty, the hanging of one
pirate is hardly the answer to our problem.
As long as these outlaws are protected
in the West Indies by the English...
Oh, the English, the English, the...
Be careful, you fool.
You see, Marquis, it isn't enough that
the ruler of Spain be bled by his physician,
these buccaneers must bleed
our kingdom, too.
My lord Marquis,
you're the governor of La Hacha,
our most important island possession
in the West Indies.
You have a galleon of 40 guns.
Therefore, we charge you
with the personal responsibility
of capturing this Captain Blood.
I shall do everything in my power, sire.
But of course Your Majesty realizes
this is no common criminal
you send me after.
Blood is a learned, intelligent man.
A doctor.
A doctor? Are the English so healthy
that their physicians must turn to piracy
for a living?
Blood is not English, Your Majesty,
he's Irish.
I have prepared a dossier on the man
which I should be pleased to read.
Read, read.
"Peter Blood, born in Ireland, 1658.
"Bachelor of Medicine,
Dublin University, 1680.
"Arrested by the English
for saving the life of a wounded rebel
"during the Monmouth Rebellion"...
Rebellion? Yes, yes, Count Harrach.
"Sentenced to death.
"Sentence later changed
to a life of slavery at Barbados.
"There, he and a group of fellow slaves
"managed a somewhat incredible escape."
That's enough, Count Harrach.
Well, we offer a reward
of 50,000 pieces of eight
for the head of this buccaneer.
Even an Englishman may find that tempting.
If not, I'm sure you, my lord Marquis, will.
Unless this Captain Blood is captured,
your wealth and position will be forfeit.
- Oh, but, sire, you mustn't...
- Captain Alvarado.
Sire?
You will accompany the Marquis
to the Indies
and will assume the post
of military position.
- That is, I mean, of military attaché.
- Yes, Your Majesty.
And you will act as our representative,
and we will charge you
with the direct responsibility
of seeing that our orders are carried out.
No sign yet, Peter?
No, the beach seems deserted.
What time do you make it, Tom?
Not an hour left before dawn.
We'll have to work fast.
Faith, yes.
There'll be the devil to pay
if the Marquis finds us
lying off his island in broad daylight.
- You still think the signal will come?
- Of course.
Pacheco is a man of his word.
Besides, we can't leave.
We must get supplies and ammunition.
There's very little left.
- We can get what we need in Tortuga.
- No, it's too far.
Besides, I've a taste for shooting at
the Spaniards with their own cannon balls.
Peter, over there.
One, two,
three!
- Lower away.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Lively, now.
- You stay here, Scotty.
- Aye.
Where is Pacheco?
Captain Blood. Captain Blood!
Captain.
- Captain.
- What is it, man?
It was a trap, Captain.
We were ambushed.
Pacheco wasn't there.
All the other men were taken prisoner.
If it's fighting they want,
we'll give them a taste of it.
But we've little enough powder and ball left
as it is.
No matter. Our men are there.
But the Marquis' ship's within sound
of our guns.
It's suicide.
For us, and those men ashore, too.
Sure, you're right, Tom.
- Let's try to get to Tortuga for supplies.
- Aye.
You men, take Scotty below.
Weigh anchor, make sail.
Look lively, now.
Your Excellency.
So, my new slaves
are Captain Blood's men, eh?
I've been anxious to meet your captain
for a long time.
Where was he headed for?
Well?
Where was your captain bound for?
Where?
Perhaps you'll be more talkative
after a short while in the pearl fisheries.
Take them away.
Well, Excellency?
Didn't I make you a good price
for such interesting slaves?
Señor Fairfax, your greediness
for the sale of a few slaves
has cost me a chance to capture
your countryman. Captain Blood.
But, Your Excellency, I didn't know
it was the Avenger in time to warn you.
By now, Blood is 20 leagues away.
In a fast ship,
-impossible to capture.
- You will have other chances.
Not like this one.
Platt.
Hokenby.
Peter, why don't we go ashore?
I'm staying aboard.
But, Peter, there's nothing we can do
to help those men now.
- Why must you keep thinking about it?
- What would you have me do, then?
Try and forget them.
Forget our own men?
Slaves of Spain,
rotting away in the Marquis' dungeons?
Do you remember what it was like
before we escaped from slavery?
The stench of those filthy holes? The swill?
The chains rotting away
the flesh from your bones?
- The whips, and the branding irons?
- Yes, I remember.
Don't ask me to forget, then.
Captain Blood!
- Captain Blood.
- Scotty, if you're in trouble
-with the father of another señorita...
- It's not me that's in trouble this time,
it's the Marquis.
- What are you talking about?
- A French ship just arrived from La Hacha.
Her mate tells me that
that hurricane that's been blowing about
hit the Marquis' ship
and just about ruined her.
- The Santa Paula?
- Aye.
She's no fit to go to sea again
until she's been repaired.
Hear that, Tom?
We could sail right to the island
and the Marquis couldn't give us a chase.
But he's still got a fort,
and 50 cannon mounted on the beach.
There's no cannon in the cove
at the back of the island.
- All the men aboard?
- Aye, sir.
But, Peter, you can't take the Avenger
right into the Marquis' grasp.
- We'd surely be caught.
- You're right, Tom,
we wouldn't stand a chance. Weigh anchor!
This is the most foolhardy thing
you've ever done.
Beyond a doubt. Stand by to make sail!
- We'll end up slaves ourselves.
- He'll probably hang all of us.
Set our course for La Hacha, Mr. Mannering.
Aye, aye, sir.
Hands aloft!
Take out the topsail!
I'm still dead set against it, Peter.
It's too dangerous.
This cove's right
on the Marquis' back doorstep.
Where would he be less likely
to look for us?
And what if somebody recognizes you?
What if Pacheco see you?
He's betrayed us once already.
Pacheco won't betray anybody else.
I'll make sure of that while I'm here.
Well, how do you propose
to get into the town?
You can't just walk in and have yourself
announced to the Marquis.
I'll leave that to Lady Chance.
She's obliged me more than once,
perhaps she'll oblige me again.
- I've great faith in the Lady.
- You'll need it.
Whoa! Señores, fruit, fresh fruit.
Would you take your pick
before I go to La Hacha?
No, no, move on, move on.
Wait!
- Where did you say you were going?
- To La Hacha, across the island.
Where else?
- There he is, Tom.
- Who?
Our messenger from Lady Chance.
- Will you buy some of my fruit, señor?
- I may buy all of it.
Thank you. Muchas gracias, señor.
Pacheco! Pacheco, open up.
Pacheco.
Miguel, Miguel.
Querido mio, I have been looking for you.
Oh, Miguel, you kiss me so good...
You are not Miguel. Who are you?
Señorita, it's a little late for introductions.
Why are you wearing Miguel's clothes?
And what are you peddling his fruit for?
- Well, Miguel is sick.
- Sick?
Si. He asked me to take his place.
I'm his friend.
His friend?
- What is your name, señor?
- Pedro. Pedro Morales.
Pedro?
That is strange.
He has never mentioned you to me.
Well, he has never mentioned you
to me, either.
But that is not so strange.
What do you mean, señor?
Something is wrong?
Oh, no, no, no. Nothing, nothing.
I can see why Miguel never told me
about you, señorita...
Señorita...
- Pepita.
- Pepita Maria Rosados.
The woman is even more lovely
than the name.
Miguel knew I would be helpless
before such beauty.
That's why he kept you a secret from me.
The señor is very kind.
- But it is true that Miguel is very fond of me.
- Oh, Pepita! Fond of you?
It is only because I'm his closest friend
that he is so helpless that...
- Helpless?
- Si, completely.
It is only because of that
that he trusts me alone in the city with you.
But I am only human,
and you must help me to resist.
Don't worry about that, señor.
I will help you.
But remember, I'm only human, too.
- Pepita?
- Si, señor?
I was seeking early today an old friend
of mine, but his shop was deserted.
Perhaps you know him.
I know all the men in La Hacha.
What is your friend's name?
Pacheco. Fernando Pacheco.
Oh, yes, yes, I remember him.
He is the thin one.
- But he left the island yesterday.
- Left?
Oh, no. I'm sure you're mistaken.
I'm certain he is still here.
I was told he had gone to Portobelo.
Oh? Who told you this?
The overseer, Carmilio.
But, señor, why worry about old friends,
when it is so easy to find new ones
in La Hacha?
What is that?
Oh, just the slaves.
They're on their way back
from the Marquis' pearl fisheries.
The ones that are left.
- The ones that are left?
- There are fewer every day.
Last week, 34. Yesterday, 32.
- Today, who knows?
- What happens to them?
What happens to anyone who has to dive
for pearls in water filled with sharks?
Oh, please excuse me.
I forgot. The overseer's wine.
Papá!
Papá? Wake up, Papá.
The señor overseer is here.
Must I run this inn all by myself?
Get moving!
Halt!
Sit down!
My beautiful Pepita.
Have you no welcome for your friend today?
- Pablo is bringing it.
- Pablo?
Pablo.
Now I feel better, my beautiful Pepita.
Don't touch!
Don't touch?
Women. Women, they're all the same.
If the señor would care
for a little more wine,
I should be most happy
to buy it for him, huh?
Another time. I must take
those slaves back to the dungeons.
This is the day for the Marquis' inspection.
Get moving! On your feet!
Come on! Get moving!
- Señor.
- Pepita. I must go.
This is for the wine, huh?
Oh, no, señor. Not from a friend of Miguel's.
Thank you, señorita. I'll be back.
Si. I know.
Get along! Get along! Hurry up!
Come on.
Why don't you wait in the carriage,
lsabelita? I'll only be a few moments.
Please don't be too long, Uncle.
The sun is very hot.
I should be most happy to escort
the señorita back to the residencia.
You don't seem too anxious
to inspect the dungeons, Captain.
Well, I hardly find them attractive,
Excellency.
I'm afraid the Captain still judges us
by Spanish standards, lsabelita.
He forgets we are in a new world,
where men live by new laws.
Or die by them.
Come now, Captain,
these slaves dive for pearls.
And pearls are one of the few things
that make this dull little colony bearable.
Your Excellency,
everything is ready for the inspection.
Splendid, splendid. And the day's catch?
Three pearls, Excellency.
Two of fine quality.
Uncle,
don't you think I deserve some reward
for waiting in this heat?
Of course, my dear.
A small pearl like this for a Marquis' niece?
It's fit only for a...
For a peddler.
Excuse me, my dear.
How clumsy of you, peddler.
Forgive my hands, señorita.
They are not accustomed to pearls.
Perhaps you would appreciate them more
if you were to dive for one yourself.
Perhaps.
Darling.
I thought I'd never get away
from your uncle.
Don't tell me business bores you.
By contrast? Yes.
Look, I'm over half finished.
How do you like it?
It's very charming, my sweet.
Oh, George,
why don't you take me away from here?
Back to Spain, to the court
and the life I was meant for?
You know I will, lsabelita, as soon as I can.
I'm sick to death of my life here.
Sewing and embroidering,
supervising the kitchen maids,
waiting on my uncle.
And those dull, dull official parties.
"Ah, sf, Señora Second Assistant Clerk,
"your new gown is quite, quite ravishing."
It's only three years behind the fashion.
"Oh, and Señor Plantation Foreman,
"your little Ramon is so, so unspoiled."
He thinks nothing of wiping his filthy hands
all over the draperies.
Oh, George, don't let's wait any longer.
Oh, but, darling,
even if we could get off the island,
it would take gold.
But I have my jewels.
The pearls alone are worth a fortune.
But I can't take your money.
Don't you see that it means my happiness?
Our happiness?
You must take them, querido.
That's what you really want?
Oh, yes, it is.
More than anything in the world.
lsabelita.
Go to your room.
- But, Uncle, I...
-lsabelita!
You...
You must understand, Your Excellency. I...
It is bad enough that I should
have business dealings with vermin.
I don't wish them to infest my family.
Señor Fairfax,
if you attempt to see my niece again,
I shall have the distinct pleasure
of watching you
being torn apart by the sharks.
Pepita.
Please, Carmilio, suéltame, be careful.
You will make me break the wine bottles.
Sol must be careful
the bottles must not be broken, huh?
Si.
But you. You break men's hearts.
My heart, Pepita.
Oh, Carmilio.
Pepita.
You hold this, Carmilio.
- Señor Morales.
- Good evening, Pepita.
Welcome to Venta de Rosados.
Whatever you wish is yours.
Would you not like a table
in the other room?
It is much cooler and much more private.
A little later perhaps, señorita.
First, I must talk with a friend.
Señor.
Now will you allow me the honor
of buying you a glass of wine?
- Well...
- Pepita,
bring us some of your father's best sherry.
- Si, señor.
- Pepita.
Gracias.
Delightful girl, this one.
To some people, perhaps.
Surely, my dear Carmilio,
a man of your intelligence
is not taken in by this little trick of Pepita's.
You must see what she's trying to do?
- Trying to do?
- Si.
She's using me, as she would any stranger,
to make you jealous.
- Are you sure?
- Of course.
You know, Carmilio, you're quite a catch.
I am?
Well, certainly.
You have
authority,
position,
strength.
Your wine, señor.
Authority, position, and strength.
And such charming manners.
My friend, what woman could resist you?
Morales, you're right. It's impossible.
She should fall at my feet.
I agree with you.
Now, it's getting late, and don't forget
we are going to have our last drink
at your place.
- We are?
- You promised.
I tell you, Pedro,
the slaves, they are nothing but trouble.
They are lazy, they get sick, they die.
They try to escape.
How do they get away?
They don't. Not from this prison.
You should see the dungeons
deep underground.
Seems very interesting.
I should like to see them.
Without a pass with the Marquis' seal,
not even the King of Spain
could come though that door.
Without the seal of the Marquis,
not even the King of Spain, huh?
If it's bad like you say,
heaven knows why he should want to.
Carmilio. Huh? Well, it's almost midnight.
If you don't want me to see the jails,
I think I'll take my leave.
Why don't you have another drink?
Oh, excuse me.
What's this?
It's nothing. It's just a keepsake.
- Let me see it.
- It's nothing, I tell you.
I say, let me see it.
Where'd you get that?
It was given to me today by a friend.
His name was Fernando Pacheco.
- But...
- But Pacheco is dead, huh?
I know.
You might say he bequeathed it to me.
It was in his hand when I found him.
I don't know this Pacheco.
I made a mistake about this medallion.
It looks like something else.
Does it?
Thanks for your hospitality.
Juan!
- Juan!
- Si, señor?
- Find Señor Fairfax. Bring him here. Hurry!
- Si, señor.
But a man like you...
A man like you does not come to La Hacha
only to sell fruit.
Why you don't tell Pepita your real reason
for being here?
I have told you.
Lies, lies, nothing but lies.
If you were really a fruit peddler,
people would not be
asking questions about you.
About me?
Who has been asking about me, Pepita?
You don't answer my questions, señor.
Why should I answer yours?
Well, you are my friend, little one.
You must trust me, have faith.
Let go, señor, or I'll awaken Papá.
Please, señor. Stop it, señor.
Papá.
Oh, Papá.
Oh, señor.
- Stop it.
- It is too late to stop, señorita.
From the first moment we met,
it was too late.
- You are lying to me again, I know.
- Does this seem like a lie, señorita?
Lie to me some more, señor.
First you must tell me
who was asking questions.
It was only the overseer.
But let us not talk about him now. Let us...
What did the overseer want, Pepita?
Just to know who you are
and what you are doing in La Hacha.
- Was that all?
- Si.
Now, I have told you my secrets,
you must tell me yours.
Of course. But not tonight, it is too late.
- If you do not trust me, señor...
- Oh, I trust you, Pepita.
But as I told you before,
I do not trust myself.
- Pedro, you're not going to go?
- Si.
- But I thought...
- Adiós, little one.
Have you lost something, señores?
- No, señor, we have found what we lost.
- That is good.
Whoever your master is,
he could have taught you to be
a little more polite.
Nothing like a long nap
after a strenuous exercise.
But it was quite unnecessary
for your associates
to go to so much trouble to bring me here.
After all, I am just as anxious to make
your acquaintance as you are to make mine,
Señor... Señor...
My name is George Fairfax.
In my line of work, one can't be too careful.
And what exactly is
your line of work, señor?
What are you doing in La Hacha,
Señor Morales?
I sell fruit.
Persimmons, mangoes, pomegranates...
And is that all you have for sale?
Everything.
I'm afraid we can't do business after all.
- Then if the señor will excuse me, I will...
- Sit down, Morales.
You are a stranger in La Hacha, my friend,
and perhaps you're not aware
that the laws here are very strict.
For instance,
the penalty for robbery is death.
For example, suppose you were
to have stolen something of mine.
A ring, say, or a timepiece, or a medallion.
And were you to be caught with it
in your possession,
I could have you hanged.
It's a very harsh law,
but sometimes a useful one.
And what is the penalty for murder
in La Hacha?
Well, that depends on whether or not
the murderer is caught.
For example, there was a regrettable death
of a local shopkeeper,
a ship's chandler, just yesterday.
Poor fellow, he became too talkative,
and yet there have been
almost no questions about his death,
and I do not think there will be any.
Incidentally, if I should
shoot a robber in my quarters,
and he happened to be armed,
there'd be even less trouble
with the authorities.
But how would I be expected to know
that he was holding an unloaded pistol?
This one, however, is loaded.
- Who is it?
- It's me, lsabelita. Let me in.
lsabelita, what are you doing here?
George, we must leave
La Hacha now, tonight.
- We can't.
- The Santa Paula is ready to sail.
She wasn't as badly damaged
as they thought
and the Marquis
doesn't trust his niece alone in the city.
Tomorrow morning
I'm being sent to a convent.
I'm sorry, lsabelita,
but I don't see how we can possibly...
But we must. We must.
Look, these will buy us a boat
and whatever else we need.
Please, George, please.
All right. All right, we'll leave.
The guards followed you here.
Señor Fairfax, our orders are to return
the señorita to the residencia,
and to place you under arrest.
- And my sword?
- Si, señor.
Very well.
Come and take it.
I'll be all right.
- George.
- It's not too bad.
Sit down, sit down.
There are three more guards
coming up the stairs.
Now go, and go fast.
- He's badly hurt.
- We must get out of here,
before those four guards are replaced by 40.
I know a place near the quay
where we'll be safe.
You are very lucky, señor.
If the lead had hit you six inches
nearer to your right,
you'd have been lying
in a different kind of bed.
As it is, you'll be well enough
to fight another duel tomorrow.
Open up!
Ope" up, I say!
Open, in the name of the Marquis.
It's the guard.
- I know that.
- I've got to let them in, or they'll break in.
I'm aware of that, too, Señor Bragg.
Ope" up, I say!
Just a minute, just a minute. I'm coming!
All right.
- Open, I say.
- I'm coming.
What may I do for you, gentlemen?
Me tavern's closed for the night.
We do not want your rotten liquor,
innkeeper.
We're hunting for the Marquis' niece,
and two men who attacked our guards.
The Marquis' niece? In Billy Bragg's place?
That's a rich one.
We're searching everywhere.
The Marquis' orders.
- Please...
- Upstairs, go.
Gentlemen, please walk quietly.
Customers are asleep.
Oh, no. No, Lieutenant, not in there, please.
Stand to one side, innkeeper.
What do you mean,
bursting into my private room,
waking up my husband?
Get out. Get out, you filthy pig!
Get out, you pig- Pig!
Any more rooms
you'd like to see, Lieutenant?
Oh, no. No, no, no.
No fine ladies at Billy Bragg's, you know.
This being a soldier is a risky business,
ain't it?
Si, you speak the truth. Come along, men.
- Come along.
- Buenas noches.
Same to you, sir.
All clear, Mr. Fairfax.
Señor Bragg, the world lost an honest actor
when you turned rogue.
- You're a man of many talents.
- That I am, sir.
This is a night for genius, Señor Morales.
An innkeeper turned actor
and a fruit peddler
who is both doctor and fencing master.
You seem to forget, Señor Fairfax,
that you owe me your life.
A debt I may later wish to collect.
At your service.
George!
Señor Morales, we're deeply grateful to you.
- Both of us.
- Yes. How can we ever repay you?
Well, l...
What did you do with my jewels?
I? Do with them? I never had them.
I must have left them on the quay.
I remember now,
I put them down when you were wounded.
- It doesn't matter.
- Doesn't matter?
You spill jewels worth 30,000 doubloons
in the dirt and say it doesn't matter?
Yes, George, you're right.
My jewels do matter.
They matter a great deal.
You see, querido,
I wanted to go to Spain with you.
But without my jewels,
we'd be paupers, wouldn't we?
- And that would be frightful, wouldn't it?
-lsabelita, stop it. I didn't mean...
I know exactly what you meant.
- But, lsabelita...
- You should rest, señor.
- Perhaps you would like a glass of wine?
- No, no.
Pardon me if I get one for myself.
Bragg, stay with the señor.
- Perhaps he might need something.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Is this, by any chance,
what you were missing, señorita?
I found it on the quay.
Gracias, señor.
Now everything is all right, huh?
You and Señor Fairfax can elope.
You deliberately hid my jewels.
- You wanted me to quarrel with George.
- Of course I did.
Why?
Are you in love with him?
I... I don't know. I'm not sure.
I suppose I thought he'd take me away
from this horrible place.
It's unfortunate you picked the wrong man.
I could've told you that.
You?
What would a fruit peddler know about?
Or are you a peddler, señor?
You no longer talk like one. Who are you?
At the moment,
I find it convenient to be a peddler.
My uncle would have ways
of discovering your true identity.
I don't doubt it for a minute.
But if he were to take up my time,
how could I be of service to you?
- Service?
- Yes.
I've had business dealings with Mr. Fairfax,
and I began to suspect his true nature.
So I left my ship in the cove
on the other side of the island
and came here in disguise to...
To, shall we say, investigate.
And what has all this got to do with me?
Well, you're anxious to leave La Hacha,
and I have a boat, so...
You could take me away from the island.
To Maracaibo.
Or Port of Spain!
Why not?
Oh, señor,
how can I ever thank you enough?
Well, you might try
throwing me another pearl.
I suppose I do deserve that.
You'll not let this one slip
through your fingers?
Have no fear.
I didn't know you then,
or I'd have been more careful.
You're gallant, whoever you are.
In my fashion.
Now I'll send you back to the residencia.
As it is, if we were to set foot
on the waterfront,
the guards would send you back
to the Marquis
and me to the pearl fisheries.
You must go back to your uncle at once.
What can I say to him?
He'll send me to the convent.
Not if you were to tell him that
you've discovered Mr. Fairfax's true colors,
and beg him to forgive you
and pardon the poor fruit peddler.
Yes. Yes, of course.
I'll come to the residencia tomorrow
for the pardon, and if it's safe, we can go.
Very well, I trust you.
I know nothing about you,
and yet I do trust you.
Perhaps because you have no choice.
Oh, I don't know. You are different.
You save a man's life or take it, like that.
Perhaps I'm not so different.
You said yourself
you know nothing about me.
How much do I need to know?
Doctor? Swordsman?
I got it!
Port Royal. Tortuga.
That's who he is. Captain Blood.
- Blood?
- Aye.
Billy Bragg's still got his two eyes,
hasn't he?
How come you're traveling with him,
Mr. Fairfax, and don't know?
A reward of 50,000 pieces of eight.
Billy Bragg,
we've turned some good deals in our time,
but this is the biggest one of all.
Get to the Marquis as fast as you can.
Bragg, I have something for you to do.
You will take the señorita to the residencia.
- But I can't leave, sir. I...
- Go along, Billy.
Go to the residencia. I'll be all right.
You'll stay here with me, won't you,
Señor Morales?
You may be sure of that, señor.
- Señor Bragg, huh?
- Aye.
- The señorita, she is safe at home?
- Aye, sir.
But I've got something more important
to tell you, Captain Blood.
I met you in Tortuga, Captain.
The Red Lion Tavern.
- You remember Billy Bragg?
- Bragg?
Aye. I know I've put on a bit of weight,
but you remember Billy Bragg?
Oh, yes.
Billy Bragg-
I finally stole enough money
to get a place of me own.
Well, if you're charging
for these accommodations,
you're still engaged in piracy.
Leastwise, Captain, I'm too much
of a buccaneer to ever turn informer.
I've not accused you of it.
Aye, but your friend Mr. Fairfax
put me up to it.
That's why he wanted me to go with the girl,
so I'd turn you in, and we'd split the reward.
That adds another count against him.
- Another?
- Yes.
He murdered a man who used to supply us.
And sold six of my crew into slavery.
Would you like me
to dispose of this Fairfax, Captain?
Not yet. I may have use for him.
The Avenger is on the far side of the island.
I may be back for friend Fairfax
before we sail.
He'll be here.
Now I must surrender myself to the Marquis.
- What?
- Oh, not as Peter Blood,
but as a fruit peddler
who served the Marquis' niece
and who earned her confidence.
Why take such a risk, Captain?
Billy, if I'm to get my men out of prison,
I must first get myself into the residencia.
- Pedro Morales.
- Morales.
- Excellency.
- So,
my niece tells me
that you've proved an invaluable friend.
- The señorita is most generous, Excellency.
- Perhaps.
And yet I can't help wondering
if she might not have been returned
to the residencia
without your invaluable assistance,
and without costing me the lives
of my guards.
I apologize for my enthusiasm, Excellency.
However, you have been of some assistance.
- You are free to go.
- Gracias, Excellency.
And, Morales,
in the future, try to curb your enthusiasms.
At another time,
you may not find me so lenient.
- Excellency.
- If Your Excellency
will seal the order
for the prisoner's release?
This is the wrong seal.
- The square one is the order for release.
- Pardon, Excellency.
Are you a murderer as well as a thief, señor?
It's hardly murder.
I was watching you from the corridor.
- What did you steal from the courtroom?
- Well, I...
I took a pass, to help us escape.
"Us"? I'm not as stupid as that.
- You were planning to leave without me.
- Well, this is hardly the place to explain.
- Come with me and I'll...
- I'm not going anywhere.
And neither are you.
There are guards to prevent that.
Señorita, wait.
You're right,
I wasn't going to take you with me.
I told you I was,
so I'd have a chance to steal this pass.
You must believe me.
I only came here to help some friends
escape from La Hacha.
I've listened to enough of your stories.
You can tell this one to my uncle.
- He may be more interested than I.
- Wait, please.
lsabelita, you want to leave this island.
Then think of my friends in the dungeons.
Compare your reasons for escape
with those of men living in slavery.
You came here to help criminals escape?
They're not criminals.
They're men who were trapped
and sold into slavery by your friend Fairfax.
I know what it's like to be an innocent man
and live as a prisoner.
I was a slave once myself.
And there was no reason for that?
No reason except as a doctor,
I treated a dying patient.
For that I was sentenced to a life of slavery.
I felt the whips and knew the weights
of those chains, and asked no favors.
- You're asking one now.
- Not for myself.
You may have many reasons for hating me.
I don't blame you.
But you can't hate the men I want to help.
Did you really think
I'd be moved by all this?
Yes, I did.
lsabelita.
Why are you out here?
It was stifling inside. I wanted some air.
You'd better go to your room.
You might catch a chill.
Yes, all right. I'll come in.
So, you're going to go away?
You're going to leave La Hacha?
Perhaps I am, perhaps I may never leave.
That is true. You may never leave,
if you do not let me help you.
What do you mean?
Carmilio, the overseer,
has told me he would like to kill you.
Carmilio, huh?
Possibly I do need your help, Pepita.
Si, perhaps I need your help very much.
We will be partners, huh? You and I.
Oh, no, no, señor. I will not be a fool again.
- I will make you rich.
- No, I tell you I won't...
- How rich?
- Here.
The rest is for you. For one little favor.
There is something I want you to do for me.
Of course.
From now on, we live only for each other.
- Now, your friend Carmilio...
- Oh, Carmilio. I forgot about Carmilio.
Pepita, tonight I don't want you
to forget about him.
So I won't forget about him, partner.
- You know, Carmilio?
- What?
I think you have the most beautiful hair
in all of La Hacha.
- You do?
- Si, I do.
- You love me?
- Oh, sf, very much, Carmilio.
If you love me,
why you always making fun of me?
Oh, my silly little blockhead.
How else would Pepita fool them?
If Papá knew how much I loved you,
he would lock me in the cellar, nights.
I would much rather be here with you.
- Don't you like that, Carmilio?
- Yes, very much.
- But it's against the regulations.
- Regulations!
What do we care about regulations?
Official business. Orders from the Marquis.
Oh, Carmilio.
Well, my little one,
I leave you now to inspect the guards.
- But I coming back.
- Oh, Carmilio,
there is no hurry, is there?
Oh, no. There is no hurry.
Lieutenant.
The Lieutenant has an order
for the release of the six pirates.
- Take him to the lower dungeon.
- This way, Lieutenant.
Guard, seize the lieutenant
who just came in!
Bring him back!
Wake up. Wake up.
You've taken our freedom and our food.
You want to take our sleep now?
Silence.
You're being transferred into the interior,
at once.
Hold that officer!
- Pick up the keys.
- Señor Carmilio.
- Señor Carmilio!
- What do you want?
A man has come from the Marquis
with a purchase order
for the release of six slaves.
Why do you bother me with it? Go away!
But, señor,
it is stamped with the wrong seal.
Get back.
You all,
get back.
One more step and I'll...
Take that step, Captain.
Jensen.
Captain.
Captain, I...
Hardy, you come with me.
The rest of you, stay here.
Get in the cart.
You four men, go this way.
The rest, follow me.
Pedro, where are the slaves?
I'll tell you later, Pepita.
Now, please go away.
We'll go together, partner.
You there, wait.
- I told you to go away.
- Don't worry, I fix, I fix.
- Listen, fruit peddler, did...
- Lieutenant, this is my friend.
Don't you remember me? Pepita?
Pepita Maria Rosados?
The night of the fiesta, in the garden?
- Oh, Pepita.
- Si.
Yes. Yes, I remember.
We are searching for some escaped slaves.
I had to meet Pedro, but I was a little late,
so we know nothing about escaped slaves.
- My apologies.
- That's all right, Lieutenant.
Oh, Lieutenant,
would you care for some fruit?
No, thanks. I have no time.
- A melon perhaps?
- Some other time.
The melons are very good.
Pedro, how many times must I tell you?
No, no, no, no, no!
Go away, Pepita, you'll get me into trouble.
Oh, no,
Pepita will get you out of trouble, partner.
So, my guards have begun
to smoke the rats out of their holes.
- They're to be hanged, Captain Alvarado.
- Yes, Excellency.
One moment, Your Excellency.
I should like a sporting chance.
- I have no time to waste, señor.
- The stakes are good.
My neck, against an opportunity
to capture Peter Blood.
If you find the fruit peddler
who released the slaves,
you'll have no reason to set sail tomorrow
because he is Captain Blood.
Why should I believe you?
The only slaves who were freed
were men from his ship, the Avenger.
Very well, Fairfax, you win.
You may keep your neck.
Provided, of course,
you can tell me where Blood is now.
I'm afraid I can't tell you,
but I'm sure there's someone here who can.
You have only to say where Blood is.
Stop it.
You're wasting your time, Uncle.
If you want to know where Blood is,
release him, and I'll tell you.
- You?
- Yes.
Well! Please forgive the oversight.
His ship was anchored in the cove
on the other side of the island.
- Are you sure?
- He told me himself.
Find Captain Valdez.
The Santa Paula will sail at once.
- Yes, Excellency.
- It's already too late, Uncle.
By now, Blood's ship will be far out to sea.
One moment, Excellency,
Blood can hardly change the tides.
If his ship was in the cove, it is still there,
waiting to get over the shallows.
And it will be three hours
before the tide will permit him to sail.
Señor Fairfax,
apparently you are still of value.
We will reach the cove in two hours.
Get a guard. Have him taken to the prison.
lsabelita, whether you intended it or not,
you, too, have been of service.
Oh, thank you, milady,
but you shouldn't have told him.
I told him where Blood was
because I wanted them to catch him.
Because you thought the Captain
had already sailed.
You're in love with him, aren't you?
In love with a pirate?
- A cutthroat, a liar and a cheat?
- You're wrong, milady, you're wrong.
He may not have told you all about himself,
but what he told you was true,
every word of it.
Let's hurry, Billy Bragg.
Side guard!
Captain Valdez, weigh anchor.
- Get under way immediately.
- Your Excellency.
Hands, stand by to make sail!
Fo'c'sle at topsails!
Helm midships!
Look, the Santa Paula!
Wait a minute, me lads.
Let's give Jonesy a drink.
- Aye, he looks like he needs one.
- Warm your insides up.
They're warm enough.
Miguel, this should be enough
to pay for the use of your cart.
Anytime I can be of service,
Señor Capitan Blood.
Capitan?
Capitan Blood, I've got a surprise for you.
- Look.
- What is it?
Curtains. They're for our cabin.
Don't you like them?
- Yes, very much.
- I am so glad, Pedro.
Miguel, the use of your cart
was worth more than gold.
Much more. Here's your final payment.
You lied to me!
Pepita, here's the rest
of what I promised you.
With regrets, I dissolve our partnership.
Oh, Miguel, if you only knew how much
I worried about you.
Ship ahoy!
Captain Blood!
Another woman?
How did you ever find time
to save anybody?
Carter, bring them back with you.
Aye, aye, sir. Pull away.
Peter, I'm frightened.
Now don't be, lsabelita.
Lady Chance is still with us.
The Santa Paula's not in sight here.
A few minutes more,
and we head for open sea.
- How's the tide?
- Up about a foot.
Up about a foot.
We may scrape the barnacles off going over.
That's better than letting the Santa Paula
blow us to our graves.
We'll make a run for it.
You have to go ashore now.
Peter, I don't want to go ashore.
You must.
The Santa Paula!
What now, Peter?
- Shall we man the guns?
- It's no use, Tom.
The Santa Paula has 40 cannon to our 12.
There's only one chance left for us.
As soon as Scotty and Ward finish their job
and join us,
we'll go into action.
Blood's position is hopeless.
Captain Valdez, attack at once.
Larboard guns, prepare to fire.
- They're in firing position now.
- Aye.
Number one gun, fire!
Number three gun, fire!
Number five gun, fire!
Larboard broadside, fire!
Scotty, you're the best
gun spiker in Scotland.
In the whole world.
Just let them try to fire this one.
We'll give them another one for luck.
Now for the flag.
Lower the boats.
I will accept the surrender
of Captain Blood personally.
Yes, Your Excellency.
While the Marquis and his men are busy
accepting my surrender aboard the Avenger,
we'll swim out to his ship
and surprise what's left of his crew.
Aye.
Aboard the Avenger!
Captain Blood!
I've come for your surrender!
Grappling hooks.
Your Excellency, the ship's deserted.
Not a soul aboard.
They're boarding the Santa Paula.
What are you waiting for? Fire on them.
- But, Your Excellency...
- Quickly, you idiot.
Yes, Your Excellency.
Form gun crews! Prepare for action!
Throw these swine overboard.
No! No! No!
They've spiked this cannon,
Your Excellency.
And this one,
and this one.
- Here's one they missed.
- You have your orders. Fire!
Up anchor! Make sail!
Get under way!
Quartermaster, helm hard to larboard!
It's another kind of surgery
I'll be performing tonight, Mr. Fairfax.
Look to your own wounds, Dr. Peter Blood.
I will.
To the sharks, Fairfax,
and join the slaves you sent to them.
That's enough. They're done for.
Surrender now, Captain,
and save those of your men who remain.
You leave me no choice.
Keep her close to the wind!
Helm steady!
We'll ram them.
Captain Blood!
Tom! Tom!
They're trying to ram us.
The Avenger served us well, Tom.
I'll not sink her, just stop her.
Put a shot through her sails.
Number two gun, ready.
Fire!
Cram on more sails!
Hit her in the rigging. That'll stop her.
Number three gun, ready.
Aim at her rigging.
Fire!
Steady as she goes!
Help! Help!
Help.
She'll ram us.
Hit her amidships,
aim for the powder magazine.
Give her to broadside as she closes.
Larboard broadside, ready.
Fire!
We've lost our ship and taken yours,
and we intend to keep her.
We're freebooters and privateers
with no land of our own.
But we fight for something
more precious than land.
Freedom.
- And what of our freedom, Captain?
- Captain Alvarado,
I'll exchange your lives
for the lives of the slaves
-that are still in the dungeons.
- Gladly. You have my word.
And the señorita has promised,
with the influence of her family,
to help me bring a new government
to La Hacha.
The señorita?
I thought you told me
you were going to Spain.
No, señor, I did not tell you that.
- Only yesterday you said that...
- Yesterday.
Yesterday,
a Marquis' niece met a fruit peddler.
Today, that fruit peddler no longer exists.
And neither does that selfish girl.
But why do you want to stay here?
Because I've learned
that this is where I belong.
This is where I'm needed.
I like this new girl better
than the one I talked to yesterday.
I'm not sorry she's gone.
Neither am I.
And this fruit peddler, will you miss him?
Yes, Peter. I'll miss him.
- Billy Bragg.
- Ave. aye, sir?
Take the señorita ashore and stay with her.
But I'm sailing with you, sir.
Have you forgotten the oath?
No, and don't you forget it, either.
Do you think I'd trust her with anybody
but one of my own men?
- Aye, sir.
- I'll be checking on you, Billy,
because one of these days, Lady Chance
will bring me back to La Hacha.
Orders is orders, sir.
You can always depend on Billy Bragg, sir.
- This way, milady.
- To the boat, men.
She's the prettiest lady I've ever seen.
- Let's put to sea, Tom.
- Aye, aye, sir.
All hands, stand by to make sail!
Weigh anchor.
Weigh anchor!
Man the lookouts, lads!