[Whispering]
Happy birthday, son.
Here! They were your fathers.
Hey.
Hey, these aren't ordinary dice.
They're very special.
Watch.
Numbers 1, 2, or 3 means you
can sit there and keep sulking,
but numbers 4, 5, and 6 means you
have to forget about all your so-called friends
and make the most of the party. Agreed?
Agreed?
Good.
Here we go.
It's settled!
You don't have any say in the matter.
YOUNG ROLAND: 5.
You go first.
Get on the raft.
No.
I said get on the raft, Matthew.
Come on, Matthew boy, it's easy.
- No!
- Мom!
Help!
Mom!
Matthew! Hang on, boy!
Hang on!
Help!
Stay calm, I'm nearly there, sweetheart.
- Give me your hand!
- Help!
Come on, Matthew! Give me your hand!
Give me your hand, boy!
Got you.
Hold on!
Hold on, Matthew! Hold on
[screams]
No!
Matthew!
Hey, you guys, dinner's ready!
Hello?
- What are they doing out there?
- They're playing with their toy soldiers.
- Cute, huh?
- They're a bit old for soldiers, aren't they?
Well, I thought dragging Jonathan down the aisle
might knock it out of him.
It did for a while,
but recently...
the best man's had other ideas!
And I've been happily married to the two of them ever since.
JONATHAN WHEATS: Up here, we have the outliers,
Down here we have the bad guys, the French..
And when the sun goes down, the bad guys
are going to sneak up towards the big guys
and kick the living daylights out of them.
French divisional assault
on the Pratzen Heights,
Austerlitz, December the 2nd 1805.
December 2nd 1805?
I can't believe you still
remember this garbage.
Well, I remember when this garbage
used to take up most of our weekends.
The old times have changed. Now I've got
more important things on my mind.
Like what?
Like Mary.
No.
- Michelle?
- No.
Melissa?
Margaret?
You are turning into
one big walking hormone.
You know I can have her
off the property by midnight.
You want to bet?
No, no, I think you're taking on
a huge responsibility.
It's a specialized job that requires
a very special person, Mary.
My name is Margaret.
Margaret.
Sorry.
What is he doing here?
- Doesn't he ever give up?
- He's just spinning the ball around the park.
God. He was on first base by the
appetizer and second base, by the time we got to the potatoes.
If he gets to dessert, he'll
think he's on a home run.
We'll see about that.
- You haven't heard the worst of it.
- What?
She didn't drive.
Oh god.
Michael, I still say this is the dumbest game
you have ever come up with.
Beats bridge.
I've played this
naked with baby oil.
- Really?
OK, OK, it's my go.
Left hand green, left
hand green, left hand green!
- Left hand green!
- Yes!
- I'm going to go.
- Jonathan!
Thanks for a great evening!
Wish we didn't have to go.
- Well then, don't! Stay for another couple of drinks.
Oh, no, no, no. It's almost midnight and
I've got a big day tomorrow. Bye.
There you go.
- Are you sure you don't mind driving her home, Michael?
- Not at all.
Oh, I almost forgot.
If you two aren't doing anything on the 26th,
I have two tickets to "La boheme" that I can't use.
- "La boheme?"
- Oh, you've got to be joking.
- You shut up!
- I won them at an agency raffle.
- So how about it?
- Thank you! We'd love them!
Good.
Bye!
- What's "La boheme?"
- It's a musical.
Ah shit!
Hello?
Baby, it's only me.
Hi. Listen, can you hold on? I'll be right back.
I'm having a small problem.
OK, guys. Cool it!
One elephant.
Two elephants.
Three elephants...
Hello?
PA: Ladies and gentlemen, this
evening's performance of "La boheme" is about to begin.
Would you please take your seats?
When it rains, it pours.
Right, Mrs. Waterson?
Damn.
Damn, damn!
God damn you, Jonathan, when are we going
to get a new roof?
Hi, it's Jonathan.
I'm at the opera house. Where are you?
Oh, no!
No, no!
Surprise!
Jesus Beth, can't you take a joke...
ROLAND COPPING: Yes?
Oh, fine.
Thank you very much.
Good bye.
JUDGE: There's no doubt in my mind, Mrs. Wheats,
that you considered your life to be at risk.
And in extreme conditions, you acted
with resourcefulness and courage.
I only hope that the scars that you and your husband
now possess will heal as quickly as possible.
It is my opinion that the deceased was a tragic victim of his own misguided judgement.
And it will be my recommendation that no charges
be laid against Elizabeth Mary Wheats
by the Department of
Public Prosecutions.
And it is the finding of this inquest, that death occurred by accident.
You may stand down.
Jonathan!
Don't worry, I'll get it.
Yes?
- Mrs. Wheats?
- Yes.
Roland Copping, Carton Insurance.
Oh, yes, please.
Please come in.
My husbands' out back in the study.
BETH: Jonathan!
Sweetheart!
- I'm busy, Beth!
BETH: The
insurance man is here!
All right, I'm coming.
Therapy?
Well, I guess you could call it that.
Do you mind if I, uh...
- Hello. Jonathan Wheats.
- Roland Copping, Carton Insurance.
Oh, I'm sorry. It's the painting.
It reminds me of my childhood.
- Would you like to come into the lounge room and we can...
- Certainly. Absolutely.
Ah, little soldiers.
You know, I never really had
much time for them myself. But emm...
They don't really do much, do they?
They just sort of...
stand there.
Can I get you a drink? Beer, wine...
whiskey?
- Coke.
- I think we can handle that.
- Splendid.
Smells new.
Yes, it is.
Well, I'll try not to take up too much
of your time, Mr. Wheats.
It's about your claims.
One for property
damage, one for theft.
Damage: one sofa, video recorder,
CD player, lampshades...
Carpets, table, two broken cabinets.
Theft:
One set of
solid silver cutlery.
- The only thing stolen?
- Yes.
What a shame. They're really
fine-looking pieces, too.
- Victorian?
- They're Georgian. They're our family heirloom.
Thief with taste, eh?
Well, that's a rare thing these days.
So is this the room
where the guy, you know, got the...
Yes.
Mr. Copping, the guy was a really good
friend of ours, so I'd prefer not to discuss
the subject in front of my wife.
It's been six months and our lives are
just starting to get back to normal, so...
Understood.
- Please.
- Mum's the word. Mum's the word.
Thank you.
Well...
Everything seems to be in order.
The police have got their hands full, of course,
trying to trace the missing cutlery
and whoever was driving the getaway car. But...
To be quite honest, I don't reckon there's
much chance of you seeing either of them again,
which is...
a bit of a shame, really.
Would you like to see anything else?
No, no, no. I've taken up too much
of your time already, Mr. Wheats.
I'll just get straight home
and start processing the claim.
- Which should take how long, Mr. Copping?
- Oh, if all goes well, maybe two, three weeks.
So we'll be seeing you again?
Most definitely.
- Well, would you like my card, just in case?
- No, that's OK. I've got that.
Of course, if you've got any other questions,
you can always call me at home on this number.
- Fine. No problem.
- Excellent. Well, goodnight.
Oh, thanks for the Coke.
Hi.
What are you doing?
Remembering.
Hi!
Sorry I'm late.
Beth?
Come into the dining room.
What?
Come over here and sit down.
What are you doing?
- Sit.
- What's going on?
Fun.
Remember when we used to have fun?
- Oh really?
- And I have an even bigger surprise.
Why do you want to do this?
Because Michael would have.
It's been seven months, Jonathan,
and it's time we let it go.
So let's do it with a bang. Let's do something
he'd be proud of.
For one night in our lives,
let's think with out dicks.
Shit!
Good evening, Jonathan.
Hello, Beth. Sorry about the hour.
- I hope I'm not interrupting anything.
- No, not at all.
I actually need to run a few details
pass Beth, if that's all right.
At 10 o'clock at night?
No Mr. Copping, to be perfectly
honest, that's not all right.
Don't you think business hours would be
a better time to discuss details?
I am interrupting something, aren't I?
Um, well, look, if you could just
spare me a couple of minutes,
I could get rid of these questions and I'll
probably be out of your hair for good.
I don't think I have anything to say that
I haven't said 100 times already.
If you have any questions,
I suggest you read the police report.
- I think I'll come back tomorrow.
- That's a good idea.
Oh, for God's sake!
No. Let's just get this over with.
Thank you.
Shouldn't be just a couple of minutes.
Now about this accomplice.
When approximately did you hear the
getaway car driving off?
I mean, what time?
I don't remember exactly.
It was the neighbor's who reported that.
I was too busy trying to get to the opera.
So we'll assume whoever this... mystery
accomplice was saw you go inside,
waited around in the hope that
Michael would get wise and come out,
heard the first scream and then
just took off?
No I recall it took off just
after I entered the front door.
- I can't tell you the exact time.
- You do remember now?
- No, I don't remember.
- So do you recall?
I...
- I don't know why you're...
- Well, what do I take as fact, Beth,
recall or remember?
- Did you identify a driver?
- No! Mr. Copping, please!
Oh, I'm sorry.
It's an old habit I picked up from my father.
He was a war hero, you know.
This was grand-dad's.
It's very old.
You see how they shine?
It's always said that in the right hands
they would become transparent,
the numbers would just melt together.
They can do wonderful things.
Mr. Copping...
What are you talking about?
My dice.
Well, they're very nice dice, but...
I don't see what relevance they have
to your being here.
What relevance.
1 to 3 says we continue our discussion now...
...4 to 6 says I return tomorrow.
Very well, Mr. Wheats, I shall return tomorrow.
- I'll make sure I'm in.
- Now just hold on a minute!
Goodness me, look at the time!
Doesn't it fly when you're having fun?
Mr. Copping, if you have any questions,
I'd suggest you ask them now.
Right.
What, have either of
you seen this fork before?
Yes, it's ours.
I mean, it looks like ours.
- Where did you get this?
- These things turn up.
Jonathan?
Well, I'll leave it with you, shall I?
Till morning, when I return for the search.
- What?
- Well, new evidence requires a
new search, Beth - boring, I know.
But it is standard
company policy, I can assure you.
Don't worry, I'll see myself out.
Good night!
Well, at least we know what
happened to Rosemary's baby.
What the hell is going on around here?
The guy was here to assess the damage
to the table,not to play Yahtzee on it.
Jesus Christ!
If you think I'm going to let that
nutcase tear apart my house, then...
Sorry, Beth, but that eye was
going to bother me all...
...night.
Good night, again.
Goddamn it!
Don't you dare walk out on this!
Jonathan, you get your ass back in here!
One elephant!
Two elephants!
Three goddamn elephants!
Do you mind? I'm creating.
You know, we spent all morning
at school today making these cities
out of egg cartons.
I didn't know what to say then. So I said,
well, maybe one or two trees grow
and then Edward decided to tell them
the truth about Christmas.
And that they couldn't grow any trees
because of the yellow goop, anyway.
And I said, well, what happens at Christmas time?
This is why I was asking him
what the matter was.
And I saw in the corner little Jack looking...
Jonathan?
Hi, there.
I'm sorry.
It's just that man gives me the creeps.
Come here.
I'll get it.
Waky-waky, Beth! Rise and shine.
Jonathan, top of the morning to you.
You're early.
You're late.
Oh Christ!
Just let me have a shower and you
can unleash the sniffer dogs.
That won't be necessary. I have decided
to approve your claim immediately.
That's great.
How come?
Simple, really.
Just retracing the steps.
Michael Allen, he breaks into his
best friend's house, and having
just removed the first load of goods,
he finds himself trapped inside by the...
unexpected arrival of the now missing
cutlery's owner, Mrs. Beth Wheats.
Realizing that the game's up,
he decides on a bit of fun.
So wielding the old
Sunday roast carver,
he takes the joke a little
bit too far, as usual.
His reward - oh dear!
A six inch crossbow bolt
right through the heart.
And the mystery accomplice does not
speed off into the night with the goods.
What are you talking about?
Well, the mystery accomplice stands
patiently outside the opera house,
awaiting the arrival of his
faithful wife.
- What?
- What are you insinuating?
I'm not insinuating anything, Johnny
old boy. I'm stating a fact.
Your husband, Mrs. Wheats,
is the mystery accomplice.
Get out!
Let's not get overexcited here,
Johnny boy.
- Let's discuss this like gentlemen.
- Get out.
Don't make things any worse for yourself.
I dropped my...
Out!
You forgot this.
Well, goody.
I'll swap you.
The fork I gave you last night
was a very good copy.
This one, though,
is for real.
You shouldn't have checked
your hiding spot, Jonathan.
What?
Jonathan?
What the hell is going on?
Talk to me!
Close the door.
Jonathan?
Oh, no!
It was so simple.
You spend half your life
drowning in interest rates,
dishing out stupid premiums and
up-to-you hilton mortgages.
Then one day you come home
after going out to dinner.
Your house has been stripped, and
whamo, you can buy the new car.
It's simple.
Everybody does it.
Nothing could go wrong.
Except you coming home.
If it was all so goddamn simple,
why didn't you just tell me?
How many...
Look, I didn't have a choice.
He started putting words
in my mouth - insurance claim,
the accomplice, the getaway car.
I mean, what... what getaway car?
I didn't know what to say so
I didn't say anything at all.
I understand why you and Michael did it.
I understand why you played along.
But I don't understand
why you didn't tell me.
Well, what difference does it make now?
Whether it's fraud or perjury
or manslaughter,
I'm going to go to jail.
Call him.
Let's hear what he has to say.
- Ronald Copping.
- Hello, it's Jonathan Wheats.
- Yes, Jonathan.
- I think we have to talk.
Would you liketo come to my house?
- Oh, I'd love to. Shall we say 10:00 AM?
- That'll be fine.
- Excellent. Well, I'll see you then.
OK, Cesar, 1 to 3 says they'll play.
2, 3, 4, 5.
I think I'll have another hotel on Mayfair,
and just a little bit of cash
for the decorating.
Come on, Beth. Your go.
Your go, Beth.
5.
1, 2, 3, 4...
Oh, dear!
Do not pass go. Do not collect 200 pounds.
Go directly to jail.
What do you want?
[I've Got You Under My Skin" starts playing]
You're not going to count it?
Oh, I don't think there's any need.
If you're short, I'll be the first to let you know.
Look, I'm sorry about all these mucky dealings,
you know, but in the great card game of life...
Get out!
It has been a pleasure.
Hope to see you again soon.
Don't hold your breath.
3 to 5 says I leave them alone.
1, 2!
Welcome back, Beth!
Thanks, gang.
It's good to be back.
You have me walking my cat.
I'm looking very tall there, aren't I?
That's great.
Jenny, is that me on a beach?
- Did we collect shells on that beach?
- Yes.
That's a beautiful one.
And Ethan, where did you
have me go on my holiday?
Is that a ski resort?
No?
It's a car accident.
Well, you are far off.
- Hey, you all right?
- Jonathan?
I know.
I know. Just hang on a minute.
I'm coming to get you.
I want the set.
The whole set.
And this.
All right, that's enough! First time was fair. You've got your money.
This is straight blackmail. I'm not going to stand for it!
I'm going to go to the police.
Oh, really?
Well, right here, there's the telephone.
Go on, call the police.
Can I have my cutlery now, please?
No.
Give him the silverware, Jonathan.
No!
- Give him the silverware!
- Like hell I will!
All right. Now let's get one thing quite clear.
You're not going to get anything else out of me!
Well, it has been a pleasure
doing business with you both...
...again.
Oh, probably not a good time, Beth, but I'd like
to lend you these to help out with your paintings.
Get out.
- He's not going to stop.
- Oh, yes he is.
- He's going to take everything we own.
- He wouldn't dare!
Excuse me, can I help you?
Oh, I am sorry. I knocked earlier
and nobody answered.
- Well, we were probably in the shower.
Can I help you?
- I'm from Copping Insurance.
Roland Copping sent me down to
do the valuation you requested?
Get away.
Get away from my car!
The car is next, fine!
I don't mine handing over the lease.
While he's at it, he might as well
pick up the mortgage on the house!
Why?
Why is he doing this to us?
No!
This has got to stop.
I can't take this anymore.
ROLAND COPPING: You know, the most honest
and unique period of life is childhood.
I mean, the only way that child is going
to learn that jumping off the monkey bar
is going to hurt him
is by taking the chance and jumping
off the monkey bar.
Which I suppose makes children
the biggest gamblers of all.
Still, doesn't last forever.
Kids grow up,
don't they?
What do you want, Roland?
Whatever it is, just ask.
But please, leave my wife out of it.
I'll tell you what we're going to do.
We're going to roll with the dice.
Now, if it lands on a 1, 2, or 3,
you get to walk out of here scot-free.
And by that, I promise,
cross my heart, hope to die,
you'll never, ever hear from me again.
But...
If it lands on a 4, 5, or 6...
You get to be my slave for one hour.
And by that, I mean you have to do
exactly as I tell you for 60 minutes.
Fair?
Here.
You roll.
You're out of your mind.
- Hello?
- Yes, is Mr. Wall there, please??
- No.
- Is Mrs. Wall there?
- Are there any Walls there?
Hey, listen, you've
got a major wrong number.
This is a telephone box
in the middle of nowhere.
So there aren't any walls there?
I'm afraid not.
Well, you'd better get out quick
because the roof's falling down.
Na, na, na, na!
[inaudible] I fooled you!
Oh my god!
My god!
[non-english speech]
Oh, shit!
Jonathan?
Hello?
Ah, Betty old girl. What's cooking good looking?
What do you want?
Oh, lots of money would be nice.
- Sorry, we're out.
- Antique cutlery?
- No.
- Then I suppose dinner is out of the question.
- Listen, you asshole!
- May I speak to Jonathan, please?
No.
- You can speak to me. What is it you want?
- A car, Beth. I'm sick of mine.
Which car, Roland?
Both of them.
OK.
Here's what we're going to do.
I'm going to pretend I never got this call.
I'm going to hang up the phone.
I'm going to go back to work.
And I am going to attempt
to lead a normal life.
I'm calling your
bluff, Mr. Copping.
Somebody has to draw the line
around here somewhere.
And I guess it's going to have to be me.
Because I'm damned if I'm going to sit back
and let you destroy my marriage!
Am I to understand that this round
is between you and I, Beth?
It's a beautiful day.
SPEAKER [ON TAPE]:
I enjoy my work.
It's very challenging.
I enjoy my work. It's very challenging.
SPEAKER [ON TAPE]:
I won't get angry today.
Let's not jump to any conclusions.
Mrs. Wheats.
Excuse me.
Detective.
How are you today?
Not bad. What can I do for you?
Is Mr. Wheats inside?
No, No, he's not.
Oh, well, he said he wanted us to meet him here.
- Oh, really? Why?
- Your crossbow.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to startle you like this.
Oh, it's all right.
Mrs. Wheats...
I don't quite understand what's going on.
You see, your husband phoned us this morning
and asked us to bring this back here.
Well, I wish he called me.
It's all right.
Shall we move in there?
Thank you.
So how is your investigation going?
Nothing new, I'm frankly.
No leads at all, as a matter of fact.
You see, stolen goods of this nature
are always the most difficult kind.
And well, your things being solid silver and all,
well, I wouldn't take any bets on them
turning up in a pawn shop.
As sad as this must be to hear, I'm afraid
we're just going to have to say good bye
to your silverware.
Which is a great shame, I know.
It was a beautiful set.
- Yes.
- From what your husband tells me,
impossible to replace.
No. I mean, yes.
I'm not sure...
Oh my god.
I am so sorry.
Quick, into the kitchen.
I am so sorry!
Don't worry about it, Mrs. Wheats.
It's just that whenever I think of the silverware,
I throw up.
I'll get some disinfectant.
Hi, Wendy, it's Beth Wheats.
Is Jonathan there?
What do you mean he took the afternoon off?
Oh, shit!
Oops.
Nice goose!
Have we had a visitor, Cesar?
Jonathan, you bloody little jenius!
You did it! You did it!
Are you with us, Jonathan?
- Jonathan?
- "Deck the hall with bells of holly,
tra-la-la-la-la, la-la, la-la."
Hello, Beth. You put your tree
out early this year?
At least you don't have to
eat with your fingers anymore.
What is the matter with you?
Are you completely insane?
What more do you want from us?
Oh, the holiday in Tahiti. The house in the country.
But for the moment, I'd be content with the BMW.
Where's Jonathan?
ROLAND COPPING:
Afternoon, nurse!
Hello?
Excuse me?
Metthew!
Beth, hi, honey!
I'm home! Did you have a good day?
Oh yes, yes I did! Two police turned up
with their crossbow,
and your silverware was hung
out to dry on a Christmas tree!
Jesus, what happened to you?
- And why weren't you at the office?
Where the hell have you been?
- I've been on a little field trip.
And if I do say so myself, I think I've struck gold.
Everyone's got an Achilles heel.
- And Roland Copping's got a whopper.
- Did you hear me?
Hello?
He sent the police over this afternoon!
He set us up. I almost got arrested!
And then I threw up on them.
Good girl!
I should have thought about this earlier.
The first day he came in here, he gave us
his card, which said please call home.
He doesn't have an office. He only works
from home. It was like an invitation, and it's
there. It's all there.
Where's the mobile phone?
Listen to you. You sound like a madman.
What the hell is going on?
I don't have time to explain.
I'll tell you everything when I'm set up.
Jonathan, tell me now!
I found a hole, Beth. A hole.
I went there today, to his house.
I followed him.
There might be a way out. There's a chance
that we can turn the tables, but we have to play him
at his own game.
That's it, isn't it?
Whether it's playing
with toy soldiers
or ripping off insurance companies,
it's all just a game?
Yes.
But it's his game, and at
the moment, we're losing.
Get out of my way.
- One elephant, two elephants, three elephants...
- Stop it!
- four...
I've had enough!
I don't want to play anymore.
So.
What are the options?
We can go to the police and maybe
spend, what, the next 10 years in jail,
or we can give him everything and
let him suck us completely dry,
or we can fight.
We play or we pay.
And I can win. Just 48 hours, that's all I need.
Just two days and this whole thing will be over.
Two days, huh?
Two days to win this one and it will all be over?
Oh, really?
And then what? What happens next?
Another insurance claim?
Or is that too small now?
How about insider trading?
Does that sound attractive?
Where does it stop, Jonathan?
Please.
I can't do this on my own.
Hello, Roland.
Jonathan?
I've always had a soft spot
for German craftsmanship.
Fear not. She'll have a good, safe home.
Oh, I took out a cover note this morning,
just in case you decided to cancel the insurance.
Last chance, Jonathan.
- Roland Copping.
- We have to talk.
- Is that you, Beth?
- Yes.
- Fine. Well, when would you like to get together?
- How about tonight?
- Tonight?
- Is that a problem?
- No.
- It's not a problem.
- It's not a problem at all.
See you next year, Mr. Copping.
I really am very pleased
you came to my party, Beth.
Is anybody else coming?
No.
I know you didn't know it was my birthday,
so I don't expect a present.
But I would like to give you one.
If you really want to give us a present,
stop what you're doing.
My life is falling apart.
My husband thinks it's all
some kind of weird game.
So here's the deal.
You can have the house.
You can have the car. You can have everything.
I don't want it anymore.
And in return...
You let us go.
I wish it were that simple.
But the choice isn't mine.
You know, choice is a wonderful thing,
but too much of it can lead to hesitation.
And he who hesitates
loses his parking space.
So you have to find that middle ground.
And I've found 6.
Oh, for God's sake!
Cut it out!
I can't.
Well, I can.
You can't hurt me anymore, Roland.
You can't take anything
more away from me.
Because I have... nothing...
left to give you.
I don't care what number your
goddamn dice rolls because I
don't give a shit anymore!
Happy birthday, Roland.
And in a really weird way...
Thank you.
Where are you going?
4 to 6 and I call Jonathan.
- Beth, have you got them?
- Yes.
- I have them.
- Good girl!
- Where are you?
- I'm in a phone booth.
OK, now go, get out of there,
as quick as you can.
Right.
Hey.
Love you.
Wait.
Give me back my dice.
[MUMBLED] Jonathan!
What's the matter? Aren't you at your sisters?
No, she's at her favorite uncle's.
Hello, John-John.
Roland, where's Beth?
Oh, I'm sure she'd love to speak to you,
but she's a little bit tied up at the moment.
As to her whereabouts, I think
you'll find her at my house.
And I'd get over here pretty quickly, if I were you,
before she gets added to one of my collections.
She's got nothing to do with it, Roland!
Leave her out of it!
Oh, but she's been stealing, Jonathan.
And all little girls who steal
deserve a good spanking.
I gather you're up to something.
Where, may I ask, are you?
Over here.
Good evening, Jonathan.
Beth!
Here, pass you a piece of watermelon.
Another step closer and she
never rides a bike again.
Very, very clever, Johnny.
But you've really overstepped
your mark this time.
You wouldn't dare.
Oh, wouldn't I?
No doubt about it, you're very good.
Probably the best yet.
But you've got to think ahead.
You've got to learn three-dimensional thinking.
3, 3, 3.
3?
That's right, your home number.
If I dial the last three,
the phone will ring, correct?
Yes.
Let's go for a walk.
I want to show you something.
No tricks.
You've got the gun.
Just come and take a look at something.
Come on.
Indulge me.
OK.
But remember, the future halves
of your wife are at stake.
- What are you up to?
- A surprise. You like surprises, don't you?
Very much.
You had me a little worried.
You worked a little quicker than I had anticipated.
I might have had you over a barrel.
You shouldn't have relied on your wife. Women are
inconsistent. That's why I never married.
Do this, do that. I just avoided the problem. Surely you understand
that, Jonathan.
The perfect bachelor,
with a life devoted to...
Matthew?
Oh my god, Matthew! What have they done to you?
No worries, Matthew.
All I have to do is to press the redial button, the phone
will ring, set off the answering machine, and - smash! -
Matthew has to swim. Again.
I'm serious, Roland.
You... bastard!
Flattery will get you nowhere.
Let's go upstairs.
Come on.
How could you?
He's a quadriplegic.
He can't even speak.
Oh really?
I'd thought he had a lot to say.
He told me all about your father, the war hero,
the man who died in action...
Or was it just the man who didn't
want to come home?
He told me all about his
present state of health.
Achieved whilst trying to humor his brother
with the roll of a silly, little dice.
And the dice, given as an afterthought to a
spoiled, unpopular, little brat
because nobody turned up to his party.
So what happens now?
I'll tell you what we're going to do.
We're going to roll for it.
Numbers 1, 3, and 5
Beth and I walk away from here.
2, 4, and 6?..
50/50 odds. That's quite a gamble, Jonathan.
I'm prepared to take it.
You roll.
Bad luck, Roland.
You lose.
Like hell I did.
So long, Beth. It's been a pleasure having you.
Beth!
Surprise.
You vicious son of a bitch.
This is for me.
And this is
And this is for my brother!
Matthew!
Help!
Beth?
What are you doing?
I'm calling the police.
- No!
- I'm calling the police!
It's over.
Help!