LET ME SPEAK
TO SHAWN, PLEASE.
YES, I KNOW
IT'S NEW YEAR'S EVE.
IT'S MY
NEW YEAR'S EVE, TOO,
AND I WOULDN'T BE CALLING HIM
IF IT WASN'T IMPORTANT.
LISTEN, YOU TELL SHAWN
THAT MONK RILEY--
HIS EDITOR, HIS COMMANDING
OFFICER, HIS BOSS--
SAYS IT'S A MATTER
OF LIFE AND DEATH--HIS!
AND IF I DON'T REACH HIM,
GOOD-BYE.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
CLEVE, GET THE PHONE
FOR ME, WILL YOU?
[RING]
HELLO.
NO. IT'S
HER BROTHER.
IT'S YOUR BOSS!
SHAWN? WHY WOULD HE
BE CALLING ME
ON NEW YEAR'S EVE?
NO, IT'S NOT SHAWN!
IT'S THE H.N.I.C.--
THE HEAD NIGGER
IN CHARGE!
MR. RILEY?
MR. RILEY.
HAPPY NEW YEAR, BOSS.
IF IT'S SHAWN YOU'RE
LOOKING FOR, I DON'T--
I DON'T WANT SHAWN.
AT THIS POINT,
I WANT YOU.
OH, BOSS, I DIDN'T
KNOW YOU CARED.
THIS IS SERIOUS, FRIDAY.
I CAN'T REACH
ANYONE ELSE,
SO I WANT YOU TO GRAB
A PENCIL AND PAPER
AND LISTEN
VERY CAREFULLY.
ALL RIGHT, HOLD UP.
OK, ALL SET, BOSS.
FRIDAY, I WANT YOU
TO TAKE
YOUR LITTLE CAMERA
AND SHOOT YOUR
LITTLE PICTURES
AND GET
THE HELL OUT,
AND DON'T GET INVOLVED,
UNDERSTAND?
NOW, YOU KNOW I WOULDN'T
DO ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
GET INVOLVED WITH WHO?
BLAKE TARR?
THE BLAKE TARR--
THE BILLIONAIRE?
THE BROTHER THEY CALL
THE BLACK HOWARD HUGHES?
WELL, WHY WOULD HE
BE COMING BACK HERE
AFTER ALL THESE YEARS?
DON'T WONDER, FRIDAY.
JUST TAKE YOUR CUTE
LITTLE BEHIND OUT THERE
AND GET THOSE PICTURES.
AND GOD DAMN IT,
DON'T GET INVOLVED.
[CLICK]
[MUSIC PLAYING
AND PEOPLE TALKING]
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
[RING]
Friday: CLEVE,
CATCH THAT, WILL YOU?
[RING]
WHAT DO YOU HAVE
IN THAT CLOSET--A CADILLAC?
I'LL GET IT.
[RING]
HELLO.
YEAH, IT'S CLEVE.
IT'S CLORIS!
NOT NOW.
SHE SOUNDS FUNNY.
HAPPY NEW YEAR,
CLORIS.
HEY, I CAN'T MAKE IT
TO THE PARTY.
BUT I CAN'T!
PLEASE? I'VE GOT
TO TALK WITH YOU.
THERE'S NOBODY ELSE
WHO CAN HELP.
IT'S A MATTER OF--
LOOK, I'D LIKE TO,
BUT I JUST CAN'T.
SOMETHING'S COME UP,
AND I CAN'T
GET OUT OF IT.
IT'S IMPORTANT TO ME.
FRIDAY, PLEASE.
LOOK, LET ME CALL YOU
AS SOON AS I GET BACK, OK?
HAPPY NEW YEAR, CLORIS.
P.A.: ATTENTION, PLEASE.
ATTENTION, PLEASE.
FLIGHT 502 NOW LOADING
AT GATE 5.
ATTENTION, PLEASE.
FLIGHT 106 IS
NOW DEPARTING...
P.A.:
ATTENTION, PLEASE.
FLIGHT 106 NOW DEPARTING
AT GATE 7.
IMMEDIATE DEPARTURE.
LEROY! LEROY, I GOT
ENOUGH STUFF FOR US
TO LAST US FOR DAYS!
OH, YOU'RE NOT LEROY.
NO, I AIN'T
LEROY.
WELL, HE MUST BE
WORKING
AT THE OTHER GATE.
I'LL CHECK--
HOLD TIGHT, BABY.
NO VISITORS ALLOWED
IN THERE.
OH, MY OLD MAN'S
WORKING TONIGHT.
UH-HUH.
IT'S NEW YEAR'S EVE.
COME ON.
I JUST WANT TO FIND OUT
WHAT TIME HE'S GETTING OFF.
OH, YEAH, OK.
WHY DON'T YOU KEEP THIS--
HAVE A LITTLE TASTE?
COME ON, COME ON.
TRY IT. COME ON!
ALL RIGHT? AND I'LL GO
AND FIND OUT
WHAT TIME HE'S GETTING OFF,
AND WE'LL COME BACK,
AND WE'LL ALL PARTY.
PARTY!
PARTY, YEAH!
HEY, MISS!
NEXT TIME,
ASK FOR SOMEBODY
OTHER THAN LEROY.
HE DON'T WORK HERE.
HA HA!
HAPPY NEW YEAR!
TURKEY.
OH, MY GOD!
[SIRENS]
[GROANING]
[GUNSHOT]
HEY, YOU!
[TIRES SQUEALING]
[SIRENS]
[TRUCK HORN HONKS]
[TIRES SQUEALING]
[DOOR OPENS]
CHET.
THANK GOD. YOU'RE NOT
DOING THAT ANYMORE--
NOT FOR BLACK WIDOW,
NOT FOR BLACK NOTHING!
CHET. CHET.
CHET! CHET!
Friday: CLORIS, HEY,
I'M FINISHED. I'M BACK.
I'M AT THE OFFICE.
I'LL BE OVER
AS SOON AS I CAN.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO.
I KNOW IT'S ALL RIGHT,
BUT I THOUGHT YOU SAID--
LOOK, IT'S OVER.
DON'T COME HERE.
WHAT'S ALL OVER?
I THOUGHT YOU WANT--
FRIDAY,
DON'T COME HERE.
OK. WELL, OK!
LOOK, I'LL SEE YOU TOMORROW
AT THE FASHION SHOW.
BYE.
[CLICK]
MR. RILEY, I'VE GOT
A COUPLE MORE.
NOW, LOOK AT THESE.
GOOD. GOOD.
SOME OF THESE
ARE GREAT!
NOW, IF WE CAN
JUST FIND ONE
THAT SHOWS FOR SURE
THAT'S BLAKE TARR
AND NOBODY ELSE.
THIS ONE.
HEY, MONK!
I GOT THIS FRANTIC MESSAGE
THAT YOU WERE LOOKING
ALL OVER TOWN FOR ME.
WELL, THE LATE
MR. SHAWN NORTH,
DEMON PHOTOGRAPHER.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
WORKING ON C.P. TIME?
AH, COME ON, MONK,
THIS WAS NEW YEAR'S EVE.
WAS IT SOMETHING
IMPORTANT?
WOULD YOU SAY THE WORLD'S
RICHEST BLACK MAN
COMING HOME IMPORTANT?
BLAKE TARR?
OR WOULD YOU SAY
3 HIT MEN
WAITING TO KILL HIM
IMPORTANT?
AND A SHOOT
WITH TARR WOUNDED
AND MAYBE DEAD--
IS ANY OF THAT
IMPORTANT?
YOU TELL ME.
WELL, I'LL TELL YOU.
IT WAS
DAMNED IMPORTANT--
THE BIGGEST STORY
OF THE YEAR--
AND I'M FORCED
TO SEND
MISS TOTAL
INVOLVEMENT HERE,
WHO ALMOST GOT
HERSELF KILLED
BY AN ASSASSIN
GETTING
THESE PHOTOS!
OH, BOSS, I--
FRIDAY, I TOLD YOU.
HEY. I KNOW THIS GUY.
WHO'S HE?
I DON'T KNOW,
BUT I'VE MET HIM SOMEWHERE.
YOU JUST DON'T FORGET
THE FINE ONES.
I'M GOING TO PARK HERE
FOR A MOMENT
WHILE I RUN
MY GAME. HA HA!
IT'S YOUR SHOW,
FANCY MAN.
HA HA HA!
HEY, YOUNG BLOOD,
WHERE IS YOUR SISTER?
SHE'LL BE RIGHT DOWN
IN A MINUTE.
WHATCHA GOT THIS TIME?
CHANEL NO. 5.
HELL, MAN, WHY CAN'T YOU
GET SOMETHING
FROM TIFFANY'S
OR GUCCI?
GUCCI? NIGGER!
MAN, I DON'T MESS
WITH THEM ITALIANS.
Cleve: I'LL TAKE IT
UP TO HER.
ALL RIGHT.
FANCY, SHE JUST LOVES
YOUR PRESENTS!
GUCCI?
OH, IS MY TAXI
HERE YET?
YEAH. HE'S WAITING
DOWNSTAIRS.
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
OK, YOU GOT
YOUR HOUSE KEY?
YEAH, I GOT IT.
Friday: STAY OUT
OF TROUBLE!
AT YOUR SERVICE,
SWEET THING.
WELL, IF IT ISN'T
KING FARUK
AND HIS BEVY
OF BEAUTIES.
HAVE YOU SEEN
MY TAXI, FANCE?
YOU DON'T NEED NO TAXI.
WHERE TO?
WELL, RENA'S, NOW
THAT YOU MENTION IT.
HEY, WELL,
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
YOU'RE GOING TO CHECK OUT
SOME FINE LEATHERS AND STUFF?
FANCE, I HATE
TO TELL YOU THIS,
BUT SOME OF DO WORK
ONCE IN A WHILE.
WHY?
WELL, WELFARE IS
JUST NOT MY STYLE.
WELL, I GOT YOUR STYLE,
SWEET THING.
SEE, YOU ARE WASTING
YOUR PRETTY FACE
AND ALL OF YOUR...
REAL TALENTS.
FANCY, THERE IS NOTHING
YOU HAVE THAT I WANT,
AND I DON'T HUSTLE
FOR NOBODY.
HUSTLE?
THEM WHITE BOYS
WILL BE TEARING DOWN THE DOORS
TO GET NEXT TO YOU.
OH...
AND WE COULD HAVE
OUR THING, TOO.
OH, NIGGER, PLEASE.
YOU HAVE LOST YOUR MIND.
MY BITCH--
LADIES DON'T THINK
THAT THEIR NIGGER
HAS LOST HIS MIND.
WITH THEM BAD RAGS,
TOUGH PAD--
I MEAN, SOME HEAVY BLOW
AND A BOSS RIDE.
SHIT! AND EACH
AND EVERY ONE HAS GOT
HER OWN PERSONAL HEALTH
AND WELFARE PLAN.
YOU HAVE LOST YOUR MIND,
YOU KNOW THAT?
BUT YOU GOT TO ADMIT,
MY SHIT IS HEAVY.
HA HA!
[JAZZ PLAYING]
CHARLEY, LISTEN TO ME.
PLEASE.
YOU HAVE GOT TO GET HIM
TO HELP ME...
BEFORE THE POLICE COME.
CHARLEY,
DON'T HANG UP.
CHARLEY, PLEASE.
CHARLEY!
CLORIS.
GIRL, WHEN I TELL YOU
WHAT HAPPENED,
YOU WILL NOT BELIEVE.
WHAT'S WRONG?
OH, FRIDAY,
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
I KNEW I WAS
DOING WRONG,
BUT I JUST KEPT GETTING IN
DEEPER AND DEEPER.
WELL, LAST NIGHT, HE--
OH, IT'S A "HE."
COME ON,
WHAT'S HIS NAME?
LISTEN, WILL YOU
STOP IT, PLEASE?
CLORIS, WHAT IS
WRONG WITH YOU?
I TOLD YOU LAST NIGHT
IT WAS ALL OVER,
SO LET'S JUST FORGET
ABOUT IT, OK?
SO THERE YOU ARE!
COME ON, CLORIS.
LET'S GET YOU OUT OF THIS
AND INTO YOUR FIRST OUTFIT.
WHAT DO YOU THINK,
THE ONLY THING
WE HAVE TO DO
IS DRESS YOUR BOD?
[PLAYING JAZZ]
WELL,
LOOK WHO'S HERE.
OH, SHAWN, I'M SORRY.
I HAD TO GO BACKSTAGE
TO SEE A FRIEND.
IF YOU CARED ANYTHING
ABOUT YOUR JOB WITH ME
INSTEAD OF DATING EVERY
HANDWRITER IN TOWN,
DRINKING,
PLAYING AROUND,
AND STAYING OUT
ALL NIGHT--
NOW, LOOK HERE,
SHAWN NORTH,
YOU KNEW WHERE
I WAS LAST NIGHT,
AND FURTHERMORE--
[CLICK]
AH, AH, AH, AH.
NONVIOLENCE.
BESIDES, IT'S TOO NICE A DAY,
TOO NICE A PLACE.
BESIDES, ANY CLOSER,
AND HIS MOTHER WOULD
DISOWN HIM.
SORRY ABOUT THAT.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE
AT THIS FASHION SHOW?
WHAT ALL
PRIVATE EYES DO--
WATCH AN UNFAITHFUL WIFE
CHEAT ON HER
UNFAITHFUL HUSBAND.
ALL RIGHT. WELL,
FOR A MOMENT THERE,
I THOUGHT
YOU SWITCHED ON ME.
NO WAY.
I'M ON MY J-O-B.
WELL, IT'S NICE WORK
IF IT PAYS WELL.
IT PAYS WELL.
ALL RIGHT.
SEE YOU LATER.
HOW ABOUT YOU AND ME
GETTING ON OUR J-O-B?
I'LL TAKE A 48 MAG
ON THAT,
AND WE'LL SHOOT
BLACK AND WHITE
IN THE NIKE.
[PLAYING FANFARE]
Announcer:
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
MAY WE PRESENT THE
MAGNIFICENT MADAME RENA.
HELLO, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
HA HA! WELL,
HELLO, GEORGE.
YOU'RE LOOKING
ABSOLUTELY FANTASTIC.
HOW DO YOU MANAGE IT?
OH, HELLO, CLEO.
YOU'RE HERE TO STEAL
MY ORIGINALS AGAIN,
AREN'T YOU, DARLING?
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
WELCOME, WELCOME.
TODAY I HAVE
FOR YOUR PERUSAL--
AND I'M QUITE SURE
YOUR APPROVAL--
ONE OF MY MOST FANTASTIC
ORIGINAL COLLECTIONS,
AND I CHOOSE TO CALL IT
"SAPPHIRES AND SISTERS."
WE'RE ALL FAMILIAR
WITH THE JOY OF SEX,
PARTICULARLY SINCE THAT
DOCTOR HAS DETERMINED
THAT SEX IS ON THE MALE'S MIND
EVERY OTHER MINUTE
AND ON THE FEMALE MIND
EVERY OTHER SECOND.
WELL, I'VE PUT IT
ALL TOGETHER IN ONE GROUP,
WHICH I CALL
THE 4 SEASONS OF S-E-X.
NOT EXACTLY SUBTLE,
IS SHE?
SHE NEVER WAS, EVEN WHEN
I WAS MODELING FOR HER.
[APPLAUSE]
Woman: CLORIS!
WHERE'S CLORIS BOSTON?
HAS ANYBODY SEEN CLORIS?
SHE SHOULD BE HERE.
CLORIS!
OH, BUT THAT'S ONLY
OUR BEGINNING.
THE BEST IS YET TO COME.
I WOULD LIKE NOW
TO PRESENT
MY MOST FANTASTIC
CREATURE--
A SUPERIOR BEING,
A VISION
OF AFRICANIC BEAUTY,
A BLACK GODDESS
COME TO EARTH--
MISS CLORIS BOSTON
AS KALAHARI SUNRISE.
[PURRING]
[PLAYING FANFARE]
KALAHARI SUNRISE!
[BAND PLAYING FANFARE]
I SAID
KALAHARI SUNRISE.
SOMETHING'S THE MATTER
WITH CLORIS.
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
Friday: CLORIS.
OH, CLORIS, WHY?
OPERATOR, CONNECT ME
WITH THE POLICE.
WHY? WHY?
I...
WANTED TO ASK YOU...
TO SAVE CHET...
THEY...
BLACK...WIDOW.
[GASP]
CLORIS. CLORIS!
SOMEONE CALL
AN AMBULANCE!
PLEASE!
[SOBBING]
CLORIS!
TELL THE BODY SNATCHERS
THEY CAN TAKE THIS ONE AWAY.
AND GET ON IT.
COLT, YOU PHONED IT IN,
RIGHT?
WHAT PUT YOU
ON THE SCENE?
GET YOUR ROCKS OFF
AT FASHION SHOWS
THESE DAYS?
YOU KNOW SOMETHING,
LIEUTENANT?
I'D RATHER SPEND MY TIME
LOOKING AT THE LIVE ONES
THAN GOING AROUND THE CITY
PICKING UP THE DEAD ONES
LIKE YOU DO FOR LOW PAY.
BESIDES, I'M BETTER-LOOKING
THAN YOU ARE.
WELL, YOU MAY HAVE
A POINT THERE.
MAYBE THAT'S WHAT'S
RUINING MY STOMACH.
GOT ANY IDEAS
WHO DID IT?
WHY DON'T YOU ASK
FORD MALOTTE?
WHO'S FORD MALOTTE?
SOME SON OF A BITCH
WHO'S BEEN TRYING
TO RUIN ME FOR YEARS!
HE'S BEEN STEALING
MY DESIGNS
AND SELLING THEM
FOR READY-AND-WEAR!
IS HE
A DESIGNER, TOO?
THAT'S WHAT
HE CALLS HIMSELF,
BUT THIS PLASTIC FAGGOT
COULDN'T DESIGN A HANDKERCHIEF,
LET ALONE A DRESS!
THE ONLY THING HE CAN DO
IS STEAL FROM ME. OH!
SO YOU THINK HE
KILLED THIS GIRL, HUH?
WELL, LET'S PUT IT THIS WAY.
THIS ILL EXCUSE
OF A HUMAN BEING
HAS HAD THIS GIRL
ON A REGULAR BASIS
COMING AND GOING
BETWEEN HERE AND D.C.
HE MIGHT HAVE THOUGHT
SHE KNEW TOO MUCH.
HEY, KID.
I'M LOOKING FOR
A MISS FRIDAY FOSTER.
YEAH. SHE'S MY SISTER.
NO KIDDING.
I'M FROM ACE PHOTO SHOP.
I GOT THIS CAMERA
SHE ORDERED,
AND SHE'S
GOT TO SIGN FOR IT.
SHE'S UPSTAIRS IN 807.
GO ON UP.
ALL RIGHT.
THANKS, LITTLE BROTHER.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
CLEVE, GET THE PHONE
FOR ME!
[RING]
CLEVE!
GET THE PHONE!
COULD YOU GET
THE PHONE FOR ME?
AAH!
LORD HAVE MERCY!
YOU ENTERTAIN
IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE DAYTIME, TOO?
Y'ALL IS TOO MUCH!
ARE YOU SURE YOU'VE GOT
THE RIGHT MAN, FRIDAY?
IT'S THE SAME MAN I
BUMPED INTO AT THE AIRPORT.
WHAT WE'VE GOT HERE
IS AN ATTEMPTED
MURDER,
AN ASSASSINATION,
AND A STIFF
FULL OF BULLETS
AT THAT CLORIS
GIRL'S APARTMENT.
WAIT. WHAT DO
YOU MEAN, STIFF?
SOMEBODY NAMED
CHET FREED.
CHET FREED?
THAT'S CLORIS' BOYFRIEND
FROM OUT OF TOWN.
JAKE, HE'S
A PART OF THE TRIO
THAT TRIED
TO KILL BLAKE TARR.
THEN THAT'S WHY
SHE CALLED ME.
YOU WANT TO TELL ME
HOW LONG
SHE'S BEEN DEALING?
DEALING? COME ON. WHAT
ARE YOU TRYING TO SAY?
WAIT A MINUTE.
WAS SHE A JUNKIE,
OR WAS SHE PUSHING,
OR WHAT?
YOU SCHOOL ME.
WE FOUND 50,000
UNCUT PURE JUNK
IN HER BEDROOM.
HOW DOES THAT READ?
THAT'S A LIE!
CLORIS WAS A LITTLE WILD.
SHE MIGHT HAVE HAD
A FEW HEAVY BOYFRIENDS
HERE AND IN D.C.,
BUT SHE WAS NOT DEALING!
NO WAY! I KNEW HER.
JAKE, SHE WAS MY FRIEND.
FRIENDS IN D.C.?
WHAT KIND OF FRIENDS?
POLITICIANS, MAYBE?
I DON'T KNOW.
DO YOU KNOW ANYONE
WHO WOULD INVITE HER
TO A BIG-TIME PARTY?
WE FOUND AN INVITATION
MADE OUT TO HER NAME.
NOW, WHO WERE SOME
OF HER FRIENDS, HONEY?
I DON'T KNOW THEM
PERSONALLY.
PUBLICLY, MAYBE?
I DON'T KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT THAT!
THEN SHE WAS KILLED
BECAUSE OF THE JUNK.
NO. BELIEVE ME
THIS TIME.
SHE WAS NOT INTO DOPE.
THAT WAS NOT HER THING.
THEN WHY WAS SHE
KILLED, HONEY?
I THINK THE MAN
HAS A POINT.
SURE WISH
I HAD SOME BEER.
O LORD, I GIVE TO YOU
THE SOUL
OF THIS YOUNG WOMAN,
A CHILD OF GOD
WHO ALWAYS HELD OUT
HER HAND TO OTHERS,
WHO ALWAYS GAVE
AND NEVER ASKED IN RETURN.
WE ASK THEE,
ALMIGHTY GOD,
TO LOVE CLORIS
AS WE HAVE LOVED HER
AND TAKE HER
INTO YOUR KINGDOM.
THE LORD IS MY SHEPHERD.
I SHALL NOT WANT.
HE MAKES ME LIE DOWN
IN GREEN PASTURES.
EXCUSE ME A MINUTE.
HE LEADS ME
BESIDE STILL WATERS.
HE RESTORES MY SOUL.
HE LEADS ME IN THE PATH
OF RIGHTEOUSNESS
FOR HIS NAME'S SAKE.
EVEN THOUGH I WALK
THROUGH THE VALLEY
OF THE SHADOW OF DEATH,
I FEAR NO EVIL,
FOR THOU ART WITH ME.
THY ROD AND THY STAFF,
THEY COMFORT ME.
THOU PREPAREST
A TABLE BEFORE ME
IN THE PRESENCE
OF MY ENEMY.
THOU ANOINTEST
MY HEAD WITH OIL.
MY CUP OVERFLOWS.
SURELY GOODNESS AND MERCY
SHALL FOLLOW ME
ALL THE DAYS
OF MY LIFE...
IT'S HIM, COLT.
IT'S WHO?
IT'S--IT'S--
THAT'S FUNNY.
I DON'T SEE ANYBODY.
[TIRES SQUEALING]
LET'S GET THIS STRAIGHT.
YOU SAY SOME GAL
STOLE THE HEARSE?
THAT'S RIGHT.
HOW DO YOU SUCKERS
FIND THESE PROBLEMS?
ANY IDEA WHO SHE WAS?
LOOK, LIEUTENANT,
ALL I KNOW, IT WAS
A BLACK FEMALE,
ABOUT 5'7".
IF I MIGHT SAY SO,
SHE WAS KIND OF
ATTRACTIVE.
OH, YEAH. SHE HAD
THIS LARGE BAG
HANGING
OVER HER SHOULDER.
A CAMERA GADGET BAG?
EXACTLY.
Jake: COLT! IS FRIDAY
INTO STEALING HEARSES NOW?
COME ON, LIEUTENANT.
YOU KNOW
BETTER THAN THAT.
SHE MUST HAVE
SPOTTED SOMEONE
FROM THAT TARR SHOOTING
AT THE AIRPORT.
SHE GRABBED THE FIRST
THING AVAILABLE--
A HEARSE.
WHAT ARE YOU
GOING TO DO,
STICK HER
IN THE GROUND FOR IT?
MAN, THE GAL'S GOT
MORE BALLS THAN BRAINS.
SHE NUTS OR WHAT?
SHE'S JUST ALL WOMAN,
LIEUTENANT.
DAMN, I NEED A BEER!
[HORN HONKS]
AAH!
HOLD IT RIGHT THERE,
LADY!
THANK GOD! THE COPS.
THERE'S A GUY BACK THERE
WHO'S TRYING TO KILL ME.
RIGHT. SURE.
AGAINST
THE WALL, MAMA.
BUT YOU'RE GONNA LET HIM
GET AWAY! OH, NO!
COME ON. HIGHER.
HE'S THE ONE THAT--
HE TRIED TO KILL
BLAKE TARR.
HE'S THE ASSASSIN!
OH, GOD!
MAYBE WE SHOULD SEND
FOR A MATRON TO SEARCH HER.
OH, MAN!
YOU HAD NO RIGHT
TO DO THAT, FRIDAY.
STEALING A HEARSE,
FOR CHRIST'S SAKE,
AND DESTROYING
PUBLIC PROPERTY
AND LOSING A $600 CAMERA.
IS THAT YOUR WAY
OF NOT GETTING INVOLVED?
MR. RILEY, IT WAS
THE MAN THAT--
AND DO YOU KNOW
WHAT IT COST GLANCE
TO KEEP YOU OUT OF JAIL?
AND WHAT IT'S LIABLE
TO COST US
IF THAT FUNERAL DIRECTOR
DECIDES TO SUE
OR PRESS CHARGES?
THERE WAS NOTHING
ELSE I COULD DO.
YEAH, AND MY OLD MAN
INVENTED THE COTTON GIN.
CAN'T YOU GET IT UNDER
YOUR SKULL, FRIDAY,
THAT YOUR LIFE
IS IN DANGER
AND THAT SOMEBODY IS
TRYING TO KILL YOU?
SO YOU'RE OUT
OF THE SLAMMER.
I THOUGHT I WOULDN'T SEE YOU
UNTIL VISITING HOURS.
HOW WAS THE BREAD
AND WATER?
YOU GOT SOMETHING
FOR ME, COLT?
THAT'S DEPENDING
ON WHETHER OR NOT
YOU DIDN'T SPEND UP
ALL YOUR MONEY
ON LAWYERS
AND BAIL BONDSMEN.
I MIGHT LOOK INTO
SOMETHING FOR YOU
IN WASHINGTON, D.C.,
TOMORROW.
LIKE WHAT?
LIKE A BUNCH OF FLOWERS
SENT TO CLORIS BOSTON'S
FUNERAL FROM A NO-NAME FRIEND.
FRIDAY SAW IT.
TELL ME, DO YOU KNOW A FELLOW
NAMED DAVID LEE HART?
THE SENATOR?
CLORIS BOSTON HAD
A SENATOR STASHED AWAY?
SURE. CLORIS HAD QUITE
A FEW FRIENDS IN D.C.
SHE WOULD FLY DOWN THERE
FOR THESE WEEKEND DATES.
SOME BROTHER NAMED
FORD MALOTTE SET THEM UP.
THAT'S A COINCIDENCE.
HE'S THE MAN--
AND I USE THE TERM LOOSELY--
THAT I'M GOING TO SEE.
ALL RIGHT.
WHEN DO WE GO?
YOU'RE NOT GOING
ANYPLACE.
AW, MR. RILEY--
NO WAY.
PLEASE. I GOT TO FIND OUT
WHO KILLED CLORIS,
I WANT TO KNOW ABOUT
THIS BLACK WIDOW THING,
AND I WANT TO PROVE
THAT SHE WAS NOT DEALING.
WHAT YOU REALLY WANT
IS SENATOR HART
TO SEND YOU
SOME FLOWERS
FOR YOUR FUNERAL.
HERE'S THE PRINT.
CLEAR AS A BELL.
THE BLOW-UP
CAME OUT PERFECT.
IT'S HIM!
THIS IS THE MAN THAT'S
BEEN TRYING TO KILL ME!
LET'S GET
A PRINT OF THIS
TO THE POLICE
RIGHT AWAY.
I WANT THIS GUY
CAUGHT
BEFORE HE CATCHES UP
WITH FRIDAY.
BUT, MONK, NOW YOU SEE
WHY I HAVE TO GO TO D.C.?
FRIDAY, THERE'S
ABSOLUTELY NO DAMN WAY
THAT YOU OR
GLANCE MAGAZINE
IS GOING ON A MANHUNT
TO WASHINGTON,
AND THAT'S
THE BOTTOM LINE!
YOU MIGHT AS WELL
FORGET IT. NO WAY.
NO WAY!
Colt: FOR GOD'S SAKE,
FRIDAY,
COULDN'T WE HAVE
MET HIM ON A PARK BENCH?
WHY THIS PLACE?
WOULD
THE WHITE HOUSE LAWN
SUIT YOU BETTER,
MR. HAWKINS?
ANYWHERE IS BETTER
THAN THIS.
AND BESIDES, SINCE
YOU'VE BROUGHT ME HERE,
I'M BEGINNING TO WONDER
ABOUT YOU, FRIDAY.
[AS DRACULA]
DON'T BE AFRAID.
I WON'T BITE YOU.
THIS IS
A PUBLIC PLACE.
YOU'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
YEAH, BUT I THINK
I'LL NEED PROTECTION.
OH, JESUS.
EXCUSE ME, MISS.
COULD YOU--
COULD YOU TELL ME
WHERE I CAN FIND
FORD MALOTTE,
PLEASE?
MAYBE. WHAT'S
YOUR BUSINESS, SWEETIE?
JUST TELL HIM THAT
FRIDAY FOSTER IS HERE
FROM GLANCE MAGAZINE.
HE'S RIGHT OVER THERE.
HIS MUSCLES ARE BIGGER
THAN MINE.
AND THAT'S NOT ALL.
UM, FORD MALOTTE?
COOCHIE COOCHIE.
FRIDAY FOSTER
FROM GLANCE MAGAZINE.
HOW ARE YOU, DARLING?
IT'S ALWAYS SO NICE TO MEET
SOMEONE FROM THE PRESS.
AND WHO IS HE?
COLT HAWKINS,
PRIVATE INVESTIGATOR.
OOH! OH,
DO BE SEATED.
OH, YES, DARLING.
SIT DOWN.
I HATE CLICHES,
SO I WON'T USE
ANY NOW.
YES. I KNOW.
THE "WHAT'S IT ALL
ABOUT" BIT, RIGHT?
YES. IT'S BEEN DONE
TO DEATH.
AND SO WAS
CLORIS.
OH, YES.
I...HEARD ABOUT IT.
SOME, UH, LIEUTENANT
JAKE WAYNE
CALLED ME ABOUT IT
EARLIER.
AH, CLORIS.
A MARVELOUS GIRL.
I MEAN, NOBODY,
NOBODY
COULD WEAR THINGS
THE WAY SHE COULD,
WITH A BODY
PUT TOGETHER IN HEAVEN
WITH TENDER, LOVING HANDS.
AND TO THINK THAT
THAT SIMPLE POLICEMAN
WOULD INTIMATE
THAT I WOULD TERMINATE
SUCH A TALENTED GIRL.
I'M AFRAID
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
THAT'S A PRIVATE PARTY,
THAT RECEPTION.
OH, MALOTTE, YOU'VE
BOOKED DATES FOR CLORIS
WITH GOVERNMENT V.I.P.s
AND SENATORS.
NOW, WHY CAN'T YOU
DO IT FOR ME?
BUT THAT
WAS DIFFERENT.
SHE HAD
THAT, UH, TOUCH.
Friday: LOOK, MALOTTE,
CLORIS AND I
GREW UP TOGETHER.
WE WERE LIKE SISTERS.
IF SHE CAN BE INVITED
TO THIS RECEPTION, SO CAN I.
INTERESTING. MAYBE.
WITH THE RIGHT GOWN
AND A NEW COIFFURE,
YOU MIGHT PASS
FOR HER,
BUT THERE'S NO WAY.
YOU KNOW,
THERE IS SOME REASON
WHY YOU DON'T WANT ME
AT THIS RECEPTION.
ARE YOU AFRAID THAT
BLACK WIDOW MIGHT BE THERE?
YOU KNOW
ABOUT BLACK WIDOW?
FRIDAY, DARLING,
WHEN YOU ARE
FOOLING AROUND
WITH AMBITIOUS MEN
LIKE SENATOR HART,
IT CAN BE HAZARDOUS
TO YOUR HEALTH.
TAKE MY ADVICE.
STAY OUT OF IT.
GO BACK. GO HOME.
GET LAID.
HAVE A BABY...
OR SOMETHING.
WHAT YOU'RE TRYING TO SAY
IS YOU WON'T HELP US, RIGHT?
SWEETIE...
TELL YOUR LIBERATED
LITTLE WOMAN
THAT I CAN'T
POSSIBLY.
WITH OR WITHOUT
YOUR HELP, MR. MALOTTE,
I AM GOING TO BE
AT THAT RECEPTION!
WELL, SUIT YOURSELF,
SWEETIE.
ISN'T SHE MARVELOUS
WHEN SHE'S MAD?
OH!
UH, FRIDAY,
JUST A MOMENT.
I WANT TO STAY AND TALK
TO MR. MALOTTE
AND ASK HIM
A FEW QUESTIONS...
MAN TO MAN.
TAXI! TAXI! TAXI!
OH, SHOOT.
[TIRES SQUEALING]
[HORN HONKING]
COLT! OH, COLT!
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
HE WAS TRYING
TO KILL ME, COLT.
DID YOU GET A LOOK
AT HIM?
DO YOU KNOW
WHO HE WAS?
NO.
WE'RE NOT GONNA FIND
THE REASON OUT HERE NOW.
NO.
COME ON. LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE.
Malotte: I DIDN'T WANT
TO BOTHER YOU WITH IT,
BUT WHEN THE GIRL
SHOWED UP HERE
AND SHE KNEW
ABOUT BLACK WIDOW,
I THOUGHT, WELL, THIS COULD
REALLY CAUSE TROUBLE,
ALL KINDS OF TROUBLE.
I MEAN, LOOK...
IT'S ALL RIGHT FOR YOU
TO SIT UP THERE
ON YOUR HIGH THRONE
AND FEEL SAFE.
YOU DID RIGHT TO CALL,
BUT THE GIRL CAN'T KNOW
TOO MUCH.
YOU LISTEN TO ME.
SHE WON'T HINDER US.
THERE'S TOO MUCH AT STAKE.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
I'M ON TOP OF IT.
AAH!
[ENGLISH ACCENT]
THANK YOU, JEEVES.
YOU KNOW SOMETHING,
FRIDAY? I DON'T THINK
WE SHOULD GO
THROUGH WITH THIS.
I DON'T LIKE IT. I DON'T
FEEL RIGHT ABOUT IT.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU'RE RIGHT.
YOU PUT THE DRESS
AND YOU GO ON IN THERE.
THAT'S NOT FUNNY.
YOU KNOW THERE'S
TROUBLE IN THERE.
YOU COULD BE HURT
OR SOMETHING.
DANGER.
YOU KNOW YOU LOVE ME.
WHERE'S THE INVITATION?
THAT'S RIGHT.
THE INVITATION.
OH, YOU DIDN'T.
I GOT IT.
HERE IT IS.
YOU SCARED ME
FOR A MOMENT. OH, BOY.
ARE YOU SURE THIS
IS GOING TO WORK?
IT AIN'T THE SIZE
OF THE SHIP.
IT'S THE MOTION
OF THE OCEAN.
WELL, WATCH THIS OCEAN.
MMM, MMM! MAN,
THAT'S SOME FINE LADY
YOU WORKING FOR.
SAY, MAN,
WHAT'S SHE INTO?
OH, WELL,
SHE'S INTO, UH...
WELL, YOU KNOW,
SHE'S, UH...
DON'T BOTHER
TO ANNOUNCE US.
JUST TELL MY HUSBAND
I'LL BE IN THE POWDER ROOM.
YOU MUST BE THE REVEREND
NOBLE FRANKLIN.
WHY, YES. MY, MY,
YOU ARE AN ATTRACTIVE
YOUNG LADY.
WHY, THANK YOU,
REVEREND FRANKLIN.
OH, JUST CALL ME
NOBLE, SISTER.
YOU SEE, I'M NOT ONE
TO STAND ON CEREMONIES.
NOW, WHAT CAN I DO
FOR YOU?
UH, OH, IT'S SO SILLY.
SPEAK UP, SISTER.
I'M A VERY
UNDERSTANDING MAN,
VERY UNDERSTANDING.
YOU SEE, I'M A CHURCH REPORTER
FOR OUR NEWSLETTER,
AND I WOULD LOVE TO DO A STORY
AND TAKE PICTURES OF YOU.
NO PROBLEM AT ALL.
WHERE'S YOUR CAMERA?
YOU SEE, THAT'S JUST IT.
I FORGOT IT,
AND I COULD JUST KICK
MYSELF FOR BEING SO--
I SEE. DON'T WORRY
ABOUT IT.
I CAN SET UP A SPECIAL
APPOINTMENT FOR YOU
UP AT JERICHO.
UH, JERICHO?
UH, WHERE'S THAT?
THAT'S MY ESTATE,
MY MEDITATIVE RETREAT
UP THE RIVER.
AND, UH, WE COULD
SPEND SOME TIME
FOR, UH, PURPOSES.
WELL, YOU KNOW,
THEN AGAIN, REVEREND,
I'M NOT SO SURE.
REVEREND FRANKLIN NOT ONLY
HAS A WAY WITH A PRAYER,
BUT BEAUTIFUL WOMEN,
AS WELL.
I DON'T THINK
I'VE HAD THE PLEASURE.
OH, YES.
SENATOR HART,
I WANT YOU TO MEET
MISS FRIDAY FOSTER,
A VERY, VERY PRETTY
CHURCH REPORTER.
AND WHAT CHURCH ARE YOU
A REPORTER FOR?
YOU SEE, SENATOR HART,
THAT'S NOT EXACTLY THE TRUTH.
I REALLY CAME HERE
TO SEE YOU,
REGARDING A MUTUAL FRIEND.
I'M SORRY WE MISSED YOU
AT THE FUNERAL.
FUNERAL? WHOSE?
CLORIS BOSTON.
I THINK WE OUGHT TO GET
TO KNOW EACH OTHER BETTER.
EXCUSE US, REVEREND.
Reverend: SURE,
AND YOU STILL
HAVE AN INVITATION
TO COME UP TO JERICHO,
YOU FINE SISTER, YOU.
YOUR FLOWERS WERE
A COMFORT TO CLORIS.
IT WAS THE LEAST
I COULD DO.
SHE WAS A FRIEND.
JUST A FRIEND?
BUT THAT'S NOT WHAT
THE D.C. GRAPEVINE SAYS.
A SMART GIRL LIKE YOU
SHOULDN'T BELIEVE
IN GOSSIP, SHOULD YOU?
EXCUSE ME, DAVID.
I SPOKE
WITH THE CONGRESSMAN,
AND HE HAS AGREED
TO THE MEETING.
GOOD. UH,
FRIDAY FOSTER,
THIS IS MY
EXECUTIVE ASSISTANT
CHARLES FOLEY.
MISS FOSTER.
MR. FOLEY.
UH, CHARLES,
MISS FOSTER AND I
ARE GOING
TO MY PLACE
TO, UH, DISCUSS SOME
MUTUAL INTERESTS,
SO WATCH THE STORE,
WILL YOU?
YES, SIR. NICE
MEETING YOU, MISS FOSTER.
WHILE YOU'RE
IN WASHINGTON,
IF I CAN BE OF ANY
ASSISTANCE WHATSOEVER,
FEEL FREE TO CALL.
WHEN YOU DO,
JUST ASK FOR CHARLEY.
THANK YOU.
I'LL REMEMBER THAT...
CHARLEY.
Hart: AFTER
ONE DIVORCE
AND 12 YEARS
IN WASHINGTON,
ONE GETS TO KNOW
HIS PEOPLE.
MORE BRANDY?
MORE BRANDY AND I MIGHT
LOSE ALL MY INHIBITIONS.
MAYBE WORSE.
LOOK WHAT HAPPENED
TO CLORIS.
CLORIS WAS ONLY A PAL.
JUST A FRIEND.
SO WE MADE IT
A FEW TIMES,
BUT OUR RELATIONSHIP
WAS ONLY PHYSICAL.
I'M REALLY SORRY
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
IF I COULD CHANGE IT,
I REALLY WOULD.
WILL YOU BELIEVE ME?
TRUST ME?
THEN YOU CAN START
TRUSTING ME.
YOU CAN TELL ME
WHAT THE HELL IS GOING ON.
OK.
FIND YOURSELF A CERTAIN
MR. BLAKE TARR,
AND IT WILL ALL
COME AS CLEAR
AS MONDAY'S WASH.
I'M TOLD HE'S THE MAN
BEHIND IT ALL.
NOW, WHY WOULD HE PLAN
HIS OWN ASSASSINATION?
IT'S ALL PART
OF A BIG POWER PLAY
TO MAKE YOU BELIEVE
IT'S SOMETHING
IT ISN'T.
AND WHAT'S
YOUR POWER PLAY?
ARE YOU SOMETHING
YOU'RE NOT, TOO?
NOW, WHAT WILL
ALL THE GOSSIPS SAY?
OH, THEY WILL PROBABLY
SAY THAT I MADE LOVE
TO ONE OF THE MOST
BEAUTIFUL WOMEN
D.C. HAS EVER SEEN.
YOU'RE VERY SURE
OF YOURSELF, AREN'T YOU?
AREN'T YOU?
WHEN I THINK ABOUT IT,
IT'S JUST AS WELL
THE GIRL WASN'T KILLED.
YOU REALLY
THINK SO, HUH?
HERE YOU ARE, SIR.
I THOUGHT YOU SAID
SHE CAME FROM
GLANCE MAGAZINE.
I DID.
IT SEEMS SHE CAME
TO WASHINGTON
AND BLUFFED HER WAY
INTO THE RECEPTION
SPECIFICALLY TO MEET
WITH SENATOR HART.
IT SEEMS SHE TIED
THE MURDER OF HER FRIEND
TO THE SENATOR.
DID THE SENATOR
TELL HER ANYTHING?
NO.
WELL, THAT'S GOOD,
ISN'T IT?
DID SHE TELL THE
SENATOR ANYTHING?
ONLY THAT SHE'D HEARD
ABOUT BLACK WIDOW.
AREN'T YOU WORRIED
ABOUT THAT, CHARLES?
THAT'S WHY I THINK
SHE CAN BE OF USE TO ME,
IF THE SENATOR
WILL GO ALONG,
AND I THINK HE WILL,
OR ELSE I'LL HAVE TO TELL HIM
HOW THOSE THOUSANDS OF
CONTRIBUTORS TO HIS CAMPAIGN
IS REALLY JUST
ONE BIG CONTRIBUTOR--
ENOS HARTMAN GRIFFITH,
WHO IS NOW WILLING
TO GO ALONG WITH ME.
WELL, BY HERSELF,
SHE'S NOTHING,
BUT WITH GLANCE
MAGAZINE BEHIND HER,
SHE MAY BE ABLE
TO HELP YOU
FLUSH OUT BLAKE TARR.
THE SENATOR HAS ALREADY
PUT A BUG IN HER EAR.
HE SAID THAT BLAKE TARR
IS THE ONE THAT CAN TELL HER
ABOUT THE MURDER
OF HER FRIEND CLORIS.
WELL, HE'S CERTAINLY
RIGHT ABOUT THAT,
ISN'T HE, CHARLES?
BLAKE TARR
IS THE ANSWER
TO ALL OUR PROBLEMS,
MR. GRIFFITH.
WELL, THAT'S WHAT THE
SENATOR SAID, MR. RILEY.
HIS OFFICE WOULD
GIVE US FULL COOPERATION.
Colt: WHY DON'T YOU PUT
SOME SUGAR IN YOUR CEREAL?
NAH...I DON'T
LIKE IT TOO SWEET.
HEY, BLACKHAWK,
YOU GOT ANY MONEY?
I'VE GOT BARRELS
OF IT. WHY?
I GOT SOME
DYNAMITE PERFUME,
OUT-OF-SIGHT WATCHES,
LADIES' LINGERIE,
AND A WHOLE LOT
OF OTHER STUFF FOR SALE.
SO NOW YOU'RE
HUSTLING, HUH?
NOPE...STRICTLY
BLACK CAPITALISM.
Friday: IF GLANCE
DOESN'T WANT THE STORY,
THEN MAYBE
SOMEBODY ELSE WILL!
WHY'D YOU DO THAT?
WHY'D YOU
HANG UP ON HIM?
CALL HIM BACK.
WHY SHOULD
I CALL HIM BACK?
HE DOESN'T CARE!
I'VE TRIED SO HARD!
WELL, YOU'RE GOING
TO HAVE TO TRY HARDER.
COME ON.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
OH, MR. RILEY, I'M SORRY
FOR TALKING TO YOU LIKE THAT.
OH, MADAME RENA?
NEVER MIND THAT.
I'VE GOT INFORMATION ABOUT
YOUR TRIP TO WASHINGTON.
OH? WHAT?
I CAN'T TALK ON THE PHONE,
BUT I THINK YOU'D BETTER
GET YOUR LITTLE DERRIERE
DOWN HERE TO MY OFFICE NOW.
FRIDAY, I SAID NOW!
WAS THAT MONK BEGGING
YOUR FORGIVENESS?
UH-UH. NO, IT WASN'T.
IT WAS MADAME RENA,
AND SHE WANTS ME
TO COME OVER.
CAN YOU GIVE ME
A RIDE?
ONLY IF YOU
PROMISE ME
THERE WON'T BE
ANY DEAD BODIES
LAYING AROUND.
NOW, PROMISE.
ALL RIGHT, I PROMISE.
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
MADAME RENA,
IT'S FRIDAY FOSTER!
WHY DO YOU HAVE TO
STIR THINGS UP?
WATCH OUT!
COLT, DON'T LET HIM
GET AWAY!
YOU'RE WRONG
ABOUT BLACK WIDOW.
BUT SENATOR HART SAID--
GET A PENCIL AND WRITE
WHAT I SAY TO YOU,
IF YOU WANT
TO KNOW THE TRUTH.
WHAT AM I DOING HERE?
SON OF A BITCH!
AAH!
Rena: CALL THIS NUMBER
WHEN YOU CAN.
BUT WHOSE?
THEY'LL...EXPLAIN.
YOU'RE WRONG ABOUT...
BLACK...WIDOW.
RENA! RENA!
SHE'S DEAD, COLT.
WELL, THAT MAKES
TWO FOR TODAY,
BECAUSE ONE
OF THOSE KILLERS
WON'T BE
HUNTING YOU NO MORE.
DID SHE SAY
ANYTHING?
JUST, UM...NOTHING.
HELLO?
I'M FRIDAY FOSTER,
AND I'M CALLING
FOR MADAME RENA.
NO, SHE CAN'T
COME TO THE PHONE.
SHE'S DEAD.
JUST NOW.
NO, HE'S DEAD, TOO.
HEY, I HAVEN'T
THE SLIGHTEST IDEA.
HEY, SHE JUST
ASKED ME TO CALL
BEFORE SHE DIED.
THAT'S ALL I KNOW.
COME WHERE?
THE CITY BANK
BUILDING?
HELLO? HELLO?
Friday: HELLO?
IS ANYBODY UP HERE?
[HELICOPTER FLYING OVERHEAD]
MISS FOSTER?
I'M BLAKE TARR.
I DON'T CARE WHO YOU ARE!
YOU HAVE GOT NO RIGHT
TO COME UP HERE
AND SCARE ME
HALF TO DEATH!
LOOK, I'M SORRY,
BUT THERE ARE
CERTAIN PRECAUTIONS
I HAVE TO TAKE.
ROOFTOPS AND HELICOPTERS
AND HENCHMEN!
RENA WAS RIGHT.
YOU'VE GOT GUTS.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT RENA?
SHE WORKED FOR ME.
IT'S BECAUSE OF HER
AND MALOTTE
THAT I CAME BACK
TO THE STATES.
THEY TOLD ME
WHAT WAS GOING ON.
AND WHAT IS GOING ON?
BLACK WIDOW.
SO SENATOR HART
WAS RIGHT AFTER ALL.
YOU ARE BEHIND
BLACK WIDOW.
WHAT ELSE DID THE CHARMING
SENATOR TELL YOU?
THAT YOU KNOW WHO KILLED
MY FRIEND CLORIS.
MM-HMM, AND THAT
I GO AROUND
KILLING MY OWN PEOPLE,
THAT I SET MYSELF UP
TO BE ASSASSINATED
AT THE AIRPORT?
COME ON. DOES THAT
MAKE SENSE TO YOU?
THAT HART'S A CLEVER
SON OF A--
YOU KNOW,
HE'S GOT EVERYBODY
BELIEVING IN THAT
UNITY SCAM OF HIS,
WHEN IN REALITY,
IT'S JUST A FRONT,
A POWER GRAB.
I THINK THAT BLACK WIDOW
IS A CODE NAME FOR IT.
DAVID LEE HART, HUH?
RENA SAID YOU COULD BE
TRUSTED. THAT'S WHY I'M HERE.
THIS IS ALL A LITTLE
CONFUSING, YOU KNOW.
I'VE GOT TO KNOW
THE WHEN, THE WHAT,
THE WAY OF
HART'S TIMETABLE.
ALL SHE WAS ABLE
TO FIND OUT
WAS THAT IT HAD
SOMETHING TO DO
WITH ST. VALENTINE'S DAY.
THAT'S THE DAY
AFTER TOMORROW.
RIGHT, BUT THE QUESTION IS,
WILL YOU HELP ME?
WHY WOULD I?
BECAUSE I'VE ASKED YOU.
YOU'RE QUITE SURE
OF YOURSELF, AREN'T YOU?
ARE ALL BLACK
MILLIONAIRES LIKE THAT?
PROBABLY.
IT GOES WITH THE JOB.
SOME JOB.
Blake: I CAN'T SAY
I DISLIKE IT.
COMING FROM THE GHETTO
ALL THE WAY TO THE TOP
WAS QUITE A TRIP.
BUT I'M CURIOUS
ABOUT YOU.
THERE ARE THINGS
I'D LIKE TO KNOW.
LIKE WHAT?
LIKE WHO IS FRIDAY FOSTER?
WHERE'S SHE GOING?
WHO AM I?
THAT'S A FUNNY QUESTION.
WELL, FIRST,
I'M A WOMAN.
SECOND, I AM
A PHOTOGRAPHER
AND A BIG SISTER
TO A LITTLE BROTHER,
WHO'S REALLY
A 40-YEAR-OLD MAN.
[CHUCKLES]
AND, UM...I LIKE
CATS AND DOGS
AND HORSES AND MEN--
BUT NOT NECESSARILY
IN THAT ORDER.
I MAKE
MY OWN DECISIONS...
AND I'M A GEMINI.
THAT IT?
WELL, THAT'S ENOUGH.
WELL, AS FAR AS
WHERE I'M GOING...
DO YOU MEAN NOW
OR IN THE FUTURE?
EITHER WAY.
I SEE THAT I'M
GOING TO BE
GETTING
INTO SOMETHING
I DID NOT EXPECT.
WHAT DID YOU EXPECT?
YOU KNOW
WHAT I EXPECTED?
I EXPECTED
YOU TO BE A RAT,
BUT YOU'RE
DIFFERENT.
BABY, YOU FORGET
I'M STRAIGHT OFF THE BLOCK.
I KNOW THAT'S WHAT
CANCELED MY THEORY.
YOU TREAT A PERSON
LIKE A PERSON
AND A WOMAN
LIKE A WOMAN.
I TRY TO TREAT A LADY
LIKE A LADY.
HAPPY VALENTINE'S DAY.
Colt: YOU DIDN'T PHONE.
YOU DIDN'T WRITE.
YOU DIDN'T DO NOTHING.
YOU KNOW, YOU
COULD HAVE BEEN DEAD
FOR ALL I KNOW?
WELL, I WASN'T,
WAS I?
YOU KNOW, FOR TWO DAYS,
YOU'RE MISSING,
AND THE MINUTE
YOU'RE BACK,
YOU DRAG ME HERE.
WOULD YOU MIND TELLING
ME WHY WE'RE HERE?
WE ARE GOING TO
SEE THE SENATOR.
I WANT TO ASK HIM
A FEW QUESTIONS,
AND I WANT SOME
NO-JIVE ANSWERS.
TO WHAT?
TO WHERE ARE ALL
THE BLACK LEADERS?
I HAVE BEEN CALLING THEM
ALL OVER THE PLACE,
AND NO ONE SEEMS TO KNOW
WHERE THEY ARE.
HOW WOULD
THE SENATOR KNOW?
NOW, WOULD A PIMP
LOSE TRACK OF HIS STABLE?
I UNDERSTAND YOU'RE
ASKING FOR SENATOR HART.
I'M HIS
EXECUTIVE SECRETARY.
WOULD YOU TELL HIM
THAT FRIDAY FOSTER
IS HERE TO SEE HIM?
AND I DON'T INTEND
TO BE KEPT WAITING.
WELL, YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO BECAUSE HE'S NOT IN,
AND HE WON'T BE
AT ALL TODAY.
COULD YOU CALL HIM
ON THE PHONE?
HE DIDN'T LEAVE
A NUMBER. SORRY.
WHAT ABOUT
CHARLES FOLEY?
WITH THE SENATOR.
COLT...
COLT, THIS HAS GOT TO BE
THE DAY FOR BLACK WIDOW.
HMM?
ON VALENTINE'S DAY.
NOW, DOESN'T THAT MEAN
SOMETHING TO YOU?
A MASSACRE.
DID HE SAY ANYTHING
ABOUT TODAY? ANYTHING?
WELL, THE ONLY THING
HE SAID BEFORE HE LEFT
WAS THAT THIS WAS THE DAY
THAT THE WALLS
COME TUMBLING DOWN.
DON'T MAKE
MUCH SENSE TO ME.
NOTHING MUCH WOULD.
I DON'T GET IT. DOES IT
MEAN ANYTHING TO YOU?
THE WALLS COME
TUMBLING DOWN.
JOSHUA FIT THE BATTLE
OF JERICHO, HUH?
THAT'S IT!
JERICHO! DON'T YOU KNOW
WHAT JERICHO IS?
SWEETHEART, I'M
A SUNDAY-SCHOOL DROPOUT.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE--
THAT'S REVEREND
NOBLE FRANKLIN'S PLACE.
HE INVITED ME THERE--
DIRTY OLD MAN.
YEAH, WELL, SO WHAT?
SO THE NAME OF
THE PLACE IS JERICHO!
THAT MAKES SENSE!
IT DOES, HUH?
THAT'S WHERE THE
BLACK WIDOW STARTS.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
JERICHO! JERICHO!
Friday: WHAT'S
THE MATTER, HUH?
WE'VE GOT COMPANY,
AND NOT THE FRIENDLY KIND.
YEAH, I SEE THE UGLY
AND THE UGLIER.
LET'S GO OUT BACK.
NO. WAIT A MINUTE,
WAIT A MINUTE.
THEY DON'T KNOW ME.
I'LL GO DOWN THERE
AND GIVE THEM
THE OLD FAST SHUFFLE.
YOU GO BACK OUT AND GET
ON THE HORN WITH BLAKE TARR.
CAN YOU DIG IT?
YEAH, I CAN DIG IT.
ARE YOU SURE
HE DIDN'T LEAVE A MESSAGE?
NO, HE CAN'T
CALL ME BACK.
I'LL TRY AGAIN LATER, OK?
HEY, HEY, BROTHERS,
WHAT'S GOING ON?
HOLD IT, BLOOD.
WHERE IS SAPPHIRE?
SAY WHAT?
OH!
COLT, COME ON! WE GOT TO
DO IT ALONE. FOLLOW ME.
LET'S PULL IT TOGETHER,
FELLOWS.
[CAR HORN HONKS]
[TIRES SQUEAL]
COLT?
WHERE'S FRIDAY?
MAN, HOW YOU GOING
TO RIDE IN HERE,
SCREECHING AND
BLOWING YOUR HORN--
SCARE THE LIFE
OUT OF ME LIKE THAT?
I WAS FIXING MY CAR,
AND YOU COME
ROARING IN HERE
WITH YOUR BAD BOYS
IN THE FRONT
AND SCARE
THE LIFE OUT OF ME.
MAN, WHO ARE YOU?
BLAKE TARR. NOW, COME ON,
GET IN THE CAR, QUICK!
WHERE WE GOING?
TO THE AIRPORT.
COME ON!
MAN, IF THAT BROAD GETS
IN ANY KIND OF TROUBLE,
I'M GOING TO DEAL WITH
YOU MYSELF, HEAR ME?
FIRST RENA GOT KILLED
AND THEN MALOTTE,
AND THEN YOU COME UP
WITH THIS BULLSHIT ABOUT
WE GOING TO THE AIRPORT.
LET ME TELL YOU
ONE GODDAMN THING--
[HORN HONKING]
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
I'M DELIVERING
THE MILK.
HOLD YOUR FIRE!
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S MOVE IT.
NOBLE! NOBLE!
NOBLE, IT'S FRIDAY FOSTER!
OPEN UP! QUICK!
NOBLE! NOBLE!
NOBLE!
WHERE'S NOBLE FRANKLIN?
I'VE GOT TO SEE HIM.
NOBLE FRANKLIN!
WHAT'S ALL
THE COMMOTION?
THERE'S AN ARMY OUTSIDE
WITH ENOUGH GUNS
TO START WORLD WAR III!
HE SAID
THE WALLS OF JERICHO
WERE TO COME
TUMBLING DOWN TODAY,
BUT I DIDN'T KNOW HE
MEANT TO SHOOT THEM DOWN!
WHO?
OUR GREAT LEADER
SENATOR DAVID LEE HART.
HE'S THE ONE BEHIND
BLACK WIDOW, AND HE'S--
ARE YOU OUT OF YOUR MIND?
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
Hart: WHAT WOULD
I BE DOING HERE?
HE'S OUR LEADER. THE WHOLE
UNITY CONCEPT IS HIS.
BUT THE WALLS OF--
THE WALLS OF PREJUDICE,
OF DISCRIMINATION,
OF MISUNDERSTANDING
AND HATE--
EVERY IMPORTANT BLACK
LEADER IN THE COUNTRY
IS HERE TODAY.
WE'RE ACTING TOGETHER...
AS ONE
FOR THE FIRST TIME.
BUT IF YOU'RE NOT
BEHIND BLACK WIDOW
AND BLAKE TARR ISN'T
BEHIND BLACK WIDOW,
THEN WHOSE ARMY
IS THAT?
WHAT ARMY?
LORD, WHY ME?
SHOTGUNS ARE FOR SKEET.
AT BEST, THEY MAY
BUY US A LITTLE TIME.
TIME FOR WHAT?
DAVID, DOES THIS MAKE
ANY SENSE TO YOU?
SUPPOSE YOU WANTED
TO DESTROY BLACK POWER.
WHAT OTHER WAY THAN TO
GET ALL OF OUR LEADERS
TOGETHER IN ONE PLACE
AND WIPE THEM OUT?
BUT I SAW BLACKS
WITH THE WHITES.
I SAW THEM.
SOME NIGGERS WILL DO
ANYTHING FOR A DOLLAR.
Friday:
DAVID, LOOK OUT!
DAVID, ARE YOU
ALL RIGHT?
YEAH.
I'LL GET HIM.
WHAT YOU NEED
IS AN EDUCATION.
2 AND 2 ARE 4.
4 AND 4 ARE 8.
SEE SPOT RUN.
OH, BLAKE!
TARR, MAN,
WHAT THE HELL
IS GOING ON HERE?
SO IT'S EVIDENT
WE WERE WRONG
ABOUT EACH OTHER.
I WAS WRONG
ABOUT YOU, AND YOU--
WELL, YEAH, I WAS
CERTAINLY WRONG ABOUT YOU.
I FIGURED THAT YOU WERE
BEHIND BLACK WIDOW
AND THAT IT WAS
JUST A POWER GRAB.
BUT THEN
WHO THE HELL
IS THE DEVIL
BEHIND ALL THIS?
FRIDAY, I'VE TOLD YOU
OVER AND OVER,
I'M NOT A MAN
OF VIOLENCE.
RIGHT, MR. FOLEY?
Foley: MR. TARR,
I'M SORRY MY FRIENDS
MISSED YOU AT THE AIRPORT,
BUT THEY WERE GODDAMN
BUNGLING FOOLS!
OH, MR. FOLEY,
YOU'RE THE BUMBLING FOOL.
YOU THOUGHT
YOU COULD SUCKER DAVID
INTO GETTING ALL THESE
BLACK LEADERS UP HERE
TO MASSACRE
EVERY LAST ONE OF THEM.
YOU COULDN'T
LEAD ANYBODY ANYWHERE.
YOU'RE SUCH
A FOOL, MAN.
MR. FOLEY,
SOMETHING YOU FORGOT--
THAT US FOLKS CAN STICK TOGETHER
WHEN IT IS NECESSARY.
HEY, FANCY,
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
HEY, SPECIAL DELIVERY
MAN IS HERE!
WHERE IS THAT FINE
SISTER OF YOURS?
I WANT HER
TO CHECK THIS OUT.
NOW, I GOT A DYNAMITE
GUCCI PURSE
AND SOME ROCKS
FROM TIFFANY'S.
NOW, GET TO THAT.
HEY, THAT'S REAL COOL, MAN.
THAT'S REAL COOL.
I'LL TAKE IT
UP TO HER RIGHT NOW.
OK, WELL, YOU DO THAT,
LITTLE MAN,
'CAUSE I'M GOING TO
LAY RIGHT OUT HERE.
HEY, FRIDAY, LOOK
WHAT FANCY SENT FOR--
WOW!
SEEMS LIKE I HAVE
A FEW ADMIRERS,
DOESN'T IT?
WOW!
[DOORBELL RINGS]
THE DOOR'S OPEN.
OH, COLT, LOOK
AT ALL THIS STUFF!
HAVE YOU EVER SEEN SO
MANY BEAUTIFUL THINGS?
MY GOD!
I BROUGHT YOU A LITTLE
SOMETHING, BUT, UH...
IT'S TOO LITTLE
AND TOO LATE.
OH, COLT. OH!
OH, IT'S BEAUTIFUL!
IT'S CHEAP!
YOU KNOW, BETWEEN
SENATOR HART AND BLAKE TARR,
I FEEL LIKE, UH...
A LIGHTWEIGHT.
YOU SHOULD.
I'M GOING TO KILL HIM.
OH, COLT, BUT WHEN
IT COMES DOWN TO IT,
YOU'RE MY MAIN MAN.
SHALL WE GO?
BY ALL MEANS.
I GOT THE CHARIOT
DOWNSTAIRS.
DINNER...
DANCING...
FLOWERS...
MOONLIGHT...
AND, UH...
Both: NO KIDS.