Lizzie Borden...
Violette Noziére...
Ulrike Meinhof... Kim
Gordon... Patty Hearst...
Camille Henrot...
Bernadine Dohrn, Aileen Wuornos,
Angela Davis, Jennifer Urmila.
Jeanne Manning...
Winona Rider, Winona Rider!
Those are the real revolutionaries...
Oh fuck...
-Winona Rider.
Shoplifting is always revolutionary.
Oh my God...
I'd better go.
I have to make dinner for Marie.
- Okay.
- See you tomorrow.
- Okay, bye.
Did I say Gudrun Ensslin?
Marie?
Lake? Are you there?
Lake?
You and your books. Aren't
they supposed to be obsolete?
What do you want?
How was work?
Thanks for cleaning up.
I fixed you something,
it's in the fridge, nuke it 3 minutes.
Pull him out. This way.
I don't want to be a lifeguard.
It was my stupid idea
in the first place.
-What are you going
to do for money?
-Everyone is always
so worried about money.
-I think this is just
our gap year anyway.
-For me, it's going to be
a permanent gap. I'll never
be able to afford tuition.
-You can always get
out of town together.
-Are you serious?
-Always.
Shit...
Looking pretty rough, Marie.
- Gee, thanks.
Hi Desiree!
- Hi!
- How did you get all banged up?
- I had a little dispute
with a dancer at the club.
She wasn't sharing hertips.
-What's your degree, I still don't
get why you can't find
a better job.
- Lake, stop.
-It's not that easy, Lake.
-Woman in the nigger
of the world.
What?
Yoko Ono.
- She's right.
Anyway smartie, a gentleman
I used to know when I was
in college came into the club
the other night and offered
me a position.
- Where?
- At an assisted living facility.
- You mean an old folks home?
Who knows? If things work out,
I might even be able
to get you a job there.
- At an old folks home...
Disgusting!
You were supposed to be
finished bed pans an hour ago.
-Sorry, I got involved
in a pretty heated game
of Chinese checkers.
- It's not your job
to fraternize with patients. Anyway,
your mother wants
to see you in the office. Now.
I have to see Lake
and get back to work.
- Yeah.
Alright...
- Hi mom!
- Lake, can't you knock first?
- Mom, I didn't know you'd be
in a meeting.
- I told you not to call me
mom at work. Say hello
to Mister Nelson.
-Hello...
-Look, he got me these for
the car. Aren't they nice?
Hey, how are you getting
along at the wrinkle ranch?
- The wrinkle ranch, really?
- Oh well now son, let's...
Let's not get off on the wrong foot.
I want all the employees
here at Coup de Coeur to feel
like part of the family.
Can I go now?
Who are you?
- I'm Lake. I've been asked
to give you...
To help you clean up.
Are you ready for your
afternoon medication?
Here we go.
Oh, that's the way
it's going to be.
Okay then...
open up.
You can do this, come on.
Come on Mister Peabody, open up.
Fine... That's it. Very good.
Take the glass of water now.
I know...
Very good. Very good.
Boy, there are bed pans that
need to be sterilized.
Take your chariot
and come with me. Now!
-The clarion call
of Coup de Coeur.
Bed pans...
-I'll see you
around, M. Peabody.
-See you where ever you are.
What kind of medication
is he on?
-It's none of your business.
-It must be pretty
strong, he seems...
-M. Peabody is
a very sick old man.
Are you giving him
psychotropic drugs?
-Where did you learn that word?
In the school yard?
Boy, you don't know what
you're talking about.
Hey!
- You're new.
- Yeah.
What about you?
- I've been here a few months.
It's pretty disgusting.
Old geezers pissing all over
themselves.
-It doesn't bother me.
Let's be friends.
Sure.
And then she waved...
-Yeah, not bad.
-Well I think she's great.
-She's alright.
So tell me about the old men.
- I gave one a sponge bath.
- Was it gross?
-Not really.
Somebody has to do it.
-You're amazing.
You're always taking care of other people.
- What do you mean?
- I don't know, you're always
picking up after Marie and
you like giving old men sponge
baths.
- I didn't say I liked it.
You see what I mean?
You're such a saint.
-I'm not a saint.
Oh my God! That's blood.
- What?
- The blood of a saint.
- I'm not a saint.
- But you are.
-I'm the revolutionary
and you are the saint.
-What makes you think
you're so revolutionary?
You couldn't even
make your own list.
- Hey, are you okay?
- Oh, of course!
-Have you heard
the show tonight?
-Totally!
Oh, this is Lake.
- Hi.
- What happened to you?
- Oh actually that's nothing.
That is just a little bit
of stigmata because Lake's
an actual saint.
- Ah, that's all.
-No really, he's like
an actual saint. Saint Lake.
- Desiree?
- Okay I've got to get back
to my band.
- Okay, see you later.
It was nice to meet you.
M. Peabody!
- M. Peabody!
-Come back! M. Peabody!
What is he doing?
- Oh he's done this before.
He says he needs
to get to the ocean.
He's totally delirious.
Tada!
-This is definitely
better than your last job.
-No kidding! Naomie Klein is doing
a signing here next week
and I am in charge
of setting it up.
- She's on your list?
- I cannot believe it.
-Are you going to ask Naomie
about the cover of No Logo?
-What about it?
-It's become so iconic, it's like a logo.
I wonder how
she feels about that.
- I don't know,
ask her yourself.
Desiree, I'd like
to show you something.
- Okay.
- Are you with a customer?
-No, actually, this gentleman
found everything that he was
looking for. So...
- Excellent. I could really
use your help.
- Okay, cool.
The new Atwood? Get out!
She's on my list too.
Your list?
- Never mind.
-It's an advanced copy,
I thought you'd like it.
-I love it.
Um, Desiree, are you
busy on Friday night?
-Why? Do you want me
to pick up a shift?
-Um, no I um...
I'm asking you over for dinner.
Ah yeah.
Yeah, I'm free.
-Excellent. Great.
He's been moved to room 219.
His son called and had him
upgraded to a private room.
- His son?
Nobody told me?
- Right, next time we'll make
sure to consult you first.
What's this game called again?
It seems pretty easy.
-Beginners always say that.
It's called Gin Rummy.
- Why is it called that?
-Apparently the game's inventor
had a preference for gin.
And it became known as Movie Star Gin
in the 30's, it was
the Hollywood elite past time between
takes on movies sets
with a quick game.
- That's really interesting.
- When you've been around as long
as I have my dear, you learn
a thing or two about even
the most trivial of pursuits.
Gin.
- Do you play poker?
- I've been known to win a hand
or two. We must play sometime.
- Are you ready for your
afternoon medication?
It's time.
-We are kind
in the middle of something.
-If you would just leave
them, I promise, I'll take
them in a little while.
- It's more effective
if you take them on schedule.
- Like the trains in Germany.
- Oh you devil.
-Excuse me.
Not again M. Abernati!
-Don't worry, I'll make
sure he takes them.
-You're sure?
Alright, but don't forget.
Give me these pills.
We wouldn't want you
to have an unfair advantage.
-There's a photo in that top drawer,
would you hand it
to me, please.
Look at him. So smooth like the
cactus liked off his whiskers.
And that's me.
I was in rather good
shape don't you think?
-I guess so.
I like the way you look now.
When medication are you on?
Anaïs Nin. There's a feminist you
don't want to fuck with.
She's on my list.
-What is this list you're
always talking about?
-Private joke.
Ouh! Alice Monroe. I love
Lives of Girls and Women.
Margaret Laurence, Jest of God.
- What can I say, I love
Canadian feminist writers.
- So, can I borrow these?
-To tell you the truth,
I have a thing about lending
my books, but you're welcome
to come over anytime you want
to read.
-Seriously.
Oh wow! SCUM Manifesto.
-First edition.
I'm impressed.
But...
Now, I might have to kill you.
- Seriously?
- I'm not kidding.
Your hair is nice.
- Thank you, so is yours.
This band sounds like
The Pixies. Hut the good part
of The Pixies, Kim Deal.
Kelley is hotter.
- They're both hot.
They're on my list.
Don't be anal.
I have to pee.
Don't forget to wash your hands.
Hit me.
-Not just yet. First
we need another tip off.
I hope we have enough
for Vermouth.
- 'Muth', dear, 'muth'.
Remember just a tad.
You don't want
to bruise the gin.
Old men and gin
bruise so easily.
M. Peabody, what's
going on in there?
Are you both out of your minds?
- It was his idea.
-Great. Pick up
your shoes. Let's go.
Do you know what your mother
would say if she found out
about this?
- How will she find out?
-What am I going to do with you?
Aille, aille, aille get dressed.
Let's go.
Come on, hurry up.
Come on, come on.
I really don't know what
I'm going to do with you.
Sorry, I haven't been
around much lately.
I've been working a lot.
So have I.
Are you sure there isn't
something else?
Lake, tell me.
You know that you can talk
to me about anything.
-Are you sure about that?
I think there might
be something wrong with me.
I think I may have a...
A fetish.
You mean like leather?
- Not that bad.
I saw your sketchbook.
Is that what you're
talking about?
Those drawings?
Okay, this is like freaking
me out a little bit,
so um... I have to give the car
back to my dad. Do you want me
to drop you off?
- No, thanks. I think I'll walk.
I'm not a saint.
What's wrong with
you today, boy?
I think I broke up
with my girlfriend.
What was her name again?
- Desiree.
- Ah yes, Desiree.
-Such a poetic name,
the desired one.
Did I tell you that historically
she was the fiancée...
-Of Napoléon, yeah, you told me.
Would you like to talk about it?
-No, that's okay.
Melvin,
Do you ever think
about the future?
If you could go anywhere
in the world, where would you
want to go?
-I've always wanted to visit
the Pacific ocean again,
but maybe that's a little
too pie in the sky.
At this point, I'd settle
for some fresh air.
Hey bro.
There you go.
Okay, that's good.
Melvin?
I'm going to get
you out of here.
What did you do to him?
Lake, have
a drink. What's wrong?
-I'm talking about Melvin,
Mr. Peabody.
You and this old man...
it's just not right!
- I don't know what you're
talking about.
- You know what I'm talking
about. Everybody knows what
I'm talking about. It's disgusting.
Didn't I raise you right?
-Mom, you're drunk,
you're imagining things.
Don't lie to your mother!
Of course I'm drunk.
My son is fucking
an 80 year old man!
-Mom, what's disgusting is how
those old men are being treated.
It's like Night of the
Living Dead in that place.
-Don't make excuses
about what you're doing.
And don't walk away
while I'm talking to you.
Lake, open the door!
Lake, open the door now.
- Where are you going?
- For a drive.
-Not with my car, you're not.
Give me the keys.
Give me my goddamn keys!
-You mean these?
Mom!
I'm sorry!
Forget about those, they're
the worst car accessory.
You're taking away my dice.
I love those dice.
-We're not going to have
anything from Mr. Nelson
in the car.
Thanks Desiree.
I owe you big time.
- Is Marie okay?
- She'll live.
Okay Melvin.
- Lake, this is crazy.
-Can you help me?
His arm, his arm's on me, okay.
- The other arm, Melvin.
Come on, the other arm.
Okay.
I'm going to go and check
if we can get through.
All clear.
This doesn't really feel like breaking out.
It's too easy.
Shit...
Who was that?
- That's a saint.
Okay…
Oh... God! Okay.
You got him?
Where are you taking him?
- He said he wants to see
the Pacific ocean again
and something about a pie
in the sky.
-In this beater
you're taking him.
-I just have to get him out
of here. It's like horror
hospital in there, so...
It doesn't matter where we are.
- Are you sure that's where
you're going?
- Why else would I be doing it?
-Okay, I've been thinking about
this a lot since the last time
I saw you. What I wanted
to tell you is um...
I think that what you are doing
and what you are is really
brave.
And the fact that you're acting on it,
you know, like it's
revolutionary. All these ideas
that people have about like
aging and beauty and what makes
somebody desirable, you're
going against that.
You're fighting against nature.
And do you see how
radical that is?
And what I also wanted
to tell you is that...
If you were a girl,
You'd be on my list.
-Desiree...
-But the fucked up part is
that what you are means
that we can't be together anymore.
You know that right?
I don't know what I am.
My God, I wish we were
the ones escaping.
I'll text you.
-Okay, go.
Go.
I love you.
Hey!
Did you have any more
roommates after that?
-Here and there.
I was even married once.
If you can believe that.
- Married? To a woman?
- At the time it was the only
option. It was the 70's.
Even in the theater world,
if you weren't married after
the age of 40, there was
something wrong with you.
Were you in love with her?
- It was a kind of love.
Miraculously, we even conceived
one drunken winter's night.
Two years after our son was born,
she divorced me
and took him away to another city.
From that point on,
I was a confirmed bachelor.
Good afternoon, young lady,
I wonder if you could direct
me to the notions department.
- Notions, what's that?
-My apologies, sowing kits,
needles, threads, that sort
of thing. I'm afraid I've
lost a button on my jacket.
-Yeah, it's down isle 4,
at the end on the bottom.
-Ah, thank you. This is my grandson.
We're traveling
across the country together.
- He's your grandson?
-Yes. Although some days,
I really wish he weren't.
He's quite the locker, isn't he?
Well, I'll be right back.
You two, stay out of trouble.
-Such a cute old man.
My own grandpa's mean as a snake.
My parents put him into
some retirement home,
Sunny Valley or something.
I don't blame them though,
in his case elder abuse
would be entirely justified.
Um, I need a map of Canada.
- Sure thing.
It's cute that you're
traveling with your grandpa.
Where are you guys headed?
- We haven't really decided.
- Are you staying in Ontario?
-Yeah.
-Maybe I can help you.
When I was a kid, my family and I
used to go rent a cottage
around here. It's really pretty,
there are a lot of lakes.
- Are there a lot of people...
- Would you mind paying for this
dear boy, I left my wallet
in the car and don't forget
I'll have cigarettes.
Any brand.
One of the few advantages
of being old: invisibility.
- You're crazy.
- Am I?
-We have to start planning for the future.
Money isn't going
to hold out forever.
Sun block?
- Who knows, we might end up
in Palm Springs.
-I already told you,
I like your wrinkles.
I'm going to keep this.
If people only knew
how you treat me.
What did he want?
- That boy?
He saw the map and he wanted
to know if I needed directions.
So, we're here and we're
trying to get to... Here.
To be honest, I'm not sure
I'm up for such a long trip
so soon after Coup de Coeur.
That place really took
the vinegar out of me.
- What are you saying?
-What I'm saying is perhaps
we should rest for a few days
before pressing on.
You haven't been telling
anyone about us, have you?
-Don't be silly,
they would never understand.
-What about your son?
-I wouldn't worry about my son.
He paid for the home,
but he hasn't been
in touch for many years.
He hasn't introduced me
to my own grandchildren.
He never really got used to
the idea of having an old queen
like me for a father.
It always embarrassed him.
What were you talking
to that guy about?
- What guy?
- At the dinner.
You seemed to be talking a lot.
- I already told you, directions.
- And why were you laughing?
-I suppose I made a joke,
you know how I am.
-It must have been pretty
funny then I guess.
-What are you harping on this?
Don't tell me you're jealous.
Jealous of an old
sack of bones like me?
-Because I asked you to be careful
about what you say
to people. Learn to keep your mouth
shut in public and I don't
have to be this way.
- I'd never thought I'd live
to see the day...
-I'm going for a walk.
Are you coming?
You look very nice tonight.
- I'll have you know I was quite
the snappy dresser in my day.
Two gin and tonics, please.
- I need to see some ID, love.
Oh dear, I may have left
my wallet back in my room.
- Are you serious?
- He's 81.
-Not my rule. Everybody
has to have ID.
-Here it is.
Looks like you drinking
for free tonight.
- What do you mean?
- It's his birthday.
He's 82 years young.
- Let me see that.
Why didn't you tell me?
- I don't know, I already feel
like enough of a fossil.
I've never been one much
for celebrating birthdays.
- What about you?
- I love birthdays.
- No, man I need to see
your ID.
- Oh sorry.
I must have left it in
the car. I'll be right back.
Gin and tonic,
love, happy birthday.
I heard it's your birthday.
Cheers.
How old are you anyway?
- 75.
This is my seat.
Can you hold
this for me, please?
Fucking hell!
- That's enough!
That was supposed to be for you.
- I gathered that.
Happy birthday, Melvin.
That time of year thou
mayst in me behold,
When yellow leaves, or none,
or few, do hang upon those
boughs which shake against
the cold, bare ruined
choirs, where late
the sweet birds sang.
In me thou seest the
twilight of such day,
As after sunset fadeth in
the west, which by and by
black night doth take
away, death's second self,
that seals up all in rest.
You know, I have been thinking
about you said before and
it's not just about the sex.
I really think I'm in love
with you.
I know it sounds crazy, but...
That's how I feel.
Did you hear what I said?
Melvin?
Melvin!
Melvin...
That was a nice service.
- 5 people, including
the organist.
- Yeah, that was sad.
It's nice that his son came.
- I thought Marie was going
to start making out with
him in front of the casket.
- I love Marie.
- You know, if those two get
together, that kind of makes
Melvin my grandfather.
I mean retroactively.
So you're okay?
-I guess so.
Oh, I forgot.
Revolutionary...
- I got you one too.
- What?
- Okay.
No... Desiree.
I love it.
- It's perfect.
I'll text you, okay?
- Okay.
Bye.
- Bye.
Hi!
I'm Lake.
-Hi young man!
- Are you here everyday?
- Most week days.
-Maybe I'll see you around.