A typical English
New Year's Eve party.
Come, everybody,
join hands.
It is an old English custom.
♪ Should old acquaintance
be forgotten? ♪
Adios, Presidente.
Adios, Hernandez.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Ladies and gentlemen,
may I have your attention
for a minute please?
In 10 minutes time
we should be welcoming...
Large whiskey, please.
We should be welcoming
in the New Year,
but before we start to
make our good resolution--
As I said, before we start
making our good resolutions,
may I as your host
and as managing director
of Napier's International
Plantations,
known to you all
affectionately as NIP--
Hear, NIP.
Known to you all
affectionately as NIP,
may I say how glad I am
to see you all here tonight?
And to our friends
in whose country
we are, I hope,
welcome guests
and in particular
to Senor Hernandez,
who has taken time off
from his ministerial duties
to be with us tonight,
our best wishes
for the continued
peace and prosperity
of this happy
and hospitable
corner of the world.
Very good, HB. There.
Well, I think it's about time
we got ready for
Auld Lang Syne.
We shall have
to have two circles,
one in this room
and one in the other room.
And you'll help me round up
the stragglers, won't you,
Mrs. Bastian?
Leave it to me, HB. We'll
have to make two circles.
If everyone in there
will take that corner.
Herbert, you go and look
after that circle.
And everyone here will
go into the other room,
we make another...
Ah, Mrs. Jordan, I'm sure
you wouldn't mind helping
my husband over there.
No, with pleasure.
And I'll help HB.
Come along,
Senor Hernandez.
Now please
excuse me, Mr. Bryant,
I may have to leave.
I'm expecting a call.
But this will only
take about a minute.
Ah, then it is not a religious
ceremony, like cricket.
Oh, no, nothing
of the kind.
No, it's just
an old English custom.
It's no good, senor.
No good at all.
You're on the property
of Napier's International
Plantations,
known to us all
affectionately as NIP.
And when boss Bryant orders
you into the chain gang,
into the chain gang you go.
And I have job
for Charlie.
Please, please.
Here we are into
the magic circle.
Not this one, dear.
You promised to help
Mr. Bastian, remember?
Oh, oh, oh, of course.
Come on, Tom.
Come on in, Mrs. Jordan.
That's it.
By the way, the wife
and I were hoping
that you and Mr. J could
come and take pot luck
with us tomorrow night.
HB is coming,
but it's quite informal.
Oh, I'm sure we'd love to,
wouldn't we, Tom?
You're all ready,
Bastian?
Yes, HB.
All together,
everyone.
Wait for it.
There's a couple
of minutes to go yet.
Tom...
Happy New Year.
Oh, Mrs. Jordan,
a Happy New Year to you.
Happy New Year.
And you, too, Bryant.
And you needn't
bother to kiss me.
Something might
fly out of that...
Happy New Year to you.
You, too, sir,
Mr. Hernandez.
Thank you.
By the way, what are you?
Excuse me?
In the government.
I mean, mines? Fuel?
Agriculture and fisheries?
I see.
No, I'm afraid mine is a more
humble position, Mr. Jordan.
I am justice.
Adios, Rivera.
Viva Zoreno!
You know, it's extraordinary
how well you speak French.
It is not strange.
I studied in Paris
at the Sorbonne.
Ah!
Well, that explains it.
Merci, madame.
Excuse me, Mr. Bryant,
I find I must leave you now.
So soon?
Yes, it is sooner
than I expected.
I'm sorry.
Goodnight, Mrs. Jordan.
Goodnight.
I hope we may meet again soon,
at the opera perhaps.
Oh, I hope so.
Goodnight.
Do let me show
you to the door.
Please don't bother.
Goodnight, Mr. Bryant.
Goodnight
and a Happy New Year.
Viva Rivera.
Viva Zoreno!
Personally I find
him charming.
Oh, do you know, Tom,
that he speaks French
almost as well as English?
Mm-hmm, he does.
Napier's should appoint you,
Mrs. Jordan,
as public relations
officer.
Yes, you'd make a splendid
plantation hostess,
one of Bryant's nippies.
Oh, what an excellent
idea, Tom.
Now when can I start,
Mr. Bryant?
And what will be
your terms?
I never talk business
at parties, Mrs. Jordan,
and never
with beautiful women.
Aw.
Really?
Extraordinary.
Now I should've thought--
That it was a marvelous
opportunity.
I quite agree, Tom.
Now, Mr. Bryant,
you can't get out of this.
Let's talk it over while
we dance, shall we?
Delighted.
I'm so glad you don't
mind my husband's
rather schoolboy
sense of humor.
Oh, I know some people do,
especially rather
pompous people, you know.
On the contrary,
I find him rather...
refreshing.
I'm so sorry
that's over so quickly.
Tell me what part
of France are you from?
Medoc.
Oh, the wine country.
Yes, my father
had a vineyard.
As big as one
of our plantations?
Oh, I expect it is
quite small really,
but it used to seem big to me,
as big as the whole country.
And you, of course,
was his princess.
And then one day, a rather
beaten-up representative
of the London suburban
wine company
came down the drive
with dust on his shoes
and his suitcase full of empty
bottles and dirty shirts--
And they lived happily
ever afterwards.
In a manner of speaking.
Well, it's getting
frightfully late, Tom.
I think we ought
to go home.
Let's.
Well, thank you so much.
It's been such a lovely party.
So glad you enjoyed it.
Oh, yes, I did.
Let me show you around
Napier's one of these days.
Oh, I should love it.
Mr. Bryant goes out
of his way to keep
the staff happy and the wives,
particularly the wives.
Tom, you are wicked.
When you've been out here
as long as I have, Jordan,
you may learn to mix
with our little community.
What the hell
do you think I am?
A new boy,
comparatively speaking.
Three months,
still in his first term, huh?
Waiting for you to teach me
the nicknames
of all the masters,
and what they call
the lavatories
in six form B.
Well, I know what the peasants
call you anyway.
Come on, let's get some air.
Goodnight.
Thank you
for the lovely party.
What's the matter?
Go on, tell me,
what's the matter?
Oh, I know, I behaved
badly at the party.
But I always behave
badly at parties.
What about that party?
That wine tasting party
your father gave, remember?
When I said I thought
the 1953 vintage
reminded me of a rather
vivacious little cup of tea
that I found in the cafe
on the North Circular Road,
remember?
You laughed at that once.
It was a long time ago.
Tom.
Tom, coming to bed?
Coming to bed?
Tom...
it's a new year.
So they told us
at the party.
And what's this,
the thaw?
Oh, be different please.
Try.
Different?
What do you mean
"different"?
Stop being a child.
What do you want me to be?
Grown-up and mature
like Bryant
and all those idiots
with their funny hats.
Oh, God, it's starting again.
What are you smoking
for anyway?
Oh, do you mind?
I thought
if you had anything
interesting to say,
I'd keep awake and listen.
What do you want me to say?
Just how you think we're going
to go on living together,
that's all.
If you can't live with me,
that's your problem.
Oh, yes.
Oh, yes, it's always
my problem.
What were you
doing when we met?
Buying wine for a firm
that went broke.
Married to a woman who never
cared what happened to you.
Oh, Gwen.
Tch.
What a ridiculous name.
At least she liked me
just as I was.
Hmm.
With the boyish charm.
Well, that's wearing
a bit thin now
if you want to know the truth.
And I'll tell you the truth.
You always wanted me
different, didn't you?
You always wanted
to change me.
Well, I didn't succeed.
In making a man of me?
Huh, you sound like some
ridiculous headmaster.
Oh, it's not funny when you
say those things anymore,
and it's not funny
when you're rude at parties.
Now, look, I can be rude
to who I like, you understand?
I'm free.
As far as being rude
is concerned,
I'm absolutely free.
No!
You've got a job to look after
and a marriage, remember?
You make marriage sound
like some bloody awful
purchase agreement.
Pay up for 50 years,
it's yours when you die.
Oh! How can you say that
when I came with you,
when you didn't even have
a job or money or anything?
I came to that dreary hotel
to provide the evidence,
and the rooms we lived
in while you change jobs
and saved up to pay
for the cost of the divorce.
Nobody forced you.
Well, I did it because
you were human
and you were funny
and you were alive.
Not just angry
with people for no reason
and hopeless for no reason
and never doing anything
that makes any sense.
We just can't go on.
We can't go on.
We could go on if you
just be a wife.
A wife?
How could I be more
of a wife?
Well, you can hate the same
people I hate for a start.
And then you can stay at home
and bath the children, maybe.
Do what?
Bath the children,
if you'd ever had any.
You see I'm trying to sleep.
I am sorry, darling.
Well, it's too late.
Good morning, Gabriel.
Senor.
You wish I to stay here.
Yes, of course.
You will give me protection.
Gabriel, please,
this is not my day.
What are you talking about?
You had the guns
last night.
When people hear that,
they go into the hills.
My cousin
is on his way there,
but if he could
stay here 2, 3 days.
He can sleep in kitchen.
He's very good cook.
And another advantage,
he plays guitar.
All right.
Thank you, senor.
Thank you.
What is all this about anyway?
We have a new president.
Oh, congratulation.
What's his name,
the new president?
General Zoreno.
Well, viva Zoreno.
Viva Zoreno
Viva Rivera.
Good morning.
Hello.
Where is everybody?
All our workers disappear
into their holes
as soon as there's
any trouble.
They'll be back
in a few days.
In the meantime, we got
a new face to look at.
Zoreno's?
Yes.
I've arranged for photograph
of him to be laid off.
Do we have to?
Just a little courtesy.
Napier's would like
us to extend it.
To the new man in power.
Exactly.
Is it over?
Bar the shooting?
Is there going to be
much more of that?
I understand that Rivera
has made a run for it.
I heard it on the radio.
I expect they'll have
caught him by now.
There will be a trial,
of course, in the sports arena.
2,000 votes to none in favor
of the extreme penalty.
They always send their disused
presidents to the sports arena.
You made it sound
very quaint.
I'm sorry.
There's a lot to
be said for Rivera,
provided we stick
to theory, of course.
Abolishing the death penalty.
Freeing the press.
Granting the vote
to a lot of Indians
who could neither
read nor write.
And then what happens?
The army takes over.
By the way, I see your friend
Hernandez is with Zoreno.
Still minister of justice.
I always thought
he was intelligent.
You better
take one of these.
What's that for?
Flag for your car.
You may find it useful
if there's any in trouble.
What am I supposed
to do then?
Salute and sing
"Abide with me?"
You know, I wish you
wouldn't make jokes.
It'd be far better
for your career with Napier's
if you were to stop
making jokes.
Jokes?
On my way here this morning,
I saw a man.
He was running beside
the car with his face
all dabbed with
paint like a clown.
He kept on sort of clawing
at the window
and then he screamed
something I didn't understand.
Well?
They shot him.
You could have done nothing.
I could have stopped.
Just as well for you
that you didn't.
Why?
Because Napier's
might have got in wrong
with the new powers.
You won't believe me, Jordan,
but I was thinking of you.
Here you are, doctor.
Thanks.
Beautiful, isn't it?
You know, you're
the only Napier's wife
that'd buy these things.
Go into the other houses
and what do you get?
Plaster galleons
in full sail.
Why do you want to see me?
I'm pregnant.
Well, congratulations
to you both.
But Tom doesn't know.
I wanted
to tell him that...
Oh, surely, that's
the wife's privilege.
Oh, no, no, no,
not about the baby.
I wanted to tell him
that I'm going home.
Why?
Say that the climate
doesn't suit me.
Tell him I can't stay
for medical reasons.
Tell him that...
Oh, you know what to say.
What's the real reason?
I'm tired.
I'm sick of smiling
and pretending
that all his sneers and insults
are just school boy jokes
I love to laugh at.
Last night he...
Yeah?
Last night he said
that it was my fault
we didn't have any children.
Well, there's no reason
why you shouldn't have
a perfectly healthy baby
if you take care of yourself.
I've had two miscarriages.
Each time we'd be moving.
Leaving a job that
isn't grand enough
for his great,
big personality.
Well, please,
will you tell him, doctor?
That's Tom.
Well, he's early,
isn't it?
I can't think what has
happened unless...
Unless what?
Oh, nothing.
I'll leave you two together.
You tell him,
please, doctor.
Hello, doctor?
Anybody ill?
No, I was passing.
You're home early.
Oh, plantation
is all deserted.
So I drove through the town.
Been a little rough
there I understand.
You could call it that.
They don't last, you know.
Never last very long.
But there are times out here
when you have to look
in the opposite direction.
God, what a country!
Suits me.
Of course, it doesn't
suit everyone.
Your wife for instance.
What's the matter?
Is Claire ill?
Nothing, nothing
to worry about.
But may I speak
to you as man to man?
You know, the way
it strikes me I--
Is it a go?
Yes, like a bomb.
But talking of Claire,
I hope you won't think
that I'm trying
to interfere.
I know it's none
of my business.
It isn't really, is it?
Thanks for calling.
Who's that?
Goodbye, Mr. Jordan.
Who's it?
Rivera.
Riv...
He's hurt.
Shut up!
You haven't seen anything.
Get inside the house.
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna get him
off your front yard.
Why?
Where to?
Just as far as those trees.
I'll dump him over there.
Dump him?
You can't do that.
Then what do you suggest?
Well, take him in
the house, of course.
You want us all shot?
Right, you do that, you go,
and I'll call the police
and tell them that
he was in your car.
You don't understand
this place.
You're a doctor,
aren't you?
I'm not a suicidal idiot!
Shut up.
You give me a hand.
Get him out this side.
Easy now.
Amigos?
Amigos.
I'll take his legs.
Easy now.
Well?
Lost a lot of blood.
I give him about 24 hours.
That shot will kill him?
I'm thinking of the next
one he's due to receive.
Who's that?
You can trust him.
Can't trust anyone,
if you want to stay alive.
Personally I do.
You may have your own private
reasons for giving it all up.
I still find
life really bearable.
Just a minute.
Can he be moved?
For the sake
of your health,
get him out of here
as soon as you can.
What about his?
He needs rest.
I've done all I can.
And-- And don't forget,
if anyone asks, I wasn't here.
I didn't notice you anyway.
Feeling better?
Your house?
You have been very kind.
I will not trouble
you any longer.
Stay there.
Gabriel?
Gabriel, now,
I want you to lend
some of your clothes
to the president.
It is an honor, senor.
And then tell your cousin
to get something together
for us to eat. Anything
that's in the kitchen.
Pack it up and put it
in the back of the van.
Yes, senor.
Where do you think
you're going?
To the frontier.
That's 100 kilometers.
98.
I will hide in your
garden till night
where I was till
I heard the trucks.
I thought it will be
safe in the doctor's car.
Must have fainted
or something.
Very inconsiderate of me.
Should I be caught,
no one here has seen me, Mr...
Jordan.
And you're not
going to get caught.
I'm gonna hide you
where you're safe,
near the frontier.
And then when you feel more
like it, you can cross.
You must feel strongly
about politics.
Then why are you doing this?
I haven't thought yet.
Gabriel, help the president
get dressed
and then burn his clothes.
Everything that's his.
Yes, senor.
Tom?
And, Gabriel, be as quick
as you can, too.
Oh, darling, I may go
back to Napier's again.
There's no use arguing.
Something came up.
It's rather important,
it shouldn't take too long.
I'll be as quick as I can,
and I'll be back--
Tom, aren't you going
to say anything?
Aren't we going
to talk about it?
Senor, he is ready.
Good.
Help him into the car,
would you, please?
Darling, listen, nothing
that should concern you.
What?
What needn't concern me?
Who is that man?
What's been happening?
There's nothing
for you to worry about.
We found a man outside
and he's badly hurt.
So I'm gonna take him
somewhere where he can rest.
Oh. Where?
To Napier's.
To the country club.
It's closed but--
Oh, does he work
for Napier's?
No, he's going to
be sort of a guest.
Not that he's been
invited yet, but...
Well, I think it's better
to call the hospital.
No, don't do that.
Tribulacion?
I'm taking him to the club.
As a matter of fact,
I'll be doing him a favor.
They'll have a chance
to show their hospitality
to a genuine native.
He'll be able
to sit at the pool
and sleep in that
bed that Mr. Bryant
uses for his weekend
adventures.
Then when he feels
a little bit better,
he can have a nice
old English game of darts
all by himself in the
old English bar parlor.
If only you could be
serious for 5 minutes.
Try me when I get back.
I'm never serious
till after dinner.
I won't be here.
What do you mean?
I was going anyway.
I asked Dr. Swann
to tell you.
I thought you'd come in
and we could talk sensibly.
I thought we could be
quiet until I went home.
Senor?
All right, Gabriel.
Darling, look, I'll be back.
I'll be back
and then we'll talk.
Oh, Tom!
Tom, I've got to talk to you.
You must listen to someone
else for once in your life.
Look, darling, this evening
we'll go to the Bastian's
and afterwards we'll talk.
You'll see, everything's
gonna be perfectly normal.
Just as if nothing
had happened.
There we are.
Don't drink all the beer
before we get there.
We'll celebrate after that.
Give me the cover.
Right.
Just pop underneath that.
And by the way,
you better have a signal
in case I want you to
keep your head down,
so I'll whistle at you, huh?
What-- What tune?
Oh.
Pop goes the weasel.
Got it? Don't worry.
Everything's gonna
be all right.
Right.
Fasten your seatbelts.
Cosmopolitan Hotel?
Reception please.
Hello, this is Mrs. Jordan,
Claire Jordan.
I would like to be on
the flight to Paris tomorrow.
Pase?
Oh, pass.
Look, I'm English.
You saw the flag.
Pase?
I have an appointment
at Napier's rest house.
Urgent business.
Pase?
Look, I'm just going
over the other side.
It's about 5 or 6 kilometers,
I'll be back in half an hour.
Pase!
Sergeant, this man
is asking me for a pass.
I have my...
I got my international...
international driver's
license.
Will that be all right?
Is this you?
Yes. You know these
passport pictures.
No one can cross the river,
senor, without a pass.
Look, I have an important
appointment, I'm late.
It's government business.
You must go to
the ayuntamiento, senor.
To the town hall?
Si, senor.
Can I get a pass there?
It's posible, senor.
Pase?
Colonel Hernandez,
have you a statement?
And, colonel,
what about Rivera?
Have you got him?
The date of his trial
has already been arranged.
Naturally we expect
him to be present.
Colonel-- Colonel Hernandez,
we met last night.
Do you remember me?
I remember you, Mr. Jordan.
Perhaps you can help me.
Perhaps.
Well, I was trying to get
a pass to cross the river.
Why?
I have an appointment
at Napier's rest house.
Ah!
Important business
at the nets perhaps.
Whatever happens,
the English must not miss
their games of catch.
Well as a matter of fact,
you guessed it.
Is that your business
appointment?
Yes, next week is our big match
with non-ferrous metals.
I mean, you mustn't expect
your revolution to
interfere with that.
After all, that's
the most important
event of the year for us.
What a dull year you
must have, Mr. Jordan.
I don't suppose
you'll make anything
so serious as trouble.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
There. Nombre.
Jordan.
Here we are.
Bueno.
Good. Thank you.
Momento, senor.
We must look.
Oh, they looked
at the town hall.
It does not say
so on the pass, senor.
Oh, they probably forgot.
Open please the back.
It's locked.
Give me the keys, senor.
I've lost them.
Look, when I was--
Open please the back.
You have no authority
to look.
Open the back!
Look, I'm British.
I mean, I was checked
at the town hall.
From the Hotel Cosmopolitan?
Senora Jordan?
Oh, yes.
We wish to speak
with your husband.
I'm afraid he's not here.
We will wait.
But I'm just going out.
No, senora.
I think you're wrong there.
Where are we?
Just across the river
from my house.
You can see it.
In that house?
I brought some
people we know.
They have a boat.
I'll go and try
and get my wife out.
If she's still there.
Does she know about me?
No.
Do you think it
might help her?
But with Zoreno,
I'm afraid.
All right.
Take my watch.
If I'm not back
in half an hour,
leave the car
and you're on your own.
Thank you, Mr. Jordan.
Herbert!
Look, you're not
even dressed yet.
They'll be here
at any minute.
For goodness sake,
go, get dressed.
Ah.
I'm so sorry to be late.
That's all right.
The Jordans aren't here yet.
Oh, really?
He didn't even
phone like you.
He lacks your polish.
You have such wonderful
manners, Hugo.
Come in, HB.
Hello.
Come and have a little
something for your cough, eh?
We must go see about the meats.
It's too bad of the Jordans.
Senor.
They're here.
Police?
Soldiers with the senora.
Your husband
went to work this morning.
Then what happened?
Come, Mrs. Jordan.
There is a limit
to our patience.
Mrs. Jordan,
do not try to put us off.
Did your husband
not drive his car?
Good evening.
Hello, darling.
Well, look at all that ash.
Filthy smoking habits.
Mr. Jordan.
Yes?
We have been waiting
for you, Mr. Jordan.
Good, because I wish
to lodge a complaint.
A complaint?
At Tribulacion at the bridge,
some of your undisciplined
soldiers fired on my car.
I can only imagine
they were drunk.
You did not stop.
We had a report
from Tribulacion.
Of course, I didn't stop
for those trigger-happy idiots.
What'd you expect me to do?
Stay and get shot?
May even happen,
this, Mr. Jordan.
There was someone
with you, wasn't there?
I saw him leave,
there was no one.
Look, there's
a perfectly good ashtray.
Will you mind?
Did you or not have
a passenger?
Answer us.
Yes, I did.
A strange sort of passenger
that lies on a floor,
hidden under a cloth?
I thought that was
rather eccentric myself.
But then a solution
occurred to me.
I don't think he wanted
me to know he was there.
You did not know.
Perhaps he crawled into the
van when it was in the garage.
Maybe he wanted a free lift,
some tramp rather.
It's very amusing.
Oh, it's true,
they're always doing it.
Tramps, women,
children, chickens,
always crawling into cars.
You'd think they
want to live there.
Maybe it's the housing shortage
in your beautiful country.
Well, are you satisfied,
gentlemen?
Not quite, Mr. Jordan.
Where is your car now?
In the garage, of course.
I didn't hear you drive up.
Maybe because you
were shouting so much.
Now are you satisfied?
One more thing.
You have another
more thing to tell us.
What's that?
Where is your passenger?
He's still asleep I expect.
Do you want to see him?
No need
for you to come, darling.
Oh, I'd like some air.
Open quickly.
Quickly.
What are you laughing about?
Oh, it's marvelous,
isn't it?
I mean, you've
gotten thrown out
of some strange places
at quick notice,
but you've never done
anything like this before.
I try to keep you out of it.
Oh, that's right.
Tom Jordan, the lone hero,
with complete disregard
for his own safety.
He snatched his wife
from a nice clean bedroom
and saved a sick man
from going to hospital.
The regiment is proud of you.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh, but let's be
sensible, Tom.
We'll go straight
back to Tribulacion.
I'll go and see
Colonel Hernandez,
and I'll explain
everything to him.
Thank goodness,
he's civilized.
I think you're gonna
miss your nice little laugh
with Colonel Hernandez.
Why?
Because we're going
to Los Indos River
which is about 30 miles
further on.
We'll cross that somehow,
and then we'll walk
to the frontier.
Oh, I see.
Carrying a wounded man
with us, I suppose.
Yes, if he can't walk.
But I can walk, Mr. Jordan,
if you would stop the car.
I owe you so much.
Please spare me the pain
of causing unpleasantness
between you and your wife.
You don't, and I'm not
going to stop the car.
Mr. Jordan, please.
Look, it won't save
us to drop you,
you said that yourself.
Yes, but you would travel
light, much lighter.
Who are you?
Oh, forgive my manners,
Mrs. Jordan,
I should have
introduced myself.
Pedro Rivera.
Who?
Pedro Rivera, I am, I think,
president of the Republic,
I doubt if there was
time for an election.
That was quite delicious.
Oh, the wife manages
the fancy stuff, all right.
It's the boiled egg
we can't cook well, can we?
Herbert.
It's not the egg
itself so much.
It's the time that seems
to be at fault.
Really?
Herbert!
It's either pure water
or of a rock like consistency.
Herbert, Mr. Bryant
isn't interested in eggs.
Yeah, there's a simple
device on the market
for checking the time of eggs.
Ah, now that must
be the Jordans.
I hope he isn't tight.
Oh, good evening,
colonel.
Mr. Bryant, I am looking
for one of your employees,
Jordan. Where is he?
Well, that's what
we'd like to know.
What's Jordan been doing?
Some ridiculous joke?
I believe it's serious
to help a traitor escape.
What?
A man was found
hiding in Jordan's car.
Well, if he was found...
Jordan drove off with him as
he was about to be arrested.
We wish to find
this enemy of the state.
Who is he?
Our ex-president.
Rivera?
Yes.
I bet you were member
of his government
when we last met, of course.
I was justice, Mr. Bryant.
And justice does not change
with governments.
I believe that is true
even in England.
So Mr. and Mrs. Jordan
are expected here.
Quite a coincidence.
Yes, but they
haven't come.
We shall see.
Is there no longer
enough adventure
for you in the manufacture
of sugar, Mr. Bryant?
Lopez.
Hey, colonel,
what's the game?
In England I believe
you call it hide and seek.
You knew who he was,
of course.
Swann told me.
The president.
Does it make any difference?
Well, you could have told me.
I'm not a child, you know.
Oh, but no, everything
has to be so secret.
You have to do everything
on your own.
Oh, for God's sake, I let
one man get killed today,
isn't that enough?
Besides...
What?
Oh, nothing.
I need to find
a place to cross.
Mrs. Jordan.
Yes?
Mrs. Jordan, your husband
was worried about your safety.
It would have been dangerous
for you to know who I was.
Look, if you expect
anyone to be reasonable...
I don't.
I only hope we can all stay
together for a short time,
of course.
Operator.
Operator, you cut me
off three times already.
What's happened?
It seems a car has been hidden
in your bushes, Mr. Bastian.
A car?
Mr. Bryant, you still say
you know nothing
of Jordan's movements?
There are people
on the other side.
They couldn't have
got here already.
Could they?
Oh, look, a fire.
What would really happen
if they caught us?
They're not going
to catch us.
Farm workers
on their way to the hills.
All right, then we'll cross
as soon as it gets light.
Only if they've gone.
Wouldn't it be safe
with them?
I'll not be safe
if I was seen by anyone,
Mrs. Jordan,
anyone at all.
Let's eat.
It's still
New Year's Day.
Yes, it is.
A year ago today I was advised
to have General Zoreno shot.
You should
have listened.
Of course, if we were
the Swiss Family Robinson,
I would find
the dry martini tree
and we'd all have
a nice stiff cocktail.
Well, when in doubt
have a picnic.
What a sad song.
Cheese.
On the contrary,
it is a song of happiness.
But don't they care
what's happening?
They have seen
too many changes.
When I was a child,
I worked at one
of those farms.
I had to wait
on the great landlord.
Wherever he went all day,
I have to stand
beside him
with a tall glass
filled with ice.
One night I woke up,
the dogs were barking.
A man had stolen something
from the big landlord
and he had him half
buried in the ground
and the horses
rode over him.
They woke us up
and made us watch
so we would learn
from his mistake.
I grew up and I went away
and studied, studied.
And when I came back,
the dogs barked again.
That same landlord,
he was planted
in the ground
and the horses
rode over him.
All that studying to make
the dogs bark again.
You know, different dogs,
of course, this time.
But you had
no part of that?
What do you want,
Mr. Jordan?
A good reason
for saving my life?
Wake up, you don't
have to swim.
I was dreaming
about the room
I booked last night
at the Cosmopolitan.
Single and with bath.
What did you say?
I said you
don't have to swim.
The great river just about
comes up to my knees,
and it's firm
gravel underneath.
So we can
drive across.
What the hell
are you doing?
He saw us.
All right!
It was a mistake.
We should have
silenced the boy.
He saw us.
If you want to come
with us get in the car.
Come on.
We got to get out
of here quick.
I'll open the back.
Mr. Jordan.
Tom.
That's my leg, Tom.
One bar of chocolate
and a corkscrew
and no bottles
to open.
Well, at least
they were worth saving.
You are very angry
with me, Mr. Jordan.
I was only trying
to help.
Trying to help?
Not for myself,
please understand.
There are men, women,
and children there
who will be shot
unless I can get out for help.
And you, Mrs. Jordan,
and your husband,
what is one boy
against so many?
Perhaps it's true.
Now if you think that's true,
why are we doing all this?
Please, let us
forget about the boy.
It's not so bad,
Mrs. Jordan.
In those hills not very far,
there's a village, San Pablo.
People there are still
my friends I think.
They would help us
if we could reach them.
Oh, Tom,
he looks bad.
He's alive,
isn't he?
He's breathing.
What else
does he expect?
Let's go.
Come on.
Mr. Jordan,
your watch.
I've even lost
your watch for you.
Save your breath
for the mountains.
Come on now.
We shall certainly
catch them.
Napier should
have financed
the fatherland party,
Mr. Bryant.
Not Rivera's escape.
But we did not
do either.
No.
I'm afraid
we won't believe that,
unless it's proved
at Rivera's trial.
And if it isn't?
Napier's Plantation
will be taken over
for the benefit
of the people.
But we've given your people
work, money, hospitals,
and we've never
indulged in politics.
Then you'd better
start indulging now
on the winning side
for a change.
They must be trying to cross
the frontier to Bareya.
You see, we know
they crossed the river.
A boy was given a present,
a watch with the initials TJ,
Tom Jordan, perhaps?
They came from here,
San Pablo.
No doubt
he helped them.
The people there
are very backward.
Of course, they may
not have heard
the good news
of our revolution.
I think we shall have
to announce it to them
in a way they
can understand.
Alto!
Mama!
That...
That is San Pablo.
Are they looking
for us?
Get in there.
Come on.
Do you think
they saw us?
I hope not.
Do not be too worried,
Mrs. Jordan.
We are not so far
from the frontier.
Well,
about that village?
Can't we go there?
We could, but...
I'm afraid we might
bring them trouble.
Thank you.
Are you very tired?
Can't be far now.
Can't it?
What are you
thinking about?
How long we can live
on a bar of chocolate?
We'll have plenty left
for tomorrow.
Tom, why can't we
go to that village?
I could go.
I mean I don't think
anyone will recognize me.
I mean nobody
could recognize me now.
I could get food.
I can speak enough Spanish.
I mean why not?
Because it will be
dangerous, that's why.
Oh, Tom.
Oh, you won't
ever listen.
Well, I'm sorry.
Don't.
Don't what?
Apologize.
I know it went all wrong
after that party.
It seems
so long ago.
No, Tom, no.
I'm sorry but I really
don't feel like it.
I thought it might
be comforting.
It'll be more comforting
if you could find us
some food and water,
or even a bed.
Oh, Lord,
I'm hungry.
All right, then,
let's go to sleep.
Let's just go to sleep.
Oh, no.
Oh, no, I just
want some food.
Oh, just some food.
You bloody
little fool!
Mr. Jordan.
Mr. Jordan,
please...
I must rest.
I remember once when
my son was a little boy,
I took him
to a fiesta.
Hundreds of Indians
came to town,
galloping on horses
and my little boy
let go off my hand
and ran out among
those great hooves.
I called him to return,
but he would not come.
I was sure
he would be killed.
The horses passed,
and there was my little boy
alive and well.
I ran over to him
and I struck him hard.
It was out
of great relief and love,
but my little boy
could not understand that.
It's gonna rain.
Of course.
What do you mean
"of course"?
This is the temple of the god
of rain and fertility.
We shall have
a feast in his honor.
Mexican enchilada,
roast beef
with Yorkshire pudding.
Mine.
Where's mine?
You're busy eating it.
He's eating
my chocolate.
He's eating my chocolate!
That's mean,
that's disgusting!
That little piece of chocolate
and now he's eating it!
I've been thinking
about it all day,
that little piece of chocolate
and now he's eating it.
Please,
Mrs. Jordan.
Darling,
this is your piece.
Look at the rain,
it's like England.
You remember when
we first arrived in England,
and you were expecting to find
a country full of green lawns
and stately homes and tall
titled men in tweed suits,
making witty remarks and
eating cucumber sandwiches.
Hmm.
You remember
the first few weeks all we did
was sit in the railway hotel
and watch the rain,
pouring down
on Pennington station
and not a lord
came near us.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
That's all right.
I didn't know
what happened.
That's all right.
It was awful.
Tom?
I see a cactus.
I found something
to eat.
No, Mrs. Jordan,
you first.
Oh, no, no.
You eat it first,
please.
You are always
so kind.
Are we
anywhere near yet?
That is Bareya.
You would cross
is the frontier.
We always used
to argue about it.
I'll go down when
it gets dark, take a look.
Your husband does not
approve of me, Mrs. Jordan,
since the matter
of the boy.
No, he doesn't.
He's a very pure man.
Or shall I say,
a man of high ideals?
Tom?
Is he pure?
For him things have to
be either right or wrong.
If they are a little mixed,
he is disgusted, he gets sick.
He saw the good
in revolution,
but difficult to work
within the cabinet.
Did you hear
anything?
Women and prime ministers
have to be a little complicated
to survive,
isn't that right?
But, you know,
men like your husband,
they are better
than us.
It's well guarded,
but we can do it
now it's dark.
Let's spread out in the woods,
very thick all around.
So we've done it.
We saved you.
Why, Mr. Jordan?
That I cannot
understand.
Just a small
private feeling.
They are-- They are
nice, those feelings,
but they never
stay private.
I'm a politician,
understand.
In the end I may do worse
for you than losing your job
or your home
or even your watch.
Like what?
I may confuse you,
Mr. Jordan.
We've been waiting
for you, Mr. Jordan.
What did he say?
He says now we've found him,
that's all we wanted
and now we should
let you go.
Those are not
my orders.
What are
your orders?
To bring you to the justice
of the people, all of you.
A nice public trial
in the sports arena?
You will be
allowed a trial.
Can you guess
the verdict?
Naturally the verdict
is well known.
You mean,
we'll be shot?
So why the hell
didn't you say so?
Oh, I can't wait
to hear the prosecutor.
When's
the tumbler due?
The what?
The track-- the transport
to take us back.
It's waiting
on the main road.
We're going
to leave now.
Just a minute.
What about my wife?
Your wife?
She's been traveling
for 2 days without any food.
A peasant might treat
a woman like that.
A peasant?
Yes, a stupid,
brutal peasant.
Senora,
my name is Gomez.
My family has a fine tradition
of courtesy to women.
All right.
So your mother's a woman.
Now ask my wife
if she's tired.
I was about
to do so.
There's no need
for a foreigner to remind me.
Are you tired,
senora?
I'm pregnant.
If you wish
to stay here the night,
we will take turns
to guard you.
Thank you.
Yes, Mr. Bryant, Rivera has
been caught where I expected,
here, at the frontier
to Bareya.
Congratulations, and thank you
for letting me know so soon.
That's a splendid news.
For us, yes.
But not for you,
Mr. Bryant.
What do you mean?
Rivera had
two companions.
Wait till I see
that fool Jordan.
You will see him
very soon.
Meanwhile you will
have to wait here.
But I'm so sorry, I have
a rather important--
I said here.
What made you think
of that story?
What?
About being pregnant.
It's true.
Wake up Rivera.
What?
Wake him up, and get ready
to make a run for it.
I just wanted
to thank you
for being
so kind to my wife.
There aren't many people
under the circumstance
who'd be
so understanding.
That's all right.
How is your wife?
Is she resting well?
Oh, yes, thank you.
As well
as can be expected.
You mustn't think I don't
understand family matters.
I'm married, too,
you know.
You are?
Yes.
My own wife gave me
a boy just 3 months ago.
Would you be interested
to see a picture I've got?
I'd love to.
I've got it here
in my wallet.
Wife and baby
together.
Where is it?
Oh, here it is.
He has a fine
loud voice.
We believe he's been
destined for the opera.
Basso profondo,
Ah, good.
The cup that cheers, no?
Tell me, you find our
people good workers?
First rate. Of course,
we give them plenty
of responsibility.
But we make absolutely
no distinction
between the British
and the...
Natives?
Well, of course, we don't
actually call them that.
Why not? We call you
extranos, outsiders.
And which
of the natives
would you trust most
to run the plantation?
Let me see.
Well, I've got
a lot of time
for my assistant,
Rafael Trujo.
Sometimes I think
he knows more
about the job
than I do myself.
Rafael Trujo.
Good.
I must make
a note of that name.
I'm afraid you're
going to find England
rather cold
after this, Mr. Bryant.
One must be aware
of sudden change of climate.
They've escaped.
No doubt they would have
crossed the frontier by now.
Jordan killed
one of my men.
As his chief,
I'm holding you responsible.
But you can't do that,
I'm a British subject.
Whoever you are,
you can be tried as
an accessory to a murder.
But how do you know
it's Jordan?
It might be Rivera.
Rivera?
That failed man.
Rivera...
Mr. Bryant.
Please sit down.
I might give you
and Napier's one last chance.
Please.
I want evidence from Jordan
that Rivera killed my man.
I want it clear,
do you understand?
No doubts about it.
I want the world to know
that the poor old refugee
is a common criminal,
stabs a young man in the dark,
tries to kill a child.
That poor child,
a terrible story, Mr. Bryant.
Then they'll have
to send him back.
No one is going
to protest
or shed tears
in the sports arena.
Yes. You are going to talk
to Jordan, Mr. Bryant.
In that way you might save
your precious plantations.
So you are going
on a short journey.
You'll be ready
in half an hour.
And Vidal here
will keep you company.
Remember, accidents can
happen even in Bareya.
Tom.
Well, he's in a room
just below us.
The doctor's
on his way.
Oh, good.
Gosh, I hope he's going
to be all right.
Aw.
Well, he's safe anyway.
Yes.
But we can't keep him
with us forever, can we?
No, that's true.
Ooh!
Something's got to be
done about this hair.
When we get home,
would you like it
if I suddenly went blond?
When we get home,
I got to find a job.
Something tells me
I'm not exactly going to get
a letter of congratulations
at Napier's.
Another job bitched up, is
that what you were gonna say?
No.
I wasn't going
to say that.
Turn it off
for God sake!
What is it?
Oh, God.
What is it, darling?
Tell me.
Oh, Tom.
Tom.
The best
singer, the opera,
that's what he said
he wanted his son to be.
Showed me a picture.
Oh!
Oh.
It's all over, Tom.
It's all over now.
Oh, Tom.
Where's the president?
No say.
Where have they
moved him to?
No say, senor.
Where is President Rivera?
He was taken away
in an ambulance
to Santa Maria Hospital.
Oh.
When my wife calls down,
tell her I've gone there.
Yes, of course, sir.
Thank you.
Congratulations on
your journey, Mr. Jordan.
I hope you won't find
it was a waste of time.
Just a minute.
Where are you
taking him?
We're trying
to treat him.
This is a hospital,
haven't you noticed?
Not a place for
a political demonstration.
Are you
another reporter?
No, I just
brought him here.
Now just leave him
to us, will you?
Just leave him to us.
He was a great man,
Mr. Jordan.
What did you say?
He was a great man,
Rivera.
I never really knew.
Not that
it will help him.
What do you mean?
It's only a very short flight
from here to Tribulacion.
But they can't send him back,
he is a political refugee.
A great embarrassment
to the president of Bareya.
Now, Mr. Jordan, I represent
News International.
Perhaps you
would be so kind--
Oh, Jordan.
Good to see you again.
Come sit down,
there's something I want
to talk to you about.
You know you've got us
into a pretty bad jab.
But quite frankly, and
speaking off the record,
I must say I feel the sneaky
sort of admiration.
I mean I might well
have done the same thing
if I found you dumped
on my doorstep.
You might?
What do you want?
Oh, it's just this.
It's very simple.
Keep the local boys happy
and it would help if you'd
sign to correct the record.
It's a mere formality.
Ah, the beautiful
Mrs. Jordan.
He wants us
to correct the record.
What does it say?
Oh, it's just a formality
to save the government's face.
I suggest we get
this over and go
and have a good lunch
on the company.
You must have forgotten
what a good steak looks like.
"Rivera was armed
with a knife
and we clearly saw him approach
Lieutenant Gomez and kill him."
Rivera was asleep.
Look, Jordan,
all they want you
to do is to say
that he did it.
Simply to clear us.
No.
So they can
get him back.
Listen to me.
Do be sensible.
You know, Bryant,
I used to think that
you were just a bowtie,
and a big suit,
and a fat smile
put on by the wind,
but you are worse.
You are much worse.
Why don't you go away?
Go home.
Stop trying to get us
to lie about things
that you wouldn't
even understand.
Mrs. Jordan,
will you help us?
You've got
the future to think of.
What are you going to do?
Let him go through the world,
throwing away
every job he ever gets.
Can't you
make him see sense?
Tom.
He'd like to see you now,
Mr. Jordan, and your wife.
Well?
Mr. Jordan.
I'm here.
You are both safe?
Quite safe.
Remarkable woman.
Why did you do it?
I don't know.
Honestly,
Because I hate
violence I suppose,
because I can't stand the
thought of men getting killed.
And now...
to save you, I...
I killed a man.
At last you understand.
Please.
Please forgive me
for teaching you this.
They won't get you back.
No.
I don't think so.
Jordan,
I appeal to your...
Jordan, I appeal to your
loyalty for the last time.
All right, you're
a great hero, aren't you?
But what
have you got?
What exactly