In the summer of 1953,
it was announced
that an atomic bomb of foreign origin
had been exploded somewhere
outside of the United States.
Shortly thereafter, it was indicated
that this atomic reaction,
according to scientific reports,
had originated in a remote area
in North Pacific waters,
somewhere between the northern tip
of the Japanese islands
and the arctic circle.
This is the story of that explosion.
Oh!
Professor Montel.
I'm McCleary of the Herald Tribune.
Oh, yes. How do you do?
I understand that you're going
to Vienna to address the,
Central European Federation
of Advanced Scientists.
That is correct.
I will read a paper on the emission
of neutrons and collision of nuclei.
Thank you, Professor.
Will any of the American Atomic
Energy Commission be present?
I doubt it.
Will you excuse me, gentlemen?
Oui.
Professor. Excuse me.
There's one or two points
I'd like to get clarified.
You will have to excuse me, gentlemen.
The plane is waiting.
Who's the girl?
This is the BBC
with the latest news bulletin.
Professor Montel, famous nuclear physicist
and atomic scientist,
has vanished while en route
to attend a conference in Vienna.
Professor Montel's disappearance
is a complete mystery to the police.
Authoritative sources reveal today
that the former Nobel Prize winner
is the fifth noted scientist believed
to have vanished behind the iron curtain.
Professor Montel was last seen
at the International Airport in Vienna.
Speculation as to the whereabouts
of Professor Montel continues.
Ten days have elapsed
since the distinguished scientist vanished,
and so far police have been unable
to offer any explanation.
Authorities are now convinced
that Professor Montel was not kidnapped
and that his disappearance
was part of a prearranged plan.
Airport officials in Vienna
reveal that the scientist
carried a diplomatic passport.
The search for Professor Montel
continues into the fourth week.
It is interesting to note that while the
story has been given front-page space
in newspapers in the United States
and all other parts of the free world,
Pravda, the official mouthpiece
of the Soviet Union,
has, as yet, failed to take note on it.
- Corporal Lee Stockwell?
- Right.
- Mr. R.♪. MacDougall?
- That's right.
- Mr. Franklin Meredith.
- That's correct.
Jones!
I'm afraid you're mistaken.
My name's MacDougall.
You're a dead ringer for an officer
I used to know in the submarine service.
Sorry.
Mr. MacDougall?
Yeah.
My name is Eddy.
Your instructions.
There is a taxi waiting for you.
The driver knows the address.
Taxi number 63.
Number 63.
Okay.
This is it.
- You better wait for me.
- No, I go now.
Wait a minute. What if I need you again?
Where can I find you?
- What's your name?
- Eddy.
Mr. MacDougall?
- Yeah.
- Come in, please, and follow me.
Watch your step, please.
- Now don't tell me your name is Eddy too.
- "Eddy" is the password.
I'm Hokada Fujimori, Commander Jones.
I'm very pleased to meet you.
Thanks. For a minute there, I thought
this was something out of Inner Sanctum.
You've lost a little weight.
I'm on a diet.
I'll bet Captain Taylor
put a little fat on?
- Where is he?
- I'm sorry to tell you, your friend is dead.
Dead?
His plane crashed returning
from an arctic expedition.
No one survived.
He never did like to fly.
Why did he want me to come here?
What was the 5,000 for?
It's an advance payment
for a job Captain Taylor
was certain you would do for us.
- Advance?
- Yes.
- When do I start?
- Without questions?
Why talk? If Taylor lined me up
for the job, it must be kosher.
Some people might not
exactly call it kosher.
In here, please.
Gentlemen, Commander Jones.
- Mr. McAuliff.
- How do you do, sir?
- Colonel Schuman.
- How are you?
- Mr. Aylesworth.
- How do you do?
And Professor Montel.
- Montel, the scientist?
- Yes.
Everybody and his brother
is gunning for you, Professor.
They say you skipped
behind the iron curtain.
As you can see, only a wooden door.
- Glad you're here.
- Thank you, sir.
Well, it's quite a layout you got here.
What kind of business
are you gentlemen in?
The business of investigation.
The scientific investigation
of these uninhabited North Pacific islands
that lie in neutral waters
between the free world
and the iron curtain.
Our deductions make us believe
that one of these islands...
we don't know which one, Mr. Jones...
has been prepared as an arsenal
for atomic weapons.
Your friend Captain Taylor
volunteered
to undertake a photographic mission
to find out.
- Volunteered?
- Yes.
- For free?
- For free.
Is that when he had the accident?
It was no accident.
His plane was shot down.
This photograph we have just printed
came from the camera
of his salvaged plane.
Thirty years in the navy,
and he gets killed for a picture.
For free.
Each man has his own reason
for living, Mr. Jones,
and his own price for dying.
This was Captain Taylor's price.
There's nothing there, Professor.
It's a washout.
I wouldn't be too certain.
Extend these lines.
They could be atomic vault constructions.
And over here could also be part
of a concrete runway.
Look. Look, before we go any further,
exactly what country do you men represent?
We represent many countries,
as private individuals.
We are scientists,
former statesmen, businessmen.
All volunteers acting independently
for a common cause
against a common enemy.
As private individuals,
we can conduct this investigation
on a scientific basis
without violating any neutral waters.
And if what we suspect is verified,
we can then make our findings public.
And what good will that do?
Don't you think the truth
is worth knowing?
Don't you believe that factual proof
will establish, once and for all,
both the identity and the intention
of the aggressor?
Who knows?
But where do I fit into the picture?
We want you to command a ship
for an inspection tour of these islands.
- What kind of a ship?
- A submarine.
We know that four times
during World War I I,
you commanded a submarine
reconnaissance patrol
in this very area.
As I recall, you were extremely
successful in these waters
when you fought my country.
This time the enemy is different,
Mr. Jones, but the waters are the same.
You received already $5,000.
20,000 in United States currency
will be deposited to your account
in any bank you elect
to chauffeur Professor Montel
to this island.
And another 25,000 bonus
when you bring him back safely
with all the information he seeks.
What about the sub?
Did it volunteer too?
One does not pick up a first-class
submarine in the junkyard, Mr. Jones.
We have salvaged a Japanese submarine.
- What class?
- I-203.
Sewer pipe. Had one on my tail once
for six hours. Taylor look her over?
- Yes.
- Start getting her refitted?
- Armed?
Mr. Jones,
the object of this mission
is scientific investigation,
not combat.
Professor...
am I in command?
- That's right.
- Then we arm the sub.
That is, if you want me
to get you back in one piece.
Did you also salvage a crew?
We have picked volunteers,
experienced men.
There will be two scientists on board.
Professor Montel and his assistant,
Professor Gerard.
We aren't positive which island it is,
but a certain freighter, the Kiang Ching,
has been up to this area
several times before
with cargos of concrete and heavy metals.
She's loading again at Tientsin.
The last time I tailed a freighter,
my price was 650 a month,
and I had to buy my own uniforms.
All right. I want my own key men,
men who've served with me before.
You name them, and we'll get them.
Like you got me? For cash.
If it's necessary.
As I said before, Mr. Jones,
each man has his own reason for living
and his own price for dying.
I hope, for all of us,
that it will be a bon voyage.
Giovane! Help him with the line.
Giovane! You! You, Carpino,
give him a hand with the torpedo.
How many hands
you think I got, Neuman?
Mr. Neuman to you.
Now, make sure you give me
the reading on that battery.
Right, Skipper.
Come on. Come on!
Bring it on, boys.
Bring it around! Come on!
Hey! Come on now.
Easy now. Come on.
Come on. Come on. All right, hold.
All right, boys.
Make it fast to the cleats.
Hey.
- Don't you ever take a bath?
- Shut up.
"Shut up."
Is that the extent of your vocabulary?
What'd you ever give up
the wrestling racket for anyway?
I just found out it was phony.
That's the trouble with these...
I say, that's the trouble
with these phony wrestlers, Dugboat.
- They never take a bath.
- We do too.
Hey, Joto. Hey, Joto.
The after valve won't turn.
- What?
- The after valve won't turn.
No, no. The other way.
Everything backwards. No wonder you blokes
lost the war, with subs like this.
- Skipper.
- Yeah.
- That guy Welles... any good?
- Best engineer out of Australia.
- Wish we had Wilbur.
- Yeah.
With Charlie Wilbur handling
the engines on the Bowfin,
there was nothing to worry about.
Hear he's a three-striper now.
Yeah, so I hear.
Skipper,
that number two scopes don't work.
- What's the matter with it?
- Can't get the rust out of it.
- How 'bout number one?
- Didn't check it.
Lift her up, Holter.
The professor topside
wants to see the captain.
Send him down.
He's part of the brass behind this setup.
Now, if he looks familiar,
don't say anything. I'll explain later.
- Hello, Professor. Welcome aboard, sir.
- Captain.
Well, we're trying to put
this sewer pipe together
with a little spit and a lot of sweat.
- I guess we'll make it all right.
- Captain Jones.
What's the matter?
Is there something wrong?
I'm sorry to say we cannot permit
one of your crew to make this expedition.
What do you mean?
They were all handpicked.
- We cannot trust this one.
- Who?
The torpedo man, Revnik.
Oh, one of the men you picked.
I could have told you that all the time.
A knothead.
Did you screen all my men too?
Very closely, including you.
- Okay. I'll get rid of Revnik right away.
- Good.
Holter, I want...
She the replacement, Doc?
Gentlemen, this is Professor Gerard,
my assistant and my right arm.
- Hiya.
- Denise, this is Captain Jones.
- Captain Jones.
- Glad to know you, Professor.
Well, if I'd known about this,
I'd have cut my price.
Boys, these two professors
are going with us as cargo.
- What?
- You heard me.
Have you blown a gasket?
Nobody takes a female along in a pigboat.
Look, junior, you gonna give me
that 2,000-year-old navy bilge
that they're bad luck?
Take a look at her.
What's so bad about that?
Nothing. Absolutely nothing!
They're all Jonahs. It's traditional.
Look, Skipper, I made up my mind.
Count me out.
Okay.
Anybody else?
I'll give you jokers five minutes
to sleep on it, and remember,
if I have to,
I can replace every one of you.
Captain, I do not like it either.
Oh, scusami.
Perhaps you are right.
In your estimation,
I am a... a female.
But first I am a scientist
and a good one.
And I am not the only scientist
who is not of your sex.
There are many.
Like Dr. Lise Meitner,
who played an important part
in the development of the atom bomb.
Like Madame Curie, who discovered radium.
I have grown up in laboratories.
All my life, I have worked with men.
Never have I interfered,
and never have they resented me.
Professor Montel and I have...
have much to accomplish.
Much.
And I shall appreciate it
if you would not let my... my presence
be the cause of... of a minor mutiny.
I like you.
I like you all.
And I shall try my best
to make you like me...
as a scientist.
Man, that was quite a mouthful
for a female!
That's no female. That's a scientist!
All right. Come on.
We got a lot of work to do. Let's go.
Hi, Mr. Fujimori, Professor.
- Where's your assistant?
- Are you prepared to sail?
I'll let you know tomorrow
after we make the running dive tests.
There's no tomorrow left for us.
The freighter Kiang Ching
sailed from Tientsin a half hour ago.
- You must leave right away.
- What are you talking about?
We only been working for two weeks. We've
got a lot of work left to do on this tub.
- You must leave by dark to overtake her.
- What about the running tests?
As an amateur, might I suggest
that we try the running test
while we are running?
Doc, there are about a hundred ways
of losing a submarine.
You've just come up with one of the best.
We haven't even checked
the torpedo tubes yet.
You know what that means if we have
to call on fish? It means we're dead.
You've got to leave tonight.
Okay, buster, you're buying this trip.
You want me to chance it?
It's not what we want, Captain Jones.
It's what must be done.
All right. Just as long as the professor
here knows what he's letting himself in for.
We've arranged airplane contact to give you
position on the Kiang Ching.
- How'll they contact us, blinker or radio?
- Neither is without risk.
We've decided cork drop is safest.
This contains your code,
and this contains
your schedule for contacts.
Oh, just one more thing.
I want a clear-cut directive
detailing my specific authority.
You'll find it all in here, Captain.
At sea, you are in complete command.
On land, Professor Montel is in command.
May I wish you the best of luck?
Thanks.
Well, now's as good a time as any,
Mr. Neuman.
- Take her down to periscope depth.
- Yes, sir.
Clear the bridge!
Dive!
Stand right over there.
You'll be all right.
- Thank you.
- Professor Gerard, give me your hand.
Watch that top rung. It's murder.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
You sit right here.
Captain, trim satisfactory
at periscope depth.
- Very well. Joto.
- Yes, sir?
Give Welles a hand with those starboard
engine blueprint translations, will you?
I'll take care of it, Captain.
Everything's tight
in the forward torpedo room.
We're gonna try her down deep.
Have all stations checked. Let me know.
Ay, ay, Captain.
This is that test we were
talking about today, Professor.
- Now?
- Now.
Don't get nervous. If we crack up,
you won't get a chance to feel it.
Take it easy. It'll be all right.
Put her on the bottom, Mr. Neuman.
Two degrees down bubble.
- Flood negative.
Oh, thanks, Chin Lee.
- Coffee, Professor?
- No, thanks.
- How 'bout you?
- No, thank you.
Two hundred feet, Kapitän.
Better hold on, Professor.
All right. Now let's see
if we can hit the roof.
- Take her up, Mr. Neuman.
- Close all main ballast vents.
- Stand by to surface.
- Surface.
- Blow all main ballasts!
- Blow all main ballasts.
What's with the air banks, Holter?
The air bank's dry.
Open the emergency banks.
Put 'em on the line.
They won't open.
They've got to open.
We've checked everything.
These signs are all fouled up.
I'll have to try every valve.
No, wait a minute.
Joto, come to the control room.
Unsnarl these Japanese signs.
I can translate it. That one reads,
"Open emergency air bank."
- What?
- "Open emergency air bank."
Go ahead. Try it.
- Air bank's on the line.
- Good. Thanks.
Okay. Put her on the roof.
- Skipper.
- Yeah. Everything all right, Carpino?
Just a few leaks around the
stuffing glands. I marked them.
Okay. Make a full sweep, Ski.
All clear, Skipper.
Rig for red. Up scope.
You better move out, Professor.
This helps get our eyes
used to the dark when we go up.
Open the hatch, Holter.
You did a good job
translating that sign, Doc.
Professor Gerard is MOL.
- MOL?
- Master of Oriental Languages.
Oh? Très bon. Très bon.
Down scope.
Glad to have you aboard, Professor.
Glad to be aboard, Captain.
Captain. The professor wants to know
if it's all right to come up for fresh air.
- Which one?
- The one with the beard.
Oh. Okay.
Come to course 355,
ahead full on both engines.
Ay, ay, Captain.
You won't need your umbrella, Professor.
She's a dry boat.
It's nothing to worry about.
Almost everybody gets a touch
of claustrophobia first time down.
It's not claustrophobia, Captain.
It's the realization that, at last,
our mission has begun.
If anyone had told me six months ago
that today I would be on a submarine
headed for arctic waters
in search of a secret atomic base...
- I just can't believe it.
- Yeah, I know what you mean.
Well...
what about your assistant, Professor?
What makes a girl who looks like that
get mixed up in science?
She comes from a family of scientists.
She was a child prodigy.
At 14, she entered college.
At 18, she studied at Göttingen.
She is really very brilliant.
A child prodigy
with a body by Fisher?
And this is the greatest pigboat
in the whole submarine service.
The USS Bowfin.
It's one we served on together...
me, the chief, Gunner,
Dugboat and the skipper.
Beautiful, aingt she?
Oh, yes. Very beautiful.
You know something else
that's very beautiful?
All my life I've been wanting
to find a girl called Denise.
Oh, Ski,
I'm sure you will find her.
Oh, I found her, all right.
You see, I lost no time at all
in learning your first name.
Yep. Denise. It's always been
my favorite name.
I... I never met a Denise,
but I always knew I would.
You see, from the moment I saw you,
I said, "Lafayette, I'm here."
That's right. I always knew
I'd meet a girl called Denise.
ID-E-N-I...
Don't let him kid you, honey.
I just seen him put your name on his arm.
- Look.
- All right, bub. You asked for it!
No!
Come here, you big drunkard!
That's what I mean by Jonahs.
They were beefing over the dame.
Wasn't her fault. He's stiff.
- She okay?
- Yeah.
Just roughed up a little.
Take care of him, Holter.
Oh, here, let me help you, Professor.
- Thank you.
- Let's see.
Boy.
I'm really very sorry about this,
Professor.
That drunk was a last-minute replacement.
- He's all right when he's sober.
- I'm sorry.
This is the last thing I...
I wanted to happen.
It had to break out sooner or later.
Let's have another look here.
It's lucky you still got your teeth.
Don't get nervous, Doc.
Nobody's gonna bite you.
Don't you think that the pharmacist
should treat me, if it's necessary?
He's got his hands full
with those two lugs.
Besides, there's nothing
he can do that I can't, you know.
Oh, my. He got you so greasy.
Okay.
You know what a log is?
- Yes.
- You do?
Well, I'm supposed to keep a detailed
report of everything that happens.
It's for Mr. Fujimori.
How'd it start?
I was working on a new formula
when Ski asked if he
could show me his chest.
- Show you his chest?
- Yes.
Oh.
And then what?
Then he removed his shirt.
No kidding?
- He wanted me to see his tattoo.
- Oh, no.
- It was a beautiful tattoo.
- I'll bet it was.
Beautiful.
- But the intoxicated one rubbed it off.
- Naturally.
Tell me, he make a pass at you?
- A pass?
- Did he try to kiss you?
Yes, he did.
He did? Did you coldcock him?
- What?
- Did you hit him?
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Hold the phone. Hold the phone.
Now, say that in English.
- I slapped him.
- You did?
Tell me,
you hit him after he kissed you?
- Yes.
- Not before?
I do not understand.
Well, you see, Professor, I just want
to make sure my report is factual.
- I couldn't put...
- Captain Jones.
Is this report for Mr. Fujimori
or for you?
Now, really, a child prodigy oughta
be able to figure that one out.
Don't you think?
- Yes.
Au revoir, Professor.
Now listen to me.
I don't want any more beefs,
you understand?
If I hear of anybody
making a play for that girl,
I'll personally shoot him out
through torpedo tube number one.
Captain, is it still a secret
where we're going?
We're tailing a freighter
to an island in the North Pacific.
Gonna sink her?
We're gonna sneak into this island,
take a look and sneak out.
This is a scientific expedition.
- But, Skipper, what are we looking for?
- Four-leaf clovers.
Well, what if the guys on the island
don't like us?
Look, I know you're all
itching for a little action,
but you'll only get it if we
have to defend ourselves, so relax.
Capitaine Jones?
Le Capitaine Jones.
Bonne nuit.
Oh, good morning!
- Was the water hot enough, Professor?
- Just wonderful, thank you.
- Voulez-vous "fume" une cigarette?
- What?
- I'm speaking French.
- Oh.
Voulez-vous "fume" une cigarette?
Oh, you mean "Voulez-vous
fumer une cigarette?"
- That's what I said.
- No. Fumer.
- Foo-may.
- No, no, no.
You have to form your lips like this.
Fumer.
I think I better go now.
Thank you.
You know, someday I'm gonna
find out what color her eyes are.
Good morning, Captain Jones.
You wanted to see me?
Why did you let me sleep
through that plane contact?
I thought you needed the rest.
You were on duty for almost 20 hours.
Didn't you stop to think
how important that message might be?
Of course.
So I made sure that it was not
by decoding it myself.
As you see,
it reports only that the Kiang Ching
has made no change in speed or course.
I knew that was of no importance.
Professor, did it ever occur to you
that I might be steering a course to be...
You've lost us approximately two hours!
I'm very sorry, Captain.
- And I think I have learned something.
- I hope so.
If you want to listen in on conversations,
use the intercom. It's easier.
That conversation I would
prefer not to have heard.
- But I was waiting to see you.
- Okay, you see me. I'm busy.
Many years have I been
with Professor Montel,
but never before have I heard
anyone speak like you
to the greatest scientist in his field.
Professor Montel's field isn't commanding
a screwball submarine. Mine is.
If such rudeness is necessary,
I hope this will be a very short cruise.
What'd you want to see me about?
- Joto.
- Yes, sir?
In the future, when a message
comes in to this boat, I get it,
no matter who says it's unnecessary,
you understand?
Yes, sir.
Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh!
No, no, no, no.
This time, he was right.
May we come on the bridge?
Sure. Help yourself.
Contact plane
approaching on schedule!
Good enough.
Okay, Charlie.
There it is!
Well, this one's for you, Doc.
"Intelligence reports Kiang Ching carrying
unconventional-type 61 -♪ capsule."
Signed, "Fujimori." What's a 61 -♪ capsule?
The charge to explode an A-bomb.
Hey, Skipper. Radar shows
surface object approaching,
bearing 355 degrees.
- Speed?
- Can't tell yet, but he's closing fast.
- Range.
- 3,800 yards.
Maybe the freighter has seen
our signal and comes after us.
Rig for red.
A sub's after us.
A sub? I thought this was
a scientific expedition.
It is, and we're gonna play it safe.
No use getting a bloody nose
unless we have to.
She's submerged and listening for us.
- That's why she stopped pinging.
- What does this mean?
It means she's saving her torpedoes,
waiting till we surface.
Just one more day, Doc,
and we'd have finished
overhauling those torpedo tubes.
Can you see her scope?
No.
Well, we can play possum too.
- How's the hydrogen?
- Built up to three percent.
Well, we can't chance surfacing here.
We've got to make a run for it.
Professor, I think you'd both
better stay in your quarters.
Down scope.
They're still on our stern, Skipper.
- How's that hydrogen gas?
- Four percent and still building.
Take her up!
Okay, Charlie.
You better keep off the bridge, Professor.
I'm not going up.
The skipper'd blow his top if he even
found you here in the control room.
- Sit down, Professor. Grab some air.
- Thank you.
Have you identified the submarine?
No. We haven't even seen her yet.
They're topside trying to spot her now.
No sign of her yet, Skipper.
Sonar tells us she's not far.
Alert the gun crew.
- What?
- I know. We're not looking for trouble.
But we'd be fools
not to protect ourselves.
Alert for battle stations!
Gun crew stand by to man the deck gun.
What about these torpedoes?
You know those tubes haven't been checked.
Forget the torpedoes!
- Where is she now, Joto?
- Range, 1,500.
Either she's moving out,
or she's gonna surface.
There she is, Skipper!
They're coming out on deck.
Ask them where we are, Charlie.
- Why not man the five-incher now?
- No!
The minute they spot a crew near that gun,
they'll throw torpedoes at us.
What are they saying?
They want to know who we are
and what we're doing here.
Tell 'em we're a private scientific
expedition headed for the arctic.
They insist on boarding us.
Well, keep stalling.
Tell 'em we don't understand.
Ask them to repeat the message.
Put one over our bow.
Keep asking them to repeat, Charlie.
Turn our nose into her. Steer 001.
And get ready to man that gun.
Keep clear of the lifeline!
Right full rudder.
Torpedo!
Clear the deck! Clear the deck!
Dive!
Close the hatch!
My hand! My hand!
My hand!
- Give me a knife!
- No! No! No!
- My hand!
- No!
Here.
- How is he? How is he?
- It's his thumb.
All right. Get 'em all below.
Hey, you guys! Come on up here!
Give me a hand, quick!
We ship too much water. Can't hold her up.
Get the angle off
and let her settle to the bottom.
All back full.
Enemy torpedo fired.
Number two fish
out of their basket.
Secure all running machinery.
Remain silent.
Bilge pump motor's flooded, Skipper.
Form a bucket line.
Dump the water in the engine room bilges.
That tub's laying for us, Skipper.
She's coming real close.
I lost her.
Nothing out of her now. No sound.
What do you think, Skipper?
I think she's pulling
the same trick we are.
Now watch that salt water.
We don't want any chlorine gas in the boat.
Hold it.
Captain, this hot heat is killing us.
We got to turn on the fans.
If they heard our fans, you wouldn't have
to worry about the heat killing you, boy.
All right, I'll fill in the picture
for you quick.
We got torpedoes, but our tubes
aren't in condition to fire 'em.
And the Red sub's parked
on the bottom like we are,
waiting to pick us up on sonar.
Once she does,
she'll throw more fish at us.
So it's a question of who can hold out
longer without air... the Reds or us.
If we break first, chances are
it'll be our last break.
And we're loaded with hydrogen.
We're liable to explode.
But we got one thing in our favor.
We can save oxygen by shutting up.
That's all.
Nothing?
Nothing.
We gotta save juice.
Shift to red.
Keep your ears open, Ski.
I am sorry, Captain, for being so stupid.
That's all right. Save your breath.
You had to use the knife.
If you didn't close the hatch,
we would all be dead.
You're beat.
You better get back to your bunk
and take it easy. Come on.
I want to tell you how...
Don't talk.
Skipper.
He's in a bad way.
I thought that hypo was gonna do the trick, but
he's suffering from shock and loss of blood.
If he don't get some air right away, you're
gonna have only one professor for cargo.
There's 50 grand in that bunk.
Fifty grand is worth a little air.
Joto, turn on the white lights.
Boys, I'm gonna try a long shot.
If her first couple of torpedoes
miss us, we got a chance.
I'd rather pass out without air than have
a torpedo come plowing through us.
Now when we start the pump,
we're liable to get a spark.
Maybe it'll burn off the hydrogen,
maybe it won't.
If it doesn't,
we'll blow up so fast
you'll never feel it.
Good luck to all of us.
- You got everything straight?
- Yes, sir.
Now here's where we find out
if we've lived right.
No more chance of explosion.
Pass the word along.
And build up the turns slowly.
- Hold down the noise.
- Yes, sir.
- All ahead one-third.
Take her up and level her
to 175 feet, Mr. Neuman.
Yes, sir.
She's speeded up, Skipper.
Bearing 240 degrees.
Right full rudder! All ahead flank!
- Stand by to ram!
Range 200, bearing 010 degrees.
Left full rudder!
Take her down to 190 feet.
- 190 feet.
- Stand by to ram!
All back, emergency!
Blow all main ballasts!
Captain!
There you are.
Are you sure you're all right, Doc?
- Yes, thank you.
- All right.
Now take a good deep breath of fresh air.
Feel all right, Dugboat?
Yeah. For a quiet scientific expedition,
I couldn't feel better.
You look awful. Let me see your tongue.
It all real cool, man.
This are the end, Jackson.
I'm learning French. You know,
like Chin Lee learned that American song.
You're wasting your time, junior.
- Hi.
- Hello.
Say, if that music disturbs you,
I could have it turned off.
Oh, no. I... I love music.
Oh. That?
Well, how's the hand, Professor?
Wonderful, Captain, as you see.
Good. Glad to hear it.
- And how are you, Professor?
- I'm fine, thank you.
- Swell. You know, when I...
- Captain Jones!
Come topside, please.
Freighter in sight of land.
Excuse me.
Bonne chance.
I don't understand.
Our intelligence report
cannot be this wrong.
All we are getting is a normal count.
- You ought to be happy.
- Don't misunderstand.
Nothing would please me more than
to know that our suspicions are unfounded.
Then let's move out.
There's nothing here but this two-bit
garrison and some beat-up storage tanks.
It's a great pity I cannot talk to them.
We are worlds apart.
But, after all, they are human.
- Let's go.
- But Neuman.
Forget it. Shot right through the head.
Let's get out of here.
Ski, try to knock out that light!
All right, come on! Let's get outta here!
You yellow dogs!
Come on, Ski. Give me a hand.
Let's get him in the boat.
You wanted to talk to one of these humans.
I got one for you.
Wet down your coats.
Well, they must be combing
the whole area for us,
but so far, nothing?
Not even a seagull.
Hey, Dugboat, you sure this jelly I'm
rubbing on my chest won't eat off my tattoo?
What are you worried about?
You can always get another.
Are you nuts?
That's my "piece be resistance."
- Your piece be what?
- That's French.
I been practicing, "nessie-pas?"
You need more practice.
Captain Jones. Professor Montel
wants to see you in sick bay.
- Want more coffee?
- No. No, thank you, Chin Lee. Thank you.
This is wonderful.
- You want to see me, Professor?
- Yes.
Denise has just translated his orders.
His name is Sin. He's a pilot en route
to Kevlock Island for special duty.
So what?
Kevlock must be the island
Captain Taylor photographed.
Well, how do you figure that?
An air force pilot would hardly be assigned
to duty on an island without an airstrip.
And as you know, Kevlock is the only island
indicated by name in this entire chain.
It appears to be due north
of our present position.
And what do you suggest we do about it?
It seems to me our course is obvious.
- Not in my book, Doc.
- What do you mean?
I mean you said once that each man's
got his own reason for living
and his own price for dying.
Well, my reason for living is 50 grand.
I'm not sticking my neck out again.
- Is one neck that important, Captain?
- It is when it's mine.
What kind of man are you?
Hold it. Hold it.
Let's not gang up
with a lot of double-talk.
I'm a businessman.
Maybe to a couple of flag-wavers like you,
I'm a mercenary. All right.
But I lived up to my part of the contract.
The deal was to tail
the freighter to the island,
put you ashore and get you back to Tokyo.
Nobody said anything
about a second island.
So as far as I'm concerned,
mission completed. We're going home.
Any objections?
Yes.
I hate to use authority,
but if I have to, I will.
I didn't want it to come to this.
But as long as you have
mentioned the contract,
study it closely, Captain.
You will find a paragraph stating that I,
and I alone,
shall determine when
the mission is finished.
And in my book, Captain,
the mission will be finished
after I am taken to Kevlock,
given the chance to examine the island
and returned to Tokyo.
- Joto.
- Yes, sir.
- Head due north.
- Did you say north?
You heard me.
Set a new course for Kevlock Island.
- It's on your chart.
- Yes, sir.
Okay, Doc, let's go.
What's the matter?
My knee.
- I thought you said it was okay this morning.
- It was.
- I'll manage in a few moments.
- Not a chance. You'd just be in the way.
- It will improve by tomorrow. I'm sure of it.
- Sorry, Doc.
We're not hanging around these waters
that long. This is a powder keg.
Wait. Wait a minute. Wait a minute. What's
going on? What are you talking about?
Captain Jones,
my assistant will accompany you.
What?
She has sufficient training
to compute figures,
determine strength and identify elements
if there are any on this island.
You mean you'd... you'd let her go?
With the exception of me,
Professor Gerard
is the only member of this expedition
capable of performing this task.
- Oh, you're both crazy.
- You will take her ashore
and follow her instructions
as you would have followed mine.
She is not going, and that's final.
You still cannot take an order,
can you, Captain Jones?
And what's behind that crack?
Exactly what you think is behind it.
Ski, you stay here. Keep your eyes open.
What about her?
I could carry her equipment.
She can take care of her own equipment.
Take a look down there.
Looks like a bunch of doors.
I'm afraid we have found
what we are looking for.
A Geiger counter reaction like this
can mean only one thing.
These figures...
What are they saying?
They are looking for Lumfong,
a missing soldier.
We gotta stay put
till they move out. Come on.
What did you mean when you said
I still can't take an order?
Your record, Captain.
In the war you were a very good officer,
except for one thing.
Go on. I'm fascinated.
You could give orders,
but you couldn't take them.
Now look, I...
I know what you're talking about.
But if you want to know
what makes a guy tick,
you've got to look beyond the record.
Those Philippine guerrillas
were cut off and surrounded.
They had to have ammunition and supplies.
I couldn't just sit there
on my can and let 'em die.
I knew the waters were mined,
but I figured I could get in,
get out without a scratch.
So I wrote my own orders.
I lost my sub and 26 men.
And if I had to, I'd do it again.
I'm sorry...
very sorry.
It was wrong of me even to mention it.
Forget it. It's all over.
- You all right?
- Fine.
When this is over, if we get back,
what gives with you?
- Gives?
- I mean, what are you gonna do?
Go back to Paris, I suppose?
- Paris is my home.
- Yeah.
And you?
When this is over, what gives with you?
I don't know.
Have you ever been in Paris?
No, never.
You would love it.
Americans always do.
Well, we can't stay here.
If they hold us up till morning,
we might never get back.
I'm gonna see if there's
another way out of here. Come on.
You stay here. I'll be right back.
Here.
You won't need this, but sometimes
the sight of it's a comfort.
I'll be back in a minute.
Lumfong!
Denise!
Give me that. Come on.
Let's get out of here.
Come on.
Hurry up. Come on.
Let's go.
This confirms our worst fears.
The atomic reaction is unmistakable.
I don't get it.
I mean, I can't figure out
why that bomber was on the runway.
What would a B-29
be doing on a Red air base?
It just doesn't make sense.
Say, didn't you tell me
that that Red officer
we picked up on the other island
was in the air force?
Yes. A major.
- Were you ever able to question him?
- Impossible.
- I tried, but he would not say a word.
- Oh.
Oh, thanks.
Hey, did you talk to that
Chinese prisoner, Chin Lee?
He has not seen the prisoner.
The prisoner has not seen him.
Holter, dig up that portable microphone
and plant it in the torpedo room.
Then get the prisoner and lock him in there.
Make sure he doesn't see the microphone.
- Right.
- Give him a hand, Ski.
Come on. Let's get into some dry clothes.
We got work to do.
- You have a plan?
- I'm gonna find out what this is all about.
Come on, Chin Lee.
We got a job for you. Let's go.
- You guys got everything set?
- Yep.
Okay.
Now, you're sure Chin Lee understands
exactly what he's supposed to say?
- What'd he say?
- He says he would do anything for you.
He wants you to strike him in the face
to make it look more real.
Holter.
He wants you to do it.
He says it will not hurt if you do it.
You all right, boy? You okay?
What's he saying?
He says...
the prisoner is very intelligent
and must be fooled.
He wants you to hit him... harder.
I'm sorry, pal.
All right, get him out. Let's go.
Here. Come on. Take 'em.
This is incredible.
What's it all about, Skipper?
This is the screwball plot of all time.
They're gonna drop an atomic bomb
on Korea or Manchuria and blame it on us.
They're taking off tomorrow at dawn
in that made-over bomber.
He found him out!
Now listen to me.
I'm shoving off for the island alone.
I'll park myself right here,
around the mouth of this cave.
You'll submerge half a mile
beyond the runway, right around here,
so you'll be able to spot my signal.
Now a heavy load of fuel's
gonna bring that bomber out low.
So when I give you the signal...
two short, two long, two short...
that'll mean the plane's taking off.
That'll give you just time
enough to surface and fire.
I want every gun in action.
That means everybody.
That plane has to be
knocked out of the sky.
Now the minute you hit it,
crash dive to the bottom and stay there,
because everything's gonna break loose
when that bomber hits.
There's a cove at the north end,
right here. That's where I'll hide.
Tomorrow night at 10:00 sharp,
I'll give you three short blinkers.
Pick me up.
If I don't show up,
shove off, head for home.
Any questions?
I forbid this insanity.
Forbid all you want to, Professor.
That plane is not gonna make it.
It is dreadful enough to bring back
the terrifying report
that our suspicions are confirmed.
But we cannot take it upon ourselves
to commit an act of war,
no matter how we feel.
We are civilians!
I am responsible for this expedition.
I order you to take this submarine
back to Tokyo!
I don't care about you
and your expedition.
There's an enemy bomber out there
made up to look like an American bomber.
It's gonna drop the biggest egg in history,
and we're gonna take the rap for it.
I don't like that.
So from now on, Professor,
this is my expedition.
Skipper!
The boat's gone!
- What?
- The boat's gone. Montel took it.
- Well, why didn't you stop him?
- We didn't get the chance.
He was on deck with her. Before we knew
what happened, he was in the boat and gone.
- Where's the girl?
- On the bridge.
Please. He doesn't want you to stop him.
Why didn't you stop him?
All you had to do was yell.
He knows your plan.
He'll carry it out. That's his orders.
That's the trouble with you geniuses...
full of big ideas.
Now you're fouling up the whole works.
- You know that island's crawling with soldiers.
- He knows that too.
Then why'd you let a nice old guy like that
take a shortcut to the cemetery?
He's no ordinary two-bit professor,
you know.
He's Montel, top man in his field.
But he's old and helpless... doesn't
know his way outside of a test tube.
You oughta know that.
You work close enough with him.
- What kind of a woman are you?
- Stop!
- Haven't you got any feelings?
He's my father.
What?
My father.
Oh, I'm sorry, Denise.
I'm sorry. Forgive me.
He said it was his place to go...
not yours.
I'm sorry.
She's sure got a lot of guts.
Only thing I can't figure out
is why the big mystery?
Why didn't she let us know
he's her old man?
Well, that's what you have to pay
for having a famous father.
She's been on a spot all her life.
Wanted to make good
on her own, and she did.
And he was proud because she did.
Any sign of him at all?
No, not yet.
There he is.
And there's his signal.
Battle surface! Gun action! Down scope!
- You'd better get below.
- Please.
Okay.
All right, Ski. Let's go.
Come on, Willie. Joto, get up here.
Hurry it up. Hurry it up.
Fire!
You all right?
- Oh.
- The bomb must have gone off under us.
Bring her back on course.
Take her up to periscope depth.
Periscope depth.
All compartments,
report damage and casualties.
The bomber didn't crash in the ocean.
It hit the island.
Head for home.
Each man
has his own reason for living, Mr. Jones,
and his own price for dying.