I WANT TO GO HOME
Oh, Racine...
here I am...
Molière ...
I'm approaching your shore.
Apollinaire...
can you hear me ?
You, Jean-Paul, you would understand me,
and you too, Simone.
I'm escaping.
I've escaped from sufficient ...
rustics with a "closed spirit" from bourgeois Cleveland.
For the culture
where the spirit isn't ridiculed in the dinners.
Flaubert ...
I open my loins for you, my master.
My master's thesis ...
Oh, Christian Gauthier...
their succession over all.
Susan Sontag's Mentor ...
I'm crying in my new language ...
Paris, France ! "Do you speak"...
I'm going too.
Ah, no! No! You, I didn't take you!
TWO YEARS LATER...
My father.
Disgusting!
I'm honored.
A cartoonist !
I'm honored for France! Did you only read Flaubert?
- Or have you heard of him? - Absolutely.
His culture is Garfield ...
Charlie Brown...
Snoopy...
and Mickey.
The only book he gave me was a Mickey.
It's criminal ...
And I was 12 years old!
8 years !
I had already passed the Mickey age, right?
And then, he knew Stendhal, Sartre,
Genet, Christian Gauthier !
Relax.
I'm relaxed.
You don't jot down until you are nervous.
Dr Freud !
You're nervous. It's normal.
Don't tell me because I'm nervous.
It's normal. You haven't seen her for two years.
Yes. Don't tell me I'm normal, I know I am.
I know I'm normal.
You're scared.
Don't tell me I'm scared ...
Well. I don't say a word anymore.
She loves you, you know.
That dirty kid didn't write to me
for 2 years that she's in Paris.
I thought we didn't talk about it anymore.
My lips are sealed.
Good.
I love you, Joey.
Me too.
Shut up.
Oh my God...
- What's the matter ? - Where's she ?
Elise's address! My own daughter!
I ... I can't find her address.
You will leave your skin there!
I knew you would forget it! The only important thing!
The only thing ... the only reason ...
you made me to accept this ... stupid, stupid invitation ...
to participate in this ... stupid ...
international BD cretinery.
Prestigious!
Stupid.
Turn around! Get in the house !
You will leave your skin there!
I'll find her.
I know where she is.
At home. On my drawing board.
This is what to do.
One, we land.
Don't get mad, Lena.
Two, we take the first plane back to Cleveland.
Ah yes ?
Her mother has her address. Call her mother.
Rather die !
No, but at 66, poor idiot ...
you make your first trip
in a country where they don't speak English!
You will leave your skin there!
Here it is ! I found it!
You see ? No problem.
What does the letter is saying?
Come and get us.
The lady of the gallery.
The director ... Madam ...
She has to come to the airport.
Someone has to come get us.
At the airport ?
Not another airport?
At the airport where we arrive.
Charles de Gaulle?
So where is she, this ... Madame ... Madame Roget?
She has her comic book store.
She has been delayed, like Elsie.
Papa !
My dad !
Elsie...
Let's go home.
At home ?
A Cleveland !
This man has only ten additional minutes to live!
I'm in good shape.
Taxi, turn around!
Are you sure it's the right one?
We will take care of the money.
I'm dizzy.
We're only on the second floor.
Third! I'm dizzy.
Listen. I have set up everything there.
Let's go. That's 10 francs.
And that, 5 francs.
Why 5 francs, these are money
and 10 francs, aren't?
I don't know.
Shouldn't it be the opposite?
And why are the 5 francs more
than the 10 francs?
You are getting stupid, you know.
Well. What's that ?
100 francs, I think. Yes,100 francs.
If that's 100 francs ... what's that?
100 francs.
This is 100 francs, and this is 100 francs?
They are equal, Joey !
And first of all, why do they have two species of 100 francs?
One is worth more than the other?
Stop it !
Stop making stories.
I'm a simple guy.
From a very simple country.
With us, a dollar is a dollar bill.
We don't have coins and banknotes.
We don't have 100 dollar coins.
What's this crazy country?
Oh my God ! Where's my number? I lost it...
Ah, there it is !
Who are we laughing at ?
People will come to see cartoons
in a painting gallery.
They are strangers!
They'll understand nothing. It'll be in Hebrew.
How are they going to get the gags?
Gags are my strong point.
I'm not going.
I'll not be ridicules.
Wait until I wash this.
No unwashed fruit abroad.
In principle, we're there to amuse ourselves.
Would you have fun if they heckled you?
Every time Lena and I, we are on a voyage ...
there is a printing.
You never travel.
It's your father !
Let me work, silly cat.
I didn't say anything
since when you didn't go to say something, but ...
Who do you think you are ?
My shrink?
Come on, out ... get out!
I'll go to that damn opening!
You have to come when I'll submit my thesis.
And I have to integrate the influences of youth in Flaubert.
Marcel Mouse ?
Very funny !
What's this ?
Terrine is pâté, and ... baby rabbit ...
it must be duck.
Where are you, are you here?
What's this ? What's this ?
Don't you know? I took the same plane with you!
Of course, you don't know! Eating doesn't count for you.
You don't even eat breakfast.
What are you doing here?
I'm with us, at least,
whatever you don't eat costs less.
I told you not to worry, right?
You're my guest.
Yes, I see, thank you.
Maybe you should tell her who you are.
I don't know how to do this.
We'll be picked up from the airport.
The opening is only at 9 p.m.
I'm Joey Wellman.
It's closed. Sorry, closed.
Come back at 9 a.m.
I want to be reimbursed for the taxi!
Shit ... shit ... shit!
Excuse me.
Do you know what I would like to do? To go to the Musée d'Orsay.
It's a station transformed to a museum.
The only station that interests me ...
is the one who will bring me home.
You didn't get it, did you?
Which country !
You need a credit card to call ...
from a cabin!
You have to be member ...
of a club. Insane, right?
To make a phone !
You must be a member of a private club ...
to call from the street, from a booth, on the street!
Stop it.
Have you finished? Listen to me.
No one came to the airport.
Nobody came...
and this lady ... from the gallery ...
I'm coming from Cleveland ...
And she can't be bothered!
I'm leaving.
We are in Paris. So that's enough.
We'll forget all our problems and we'll have fun.
Do you understand? Enjoy !
We are in Paris !
I can't promise you anything,
but let me have your responsibility ...
My responsibility ?
You worked so hard.
I'm a simple journalist!
You're much more than that.
This is weekly work,
but to a painting gallery? No.
A cartoonist is an eye.
A "jongleur", even more.
It is our last work for the evening.
But we have Beaubourg.
The crowd !
Wonderful!
You hate the crowd. I hate it.
I'm wary of your contempt, Lionel.
You are anti-cartoonist and in eight days, you will praise the depth.
You admire painters for their depth, don't you?
When I told you in Paris that I hate comics ...
you have blamed me severely for using a viper language. No?
You're charming, Terry.
Can't you be serious?
All these cartoons ... France, Italy, Belgium ...
Japan ... even Japan has caught up with America.
Shit !
American culture is dead.
Our painting is dead. Our theater. Our music.
Our movies are dead!
Not your movies, Harry.
No one is funding me anymore. I'm dead. A walking corpse.
Why do you think I'm in France, damn it?
I've also died ...
this cartoon is stupid!
When I was a kid, in Arizona, it was my passion.
Not seen for years!
Nobody is reading it anymore, this t!
It's dead !
Snoopy! That still has a spark of life!
Why didn't you invite Charles Schultz?
Harry, take a decision for a comic book between a dog and a cat ...
would you like me to make a critical distinction?
We invited Schultz. He refused.
And Will Eisner. Another refuse.
And Al Capp. Another refuse.
It is dead.
We're all dead, old man.
This is what they said.
In any case, he wasn't free.
We contacted Crumb, Speigelman and Trudeau.
Nobody...
in America was free.
Let's get the hell out. Too much smoke.
I haven't breathed fresh air from Kennedy Airport.
Dead! We are all dead!
No ! You can't leave!
You are Joey Wellman. I'm Gauthier.
I'm fed up.
You too ? Me too. Come.
Hepp Catt is still spinning.
You are so real ...
you are so good, less  American.
And final, so hidden, so cynical.
I can't bear any longer your cynicism.
You neither also, of course.
"Isn't it amazing!"
Your work up to today, although you are no longer 20yo ...
radiates the innocence of the American emigrant.
The dreamer. Those who inspire hope.
Those who made Hollywood.
Hi, Harry!
Christian Gauthier ... old scoundrel!
Good morning, how are you ?
How I envy you for being a compatriot of the great Joey Wellman!
Do you know each other ?
Of course not !
Outside their discipline,
American artists ignore each other.
Woody Allen doesn't know Updike.
Mailer didn't know Pollock ...
while they were neighbors! Neighbors!
"It's not-amazing!"
It's your motto, isn't it?
Hello Catt this to Fatt Catt:
"It's-not-amazing"! Enjoyable.
Harry is the great director, a genius, like you.
Who can forget your remakes, "Have it or not" ...
"The Public Enemy" and "The Train will whistle three times"?
Unforgettable!
I scrape the base plates.
I "machine-gun" them, and then I "machine-gun" the plate.
Hollywood vomits me. do you know why ?
Because my remakes are better.
I haven't seen them.
Of course not.
Who is less sticking than you artists?
Your famous individualism. The anarchy. Each for himself.
The establishment despises you,
and you despise the establishment.
It's the secret of your genius. Come.
- Did you understand? - Not a word.
But yes, you understood.
I invite my friends for a drink.
No. I have to wait for my daughter, Elsie.
My Elsie ...
Joey ... go ahead. I'll wait for her.
Your wife will be waiting for her. Bring her ... Her friends too!
She isn't my wife.
I don't want to ...
leave you here, in all this smoke.
Go with Mr. Gauthier.
I'll come with Elsie, if she comes by.
It bothers me to do that. This guy has heard of me.
I don't know who he is, but he's someone.
He likes what I do.
Didn't he say I was on the decline?
Stop it! Go ahead.
- He likes what you do. - I'm going.
Bravo ... I must say that you did very well!
Hush !
So, do you really like what I'm doing?
Have you seen how I live?
It's hellish.
And you will be surprised that I can't work!
No one is afraid of me.
A man of my status. What to do ?
I don't intimidate anyone. Sit down.
I chase them away: They come back.
I am rude, insulting: They come back.
How can I work, huh?
Answer: My major work remains under construction ...
forever unfinished.
You must be wondering why?
Answer: I am irreplaceable.
It is inhuman to be so irreplaceable.
It's my cross.
So, you know everything about Gauthier.
A very sad and very boring intellectual.
And you, tell me ...
at what age did you decide to be a great cartoonist?
Well...
I had never stood against her before.
No one stood up to my mother.
Especially not my father ... but I left.
For the Dental School?
I had no idea how to get into a newspaper.
Neither do I can see how to become a cartoonist.
Thereupon, you meet Roy Crane.
He was doing a comic book for a newspaper.
You mustn't know him. I asked for his advice.
"Le grand" Roy Crane ! "Wash Tubbs and Captain Easy".
"Wash Tubbs !"
I'm going to talk to you about Al Capp.
I don't care what they say about Al.
He was a great man.
We made our debut together.
I was his assistant on "Li'l Abner" ...
Don't you know?
Who doesn't know "Li'l Abner"?
Just before starting my own comic book.
"Li’l Abner".
They demolished him, the poor man.
They were cows with him.
But Al Capp ... believe me ...
Al Capp was the smartest cartoonist.
Much smarter than me.
As much as you, you do understand.
Lena knew Al Capp well. You didn't like her, did you?
She didn't come.
I loved Al. And he liked me.
My daughter didn't come to the gallery. She had an accident.
You have a daughter ?
Are you Joey's daughter?
She isn't my daughter.
Neither is his wife.
Ah, your daughter is in Paris.
We'll find her. I will find her. Trust Gauthier.
Paris is like that. She is there. I'm there. Trust me.
That's what we're going to do, Joey.
I'll take you back to the hotel.
You ask for your vote. Right away.
I have to spend the weekend with my mother.
She lives in the countryside.
What do you want, huh?
For 2 months, I left her alone, there, the poor.
We'll leave in the morning. You and Lana ...
Lena...
You'll be my guests.
I need to see my daughter.
That's what we are going to do.
We waited, we phoned, and she didn't come.
Listen ... listen ... if you have to go, go.
I had a fantastic evening.
Lena, Lena ...
Joey, listen.
This is what we are going to do.
I'm taking Lena back to your hotel. OK ?
I'm packing your bags. I'm paying your bills.
We'll be waiting for you at my place.
I'll put the address for you. OK ? And the phone.
I don't know how to call here.
OK, OK. I'll put the address for you. We're waiting for you. OK ?
I'll give you my mother's address ...
Isabelle Gauthier.
My mother's address in the countryside.
If Elsie doesn't come,
leave this invitation with the concierge.
I can't do that.
If Elsie doesn't come, you'll return to my house. OK ?
A taxi. OK?
You'll give this paper ...
- what I'm writing right now ...
and those 100 francs, to the taxi.
You'll give ...
Elsie's invitation to the concierge.
And if...
if the concierge doesn't arrive before 9am, don't bother waiting.
Stick these words on the door, in this envelope ...
and mark on it: "Concierge". OK ?
This is for the taxi ...
plus the 100 francs, very important,
and that, for the concierge.
There's nothing simpler.
I'll take care of everything, Joey.
Papa ?
Are you here at this hour ?!
Where were you ? I was deadly worried.
That's all you tell me after two years!
Do you know what time is it?
Nothing changes.
The charms of France!
You can be messy at home too!
So what ?
I saw your name on posters.
You're skinny.
Do you eat ?
Are you asking me about Lena?
She's fine, thank you. Thanks for asking.
Can I offer you breakfast?
I never eat it.
Ah, no breakfast in France! That's not normal.
I thought France is famous for the cuisine.
I've tasted it.
Trust me, I've eaten better.
I believe you.
You believe me.
You missed the exhibition.
I was delayed.
Delayed!
You haven't missed much.
We're going to the countryside this weekend.
You are writing to your mother every two weeks.
In the meantime, she is calling me
to hear for you ...
as if you have written to me during the week
why you didn't write to her.
What could I tell her?
I never had a word from you?
I have my pride.
I'm inventing a letter. Every 15 days...
I make up a letter that I'm reading to your mother.
That's what you are making me to do.
Come with us to the countryside. You are invited.
I can't come.
Yes ... I'm no longer living with this woman ...
and you are forcing me to lie to her.
I have your invitation here ...
here...
In case you change your mind. It's in French.
This address is in Paris.
So...
that's all. Take them both.
On sale today!
Oh, do you speak French?
Is that all ? I'll do the same.
It's serious.
I did this whole trip.
I would love to hear you speaking in real good French.
They aren't bad at all !
Heck, what! I don't speak this language.
How am I going to go back alone?
There's a taxi rank around the corner.
Give him the address.
At least accompany me a little. Drop me.
You see, I'm getting there too.
For what!
You want in French!
I'm gonna rock you, in French!
Where are we going ? Where are you taking me?
I've asked for the Hôtel de la Tuilerie.
Are you taking me to the Hôtel de la Tuilerie?
It's a trap ! A trap ! I know you are managing!
Like you, we do that in Cleveland!
Oh my God !
Help !
Terrorists !
I would have done everything!
Where do you want to go, huh? To Charles de Gaulle!
It's the only place
where this taxi jerk knew to take me!
And now that I'm here ...
No, you listen to me, Lena ... I'm leaving this country!
You can't find a good single reason against!
So pack your bags. Bring your passport.
I found at TWA an adorable and pretty lady ...
who is speaking English better than me
and who helped me to phone ...
I'll buy her a return ticket
and I'll take her with me.
Because the only good in this country is that you can pay.
Paris, for me, is finished, without appeal!
Tell me you're not kidding.
When you have your crises, she ends up reasoning you.
I don't think you will reason with me this time!
On my kidnapping !
I knew you liked me. You are crazy.
Me too, but French.
My madness, it's a number!
American madness is "formidable", purely instinctive.
You have a lot to teach me.
I don't want you lost in my country.
I want to come to my country!
Mother has never seen a crazy American cartoonist.
You'll be my gift.
She's old, like you, and has no friends.
But she's very, very generous.
She forgives me for everything, even for my Americans.
It's only published in 50 newspapers.
Fifty? It's good, no ?
No. Not really. Philadelphia is the only major city that is publishing it.
In Cleveland - his hometown - we don't publish it.
Not in Cleveland!
Superman and Bob Hope were born there!
I'll never forgive him, not in Cleveland.
In short, what he doesn't want to do it, I do. Especially the funds.
Is Joey assistant you? I didn't know.
We knew each other for long.
I was in animation, in Hollywood ...
In the cartoons?
Joey came to the studio for a film on Hepp Catt.
In cartoons?
Sacrilege! No no !
Take Popeye. The cartoon killed an awesome creation.
Oh my God...
Him who came from so far!
For his exhibition!
For you ! To see you !
And you treated him ...
as you don't treat even your worst enemy ...
I don't have "worse enemy"!
I'm still too young.
In the meantime, I'll do the trick!
He was never a father to me!
He was protective for everyone ...
for this woman he lives with ...
but for me, never!
He is more paternal towards strangers!
Don't throw the invitation. You can change your mind.
Stop harassing me!
He'll leave without ever knowing
how much you have changed.
Without ever knowing how far away Cleveland is for you.
Without ever knowing how much
you "Parisianized" yourself ... "Francized".
Christian Gauthier...
Christian Gauthier ?
I can't believe it !
Christian Gauthier invited this scribbler ...
In his country house.
Pinch me, I'm dreaming!
Joey Wellman...
Who has only read illustrated books!
Ronald Reagan, despite all his faults ...
narrow-mindedness, filthy ignorance, repugnant racism ...
will go down in history
as the greatest President since Truman.
And Truman, from Lincoln.
The "American" one hundred percent.
For me, the greatest President,
was Franklin Roosevelt.
No! Wrong!
Roosevelt was a great actor, like Reagan.
America's decline began with Roosevelt.
Roosevelt was a great man.
He did nothing for the Jews of Europe.
In France, we understand that.
Roosevelt was a romantic figure, like De Gaulle.
Truman, was more in the "populist" vein,
"man in the street".
You know nothing about American politics.
Truman has done more than Roosevelt.
I admire your propensity
to be deaf to everything, so agree on nothing.
I met Truman once.
President ?
He had no idea who I was!
"I thought you were the author of Krazy Kat"!
This "Come-in-the-bacon" from Truman!
So...
Truman...
arrived at this dinner, with others ...
large vegetables, and they introduce me.
"My young friend," he said to me ...
"there are too many cats in your illustrations!"
"Put a Republican MP in your comics instead!"
"For me, a Republican,
"it's much funnier than a cat!"
"For me, a Republican is funnier than a cat."
It's the stroke of the pencil that's so striking ...
for a cartoonist. Hepp Catt, of course ...
vaguely resembles a cat. But...
Does Mickey looks like a mouse?
Donald ... to a duck?
However, a mouse is a mouse.
And a duck, a duck.
I much prefer Daffy to Donald.
Disney was a better strike breaker than a designer.
No no. Disney had a tragic vision.
Dumbo, that ridiculous baby-elephant with wings as ears,
even you must have loved it!
I hate it.
And his mother ? Poor Dumbo's mom has gone mad ...
we had to chain it!
Chain it! What about Bambi's mother?
Shot down? By hunters! By cowboys!
Not by cowboys.
Dejected!
Lena worked for Disney.
I'm speechless.
Draw us a Bambi.
No.
- But if. - But no.
I never drew Bambi ... so ...
Lena, what, let's make an effort!
Sorry, I never did that.
Joey, please.
Joey, draw us a Bambi.
No, I don't know.
What has he said ?
He asked me if you could draw Miss Piggy for us.
Toddlers, Lionel and I
we disguised ourselves as comic characters.
You were showing off in grotesque disguises,
but me, no!
Come on, Joey!
You are dressed up as a pig!
Slander!
"Next week, I'm getting organized."
The immortal "motto"!
I was sure, I was sure ...
Lionel...
tonight let's organize a comic strip ball
in honor of Joey, huh?
What an excruciating idea!
Elsie !
It's my little Elsie ...
my daughter ... remember?
We waited for her in your car.
And there she is!
Excuse me...
this is my thesis.
We waited for her all night and she was there?
Joey, your life is a real comic.
Draw me Popeye. No, Wimpy.
"I'll pay you with delicacy on Tuesday,
my burger today. "
No, Wimpy, it's too simple.
I'll implore you: Bugs Bunny. Oh yes !
Lena does this much better than I do.
No, no. Well done, Joey. Very well.
What did your mother say?
That you'll have to draw her a drawing
every time you come to see her in France.
You can't disappoint us.
They understand me in Paris! Unimaginable, right?
There's going to be a costume ball in my honor tonight.
Awesome.
No one has ever spoken to me like you.
If only I ...
I didn't have a mother after Dad left.
She hated me.
You're welcome. No secrets.
I was an orphan ...
An orphan when you left us.
Father and daughter, so alike.
Both so sad.
I thought you weren't ...
My son brings me all kinds of Americans.
Directors, television fantasists, philosophers!
Boredom!
What do you want me to do ?
I must defend myself!
Christian loves women, but ...
they don't count for him.
He doesn't think about it until one or two in the morning.
There, Christian remembers them.
But at 8 o'clock in the morning ...
he forgets them all.
He only remembers ... his books.
Lena, I'm recognized here.
No one has recognized me with us since 1961.
I have never been considered as an artist.
Unbelievable, right?
Why do you suddenly need to be an artist?
I feel bad with these people.
Why are you doing this to me?
I thought you liked France.
Have you seen my wife?
You Tarzan?
You Jane?
The Americans never ... understood me.
I'm what I am, and that's all I am!
Obviously Woody Allen is taller than Bergman.
Don't be so stupid, Lionel.
"It's not-amazing!"
I invite you to my home for an all-duck dinner.
You'll bring the duck.
Joey...
as a jew, are you with Woody Allen,
for a Palestinian state?
Because ... I'm looking for my daughter.
Have you seen my wife?
Why do I have to be Titi?
Courage, Elsie.
I don't want to be Titi!
You have to learn to be strong.
But why ?
If you don't have the strength, you have to be ironic!
In life, you need one or the other.
Strength or irony.
Are you strong?
Or cynicism.
Strength. Irony. Or cynicism.
I want to die!
The despair !
Despair will do just as well.
Excuse me...
I'm looking for my daughter.
Harry hates the court you get.
He's a director, right?
You've never heard of it ?
Oh, he would cringe!
Can you help me ?
We'll  make you the big game.
Harry was highly ... listed in France.
How does he give to the actors ...
all these indications?
Famous men attract me.
You have something on your costume.
But I have no repairing marks from you.
Are you very famous?
Are you a celebrity,
or are we just playing the big game for you?
I could have loved you, you know.
I tried.
I'm not even sure I love your father anymore.
Spielberg doesn't shoot films, but comics.
It shouldn't bother you.
Blablabla! Comics !
Why ban comics?
There is no longer a bit of energy in the American movies.
I counted twelve murders ...
and an ax-fight in your last movie.
Energy was still flowing there.
It does in violence ...
because there is no other theme ...
except for the French.
France knows each other in love.
America knows nothing about that.
Rape, perhaps, but not love.
You are crazy, Harry. Crazy.
You Americans ...
you love your deficiencies.
The French love those of others.
When I want to see a train station, I go to the Musée d'Orsay.
When I want to see a museum, I go to Beaubourg.
Have you seen Elsie?
After 2 years with the Frenchies, I know the picture.
A third of the day: Work.
Another third: Sleep ...
and on the last: Judge others.
Basic principle with Frenchies:
Be wary of their hugs.
Fabulous country if you are an artist ...
but what a band of cow skins!
Have you seen my wife?
Where can we find something to drink here?
No !
Elsie...
what are you doing here ?
And you ?
I was close, and ...
and ... the couch ...
Me too.
And ... something ... below ... or above ...
What did they say ?
Didn't you hear?
She asked Mr. Gauthier if he likes Americans,
and he said ...
He said...?
That he didn't understand why an American as bad as you ...
may have been asked to come to France.
Did he say that?
He said he and his friends are making fun of you.
They don't like the Americans who play to be European.
Did he say that?
No no. He didn't say that.
What did he say ?
He said he likes you.
It looked good to me.
And he said that I am a monster!
He didn't say that.
Yes, exactly.
- And he's right. - Doesn't that remind you of anything?
At three years old, you locked yourself in the entrance hall ...
and you invented things to scare you ...
Like there now.
It's not true. That's exactly what he said.
When I found you, I was tenderly trying to get you out ...
but you were dragging me inside, with you.
We would sit in the dark ...
and I would tell you stories to reassure you.
It's not true.
And ... I remember ... I invented ...
I invented ... this little cat for you ... Sally Catt.
I was telling you stories of Sally Catt ...
and you asked me again and again.
You used to be unhappy ...
and sometimes you didn't say why.
But you were taking me to this cubbyhole ...
and you were telling everything ... to Sally Catt.
I don't believe it ! It's a lie !
You have never been nice to me!
This is remarkable.
It's in French.
It is still remarkable. You are 19, right? No ?
20 out of 20.
Mr. Gauthier hasn't read yet my thesis.
He won't read it, Dad.
And.
Oh, you are!
I'm your father.
Have you seen Gauthier?
Have you seen my wife?
Superb disguise. It's nothing.
Adorable, this way of responding ...
to my "Me, Tarzan" ... "You, Jane".
What a beautiful night!
Irresistible, the night air.
Christian, my daughter wrote her thesis for you, and I told her ...
Delicious child, so adoring in front of her father.
It's normal, isn't it?
If I'm lucky enough to have a child ...
We can dream. Is not it ?
Joey...
I would like...
a girl ... exactly ... like ... exactly ...
Go away, or I'll jump!
Perhaps there is a simple explanation.
To hang on a wall, like a human fly?
Hide and seek?
I saw him kissing Lena.
Hold on!
You can't leave like this. You are always painted!
And shit ...
But what ...
Why is the water not flowing? Let it be known that you are here!
You landed in my bath, demanding an explanation.
Get out!
And then, basically ...
Come in.
I don't take it against Lena. I'm blaming myself!
Since I have been here,
I'm just spades-spades-spades.
And I'm groaning, groaning, groaning.
Elsie this! Elsie that!
Lena hates Elsie. Normal: Elsie can't see her.
And I'm beating her ears with my Elsie, Elsie ...
Poor American so sad!
I knew I shouldn't have come!
All the mistakes I've made in my life ...
started ... when I left the house.
Because I'm cooler.
You're not in the best of shape.
I'm doing my best...
- You're a terrible lover. - When I am tired ?
Yes, no...
Excuse me, did you see my father?
He is dead.
Perhaps...
What?
Maybe are you my destiny?
The moment you got home ...
I was suffused by your sadness.
You are the saddest American I've ever seen.
Suffused, what is it?
Submerged.
Of all the Americans Christian brings me ...
none, until now, had your beautiful melancholy.
Do you know why I was taking a bath?
I was escaping from your sadness.
Yes. I was trying to drown my sudden ...
my irrepressible concern.
His misconduct with Lena!
I will strangle my son for this betrayal.
It's all my fault.
He makes fun of her, you know.
You are taking him as a rascal, but below ...
he is very sensitive.
My son is single at heart,
women's nightmare.
In a week at most ...
he will come back to you.
But what is happening to me?
Calm down...
I'll explain everything to you.
Do you see how our two cultures differ?
The American makes his "mea-culpa" ...
French...
Explain.
Help !
My husband is chasing me!
He is saying I'll fuck with you!
Bitch!
Where are you, bitch?
What's gotten into you?
Come on ... come on ... get out of there!
Get out of there! Hop!
It's your room!
Good God ! Don't you have an outfit?
What are you doing to my wife, old pedal?
Why do you all have to unpack your problems?
Manure!
Get out of there!
Stop it !
Rape! Rape!
I'm going to rip your heart out!
Get out of my house!
He is raping my wife!
Get out of my room! Furniture!
You have the spirit of your movies!
You are crazy !
He is old ! He is fragile!
Too old for your violence!
We should put him in a cage.
Is this chair too old for my violence?
And this vase?
This painting...
too old for my violence?
And is that too old?
Is it too old for my violence?
I know the violence. I went to war.
Brute ! Butcher! Fascist!
Pork!
Christian !
Now France will never finance your films again ...
poor con!
Do you have anything ?
Why did you call me fragile?
Help !
I always hated his movies.
Oh my God !
What's gotten into you? Are you crazy ?
Stop it! Stop it!
It's Lena!
Everything is my fault!
How could you?
You leave my father alone!
I have enough. Enough, you hear? Completed.
No more good pear! At the zoo, you spit out your peanuts!
No more good pear! I took you to the circus ...
and you threw your coke at me.
Fed up! No more pear!
Finished, the: "What to do for this abandoned kid?"
You deserve to feel abandoned!
And you too !
You too !
I want to go to the airport.
I'll pay in good American dollars, that ...
who will take me to the airport ... to fly ...
... fly to America, the USA ...
"I pledge allegiance to the Flag" ...
Doesn't mean anything to you, does it?
One of you must speak English well. You?
Do you speak English?
I have to leave Paris.
I'll pay in good American dollars ...
You understand "dollars".
Everyone understands "dollar".
... so that they take me to ...
What is this fucking airport called?
Airport! Airport!
What do you all have?
Nobody speaks a little English?
But anyway ... isn't anyone going to help me?
I am an American citizen. I'm American.
United States. Humphrey Bogart.
Henry Fonda. John Wayne.
Clint Eastwood.
I'm a personal friend of Clint Eastwood.
Clint Eastwood wants you to take me to ...
Excuse me sir.
Please, Mr. plane ...
What do you want ?
I want to go back home.
Thank you so much.
Is it so hard to understand?
Yes. It's hard to understand.
I'll tell you why.
Tell you exactly.
Because I understood everything.
At home, the goal of the game is that everything ...
is made to be hard to understand.
Yes. Good.
Including my own daughter.
Including my partner.
Including those who call themselves my friends.
I'm a cartoonist.
I apologize if it doesn't go well enough.
I'm an American.
Before, everyone was speaking in American.
In the films about the Second World War ...
all French are speaking American.
Thank you so much.
I've fought in World War II.
I helped you in the "Journal aux Armées".
I was making drawings during our occupation.
Against the Nazis, I made drawings.
We were allies.
"Tonight, let's taste the salt of life ...
"Music and candles ...
"Restrained passion ... love is flowing freely ..."
Here ! Here !!
Superb! It was superb.
I don't know that one.
But maybe you know this one?
"The party is over,
"the candle flames are dropping and going out ...
"You have danced and dreamed ..."
"I'm having you in my skin..."
Lets go ahead ... it has started so well!
I know you know some of them.
These are old successes!
"Me, champagne does nothing to me ..."
This is Cole Porter, ok!
"In the seventh heaven with the man of my life ...
"Y a nothing with..."
Nothing, hear? Nothing.
OK. Continue on.
"You are the cream ...
"the colossus...
"the museum of Louvre."
The Louvre museum.
That's it!
Does anyone have a pencil?
He must have passed from here.
Someone must have seen him.
We will never see each other again.
How sad not to known each other much earlier!
What's the point ?
For us to know each other ?
When did we met each other?
He's a Wellman.
And that is ...
Hepp Catt.
Hepp.
That's it!
"It's not-amazing!"
I'm very hungry.
That's it!
It was despicable.
Yes. Dad...
My darling...
I'm sorry, dad ... so sorry ...
Calm down.
My girl.
That's it!
I have made myself some friends.
Draw me Sally Catt.
I thought you didn't like my job.
One day may be we would be able to talk about it again.
I'm not ready.
I'm coming home, dad.
No.
It's time.
It's plus time.
I'm not holding anything against you anymore.
Are you still mad at me?
I never wanted you.
You have always disapproved me.
You freaked me out.
I'll take you home.
Elsie...
I had never been anywhere before.
Nowhere.
I don't know ... if I'm ready to go home.
Can I stay, Elsie?
Would you mind ... Elsie if ... I stay?
In any case...
please take care of my father.
...How do you say...
At home, he isn't quiet
but if he could be here ...
BD and Sequential Art
Can I talk with you for a moment?
I told you my horrors.
And I regret.
Very strong.
A little water more ?
No, thank you, this ...
Excuse me, I didn't mean to disturb you ...
He will come back.
You think ?
Yes Yes.
Do I want him to come back?
We are all coming back.
Are you coming back?
Is it true ?
My little girl...
Can I help you ?
Have you seen ?
He's a cartoonist!
Izzy ?
Yes, Joey. I'm here.
Was I going too fast?
Izzy? If I'm talking too much about myself ...
as you, all Americans, are thinking, you fire me.
If I'm spreading my secrets, like any American ...
if I'm overly overflowing, overly sincere ... you fire me.
Don't explain anything to me. You fire me. You only have ...
Yes, Joey.
English subtitles translation from French subtitles: AlexN