You ready?Are you ready?
Seat belts.
Okay. Wait,
there's just...
I forgot. There's one...
All right,
here we go.
Hey.
No, it's just
for the weekend.
Well,
you can tell her
I'm gonna fly down
in two weeks, so...
Okay.
Okay, I'm thinking
about it.
Is that
your brother?
Hey, Doug.
He says, "Hi."
No, I've gotta go.
I love you. Bye.
Is everything
all right?
No more phone calls.
All right?
For the rest of the weekend,
I'm all yours.
How's your mom?
She is...
You know,
it's not good change.
So, I don't really know.
It feels so good
to get out of the city.
I'm excited.I am too.
This whole thing's
the driveway?
This is it?
Yeah. Why?
I just...
I can't believe
you've been,
withholding this
from me,
it's ridiculous.
I haven't been
withholding anything.
What a mess.
I thought you said,
it was a cabin.
It's just a house.
My parents,
got it cheap, you know.
Stuff wasn't that
expensive around
here back then.
Hey,
did you get the stuff
we have to refrigerate?
By that you mean,
the soy yogurt?
Yes, sir, though it's
not exactly known for
its spoiling properties.
I'm just gonna run to
the bathroom real quick.
Shit,
I forgot my birth control.
I know, I packed it
in your bag for you.
Does your dad
take care of this place
by himself?
No, my mom used to
do most of it, but...
Then my dad
took the house,
and now I think
he gets gardening help
from local high school
kids or whatever.
Come here.
Where are we going?Just come here.
What?
They're supposed
to be boobs?
Yeah. Yeah.
It's pretty weird.
Kids do weird things.
What do you think
about our kids
running around up here?
What kids
are those?
I forgot to tell you.
I'm late this month.
Go again. No.
Again.
You go.
That's enough. That felt good?
No,
I can't do it anymore.
I'm okay,
it's all right.
What is that?
What?
Listen to that.
Bad people coming
to do bad things.
My God!
Violent things.
What?
Fuck. What the fuck?
Who is it?
Fuck. Fuck!
What the fuck!
What, who is it?
My dad.
Let's get
this stuff upstairs.
I think
he's with someone.Who?
I don't know,
it's your dad.
Can you help clean up?
Get dressed.
Just don't freak out.Get dressed.
Hey, all right. Shit.
Here, here, here.
Don't, don't freak out.
It's gonna be fine.
It's not a big deal.
What was that?
Where's my...
Where's my underwear?
Hello.
Hi.
Seth.
Hey.
Didn't expect
to see you here.
Yeah...
It was sort of a
last minute thing.
Just grabbed
Martha's car and...
You know...
Hi. I'm Gil.
Andie.
Nice to meet you,
finally.
Finally, right.
Hello.
This is
my friend, Vicky.
Vicky, this is
my son, Seth.
Hi. And Angie.
Andie.
I'm sorry.
And Andie.
Nice to meet you.Nice to meet you.
I was just
saying to Vicky
that,
your sister,
would've called
so I was confused
about the car.
Right, Martha
offered us the car and...
We weren't really
expecting to see you,
and there was that
email about you
being away on work...
All month.
We had a...
I had a change of plans.
Well, we'll just get
our stuff together
and get out
of your hair then.
You're leaving?
Yeah. We really just
came up for the day,
anyway.
You sure?
Yeah, we were
just about to
get going.
Well,
we don't wanna
keep you.
What, you've got some
gig to get back to
in Brooklyn?
Yeah.
Some... Something
like that.
Okay.
Fucking mess
in the bathroom.
You see that?
Wet towels
all over the floor.
You see outside?
He doesn't even clean up.
He just throws shit
in the general direction
of the trash can
and leaves it there.
He didn't even
know my name.
He's never been
good with names.
You don't think
it's weird that
my boyfriend who
claims he loves me,
hasn't even told
his dad that I exist?
That has nothing
to do with you.
It's just like him to...
Do something like this,
all the time.
I don't understand,
why can't he be
more like his sister?
She'd never do this.
You think we should
ask him to stay?
What?
I don't want him to feel
like he's being kicked out
because of me.
What "kicked out?"
He said he wanted
to go back to the city.
You really think
they drove two
and a half hours,
just for the day?
Baby.
I know you had
this weekend
all planned.
Okay, and it's
really sweet.
But, your dad's here.
And I've never met him.
And I think
it's just weird
to run away.
It'd be weirder to stay
and hang out with him
and that random woman.
How do you know that?
Did you see
a hint of regret
on his face
when I said
we were leaving?
No, he wants us to go,
so...
Hope I'm not
interrupting anything?
No, not at all?
Well, I was just
thinking that...
If you really wanted to,
maybe you could
stay for dinner.
I mean you probably
want to beat the traffic,
and it's, you know,
not a bad idea.
But...
If you really wanted to,
Vicky is probably
gonna start cooking
pretty soon.
She's not
exactly a...
Well, let's just say
the kitchen's
not her forte.
But...
Um...
I think it sounds great.
We haven't eaten.
Yeah, it sounds great.
Okay, she'll be
really happy
to hear that.
So, in about
an hour or so.
Mr. Sherwood?
Gil, please,
I'm not that old.
Am I?Gil.
I don't wanna be
a buzz kill or anything
but I'm...
I'm actually vegan.
Vegan?
Yeah.
Are you a vegan too?
No, I'm vegetarian.
He's a liar,
he eats fish.
Okay, I'll let
Vicky know.
Thanks.Thanks.
This all
looks so good.
Thanks, it's nothing.
You know, I think there's
some movies over there.
If you guys wanna
watch something later.
TV doesn't work.
Paid $2,000 for that thing,
and it doesn't even
turn on.
I have to get someone in
to take a look at it.
Well, Seth might
actually be able
to fix it.
Are you good
at that stuff?
No, I just had
a little experience
from doing stuff
in the studio.
I have all these photos
on my computer,
I can't get them off,
I'm at my wit's end.
You think you
could help me, maybe?
Hey.
No, it's a fine time.
Yeah.
Why is he doing that?
Because, it will
all be resolved
in arbitration.
I've already
told him that.
That is...
Really embarrassing
when it happens in public.
It's a no brainer.
Was that, um, an opera?
Yeah, it's that song
from Pagliacci.
Yeah.
It's his favorite show.
We used to go
whenever there was
a production.
You never told me that.
Yup. No, forget
the depositions.
What're you gonna do?
You'd have to...
So, you're
a tech genius.
No. I... I...
I've just been
helping a friend
build a studio,
so, a lot of plugging wires
into the wrong sockets.
- Yeah, yeah, okay.
- bye.
Apparently Ben threatened
to bring this before a judge.
Do you believe that?
This is really good.
Thank you so much
for cooking it all.
Really great.No, it's nothing,
you guys.
You wanna be certain
people like your food,
add a lot of butter.
There's butter in here?
Seth, it's not,
it's not a big deal.
What?
You're a vegan.
It's okay.
What's the problem?
I put butter in it.
So what?
It's an animal
product, Gil.
It's not an animal.
I thought,
he said vegetarian.
What the hell
is the difference?
Well, it's not
a problem, though...
What are
you gonna eat?
Just, pass me
the salad.
Yeah.
Seth, I thought you
said you ate fish.
No, actually.
I turned vegan.Thanks.
What do you mean,
you "turned vegan?"
That means,
I don't eat this.
All right.
Seth, I would offer
you some wine,
but there are
little bacteria in here
that ferment the grapes.
So, you probably
don't wanna kill them.
Gil.Well, I don't know.
Thanks.
Absolutely.I didn't know this.
Yeah.
Thanks, honey.Thank you.
I'm sorry.It's okay.
Yeah.
Okay.
Here you go. Thanks.
Seth, maybe
you can fix the TV
and we can
watch a movie.
Yeah, sure.
I guess I could try
and take a look
and figure it out.
Already looked at it.
Doesn't work.
I'm getting someone
in to fix it.
That is a 17th
century restoration.
Anyone up for
a game of Scrabble?
Any takers?
I'm pretty good.
I'm actually
pretty tired.
I think I'm just
going to sleep.
I'm sorry he
pulled that shit.
What shit?
There is no reason
for him to act that way.
He's not a teenager.
Sometimes
people get stuck
in patterns.
I mean, who
behaves like that?
You're right, babe.
Why did you have
to put butter in
their food, anyway?
Are you kidding me?No. I'm not kidding.
We could have avoided
the whole thing with them.
How was I supposed
to know they
didn't eat butter?
Because I told you.You said vegetarian.
What the hell
is the difference?
And you could have
consulted me,
before you invited
them to stay
in the first place.
It's one night, baby.
Well, I've had
a wonderful evening.
But this wasn't it.
Yeah, exactly.
I don't know.
I mean,
it's kinda crazy here.
Interesting,
would be a good word.
Okay.
Well, I...
I totally understand.
I gotta... I gotta go.
All right, I love you.
Didn't you just
talk to him
this afternoon?
He called when
you were in the bathroom.
Um...
I think we should
probably leave
in the morning.
Okay.
I'll do whatever
you wanna do.
Why do you
say it like that?
Like what?
All passive aggressive...
I'm just saying,
like, we could go
if you wanna go.
Did you not get
enough to eat?
Are you hungry?
Good night.
I'll make you something
if you want.No, I'm not hungry.
Okay.
She's probably
my sister's age.
She's not that young.
Whatever.
If he wants to
keep secrets,
he can keep secrets,
I don't even wanna know.
Why you do that?
Ouch.Sorry.
Why does it
bother you so much?
It doesn't, it's just...
Well, I mean...
It's kind of immature.
It looks a little juvenile.
I didn't do it
front of your dad.
I don't care
if you did it
in front of my dad.
And...
You did.Okay.
All right.
Okay.
Hey.
Good morning.
What the hell
is that?
Coffee, I assumed.
It was in the carafe when
I got up this morning.
What the hell
is yerba mate?
Yerba mate, babe.
I can make a new pot.
It's okay.
No, no.
It's...
It's in the pot.
I'll clean it.
You know,
I'm not gonna spend
the entire weekend
cleaning up after them.
I didn't know
you canoed.
Those are kayaks.
I hardly ever use them.
We should take
them out later.
It could be fun.I'm not very good.
Right.
That's why you own
four of them.
I do not own four.
My dad does.
He made us have them.
He's like the kayak master.
He can do
Eskimo rolls
and everything.
There's one in
the back there that
has your name on it.
Mister.
Morning.
Where are you going?
Vicky and I,
actually have to
get back to the city.
So...
We actually...
We were going to leave
so you two should...
No, it's fine.
There is no sense
in all of us leaving.
You stay,
enjoy the weekend.
It's supposed
to be beautiful.
I don't want to have
this discussion right now.
It's easier for
everybody if you don't...
You never even tried.
Avoidance isn't trying.
I have tried.
I've tried for 15 years.
Hey.
I was just wondering
if you guys really
have to leave so soon?
Yeah.
Well...
We actually managed
to get tickets to, um,
Don Giovanni, tonight,
City Opera...
And it's supposed
to be great, so...
I just found
the canoes.
The kayaks.
He says that
you are like
the kayak master.
Really? He said that?
He loves it.
He talks about it
all the time.
That you're the only one
that knows how to do
an Alaskan roll.
Alaska roll is sushi.
An Eskimo roll.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's been a while.
Maybe you can stick around
and just give a hand,
I've never done it before
and since you're the master,
I thought...
I would like to see
some mastery. Yeah.
We could do
a little class.
Yeah, I don't think
I am qualified
to be an instructor.
I didn't bring
a bathing suit.
I mean, it's just.
It's just the basics,
come on.
I think we can
change our plans.
Right?
Come on.
I,
I think we...
I mean we could call,
but I don't think we can
change the tickets.
You just want
to keep the rhythm
pretty even.
So you don't tip
the boat inadvertently.
Like this?
Yeah, that's it!
How do I make
this thing stop?
My God! Okay.
It's not a car.
It doesn't have
water brakes.
Yeah, I'm sorry, no.
When Seth was a kid,
he was pretty good.
Is that so?
Yeah. He had
pretty good control.
He'd zip in and out of
the rocks and the rapids.
Will you teach me
one of those rolls?
You'd have to
go under to do that.
So?
Well,
you'll get all wet.
I could never
really do 'em.
All right,
I'll do one.
What is it, Gil?
Is it dangerous?
Most likely.
Hold your breath, honey.
Gil! You guys,
somebody help him.
Whoo-hoo!
Not bad for
an old fart, right?
That was awesome.
Hey! Derby.
Can't believe
you're saying that.Hey.
Derby.What's "derby"?
Derby. Nothing.
You gotta do one now.
I couldn't,
even if I wanted to.
Yes, you can.No, I don't have
a spray skirt,
my kayak would
fill up with water.You don't need a spray skirt.
Just do one.I can't.
Do it!Come on.
Do it!
Hey!Sorry.
That's it.
Now you're going in!No, you're going...no!
You're going first.
Come here.No! No!
No!
Seth! Do a roll now.
Seth. Where are you?
Do a roll now!
Seth!
God.
Seth.
I got ya!
My God.
You!
Seth!
So not cool!
You think
it's funny?
I do. Really.Really?
Wait a minute.
Hey, take it easy.Really?
Take what easy?
I'm dead serious.Really?
Gil!
Seth!
No, Seth, don't.
Seth, please, please. It's time.
I'm really sorry.
Seth, do not do that. I'm sorry.
Do not do that.
This water is corroded.
Get her!
My hair!
You have no idea.
My God!
My God.
All right.
You're okay.
None of this is funny. Come on, Vicky.
It's fine.
Here, it's shallow over here.
You can get
out this way.
It's fine right here.
I'm sorry.
Come on,
you can touch right here.
Okay, see if you can touch.
Okay. Okay.Here you go.
Not funny!
It's...
Hello.
Shit.
Should we get
the boats and stuff?
Looks like you guys
are having a great time
down there.
Yeah, listen,
I'm sorry to be rude.
It's just,
it's just not really
a good time.
Sorry.
Mommy, can we go
in the boat?
Maybe, honey.
We can ask in a second.
Is that your son,
the musician?Yeah.
Yeah. I'm sorry,
I thought
Vicky called you.
We just got
the message as we were
coming up the drive.
And we thought maybe
we could let the kids
walk around.
Yeah, yeah,
I'm sorry.
It's just not
the best day today.
I'm sorry, I thought
that Vicky had gotten
in touch with you.
It's fine.
No worries at all.
Don't want to infringe
on family time.
We know what it's like.
Any other time,
really. Okay.
Sorry for
the, inconvenience.
Mommy, I want
to go in the boat.
Pretty soon we'll be
able to go into the boat
every weekend
if you want.
Whoo-hoo. Who wants
ice cream?
Me. Ice cream.
You had
a lot of chances,
the one thing...
It's not my
fault they decided
to ignore my message.
It wasn't supposed
to be a message.
You were supposed
to speak to them.
Sure does bring
back memories.
I'm gonna go
for a walk.
Hey there.
Hi.
You won't eat
anything remotely
unhealthy
but you smoke?
Um, well...
I get it.
That's not a
cigarette, is it?
Not really.
I'm sorry, it's not.
I didn't, I didn't really...
I can just put it out.Hey, I'm not a cop.
Are you sure?
Well, do you...
Do you want some?
Are you offering
me marijuana?
Yeah. I guess.
I guess, I am.
They don't...
Drug test lawyers
do they?
They probably should.
If you want any.No, thank you,
I haven't smoked pot
in 35 years.
I'm sorry.
That's a travesty.
What the hell.
So, you were
able to,
cancel your tickets
for tonight?
Right. Yeah, yeah.
We just called
and rescheduled.
I felt uncultured,
so...
I looked up Don Giovanni.
You know,
it closed last week.
Hey.Hey.
What are you doing
up here?
This, this rung
was kinda rotted out.
I was fixing it.
Thought I might
go up, have a look.Whoa.
You built that?
Yeah, me and my dad
and my sister about
100 years ago.
What do you say?
You wanna go up,
check it out?
What, up there?
About 30
Nor'easters have come
through here.
If those didn't
take it down,
we're not gonna.
Yeah, not comforting.
You'll go first.
I'll stand and make
sure you don't fall.
Seth, I grew up
in the city.
I played in the streets.
Okay. All right.
Suit yourself.This is not good.
Suit yourself.
Wait.
Is it like super cool?
It was
when I was 12.
God, it's so
beautiful out here.
Supposed to be
a lot nicer.
I wanted to try
to copy a section
of Prospect Park.
This landscape
architect...
It's the same guy
that works for... Prospect Park?
He's the same guy
the Clintons use
on their property
in Chappaqua.
He costs a fortune.
Doesn't listen to
a word you say.
You don't like use some
like local high school
kids to help you
take care
of the place?
I don't know,
I thought...
Yeah.
Wow, I don't remember
getting high like this.
What's it like?
A lot of things
going on.
happening.
I just used to remember
it being so mellow.
You seem
pretty mellow.
Yeah, but everything
is so intense.
It's like you can
see every leaf
on every one
of those trees
moving individually.
I mean, look at that.
How many leaves do you
think are on that tree?
I... I don't know.
40,000?
100,000 leaves.
Is that your... Is that
your final answer? Well, it's just a guess.
Well, you're...
It's very precise.
A real man of science.
I just can't
believe that you...
You own all of this.
Yeah.
Right.
Like, all of this.
It's like...You ever been
up here before?
No.
No way.
This is like
a really big deal...
For him,
you know?
Bringing me up
here, you know.
I think he thinks of it
like it's the place
he got to be
with you, you know.
Yeah, I doubt that.
He spent most
of the time we
were here hiding
from me in that
tree fort of his.
I was just beginning to
feel like I got all the
grime off from the lake.
Okay. You think it's okay
that we didn't wear pants?What?
I mean we walked
through all that brush
to get up here.
I don't understand
what you're afraid of.
I don't know.
Ticks, Lyme disease,
bed bugs.
So, are you
supposed to lie
if I ask you about those
people who showed up.
I...
Is the house already sold
or is he still working
out the deal?
I assumed your
father would have
told you already.
It's his house,
he can do
whatever he wants.
I'm starting
to get hungry.
That happens.
Did you get enough nuts
and berries for breakfast?
What'd you eat,
chestnuts?
You know what, just
for that you... No...Bamboo shoots?
You're gonna get...
All right, you're
gonna get an amazing
vegan dinner tonight.
Let's not get
carried away.
No, I'm...
It's decided.
Once you've voiced
your prejudice.
Yeah, what are
we gonna have?
Twigs?
Let's not...No.
I don't know,
you might even...I take it back.
I don't know.I take it back.
You might turn vegan
once the master chef
is through with you.
The Master Chef?
I saw your show
on television.
You were excellent. It's not
me. It's Seth.
Seth?
He's never cooked
for you before?
Cooked? Seth?
Cooked for me?
No.
Why?Are you kidding?
It's like having
your own personal Emeril.
I... I find that
hard to believe.
His mother cannot
boil an egg.No.
Teresa, she...she makes
some good stuff.
You know Teresa?
Yeah.
No, we just...
We've met like
a few times.
Hey, you wanna
finish that?Yeah, spark it up.
Why stop now?
So, where did
he learn to cook?
All those restaurants
that he worked at.
Right. Right.
I knew he was a waiter
at some point.
But, he was a chef?
I mean, I don't
know about that.
But, he was like,
in the kitchen,
you know?
Some really nice places.
It was like, Mercer.
There was that place
Eleven Madison.Eleven Madison?
We used to go
to Eleven Madison
all the time.
I used to take Vicky
to Eleven Madison.
It's really nice.
It's good.
Did he like it?
No. He hated it.
He's...
It's just...
It's so good that he
doesn't have to do
that anymore, you know.
He's never...
He like, never...
Seth's never mentioned
me before, right?
He's afraid of what
you'll think of me.
How long have you
two been together?
Going on like,
two years.
Where do you live?
Are you asking me
if we live together?
Do you?
You don't want
to ask your dad?
Yeah, he's been so
forthcoming with information.
Can you stop
doing that please?
Why, is it
bothering you?
It's terrifying me,
actually.
Which I'm guessing
is your intention.
But you can consider
my stability
sufficiently dismantled.
Sorry for almost
drowning you earlier.
It's okay.
Thanks. Thank you.
So, how'd it feel?
Pulling up those boards?
You know, you sound
like a shrink sometimes.
And how does it make you feel
when I sound like that?
Seriously, you're a shrink?
God!
Manhattan, a lawyer
and a psychiatrist.
Okay, Brooklyn.
Mr. Musician.
What's Andie?
A non-profit worker?
She told you that.
No.Seriously, you
didn't know?
I swear.
Fuck.
God, is everybody
that predictable?
You know, I spent a
whole night in here once.
In the middle of February,
it was fucking freezing.
Why would you do that?
I don't know.
My dad yelled at
me or something.
So, after I went to bed
I snuck out.
Came up here
and waited.
And what happened?
Nothing.
I got the worst flu
I ever had,
missed two weeks of
school and he never
even mentioned it.
I doubt he even knew
you were up here.
Whoa.
Hey.
Where are
you going?This is good stuff.
I don't wanna let
it go to waste.
I'm good.
No, thanks.
You don't know
what you're missing.
But he was like...Then he refused.
He was like, seven.
He refused.Aw!
He absolutely refused
to go in that pond
without his little
cowboy hat on.
Entirely buck naked,
except for the hat.
That is so cute.
Shit!
They're coming.
Be cool. Be cool.
Hey.Hey.
Hey there, cowboy.
What is so funny?
We were...
We were just...
Gil, are you
smoking pot?
What...what...what.
Wow, this is something.
Have some.
Can she have some?
Of course.
No, no. I'm okay.
I'm sorry. Sorry.
Baby, come here.
Hey, is that...
Is that the syrup tap?
Yeah, just gonna
put this inside.
Hey.Just wait.
Don't get it all
over the place.
What? I can't smoke pot
in my own house?
Jeez.
She is great,
by the way.
Really great.
Who?Andie.
Yeah.
This is really
good cheese.
Hard, sheep's milk
cheese from Holland.
Twenty bucks a pound
at Balducci's.
It's cheaper
to buy a lobster.
Sorry.
I'll put the rest back.
No come on.
Go ahead.
So, I guess you turned
cheeseterian?
Gotcha.
God damn it.
Every time.
Every single time
you do this.
Every single time.
I haven't touched that
thing in probably 15 years.Doesn't matter.
Every single time,
you do that.
Shit!
Hey, will you leave
that thing alone.I'm done.
So, how is the
real estate market
up here?
How is the what?
You know...
How are things
selling in this area?
Look, I never
use the place.
It's incredibly expensive
to maintain,
the taxes alone
are a fortune.
I was meaning to
bring it up to you.
Hey, you!
Say, what's that
bed doing here?
I don't see it
doing anything.
There's something
funny going on
around here.
When I looked in this room,
there were four beds here.
Those guys never
get old, do they?
It's all fixed.
Watch what you want.
Where did you find that?
It was just laying
around somewhere.
You know,
it's not like I just...
Invited him to smoke
with me, you know.
He caught me.
You are free to do
whatever you want.
We were actually
having a very good time.
You know,
everything was fine
until you showed up and...
I'm sorry,
I interrupted you
cavorting with
my fucking dad.
Fuck you.
I don't understand
why you have
to be so dramatic.
My, you put
a nice little scratch in it.
I don't think you know,
how lucky you are
that you got to have
a place like this.
Growing up with your dad,
to take you here.
I mean,
most people don't...
You know, they don't...
They don't get
that kinda shit.
For me growing up,
this is the kinda place
I would only see in movies.
You know it was
a special occasion
when we were splurging
on going to see a movie.I know, I know.
You have a chip
on your shoulder about
growing up penniless.
No.
Actually, I wasn't
raised to pamper people
who are acting
like spoiled brats.
I'm sorry, I just never...
I've never seen you
like this before.
You know,
not everyone's family
can be as close as yours.
Baby, I'm up here
with you and your family
this weekend.
What are you doing?
Are you even
the least concerned
about me?
Like what's happening
with my mom...
I've got a lot
of other things
to be thinking about
besides you.Did something happen?
Did anything happen?
She is not getting
any better, Seth.Right.
Okay, that is
just what it is.
I know.
I'm sorry.
Look, my brother,
you know, is taking
care of everything.
I'm just...
I'm thinking
about going back.
Of course
you're going back.
I mean, is it hard
to get time off work?
Are they giving
you a hard time?
No, I'm thinking about...
Moving back.
You mean moving out?
I don't know.
Yeah, maybe.
Baby, look at me.
I'm not leaving you.
Okay? I'm just
saying that...
I might be leaving.
You can come with.
We could get a
big house for cheap.
Or we can stay
with my brother.
I'm sure that'd be his
dream come true.
He would really
like you once he got
to know you better.
I just started the
new record with Pete.
I know.
I can't smoke pot
in my own house.
So...
You and Vicky
sell the place.
What are you going
to do on the weekends?
I don't know.
But I'm sure Vicky
will find a way
to spend the money.
Rent some place.
Private beach.
Would be nice.
You can afford it.
You would be welcome
to come and stay.
Is this thing permanent?
Is anything permanent?
Vicky.
Vic.
Yeah, babe.
Where is the shampoo?
It's right in front
of you on the left.
I don't see it.
Never mind.
Here it is.
I like Andie.
She is a catch,
isn't she?
Yep!
So, how are you feeling?
Are you still stoned
out of your mind?
What?
What did you say?
Seth was really
upset before.
Well, you know Seth.
He gets like that.
You don't think
you have anything
to do with it?
What? Why am I
on the stand
all of a sudden?
This has nothing
to do with us.
Maybe it has everything
Have you ever heard
of the word "respect."
You mean like
R-E-S-P-E-C-T?
No, no. Be serious.
Seriously.
You didn't even tell him
you were selling the house.
Well, I was gonna
work up to it.You know what, Gil.
I'm just too old
for this shit.
Are we gonna make
a family or aren't we?
I don't understand
where this
is coming from.
I... You said
you wanted to stay,
so we stayed.
That was before I realized
you were gonna act
with such neglect.
Neglect?Yeah.
I see. I see.
He is the little boy
and I'm the,
neglectful father.
I get it.
You know what?
Come to think of it.
I'm not surprised that
you took his side.
Really? And what
side is that, Gil?
And what side is that, Gil?
Enough with the questions.
You know what?
You are right.
I'm just gonna sit here
and enable you
to transfer responsibility
onto everybody else
but yourself.
All right,
with the analysis.
It's ridiculous.
He's not 12 years old.
He is an adult.
We are both adults.No, you are the father.
Gil, act like it.
I made an appointment.
What?
When? Why would
you do that?
Without talking to me.
I'm talking to you now.
No, you just went ahead
and made that decision.
Somebody had to.
Can we not
talk about this?
Right now?
Here. In the middle
of all this.
There is
no more time, Gil.
Time's up.
Honestly, I don't know
if I can...
Take care of
any more people.
Baby, we will take care
of everyone together.
Really?
Yes.Really?
Like how you
took care of me
in the kayak?
Or how you took
care of Seth
when he was a kid,
up in the tree house...
Seth...He almost got pneumonia.
He gave you the
tree fort story?
With the flu and the...
Yeah, that's a classic.
And you fell for it,
I'm sure.
I wanna do this with you.
And I know you
wanna do it with me.
So, why are you
so worried?
'Cause I don't wanna
end up like this.
Like what?Like you and Seth.
It's not one of
those decisions
you can just make and
change your mind later.
I'm not changing my mind.
No one's changing
his mind.
You sure?I'm sure.
You know,
he used to sit there,
on that rock
when he was a kid.
For hours. Practicing.
And if he even thought,
you might be listening,
he would stop immediately,
and wait for me to walk away.
I don't need another
screwed up family.
Neither do I.
You checked for ticks?Ticks?
I haven't checked
for ticks.
No, you haven't
checked for ticks?
Maybe I should check
you for ticks.Yeah?
I know where you're
going to start.
Come in.
Hey. The next train
leaves in about 30 minutes.
Great. Thank you.
I appreciate it.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
It's nothing.
It's just, you know...
It's like so many things
at once and...
I'm kind of stepping
on everyone's toes here.
So I think I should
just probably
take off tonight.
You know,
I said the exact,
same thing to Gil,
about 15 minutes ago.
Great minds think alike.
Hey.
Vicky.
Yes, babe.
Have you seen
my cell phone charger?
It is right
where you left it. There you are.
Have you seen
my cell charger?
Did you move it?No.
Then it's right
where you left it.
It's not there.
I didn't move it.
Okay.Um...
I found this.
And...
It's not Vicky's,
so it must be yours.
Thank you. I was
looking for that.
Let's go
find your charger. I didn't touch it.
What's in here?
I saw you hiding it.
You know what it is.
I want you to tell me.
Did you go back
to that jeweler
on Seventh Avenue?
It's the plain
silver one?The one we looked at.
And that's why
you brought me here.
Doesn't matter now.Of course it matters.
I can return it.No, you can't.
Why not?
Because you had them
engrave some sort of funny
poetic inscription on it.
How do you know?
Because that's
what you would do.
I want...
Can I look at it?
Not unless you
wanna buy it.
I don't know.
Then don't.
I don't even know
what this means, like...
Hey. If you
want that ride,
we should go.
Andie.
I think I'm
actually going to stay,
after all.
Good.
Do you really
think I was gonna
leave you all alone,
so you could feel
abandoned and blame me?
That's what's going
to happen eventually.
Well,
I don't know
about that, but...
It's not gonna happen
tonight, so...
I don't understand
why we're doing this.
They're not going
to think it tastes
like anything.
Shit!
What?I cut myself.
The knife is so sharp.Are you okay?
Yeah. Can you, can you
manage for a bit. I'm just
gonna go deal with it.
How bad is it?
Let me look.
I'm just gonna
go clean it up.
Hey, Gil,
are you in there? Yeah.
What's up?
Hey. Sorry to interrupt.
Um, I just sliced
my finger off. What?
I...Are you okay?
Did you clean it?I'm gonna.
I just.
We're at a really
critical phase of
dinner prep
and I'm kind of
useless.
You think you could
help him out down there?
Just for like,
a little bit?
Me?Yeah.
What do I know about
vegan cooking?
Don't worry,
he'll tell you
what to do.
Andie said you might
need some help.
Um, where is she?
She cut herself.
She sent me as
a substitute.
Um.
Okay. You think you can,
go make sure
the grill is on?
Yes, sir.Thanks.
Andie!
Shit.
Did you just
yell something?...
No.
Okay, well, you're
all set out there.Thanks.
What do you want
to do with these?
It's best if you
cut them long ways.
Not circular.
It's good.
So, what's on the menu?
Um, a few things, actually.
This is a lentil dal.
Indian kind of thing
and then...
So.
What's on the menu?
There's a lentil
tomato thing there.
Then there's
some greens.
Your work now is gonna be
this ratatouille inspired
vegetable thing.
That's what I'm making.
You're just grilling
the vegetables.
I'll add them later but
it's better when you grill
the vegetables first.
Did you learn all this
at those restaurants
you worked at?
Yeah.
Did you like it?
I hated it. It was awful.
I can imagine.
Well, it's a good thing
you don't have to
do that anymore.
I do.
Every now and then,
I just pick up a shift
when I'm a little short.
Seth, I must say,
I'm impressed.
And Gil. And Gil.
I hope you realize
that's organic quinoa,
sauted tofu, corn, cilantro,
no animals, no additives.
It's one of Seth's
signature dishes.
I know.
I helped him make it.
We didn't tell you.
We put extra butter in yours.
Just for you.
I'm sorry. All right?
I'm sorry.
I'll get that.
I have
a question.
Um, what's "derby"?
You guys kept saying "derby."
We were on the
Housatonic, was it?
Class four water.
Class two at most.
It was big,
wherever it was.
Seth did a roll
and he came out of it
and then I did a roll,
then he did a roll,
then I did a roll,
and then at some point,
Seth said, "It's like
a roller derby."
And now, that's
what you say when you
come out of a roll.
"Derby."
Drove my sister nuts.She was just jealous
of the boys.
Here we go.No, you know,
it's interesting,
I was reading
an article
and this evolutionary
biologist had this theory
about why men
are generally
drawn to sports more.
The biology articles
that he reads,
are in Maxim.
No, but it's
interesting.What did it say?
The article was saying that,
there's a difference,
in the evolution of the
male and the female brain.
Basically dating
back to like, hunter
and gatherer times.
And men, were drawn
more to activities
that allowed them to
exercise their judgment
of spatial dynamics.
Like throwing a spear at
a buffalo or whatever.
Throwing a pass
to a wide receiver.
They had to judge
all these different
spaces and times
and hit a moving
target just right.
And so, women
are really good at
finding the tomato
in the refrigerator,
because we're gatherers.
Makes perfect sense.
There might be some
basis to the fact
that our brains
are different,
just because all men
seem to think that way.
No. Seth, is this true?
Seth claims women
don't know how to
step out of the wind.
What did you claim?I didn't
claim anything.
Honey!
Yeah. Maybe you should put
that in one of your songs.
You know, I saw you
down there today.
You should play them
your new song.
It's, it's really good.
I haven't performed
that one yet.
Yeah, but it'll be
the perfect opportunity.
Yeah, well, after dinner,
if you're up for it,
maybe we can get
a private concert?
I don't know. I mean
I only have a guitar
and it isn't...
It's not...
I read that review
of yours in the Voice.
You did?Yeah. Your dad
showed it to me.
It was a well
written review.
He was like a little boy,
showing off his report card.
Okay. Now, when
I get back tomorrow,
I will take you over
there and you can
pick out a new one.
Any one you want.
All right?
All right, it's getting
past your bedtime now,
so here's your mom.
Good night, kid.
Hi, sweetie.
No. No more computer
games tonight, baby.
I love you, sweetie.
Now go to bed.
Gil said that um...
I should open this.
So...
Gil.
What am I supposed
to call him?
Andie.
What are you doing?
I know how to
put wood in fire.
Just hold on and...
Shit. Sorry.
It's fine. It's fine.Are you okay?
Where's the cut?
What? Maybe it just,
it healed.
Yoo-hoo.
I shouldn't have
brought you here. Hey guys!
How am I supposed
to trust you?
Well, you didn't
trust me before.
Seth?
Is there a concert
tonight or what?
Can you hold this?
I just, I have to go
to the bathroom.
Is everything okay?
Yeah.
You want some wine?
No. I'm all right.Glass is
already poured.
God, it gets cold
out here at night,
doesn't it?
That's what
the fire is for.
Turn up the thermostat?
Here, sit here.
It's closer, it's warmer.
You're better?
Is it possible that it
actually got colder.
Are you always
this persnickety?
No.
I think these
wide open spaces
sort of...
Make me nervous.
The city just tricks
you into feeling like
you're not alone.
I don't think
you're alone.
What do you want?
What do you mean?
Is this some sort
of exchange
where you let him
fuck you and he helps
provide for your kid?
Fuck.
Are you drinking?
I'm just holding it.
Your breath
smells like wine.
I can have a glass
of wine if I want, Gil.
Hold this for
a second.
Old lady doesn't like it
when I eat this stuff.
Adds an extra layer.
So you sneak it?
And by taking this spoon,
you agree not to tell her.
Dad, I won't tell.What's the password?
Are you really
doing this right now?Password.
You're seriously
going to...What's the password?
Swordfish.Good man.
Remember that place
on the corner?
The one in town,
the ice-cream place?Yeah, I do.
That's the kind of place,
you will never
find ice-cream
like that again,
for the rest
of your life.
That's it.
Forgot to bring
the bug spray.
Here, try this.
It's Andie's.
God.
It says organic garlic
and black pepper.
Is that for vampires too?
You know,
I'll take my chances.
You know what works
really well?
Standing next
to a woman.What?
I don't
know what it is,
but their blood is
different or something.
But women are like fly paper,
did you ever notice that?
I don't know,
every time I'm with Andie
she complains
about getting bitten.
Yeah. See.I only do when
I'm by myself.
Pretty soon that'll
be the only advantage to
a heterosexual relationship.
I like Andie by the way,
a lot.
Me too.
You like Vicky?
Yeah.
But?
Nothing.
We're thinking
of getting married.
Really?
It's a '97 Barolo,
by the way.
How old is the kid?
He's eight.
Who is the father?
Not me. Some doctor,
I don't know who.
You wouldn't know him.
You like him?The kid?
He's a nice kid.
Congratulations.
So, where is
he this weekend?
Jake is with his dad.
That's crazy.
I mean it's not...
Crazy, but it's just...
You know, I... I never
would have guessed.
Well.
I had him when I
was younger than you.
Would it be okay...
Is it, is it weird if
I asked you what happened
with your marriage or...
No.
What happened.
What didn't happen.
You want my professional,
or my personal opinion?
I want professional.
Okay. Um...
Where do I start?
Michael and I,
we were...
Madly in love.
We thought that that
meant we were strong.
And we decided
to have a child.
And it's the most
amazing thing.
Starting a family.
But you have to create space.
Like, literally
create space.
So, all of a sudden, there's
this little person and he's
sleeping in bed with you.
It's like adding
another lover.
Sounds like Seth's dream.
Hey there,
it can be.
There's just so much
that changes that you
could not predict
before you have kids.
You know, like...
You can't give each other
the same amount of love.
It's weird. Like your
love gets divided.
We weren't
prepared for that.
And I think we just...
Couldn't accept that
there was some part
of our relationship
that died.
And then resentment
sets in, and...
You get the picture.
Wow.
That's your
professional opinion.
That's my
What's your
personal opinion?He was an asshole.
No. I'm serious.
It was like one morning,
he just rolls over
and says, "I don't think
I am ready for this."
For what?Exactly. Like...
We already have a son.
You know, what's there
to be ready for?
Sorry,
I didn't mean to...No.
You're not the
jerk that left.
Is that why you went
for like, an older guy,
because he'd already
been through his
mid-life crisis?
I guess I am his
mid-life crisis.
What comes after
the crisis?No, I... I.
I hadn't thought
of it that way.
See, this is...
You're selling the house
so you can take care
of Vicky and the kid?
Not that simple.
Long vacations,
pay for tennis lessons.
You never cash
the checks I send you.
I don't need
your money.
You didn't seem to
mind taking it to
pay for college.
So, this is how you
try to make up for it?
Make up for what?
How things went with
your first family.
Why would you say
something like that to me?
What do you
want me to say?
You sound just like
your mother.
God, I am so sick
and tired of being
criticized, judged.
I just want to enjoy
the rest of my life.
Did it ever occur to you,
you might be happy for me?
There wasn't room for
everyone in that family.
I'm different with Vicky.
I can...
Relax.
Actually feel good.
She listens to me.
There isn't a whole
life of mistakes
and guilt between us.
Why do we have
to talk about this?
We were having
such a nice time.
Do you realize,
this is the most
we've ever talked?
Well, maybe there is
a reason for that.
When you have kids,
you will understand.
Understand what?
You can't talk
about everything.
No.
You know,
if I ever I had kids,
I was going to turn
this into a hockey rink
in the winters.
That would have been
a good idea.
You said this would
always be here.
I know. That was
a long time ago.
Things change.
I have other people
to think about now.
Do you ever think there's
a difference between
not saying something
because there's
nothing to say...
And not saying
something because...
Well, there's
just too much.
God. God. What, what, what?
What happened? What are we
going to do?
She saw
something.What did you see?
I don't know.
I just saw a piece,
but it was huge.
Where were you? She was inside,
getting a glass of water.
In the house?
Are you sure
you saw something?
Honey, what is
the matter with you.
We are in danger.
Well, you said
it was in the house.
Well,
what if it came outside.
What if there are others.
Relax, will you.
It's probably
just a raccoon.
Well, what?
Are you just gonna
leave me here?
All right. Come on.
Shh.
I think I hear something.
You're fucking with us.We are not
fucking with you.
Probably
just a raccoon.
It is not
a raccoon.
It's probably
just a raccoon. It's not a raccoon!
Holy shit.
Holy shit!
That is so cool. My God.
My God.He's going to make
a fucking mess in there.
Gil, there is
a bear in our house.
What are we gonna do?I think we don't do anything.
What? What?
I don't...
Don't knock
that lamp over.
My God.
It's probably more scared
of us than we are of it.
I don't think
that's possible.
Where did it go?
You think it came outside?
Well, Gil, don't you have
a gun or something?
A gun?
I'm a member of
the Audubon Society.
Well, can you
call somebody?
My phone's in the house.
Well, what are
we gonna do?Just stay calm!
Everyone,
just stay calm.
We'll go look in
from the other side
of the house.
Just... Come on.
It's gonna be fine.
Just be smart.
Come on.
Come on!
Shh! Shh!
So, we're gonna just keep
walking around trying
to draw its attention?
Just relax.This is insane!
Just relax.
What are we doing?
It's spilling all over
the goddamn wood floor.
Is there oil in there?
It's organic.
Extra virgin, cold pressed... Gil!
...unrefined.
What the hell
does that mean?
It means it's
really green.Fuck!
Really? These floors
can't be damaged.
Come on, Gil!What?
Focus.On what?
Protecting me
and your child.
It's...
Early still.
I didn't want you
to find out like
this up here.
Any other children
you failed to mention?
No, Seth.
Of course not.
We haven't
told anyone yet.
You know, you can play
30-year-old all you want.
You can get a new house.
You can get a new wife.
You can get a new...
...son, but, I
can't get a new dad.
I wish I could.
You know how many
times I've called
you and hung up?
How many emails I've
written and never sent
because I knew
you wouldn't respond?
You think this just
happened to you?
You think this has
been easy for me?
That is a total cop out.
You have never done anything
to try to fix anything.
What would have been
good enough for you?
There's nothing that would
have been good enough for you.
Nothing was ever
good enough for you.
You know, we both
made a choice.
You didn't choose me
and I didn't choose you.
And maybe that was a mistake
and maybe it wasn't.
Fuck it. I'm gonna
go scare this thing
out of there.
Wait. Wait. Gil. Yeah, that's a real
responsible thing to do
with a new baby on the way.
You know, I don't
need a lecture on
responsibility from you.
You're the reason
the bear's in the
house in the first place.
How the hell do
you figure that?
Why do you think we have
a bear-proof garbage can?
So you can just
throw shit near it and
leave it on the ground?
Why didn't you leave it
a fucking invitation?
The trash can was
a mess when we got here.
I'm the one who
started cleaning it.Yeah.
And it was what?
The tooth fairy that
left the wet towels
on the bathroom floor?
What difference
does it make?
The house is sold
anyway, right?
Why not let it
just be a mess?
Why do you care
if it's sold?
You never come up here.
You're just waiting
for me to die so
you can have the place.
I come up here all the time.
I just usually do
a much better job
of making sure
that I don't run into you.
Will you guys please stop
acting like children?
Will you please just
stay out of this, all right?
We don't need your help.
Stop trying to help.
That was a $320
German casserole dish.
Gil.
What?Do something.
Hey. If you're so
worried about your
goddamn baby,
what are you doing
drinking wine?
It was probably that
vat of syrup that you
spilled all over the deck.
I didn't spill the syrup.
He did.
Whose side are
you on anyway? There are no sides.
No, you please
stay out of this.
Hey, don't talk
to her like that.
This isn't her family.It is her family now.
Shut up! Enough!
Shit.
I'll put this
in the trash.
What you doing
in here?
Just looking around.
It's held up
pretty well,
hasn't it?
Yeah.
So, why the hell did
you wanna come up
here this weekend?
I...
I wanted to maybe
talk to Andie
about getting married.
And then I showed up
and spoiled all the fun.
I don't think I can
actually blame you
for this one.
Well.
I'm sure you'll...
Work it out.
There's no reason
to rush into anything,
you know.
There's plenty of time.
I wish somebody
had told me that
when I was...
Your age.
It goes on and on.
Watch your step there.
Gil, thanks
for having us.
It was nice meeting you.
And, um,
nice meeting you.
Thanks.
Seth, it was great,
finally, to meet you.Yep.
And spend some time.
Yeah.
All right.
Here, here, here.
Take some...
Take some gas money.
I don't need any money.
Let me give you
some gas money.
I don't need that.
I know you don't
need it, but...
I'm giving it to you.
Thank you.