Yee-haw!
Whoo-haw!
Hyah! Hyah!
Yee-haw.
But it's been six weeks
since the surrender, sir.
How long must our boys remain
in your prison camps?
We can't just
turn them loose, Mr. Cole.
We have to arrange
transportation, food--
Then arrange it, sir.
By heaven, had the victory
been ours--
When may I see
General Good?
I'll tell him
you're here.
Excuse me.
Captain Martin,
right this way.
The general's
expecting you.
Captain Martin, sir.
Captain, I'm a busy man,
so I'll get right
to the point.
I have a job here
I think may interest you.
This chest
is all that's left
of a million-dollar
gold shipment
lost at Phantom Hill.
One of our patrols found it
right about here,
20 miles
from Phantom Hill.
And the gold
from that chest
and 19 others like it
is hidden out there,
somewhere.
How do you know
the gold
never reached
the Confederacy,
General?
We have
General Lee's word,
and he is an honorable
man, Captain.
Here. Take
a look at that.
Joseph Henry Barlow.
He was one of the Rebs
at Phantom Hill.
A few weeks after the raid,
he was captured.
He knows where the gold is.
He's finally admitted it.
But what's more important,
he's agreed
to lead us to it.
Why?
Because we have something
he wants.
It's all in there.
Before the war,
he was serving
a life term in prison
for murdering
a federal marshal
in Texas.
I see.
And in exchange
for a pardon,
he volunteered to join
the Reb army.
That's right.
But now the war is over,
we could send him
right back
to prison again,
but we made
a deal with him.
The United States
Government will recognize
that Reb pardon
if he leads us to the gold.
There's just one thing you
forgot to mention, General.
Phantom Hill is right
in the middle
of the Staked Plains,
and the Staked Plains
are part of the territory
the government
just gave to the Comanches.
And under the treaty,
the Army is forbidden
to set foot in that country.
That's why this meeting
is unofficial, Captain.
That's why you're to forget
this conversation
the minute you leave
this office.
And that's why, provided
you accept this assignment,
you'll be completely
on your own.
And if anything
goes wrong,
the United States Army
and the federal government
will deny
they ever heard of you.
What would I do for men
and supplies?
This will buy you
all the equipment
you need.
As for men,
you'll find them waiting
for you at Hays City.
Well, do you
want this job,
Captain Martin?
You know I do, sir.
Yes, I know you do.
I'm very sorry
about your brother.
He was a fine officer.
We lost a lot of good men
at Phantom Hill.
Well, at least I hope you'll have the
satisfaction of completing his mission.
Thank you, sir.
Good luck.
Oh, Captain,
don't forget.
Barlow is a killer.
? Look away
look away, Dixieland ?
? I wish I was in Dixie
Let's get out of here.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Oh!
When are you gonna
let me out of this thing?
When I'm through
with you.
Ha, ha.
Just relax.
You'll be a free man
in a couple of weeks.
Free, yeah,
but it ain't gonna be
like I figured it would.
Well, a man can't have
everything, Barlow.
A man can try.
Oh, hey, come on back.
The war's over.
You gotta come back,
big boy. [ laughs ]
He got away!
Hey, what's
going on there?
Stop the train.
You're right handy
with a shooting iron,
ain't you?
Don't try that again,
Barlow.
I don't want
to have to kill you.
Not yet, anyway.
That's right.
Well, let's not worry
about it till
the time comes, huh?
Meanwhile, you still
got your hand
and I still ain't got
no holes in my hide.
So no hard feelings,
huh, Captain?
No hard feelings.
All right.
Hold it, fellas.
What's it mean,
Sheriff?
It means
exactly what it says.
Army's got no right.
How you gonna hunt buffalo
if you can't get
where the buffalo are at?
All right now.
Break it up. Come on.
Come on.
Get out of here.
Break it up, boys.
Afternoon, gentlemen.
Afternoon. We'd like
a room for two.
Sign the register,
please.
25. Up the stairs
at the end of the hall.
Thank you.
Mr. Martin?
I'm Adam Long.
I think you two
know each other.
Well, I guess
you could say we met.
We didn't take time
to introduce ourselves
that day
at Phantom Hill, did we?
I'm Joe Barlow.
I guess you understand
there was nothing personal
in that roughing up
we gave you.
How many men
do you have
with you, Long?
There's four of us.
- Only four?
- That's right.
Where are they?
Krausman and O'Rourke are
down at the livery stable.
Dr. Hanneford's
at his hotel.
- Dr. Hanneford?
- That's right.
We haven't any use
for a doctor.
I was told
to ask for volunteers.
I wasn't told
to reject anyone.
All right. Have the men
at the livery stable
at 8:30 tonight.
Yes, sir.
Let's go.
- Sheriff.
- Hi, Charlie.
Sit down.
Forget it, Barlow.
Anybody ever tell you
you got a mean
and suspicious nature?
Yep.
And no sense
of justice, either.
None at all.
It ain't like
I stole the gold.
It was captured
by the Confederacy.
Legitimate spoils of war,
that's what it was.
Only there ain't
no more Confederacy,
so I got just as much right
to that gold as anybody,
including the United States
Government.
It might pay you to
think about that, Captain.
- Who is it?
- Open up.
It's Sheriff Drum.
What's this?
You signed the register
Matthew Martin.
Is there a law
against a man
giving his real name?
- Is it?
- It is.
Where you from, Martin?
Depends on
where I was last.
This man
a friend of yours?
What difference
does it make?
It might make a lot
of difference, mister.
I might have
to take you in, too,
for helping
an escaped convict.
- Get your hands up, Barlow.
- Now, wait a minute--
Hold it!
Maybe you don't
remember me, Reb.
I was a guard at the federal
prison in Austin, Texas,
when you started serving
a life sentence
for the murder
of a U.S. Marshal.
So that's the burr
under your saddle.
Well, this'll set
your mind at ease, Sheriff.
It's a full pardon
from the governor
of the state of Texas,
given to me in exchange
for volunteering
to serve in the Army
of the Confederate States
of America.
Hey.
The U.S. Government doesn't
recognize any Reb pardon.
- What do you mean--
- Joe.
Sheriff, there must be some
way of working this out.
There's nothing to work out.
I got a pardon.
Relax, Joe.
Just relax.
Look, Sheriff, do you have to
make an issue out of this?
The war's over.
Why not let bygones be bygones?
I still don't like Rebs, and I don't
want them around my town.
Well, then
you got no problem.
Joe and I are pulling out first thing
in the morning for Santa Fe.
Santa Fe?
Yeah, that's right.
We're, uh, we're starting
a freight line there.
All right.
All right, I'm gonna
do you boys a favor.
You be out of Hays City
by 7:00 tomorrow morning
and I'll forget
I ever saw you.
Don't forget,
7:00 in the morning.
That was easy.
Too easy.
When you men volunteered
for this mission,
you were told your
destination was Santa Fe.
Well, that's not true.
We're going out
on the Staked Plains.
Well, I can see you're all
familiar with 'em.
Why in the devil are we going
to that land of Satan?
We're going after gold,
O'Rourke,
$1 million in gold
that the United
States Government
lost to the Rebs
at Phantom Hill.
And Mr. Barlow's
gonna lead us to it.
Captain, the Staked Plains
are 100 miles--
100 miles inside the new Indian
treaty lands, Doctor. I know.
That's why we're going
as civilians.
If the Army was caught
violating the treaty,
it could lead to a general
Indian uprising.
So once we leave here,
we're on our own.
From now on, I want you
to forget you're soldiers.
If we get picked up
by a military patrol,
we'll be considered
deserters.
If we're caught
by the Indians,
it's our funeral.
Is that understood?
Krausman? O'Rourke?
I get it.
One more thing.
You'll all wear sidearms.
- I--
- That includes you, Doctor.
Like me, you'll each carry just
two shells in the chamber.
Since we won't be able to keep
Mr. Barlow under lock and key at all times,
he might be tempted
to appropriate somebody's gun.
If he did, he might be able
to kill two of us,
but that'd leave him with an
empty gun and three men.
Six bullets
still against him.
I want us on the road
by 7:00 in the morning.
Put a little lift
into it now, lads.
Ah. You wouldn't have
a wee spot
for the bite of the snake
in there, would you, Doc?
All right,
let's roll.
Mr. Martin.
I hope you have
a nice trip to Santa Fe.
Thanks, Sheriff.
You know, Martin,
a man does a favor,
he kind of expects
a favor in return.
Doesn't that
seem fair to you?
Depends.
Well, you know, the westbound
stages aren't running
because of that new treaty.
It means changing the routes,
setting up new relay stations.
Be a couple of weeks now before
things get back to normal.
So?
So I've got a passenger
for you.
A passenger?
That's right,
for Santa Fe.
Sorry, Sheriff,
we don't have any room.
- Make room.
- Now, look--
You make room in your wagon
for my passenger,
or I'll make room
in my jail
for Joe Barlow.
Now, it's exactly
two minutes
to 7:00, Martin.
Where is your passenger?
Waiting across the street
in front of the hotel.
Adam.
Her?
You gotta be kidding,
Sheriff.
Martin,
there are some things
I don't have
much of a sense
of humor about.
One of them is Rebs
and another
is women like that.
This is gonna be a long, hard trip.
How do you expect me to put up with a...
Oh, don't worry
about that.
Memphis
is used to traveling.
She made all the camps.
That's great.
And you're asking me
to take her to Santa Fe.
I'm not asking you
to take her
any more than I'm asking her
to leave Hays City.
I'm telling you,
telling you both.
Now, come on.
Krausman, O'Rourke.
Memphis,
this is Mr. Martin.
Ma'am.
I talked Martin
and his friends
into letting you travel
to Santa Fe with them.
Well, that was real nice
of you, Sheriff.
Shall we go, ma'am?
Why not?
Put the lady's luggage
in the wagon.
Good-bye, Memphis.
Oh, I'm not gonna say
good-bye, Carter,
'cause I'm coming back
to Hays City someday.
Oh, I wouldn't
like that a bit.
I'm coming back
and make you
and everyone else
in this rotten town
crawl on their hands and
knees to apologize to me.
Six of you, huh?
That should make
for an interesting time
between here
and Santa Fe.
Very interesting.
All right,
let's get ready to roll.
You don't have anything
to worry about.
Worry? After what
I've seen and done,
I don't know
how to spell the word.
Now, where do I ride?
Up there, Miss, uh...
Just Memphis.
No last name.
Mother was the kind
that never asked questions.
Easy now, darling.
That's the way.
Sit right down.
Git-up.
- Pull up, O'Rourke.
- Whoa.
Krausman,
ride up and tell Long
we're stopping
for 15 minutes.
At the rate we're going
the last two days,
we should be in Santa Fe soon,
shouldn't we?
- Don't you worry about it.
- Well, shouldn't we?
- Something wrong?
- No.
You're lying.
Mr. Barlow tells me
we're not going to Santa Fe.
But you'll get there, all right.
How?
Gonna be stopping for water
at a trading post
in about three days.
It's run by a man named Brant.
He has a freight line to Santa Fe.
He'll take you there.
Do you mean
you're gonna leave me and...
You'll be as safe with him as
you are with us, believe me.
Believe you?
Look, Martin, I've known
men like you all my life,
men who have no respect
for anyone.
Carter Drum
runs me out of town,
you help him,
and then you dump me off
like a sack of potatoes
in the middle of
God knows where.
Two-bit captain
or tin-horn sheriff,
you're all alike.
Shh.
I want to talk to you.
What about?
A million dollars in gold.
Over there.
Now, what's this about
a million dollars in gold?
It's what
the captain's after.
You want to hear
about it?
Well, I'm listening,
aren't I?
If I hadn't been captured
by the Yanks,
I'd be a rich man
by now.
Why are you
telling me this?
You're a smart girl.
You'll figure it out.
So what do you
want me to do?
I'll let you know
when the time comes.
Interested?
There's just
one more thing.
How do you know
it's still there?
That's a good question.
I'll tell you how he knows.
A Reb officer
and six enlisted men
made off with the gold after
the fight at Phantom Hill.
That was the last that was seen
of the gold or the men,
except for Barlow.
Remember that, Memphis.
He's the only one
who came back.
Aah!
Krausman!
No. No.
No, no.
Now, just take it easy.
Easy.
Get your hands off me.
His neck is broken.
Hardly more than a boy.
Painted for war, trying
to make a name for himself
by stealing our horses.
This spells
a raiding party.
They won't be long
in missing him
and tracking him here.
Let's get those horses
ready to move.
We're not gonna bury him?
Sorry, Doctor.
We don't have the time.
Now let's get out
of here.
Git.
Hup! Ahh.
Get in there!
Swing 'em into midstream
wide, O'Rourke.
Watch out for quicksand.
Right, Captain.
Hyah! Hyah!
That's the way, lads. Pull!
Come on. Git-up.
Hyah! Git-up! Hyah!
Pull! Pull! That's it.
Come on, lads.
Hyah!
Hup!
Ho! Git-up there.
Git-up!
Get the wagon
under cover
of those trees.
Krausman, break out the
extra rifles and ammunition.
The rest of you, picket the
horses over there.
All right, we'll dig
in here and hope
they don't spot us.
If they do, they'll have to
come across the stream.
The fight'll be on
our terms, not theirs.
Can you handle a rifle?
Just point me in the right
direction, Captain.
Me, too, Captain.
All right, let's go.
All right, stay down
and don't fire
till I give the order.
Krausman!
All right,
we got 'em on the run.
Let's keep 'em moving.
Krausman! Krausman!
Krausman, you disobey another
order, and I'll break you in half.
My bag is in the wagon.
Now, somebody, please,
this man is bleeding to death.
That was murder,
Mr. Barlow.
You don't murder
an Indian, Hanneford.
You just kill 'em,
like you shoot a rattler
or step on a bug.
I'll take the rifle,
Barlow.
What're you doing out here if
you ain't got no taste for killing?
What I'm doing out here, Mr. Barlow,
is my own business.
As far as my not having a taste for
killing, you're right about that. I don't.
And the irony of it is
for every man
you've killed in your life,
I expect I've killed
a hundred, maybe a thousand.
Thanks.
Well, even the best
of us can make a mistake
now and then.
Whoa.
Is Brant around?
Brant?
He's been dead
more than two months.
I took this place over.
I keep meaning to clean up
around here, but...
I believe the lady
would find it cooler inside.
That water any good?
I drink it.
Krausman, O'Rourke,
fill up the water barrels.
First saloon we come to, and here
we are drawing a barrel of water.
House always buys
the first drink.
Then you're on your own.
Whiskey? Tequila?
- Tequila.
- The same.
Three whiskies.
You fellas come far?
Far enough.
You going far?
I can tell better
when I get there.
Them new Indian lands
start just south of here.
Supposed to be out of bounds for
anybody except the Comanche.
Don't suppose
you heard that?
Yeah, I heard.
Government says they gonna go
hard on anybody they catch out there.
Tell you what I'll do,
friend.
What'll you do?
I'll mind my business
if you'll mind yours.
I understand you run
a freight line to Santa Fe.
No, not since the Comanche come raiding
through here and burned out the ranches.
You got some freight
for Santa Fe?
No, a passenger.
- The girl?
- Yeah.
Could be arranged, maybe.
I been thinking
about going in
for supplies.
I hear you're trying
to get to Santa Fe.
Yes, I am.
Might take me
a few days
to fit up.
There's a room in the back
you could use.
Not too fancy,
but the bed's comfortable.
Forget it, mister.
This ought to cover
the drinks.
- Let's go.
- Now, wait up now. You've got this all wrong.
Why, this lady'd be as safe
here as in a church.
Let's all have a drink
and forget it.
Just friends, huh?
That's the way.
Everybody, belly up.
I said, let's go.
But, Matt, I ain't had
me first one yet.
- O'Rourke.
- Drinks, he says.
Thanks.
Look, I'm sorry you're
still stuck with me.
Look, get this straight.
I didn't do that for you.
Do you mean you thought
I'd talk about the gold?
That's right.
Oh, well,
in that case...
Memphis, get in
the wagon.
Is that the only reason
you don't want to leave me?
Well?
Just get in the wagon and
change those clothes.
Hold on, mister.
You ain't paid
for that barrel
of water.
How much?
That'll be about,
uh, $50.
It's his water, friend.
Oh, well, you go ahead
and tell him, then.
$50.
Look, that's the only well
in 100 miles of here.
Git-up. Git-up. Git-up.
Oh!
Anybody'd pay $50
for a barrel of water
could only be headed
one place that I know of.
Like maybe
the Staked Plains.
I wonder
what they're after.
I don't know,
but whatever it is
must be mighty inviting.
Sure does arouse
a fella's curiosity.
Wait a minute.
You been here three days
eating and drinking.
What about your bill?
Oh.
I got more
than this coming.
You didn't mark
the graves?
No.
I just walked the horses back
and forth trampling the ground flat.
Hard to tell where
your brother's buried.
He came
a long way to die.
Tell me about it, Adam.
Didn't you read my report
to General Good, Captain?
I read it.
Then you know
the whole story.
I don't know
what the convoy
was doing here,
almost 100 miles south
of its original route.
- The Comanches were at war, Captain.
- So were the Rebs, Lieutenant.
Your brother wasn't to blame
for what happened here.
I hadn't thought he was.
We gonna camp here
tonight?
No.
We've still got an hour or
so of daylight. We'll move on.
Yes, sir.
There's your Staked Plains
out there, Captain.
A misplaced piece of hell
if there ever was one.
How much further, Barlow?
Well, that's hard
to tell.
We sorta lost track
of things after we left here,
what with that wagon full of
gold getting heavier and heavier
and the men and horses dropping
and the sandstorms scouring us raw.
Where's Krausman?
He was here
a minute ago.
Captain.
Krausman, what--
Still warm.
Comanche.
10, 12 ponies
headed south.
Straight for
the Plains.
I'm gonna ride up ahead,
take a look around.
Keep moving for another hour,
then make camp.
I'd like to ride
with you, Captain.
I'll bet you would.
If I'm not back by morning
break camp and keep moving.
You're not to waste any time
looking for me or waiting for me.
That's an order, Long.
Shouldn't somebody
go look for the captain?
You volunteering, Doc?
Leave him
alone, Barlow.
I was just asking
a question, Memphis, honey.
After all, the doc here
must be quite a guy,
considering all the men
he says he killed.
Tell us about it, Doc.
- Barlow.
- I want to hear about it.
How'd you kill 'em, Doc?
It was very simple,
Mr. Barlow.
I worked in a slaughterhouse
the Army called a hospital,
and when they brought the
wounded in by the thousands,
I chopped off their hands
and feet and arms and legs
and I bandaged them up
with dirty rags
and I stood there and watched
them bleed to death
or die of gangrene or shock.
When the war started,
I was a surgeon,
and when it was over,
I was nothing but a butcher.
You call me a doctor,
but I'm not a doctor,
not anymore or ever again.
Maybe things ain't as bad
as you think they are, Doc.
I mean...
if you had some money...
and could go someplace,
like, say, California,
take a nice long rest,
forget about the war,
then maybe someday you'd feel
like starting all over again.
When you come
right down to it,
we all got something
ailing us.
But you take a million dollars,
even split five ways,
that's mighty powerful
medicine.
Ain't nothing in the world
that wouldn't cure.
What about the Comanches?
They're out there,
all right.
I don't know how many,
but they're there.
So until we know where they are and what
they're up to, we're gonna keep moving.
Pull up, O'Rourke.
Whoa, boys.
Whoa.
Heavy cusses,
ain't they?
That's 'cause they're airtight
to protect the gold.
We dumped 'em
to lighten the load.
Didn't do much good.
Couldn't have been more
than 10 or 15 miles
before the horses give out
and we had to hide the stuff.
All right,
let's make camp.
You know...
I been thinking about what you
said to the sheriff back in Hays City,
how you'd be back someday
and make him
and the whole town
come crawling to you
to apologize.
Anybody with
half a million dollars
could make Hays City sit up
and bark like a dog.
You'd like that,
wouldn't you?
I'd love it.
All you gotta do
is get me a rifle.
First chance you get
after we pick up the gold.
Why not?
There it is.
There it is, boys.
Hyah! Hyah!
Look at the gold.
Just look at the gold.
Unbelievable.
All right,
let's get it loaded.
Well, Captain, I did
my part of the bargain.
Now you keep yours.
When the job's done,
Barlow.
It's done.
Your amnesty will be recognized
when we get to Fort Hays and not before.
How do I know you Yanks
won't back down on the deal
and send me back
to Austin Prison?
Because you were told.
When this gold is returned to
the Army, you'll be a free man.
Now, if you're in a hurry,
get to work.
Gold always was
my favorite color.
Are you coming?
What's the matter?
Afraid I'll hide one
in each stocking?
Well, hello again.
Just bring it
right on down here.
You know, a fella's eyes play
tricks on him out in this country.
Sees things that ain't there, like
running water, green grass, trees.
I even seen a herd of buffalo
once that weren't there, but
I never did see no gold.
That gold
is as real as real.
Drop them gun belts,
all of you.
Do as he says.
I wouldn't do that, mister.
One shot'll bring every Comanche
within five miles riding down on us.
Maybe there ain't no Comanche
within five miles.
Well, then all you gotta do
to find out is pull that trigger.
No Comanche ever heard
a skinning knife at work.
O'Rourke,
move the wagon up.
Let's get
that gold loaded.
Gonna leave them
for the buzzards, too?
That's right, Doctor.
Captain!
It's empty.
Don't look
at me, Captain.
I get just as thirsty
as anybody else.
How much
have we got left?
Well, there's only
the one barrel left,
and it's a third gone.
Let me see
that map.
I don't suppose
you'll believe this,
but there's a water hole
about 50 miles north of here.
You sure
of that, Barlow?
I'm alive, ain't I?
Of course I'm sure.
That's the way
we went.
Must mean Eagle Wells.
Do you know it?
It was on
our original route before...
before we decided
to turn south.
Here's Eagle Wells.
There's another water hole
30 miles north of that.
Sabine Springs, here.
Sabine Springs.
All right, let's get that gold
loaded and move out.
- Adam.
- What is it, Captain?
Barlow's down at the picket line.
He's saddling a horse.
Let's go get him.
No. I'm gonna follow him,
see what he's up to.
I want you to keep your eyes
on things while I'm gone.
You didn't have
to come after me.
I would have
caught up with you.
Who's buried there?
We didn't have time
to carve his name,
and without shovels,
we couldn't dig too deep.
But here lies Major Armiston,
dead by reason of snakebite.
What about the others?
Did the same snake
kill them, too?
I told you, I don't know
what happened to 'em.
A couple of them took off on their
own, and I got separated from the rest.
I kind of liked the major.
He and I got along
real good,
and I was curious
if the Comanches
had found his grave.
They'd as soon scalp
a dead man as a live one.
And you came
this far out of the way
just to make sure?
Yeah.
- Start digging.
- Huh?
You heard me, dig.
With my bare hands?
You buried him that way,
didn't you?
Now dig him up.
You satisfied?
I'm gonna tell you
just one time, Barlow.
From now on,
stay with the wagon.
Captain.
I'm just played out.
Both of us, I'm afraid.
- Drink some of this.
- No.
Drink, damn it.
That's an order.
Thanks.
Help him
into the wagon.
Ooh, ooh, easy, boy.
Let's go, Doc.
Forget the saddle,
Krausman. Just take the gear.
Captain,
I'll take care of him.
We'll travel afoot
for the next hour.
That ain't too healthy,
Captain. Take a look.
They see us
leading our horses,
they might get the notion
we're too far gone
to put up
much of a fight.
Yeah, and the only
sure way I know
of bringing 'em buzzing down
around our necks is to make a run for it.
So we'll walk.
How far to Eagle Wells?
Ought to make it
before sundown.
I figure the least they'll do
is try to cut us off.
That's not their style
of fighting.
Just waiting.
For what?
We'll know
when the time comes.
Now we know why they weren't
in any hurry to cut us off.
This hole's
been blasted
and not just
recently either.
I may be
wrong, Barlow,
but somehow I get the impression
you're not entirely surprised by this,
nor much
concerned either.
Are you accusing me,
Lieutenant?
Because if you are,
let me remind you again
that I can get just
as thirsty as anybody else.
I went through that once,
three days of no water.
It ain't something
I wanna do over.
Put that thing away, Krausman.
Put it away!
All right, break it up.
You heard me. Break it up.
Is there any chance
of getting the horses
to Sabine Springs?
They'll pull no more
without water, Captain.
We must be facing it.
'Tis the end
of the line,
I'm thinking.
Not yet, O'Rourke.
Not yet.
Just coyotes.
Ha ha.
What are you doing
up here?
You're supposed to be
on the north ridge.
What good would I be
up there without a rifle?
You can yell, can't you?
Now get up there.
Barlow's right.
Those aren't coyotes.
No, they're not.
But remember this, we've
got rifles and a clear field of fire.
Those Comanches will have to
think twice before they do more
than just squat there
barking at each other.
Yeah, and what happens
after they think twice?
You were in love with that sheriff
in Hays City, weren't you?
That farewell speech
you made,
the way you looked at him
and he looked at you.
What right
do you have--
- Tell me about it.
- You go to hell.
Tell me!
All right, Captain.
Yes, I loved him.
Then a young lady
came to town.
Oh, she was a very
respectable young lady
with a very
respectable father
who was the president
of a very respectable bank.
And that's when
Carter Drum
decided to clean up Hays City,
starting with me.
Now, is there anything else
you'd like to know
about Memphis
Whatever-Her-Name-Is?
Memphis?
What's the matter?
Anything, Adam?
No.
Barlow. Oh.
What you trying to do?
You'll get yourself
killed sneaking
up on a man like this.
Anyway, you're not
supposed to be out here.
I thought maybe
you was thirsty.
Whiskey.
Oh.
Oh, 'tis a miracle.
That's what it is.
Where did you ever get it?
Brant's.
What in the devil
you been saving it
for, man?
Oh...
Captain, I got
one of them spotted.
I'm gonna work down
from here and cut around
behind him.
- Here, you keep me covered.
- Forget it.
We're not here
to collect scalps.
I got 17
of 'em. 17.
I swore it on Anna's grave
and the baby's.
I said 10 scalps for you,
Anna, and 10 for the girl.
They still owe me three.
That's all I want.
That's all
I come here for.
Now, you
keep me covered.
Krausman. Krausman.
Now you
listen to me.
We got just one chance,
and that's getting
to Sabine Springs.
You help us get there, and you can
kill 20 Comanches for all I care.
You promise?
Yeah.
But all I want is three.
Just three more scalps.
I am not saying I will,
and I'm not saying I won't.
What I am saying is
I need another drink.
No, you don't,
Barlow. Heh.
I'm on to you,
trying to get me drunk
- and make away with my rifle, huh? No.
- Me? Trying to get you drunk?
Look, if you've had too much,
just hand the bottle back.
- Let's forget all about going partners.
- Well, I didn't say that.
I'm turning it over
in me mind.
Oh, it's that dry,
my mouth is.
What happens
if they attack, Captain?
They won't.
Not tonight,
not tomorrow.
Not till we get to Sabine Springs
and find it's been blasted, too.
Blasted?
How do you know?
Why didn't they try
to cut us off today?
Because they knew
the well was dry.
Why haven't they hit us
tonight?
Because they know when we get to
Sabine Springs, it won't help us either.
Well, what are you
gonna do?
I'm gonna get the truth
out of Barlow
if I have to use Krausman's
scalping knife on him.
- Then it's a deal?
- It's a deal.
And I have your word,
Barlow.
There will be plenty
of water for all of us.
Why did you...
why did you...
Up here, Doc.
Stay with her, Adam.
Keep under cover.
Get out of here!
Go on!
Go on,
get out of here!
Get out of here!
- Adam, what the blazes you doing?
- Drop your rifles.
Drop 'em.
Now the guns.
You first.
Left hand.
Krausman.
Stand over there
beside him, Lieutenant.
He was on top of me
before I had a chance.
It's my fault,
not yours.
You wasn't
much help to me,
was you,
Memphis, honey?
But maybe
it wasn't your fault.
Now, you think you can
pick up them guns
without getting a pretty little
finger caught in the trigger?
Try it.
How far do you think
you're gonna get, Barlow?
Just don't you fret
about me, Captain.
By the time the Comanches
get finished with you,
I'll be on the downhill
side toward home.
Now the canteens.
What good
are they gonna do you?
There's not a drop of water
among the three of them.
I know,
but there's nothing
like leaving
a tidy camp behind you.
That's fine.
Now climb on.
You better go with him.
Come on, come on,
come on.
You can count on
better treatment from me
than a dozen
buck Comanches.
Them Comanche
must be mighty curious
about what's been
going on up here.
This ought to
really stir 'em up.
All right, let's go.
Come on.
Hyah!
Adam, I want you to build a fire,
a big one.
Are you crazy, Captain?
We gotta get out of here.
Now, how far do you think we're
gonna get afoot without rifles or water?
Right now, we got only one
chance, and that's the Comanches.
Barlow invited them in. Now
let's make it easier for 'em.
Get that fire started.
Krausman, you come with me.
Hyah!
You all right, Captain?
I can make it.
I got the horses.
Let's go.
Krausman!
Krausman! Captain!
Let's get out
of here, Adam.
Whoa.
Yes, sir.
I'm gonna really
live it up.
Reach me one of them
canteens, will you,
Memphis, honey?
I got a lot
of living owed me,
two years of prison,
four years of the war,
and that stinking
prisoner-of-war camp.
Ahh.
You know, honey,
I almost forgot
what a woman's
voice sounded like,
but you sure
fixed that.
So I see.
Hyah! Git-up.
We better get off
and rest that leg, Captain.
We're not gonna be able to go
much further without water, Captain.
We'll make it.
We've got to.
I gotta tell you
something.
I gotta tell you about
your brother, Captain,
why he changed our route.
What do you mean?
Jim was out of his head.
He didn't know
what he was doing.
He'd give one order one minute
and contradict it the next.
He shouldn't have
been in command.
I should have taken over.
Then why didn't you?
Because I was scared
and I didn't have
the guts to admit it.
That's why I left it on my
report to General Good.
I was protecting myself.
Were you?
Were you protecting
yourself
or were you protecting
a friend?
- Don't waste it.
Waste it?
Memphis, honey, you just don't seem
to understand, do you?
We got nothing
to worry about.
Here, make
yourself useful.
Water them nags while
I fill up the canteens.
Where's the other canteen?
What canteen?
We had three of 'em this morning.
Now there's only two.
Where's the other one?
How should I know?
You're lying.
All right, big man, I'll tell
you where it is.
It's about five miles
behind us.
Now, you listen to me.
Dropping that canteen
was stupid.
Say Martin gets away
from them Comanche.
Say he finds a canteen.
Say he comes
out of this alive.
What then?
You looked appetizing
enough to him out here,
but back where a gentleman
like him comes from,
he wouldn't walk across the street
to spit on you if you was on fire.
Stop fooling yourself,
Memphis.
You're trash.
You're trash,
just like me.
Only difference is
I'm rich trash
and you're poor trash.
But it don't have
to go on being that way.
You just say the word.
You can have the whole world,
right here...
Memphis, honey.
All you gotta do is remember
what you are.
We lost 'em, Captain.
The wind must have
covered their tracks.
Warm some more rocks.
The principle
of condensation, Adam.
For the same reason
dew forms at night.
Cold air striking
a warm surface.
Warm rocks
against the night air.
result: moisture
and maybe enough water
to keep us alive.
Water.
Tight as a canteen.
Couldn't take much water from the
first grave, but here he really loaded up.
Farsighted man,
Mr. Barlow.
First, he kills
the officer in charge,
then he talks the others
into following him.
Hide the gold till after the
war. Then we'll all be rich.
Gets the men to fight
amongst themselves.
Then he fills
the chests at Eagle Wells
and Sabine Springs,
blasts them dry against
any possible Yank pursuit.
All the time he was burying
his own private water supply
against the day
he'd return.
Let me see
that map, Adam.
Here's the first grave,
then Eagle Wells.
Now this one.
And there's Sabine Springs.
Straight on line.
Dead north.
And with that wagon, Barlow's gonna
have to take the long way around.
I think we've eaten
his dust long enough, Adam.
Let's beat him
to the next one.
Hyah! Hyah!
Come on. You can dig
as good as me.
Right here.
Come on.
Dig. They gotta be here.
Go ahead, dig.
You can dig clear to China,
but you won't find any water.
Where's the others?
They're here.
Yeah?
Why don't they
show themselves?
Krausman.
Lieutenant.
So it's come down to you and me,
huh, Captain?
You're through, Barlow.
From now on, I'll always
be one jump ahead of you.
Grave by grave, you'll
find nothing but sand.
You stay here.
All right,
you know what to do.
Be careful.
All right, Captain.
You throw rocks
and I'll throw lead.
Matt!
Well, he dug
most of his grave anyway.
The lady helped
considerably.