- Would you autograph
this for me, please?
- Well, of course,
with pleasure.
I think
it's one of your best.
Except, of course,
Murder On A Honeymoon.
- Well, I'm always at my best
on a honeymoon, you know.
Now, then what shall we say?
To the charming hostess who
made my trip so pleasant
and never let me down.
How is that, huh?
This aircraft
is about to land.
Will all passengers kindly
button their safety belts?
- That's what's called
letting you down with a bump.
- Archie, come here.
I know you're
excited and so am I,
but there's no need to show him.
- Hey, what are you
doing there I'm driving?
- But you don't know
where we're going?
- Don't I?
A, we're going to London,
B, we're going to
celebrate and C...
- Oh, no we're not.
- I can't think why
you're so keen about
this living in the
country business.
It all seems pretty grim to me.
- You wait till you
see it in the daytime.
- Well, where is this wretched
cottage of yours anyway?
- Near Redminster.
- Kate, not that awful
place of Philip's?
Why, it's got pumps
and outside whatnots.
- Nonsense, it's been converted.
Beside, I've even got a woman
to come and look after it.
Darling, do stop worrying.
Everything's under control.
Oh, oh.
- Hurry up, darling.
- Oh.
- What is it now?
What on earth did
you put it there for?
- Well, I didn't put it
there it just put itself.
- Wheels don't put themselves
anywhere, my sweet.
Now come on, don't mess about.
Look, you just sit in
the car while I fix it.
It's gonna pour in a minute.
- I was only trying to help.
- Yes, I know, so
just sit in the car
and leave it to
someone who knows how.
- I don't want to
be inquisitive.
Are you looking for something?
- No, no.
It's just our way of having fun.
We've lost our nut.
- A rather silly thing to do.
I'd come out and help
you to find them,
but I haven't got my glasses.
- Well, can you give us a
lift to the next garage then?
- That wouldn't help.
- Why not?
- I'm the nearest garage
and I'm not there, am I?
- No, and it's very
lucky for us, isn't it?
Otherwise, you wouldn't
be here, would you?
- I'm beginning to think it's
very lucky that I am here.
- We really are in trouble.
You see, we're complete
strangers around here,
and we simply got
to get to Shepstone.
But you will help us, won't you?
- My difficulty in life
I'm never able to
resist a pretty face.
I've got an idea that
I'm not going to now.
I'll run you over.
- Well, what about the car?
- We'll see to that
later it won't run away.
Get your things and I will put
them in the back of the car.
Step back a little.
Here, we are at last.
Didn't take long, did it?
- Time is.
- Come on, gorgeous.
Careful, dear.
- Thank you so much.
I think you're wonderful.
I think you're...
Oh, never mind.
- Come on, Archie.
- Come on.
Nice cheerful welcome
from Mrs. Jones.
I suppose she's gone to bed.
- Here I've got a spare key.
- Good.
Oh, darn, now I
can't see a thing.
That's better.
Now, wait a minute while
I find the light switch.
Oh, Archie!
Drew, what are you doing?
I tripped.
- Well, stay where you are,
or you'll wreck the place.
Oh, darling.
- Well, you told me
to stay where I was.
Don't be so silly.
- Oh, well! I expect
it's woken up Mrs. Jones,
which is probably a good
thing in the long run.
Now, she can get us some food.
- Andrew!
- Yeah?
- Doesn't look as though
there's gonna be any Mrs. Jones.
- What, but I
distinctly remember...
- Look.
- "Dear Madam, I'm sorry,
"but my daughter is in trouble
"with her first and
I have to go to her.
- "Your food is in the cupboard,
"hot water bottle in bed,
"two pints ordered for morning.
"Hope to be back Monday.
"Yours faithfully," Emma Jones.
Please be careful
"with the drinking
water tap in kitchen,
"as plumber didn't
come as promised."
Well, I must say that's
a very fine start.
- You can't really
blame her, darling.
After all, it is her first.
And anyway, I think,
it'll be rather nice
to be left on our own.
Hm.
- Well?
- Well, it's not bad.
- Oh, I think it's wonderful,
and I'm sure we're
gonna have a lot of fun.
Now, darling, all you
have to do is relax.
I'll see to everything.
But there is just one little
thing I would like you to do.
There we are, Archie.
That's better, isn't it?
Andrew!
- There.
That should keep the
darn thing quiet.
- I'm sorry, darling.
- It's all right, I suppose
you couldn't help it.
- Look, you go upstairs
and get your coat dry,
and I'll finish getting dinner.
- What's it gonna be
Tinned baked beans?
- Now, darling,
don't get peevish.
I promise it's going to be.
Wonderful.
Absolutely wonderful.
- You think, my
cooking has improved.
- Who said anything
about cooking?
It's you, I'm talking about.
Oh, darling, I do love you so.
- And, I love you too.
But I've got all
this to clear away.
- Oh, let it wait
until the morning.
I really
ought to do it now.
- You know, I'm
beginning to think this
country idea of
yours is rather good.
Peaceful and quiet.
- Somebody knocking?
- No, it's probably the wind.
Don't be silly.
Look at Archie.
- Must be Mrs.
Jones has come back.
- Not at this time of night.
Besides, she's got her own key.
- Now, well, who cares.
- You'd better see
who it is, darling.
- All right.
Hurry up it's raining!
How much longer am I going
to be kept waiting here?
Are you deaf or rude?
Take my coat.
- Well, certainly.
- I'm soaked.
Tulip's the name.
- Miss?
Certainly.
Go away, dog, go away!
Go away!
- Archie, stop it.
Miss Tulip, this
is Archibald Dax.
Now, you're not to
bark at Miss Tulip.
- My car has broken down.
I've no intentions of
spending the night in it
or walking two
miles in this storm.
- No, but naturally not.
- Naturally not what?
- What you said.
- Quite, I'm glad
you see my point.
Well, isn't anyone going to
show me to my room, Misses?
Or is it Miss?
- Misses.
Allow me to present
my wife, Kate.
- How do you do Miss?
- Tulip I told you once,
Millicent Tulip, from the coast.
- Forgive our ignorance.
You see, we've only
just arrived here.
So, we haven't had time
to make acquaintances.
- Come along, cigarette.
Strangers, eh.
So, that's why I
didn't know your faces.
- Please don't apologize.
- Young man, I never apologize.
Come along, matches, quick.
What are you doing here?
Planning a murder.
- A murder?
So, you are the writer?
- Yes, he's the writer.
- Oh, why did I ever come here?
- I say, have you read
any of my efforts?
- Of course, all of them.
They're terrible.
Terrible.
Each one worse than the last.
- Surely, they're not
as bad as all that.
- I think, they're very good.
- And with any luck
"Murder By Motive"
should get the book
of the month award.
- Books?
- Are we talking about books?
Well, of course.
- Do you write books?
- Yes, he's the Andrew Dax.
- Dax?
Never heard of it.
So, you didn't
write those letters.
- What letters?
- The anonymous letters.
They keep coming.
I received the last tonight.
Those letters.
I had to get away.
Then the car broke down.
When you both started
to talk about murder,
I thought they're
after my money.
The Tulip money, you know.
You must hide me.
I'll be safe here.
I can't go back.
I can't.
- Of course, you can't.
Now, what you need is
a good night's rest,
and tomorrow morning
we'll send for the police.
- The police, never.
Idiots, the lot.
And yet, maybe you're right.
They should be informed.
- Of course, they should.
Now, I think, you
ought to go to bed,
but, first of all, I'm gonna
go make you some hot milk.
- Not hot, cold, and
put some whisky in it.
So, you write, eh?
- Occasionally, Miss Tulip,
when conditions are
favorable to concentration.
- Interesting, most interesting.
I am a distant relation
of Anthony Trollope,
the writer, you know.
- Yes, I have heard
of Mr. Trollope.
- Mr. Dax, my revolver.
If anyone attacks
us during the night,
don't ask questions, shoot.
- But, he may shoot first.
- Then you've had it.
- Here you are, Miss Tulip.
Shall I show you to your room?
- And now to bed.
Isn't he coming?
- Oh, no, Andrew wants to
stay down here and work.
Don't you, darling?
What
at this late hour?
- Yes, he's very behind
with his present book.
- I see, just bone lazy.
Oh, well.
- Distant relative
of Anthony Trollope.
- Thanks.
It's much too late
for drinking, darling.
Besides, I need it.
- So, do I.
- Cheers.
- Miss Tulip.
- Well, that reminds me.
I've got another
little job for you.
She wants you to lock
her jewelry in the safe.
- Safe, we haven't
got a safe, have we?
- I know, but I haven't
got the heart to tell her.
You think she's mad?
- God, mad as a March hare.
- Poor, old thing was
very frightened, though.
- Not half as
frightened as I was.
Oh, what a woman.
She gives me the shivers.
- This is gonna give you the
shivers in more ways than one.
I've lent her our
only hot water bottle.
You know, darling, there are
times when I almost like you.
If I let you go to bed now,
will you promise to
finish your book tomorrow?
- You know, darling,
there are times
when I almost like you, too.
- Andrew.
Andrew.
There's someone coming upstairs.
- Hello, darling.
You awake?
Of
course, I'm awake.
You crashing about the house
like a bull in a china shop.
- Oh, I'm sorry, darling.
I was being as
quiet as I could be.
- That's just the point.
If you'd made a real noise,
I'd have know who it was.
- It's all my fault, darling.
You just go to sleep and
choke me off in the morning.
- Archie?
Archie?
Andrew!
- Darling, are you
hurt, what is it?
- It's Miss Tulip.
She's dead, isn't she?
- Yes.
Quite dead.
- Andrew, if only we'd
been nicer to her.
Why, we weren't
to know, were we?
We didn't know she
was going to die.
- Of course, we didn't.
- It's all so terrifying.
If we had known.
- Stop it!
Stop it, stop it, Kate,
or I'll sock you!
- You wouldn't.
- I would, you know.
- I'm sorry, Andrew.
- That's better.
- I'm all right now.
Look, you run
along out into the garden,
and I'll have a look around.
- Andrew, I'm sorry
I was such a baby.
Anyway, you have
all the atmosphere
you want for your books now.
Andrew, it's awfully
cold out here.
- It's all right, darling.
You can come in now.
Feeling better?
- A bit.
Good, well,
sit yourself down and
here have a cigarette.
- Thanks.
You know, I just
can't understand it.
I know, she seemed a bit mad
but to do a thing like this.
- She didn't do it.
It's not suicide, Kate.
She was shot and there's
no sign of a gun.
I'm afraid, it's murder.
- But if she was shot,
we'd have heard it.
- I know, silly, isn't it?
- Besides, how could
anyone have got in?
The French windows they
were open this morning
when I came down.
- Were they?
We shut them last night.
- I know, I thought
Archie might have done it.
- By the way, where is Archie?
- He's gone rabbiting, I expect.
You know, what he's like
when he gets in the country.
- Do you think he's all right?
- Trust Archie.
- Well, it wasn't
forced, anyway.
I wonder if.
- Hm.
- I wonder if she let
someone in herself.
- Why should she?
- Haven't the remotest idea.
The whole thing's so screwy.
Oh, Lord, I suppose I'd better
telephone for the police.
- Andrew, must we
have the police?
- Of course, we must but
it'll be all right, darling.
I know what let's have
a nice drink, first.
- I'd rather have a cup of tea.
Oh, heavens, I've
left the kettle on!
- Kate?
- Hmm.
When the
police do get here,
let me do the talking.
- Of course, darling,
I won't say a word.
Andrew, tea.
May I come in?
Good morning, madam.
There's a car
outside in the lane,
in rather a dangerous position.
- A car?
That's not ours.
Ours is miles away.
We lost our nuts, you see.
- Did you?
I know it's not yours.
It's Miss Tulip's.
Can I have a word with her?
She's here, isn't she?
- No, she isn't.
Not really.
- Perhaps you can tell
me where she's gone?
- Well, I couldn't do that.
- Why not?
- That would only be guessing.
And besides, I promised
not to talk to the...
Perhaps, you better
speak to my husband.
I'll get him.
Andrew.
Andrew, where are you?
He's not there.
- Perhaps he's in the garden.
Very nice, too, early morning,
lovely fresh smell,
nice bit of sun.
"A garden is a lovesome
thing, God wot.
"Rose plot, fringed
pool, fern'd grot.
"The veriest school of peace."
That's not mine,
some other bloke.
What's that?
- What's what?
- I thought so, Aphids.
- Are they?
I'm afraid I don't
know their names.
- Greenfly, to beginners.
Look at them having
a whale of a time.
Won't do, you know,
it won't do at all.
- Terribly sorry.
- So you ought to be.
Any man or woman
who has greenfly on his
roses is capable of anything.
Anything.
- I'll take them off.
- No, no, no, no spray
them with soapy water.
Washing soap, mind you.
None of your scented stuff.
Any man or woman who
squirts synthetic perfume
over a rose is
capable of murder.
- Would you like
some tea, officer?
- Oh, well, thank
you kindly, lady,
but I'm afraid it's
against regulations.
Not on duty.
Mind you, we did have a
lecture last week on courtesy.
It would be
ungracious to refuse.
Thank you very much.
- I take it you like gardening.
- Like it, I love it.
That's why I
transferred down here.
The soil's better.
You can grow things.
Better than that mangy
allotment I had in London.
Why, I had eight years
in London in the Met.
Far too much going on.
Everybody rushing about.
Dope, hold-ups, fights, murders.
Thank you.
Never saw anything like it.
Very different down here.
Nothing ever happens,
all very quiet,
except Mr. Thorne,
our CID Inspector.
Not altogether what you
might call a quiet type.
Now, what's that?
- More greenfly?
- No, over there it's a woman.
- Yes, that's Miss Tulip.
- I thought you said
she wasn't here.
- Well, she isn't in a way.
- I don't quite follow.
Oh, I see 40 winks.
I'm afraid we'll
have to wake her up.
- I'm afraid that will
be impossible, officer.
You see, Miss Tulip is dead.
- Oh, that's different.
What did you say?
- I was just going to
ring for the police.
- It's a good
thing I came along.
What was it, heart failure?
- Yes, in a way, she was shot.
- Shot?
No, sir, don't touch
anything, if you please.
Everything is to be
left exactly as it is.
Hmm.
Nasty.
Very nasty.
I'll have to use your phone.
Where is it?
Thanks.
Hello, Maggie, get me
the station, will you?
It's urgent.
Eh?
The dahlias?
Nah, that ain't
birds, that's slugs.
I'll come around tomorrow
with some powder.
Get them number quickly
though it's very serious.
Dear, dear.
And you were just settling
down to a nice cup of tea.
- Well, so were you.
- I didn't know she was there.
- No, but I did.
That's why I wanted the tea.
- How long have you been
friends with Miss Tulip?
- Oh, we weren't friends.
She just spent the night here.
- Spent the night here,
but you didn't like her?
- I didn't say that I just
said that we weren't friends.
- Pardon, my mistake.
- We didn't like her.
As a matter of fact,
she was very rude.
Stalking in here
and demanding a bed
and milk and a hot water bottle.
And she seemed to
think that we'd just
give her whatever she wanted.
- Did she want that?
- Want what?
- Murder.
- Now you're being silly.
- Madam, as a proud but humble
member of the police force,
I must ask you to
withdraw that remark.
- Weill, I don't mean
that you're silly.
I just meant that it
was silly to think
that she'd want to be killed.
- Apology accepted.
But you better be
careful of Mr. Thorne.
As I said before, he's not
altogether the quiet type.
Oi, where are you off to?
- To finish dressing.
I want my coat.
- I'm afraid, I must
ask you to remain here
until the Inspector arrives.
- Oh, all right.
Is there any objection to
my having a cup of tea?
- That if I may say so,
sir, is entirely a matter
between you and your conscience.
Yes, yes, yes.
- Hello, Mr. Thorne?
Detective
Inspector Thorne here.
- 215 Feathers talking.
At 10:00 a.m. this morning,
as I was proceeding
along Shepstone Road.
- Get on with it.
- In the course of my duty.
Don't
blether about your duty.
- In the course of my duty!
For heaven's
sake come to the point, man!
- In the course of my duty!
Come to the point.
- I'm coming to the point.
Will you cut the
gaggle and come to the point?
- How can I come to the point
if you don't listen, sir?
What's it all about?
- It's Miss Tulip.
- What about her?
- She's been murdered.
That shook him.
- Kate, there's something very
funny about this business.
- Doesn't make me laugh.
- Let's try and work out
how it could have been done.
Now, suppose I was the murderer,
and was following her.
Then her car breaks down.
But before I can do
anything about it,
she's in here, with us.
Well, I'd wait.
And then, until
she'd gone to bed.
And then, break in somehow.
- That's no good Archie
would have barked.
- That's true.
Then she must have gone
out and let someone in.
That's it, there was
mud on her shoes.
I threw stones at
her bedroom window,
and she came down and let me
in through the French windows.
Then I did her in.
- Did you indeed?
- Hello, are you
someone I should know?
- I have a feeling
you're going to know me
extremely well, sir.
My name's Thorne.
Detective Inspector Thorne.
- How do you do, Inspector?
This is my wife we were just
reconstructing the crime.
- Reconstructing?
Or recollecting?
- Why, I'm not altogether sure
that I like the implication
of that question.
- I'm not altogether
sure that I intended you
to like it, Mr. Curtis.
- Mr. Dax.
- What's that?
- Not Mr. Curtis, Mr. Dax.
- You told me the cottage
belonged to Mr.Curtis.
- So it does but Mr. Dax
rented it from Mr. Curtis.
- Why didn't you say so?
- You didn't ask me.
- Are you here on holiday?
- No such luck, just working.
- Supposed to be working but
he hasn't done a stroke yet.
Says it's lack of atmosphere,
but it's just laziness really.
In the present murder...
- What my wife means.
- Just a moment, sir.
I'd rather Mrs. Dax
tell me herself.
Yes, Mrs. Dax?
- Well, in Murder by Marriage,
that's what he's supposed
to be writing now.
- Writing?
Oh, yes!
Dax you have all the facts.
I'm very pleased to
meet you, Mr. Dax.
- Are you really, Inspector?
- Yes, you always show us
policemen to be such half wits.
It'll be a privilege
to get a few tips
from such a brilliant amateur.
- I shall be delighted
to assist you
in any way I can, Inspector.
- You really will?
Splendid.
Then perhaps you'll
assist us by telling us
why you didn't ring
us up straightaway?
- Well, I'm afraid my
enthusiasm as a writer
overcame my duty as a citizen.
- He was looking for clues.
- Really, hmm.
Being Mr. Dax I
should have thought
they would have
given themselves up.
Did you find any?
- Oh, naturally.
Come on here, I'll show you.
Look at that button.
It's obviously fallen
from Miss Tulip's hand.
Now it's quite usual for
the victim to be found
clutching a piece of
the murderer's clothing.
But that button is torn
from Miss Tulip's own dress.
- Oh, darling, you are clever.
Isn't he clever, Inspector?
- Extremely clever,
Mrs. Dax, yes.
People do clutch at their
clothing when they're.
I wish you'd tell
me when you're gonna
fire that thing, Wilson.
- Sorry, sir.
- Always makes me jump.
As I was saying,
people do clutch
at their clothing
when they are dying.
- Maybe, but you
don't have much time
when you're shot
through the head.
- You've got a point there.
Any more theories?
- No, not at the moment.
- Oh, too bad.
Well, failing the mastermind,
we'll have to rub along
as best as we can.
I want to see that car.
- Car?
- Yes, the car
Miss Tulip came in.
- Oh, that car.
- Uh, Feathers.
- Yes, sir.
- Just keep Mrs. Dax from
feeling lonely, will you?
- Very good, sir.
- But I want to go too.
- Leave it to me I'll fix it.
Mr. Thorne, you
think Mrs. Dax might.
You heard.
- I fixed it.
You stay here.
- Oh, well.
I suppose I might as well as
make some sandwiches and coffee.
Haven't had any
breakfast this morning.
- What's the matter?
Just a minute where you going?
- There was somebody
there at the window.
I'm sure it was the murderer.
- Now, now, now, it's no
good trying to bluff me.
- But it was a woman
I saw her distinctly.
- Now, now, now.
- Well, go and look for yourself
if you don't believe me.
- Let you slip out
through the front door?
This is P.C. Feathers.
Now, lady, let's be
friends over this thing.
What about that coffee, eh?
- All right, but I'm not
gonna make it by myself.
You'd better come with me.
- Try and keep me out.
- Seems dead all right.
Funny, eh, Mr.Dax?
- Why I don't see there's
anything funny about it.
Cars do stop, you know.
It's just a darn nuisance
that this one packed
up last night.
- Yes, it's quite a coincidence.
- Do you know anything
about cars, Mr. Dax?
- Just enough to switch on
and press the starter
that's about all.
- Wasn't one of your books
called The Garage Murder?
- Yes, but that was
strictly non-technical.
- Was it, I thought
you thought it
with aid of your
mechanic genius.
- I say, you're
quite a fan of mine.
- If you care to
put it that way.
It's a pity you know
so little about cars, Mr. Dax.
- Oh, why?
- Because you could have
fixed this one in a jiffy.
All that's wrong is that
the main distributor lead
has slipped out of its socket.
- Well, it must be loose.
- It isn't.
- It looks as if someone had
deliberately disabled the car.
Almost as if someone wanted
Miss Tulip to spend the night.
Then they
didn't know Miss Tulip.
- Did you, Mr. Dax?
- Eh, did I what?
- Know Miss Tulip?
- Well, not before last night.
- Hmm, quite a short friendship.
Come on, let's get
back to the house.
You know, Inspector,
you're developing a
nasty suspicious mind,
but you're wasting your
time turning it on me.
- You think so that's
your expert view?
- That's my inspired view.
You see, I'm one of the
only two people in the world
who know the vital
fact of this murder.
- You are?
- Yes.
I know I didn't do it,
and the murderer knows he did.
And if you'd concentrate
on finding him
instead of making cheap
cracks about my book...
- I'm conducting this
investigation, Mr. Dax.
And I'll turn my
nasty suspicious mind
in any way I think
it'll do most good.
- All right, I was only
trying to be helpful.
Routine investigation, Mr. Dax.
I don't like to be caught
by unexpected discoveries.
- Well, then I don't
expect you'll like that.
- After her, Akers.
We'll head her off this way.
- You take your
hands off me, Tommy.
'Cause I wasn't doing any harm.
- Now what's all this?
- You tell this great lout
to take his hands off me.
- All right, Akers.
Who is she?
- Miss Gale, sir.
Miss Tulip's companion.
She's rather deaf.
- What are you
doing here, Judith?
- Don't you shout at me.
- All right, leave it to me.
What are you doing
here, Miss Gale?
- Speak up, can't you?
- What we want to know...
- I heard.
It's Miss Tulip.
She didn't come home last
night and I got worried.
- Why didn't you
phone the police?
- I don't hold with telephones.
I was going down to
the police station
when I saw you all
nosing around the car.
And I thought I'd better
find out what was happening
before I said anything.
Who's he?
- Mr. Dax, a tenant
at the cottage.
We'd better go inside.
- Strangers, eh?
I don't hold with strangers.
- I'm afraid you're
not going to hold
with what you'll
find inside either.
- Sit down, Judith.
- Eh?
- I said sit down.
- Why, I'm not tired.
You sit down if your
feet are troubling you.
- No, I can stand up.
- Well, where's the mistress?
- You'd better prepare
yourself for a shock.
She's had an accident.
- Accident, how?
- We don't quite know.
You don't have to try
and break it gently.
You mean she's dead, don't you?
Yes, she's been murdered.
- You forgot the sandwiches.
That's her, the
woman in the window.
Who is she?
- I'm Miss Gale.
Who are you?
- This is Mrs. Dax.
Now, there is no...
- That'll do, Feathers!
- Yes, sir.
- Well, shall we
have some coffee?
- Not for me.
- She doesn't hold with it.
- Feathers, darling.
- Uh-oh, you're undermining
discipline, Katie.
- Don't be so silly.
Of course, he can
have some coffee.
Can't he, Inspector?
- Take it, man, and
stop all this chitchat.
- Well, if you insist, sir.
Thank you.
- Now, Judith, a few questions.
Did Miss Tulip seem
at all strange lately?
- Not more than usual
except for her tantrums.
I'm not really surprised
she got herself murdered.
I'm saying that
it was her nerves.
- She wasn't strong then?
- Strong, hah.
She was as strong as a horse.
No, it was that doctor
always hanging around
and dosing her up with medicine.
- Sandwich, sir?
- Yes, thank you.
Care for another?
- Nerves, indigestion was
the only trouble with her.
She ate too much and too fast.
All she needed was a good
dose of bicarb of soda.
Told her so, and him too.
I don't hold with doctors.
- Good morning, good morning.
Sorry to be so long.
Such a fat bouncing boy,
Mrs. Capes, you know.
Thought at one time
I'd lost the father.
Nervy type.
Well, Inspector, what
have you got for us today?
Not another road
accident, I hope.
- No, worse than that, Doctor.
Over here.
- Millicent!
It's Millicent!
When did this
terrible thing happen?
What's she doing here?
- I'm sorry to give you a
shock, Willis, I didn't know.
- Don't you pretend
you're sorry.
- Judith Gale, what
are you doing here?
- I have as much
right here as you.
More, I wanted to help her.
- Help her, you know you
always hated your mistress.
- I wasn't always trying
to borrow money from her.
- How dare you.
- That's enough!
We'll go into all this later on.
Meanwhile, I want
your medical report.
You can also identify the body.
- Yes, of course, I'm sorry.
- Oh, Inspector.
I'd be obliged if you'd
let me go upstairs
and finish my dressing.
Feathers here seemed to
prefer me in my shirtsleeves,
but it's really
getting very drafty.
- He wanted to get
his coat earlier, sir.
I thought he'd better wait
till you'd been over the house.
- You were quite right.
- Thank you, sir.
- For once.
Go and get it for him.
Know the room?
- No, sir.
- First on the left.
It's a gray tweed.
I dropped it when I
heard my wife scream.
- Thank you.
- I suppose it
couldn't be suicide.
- Impossible.
- What about the gun?
- What do you mean?
- What type and caliber?
- We'll have to
remove the bullet
before we can discover that.
Where are her rings?
- Rings?
- Yes.
Her fingers were always
covered with them.
Valuable too.
- Are these the ones?
- That's them.
- No doubt about it.
- Where did you get those?
- On the floor,
by Mr. Dax's coat.
- Can you explain this?
- Yes, I can.
- I'm not talking to you!
- It's quite simple.
- I'm sure it is.
I understand now why you were
so anxious to get your coat.
You know, Mr. Dax,
this puts rather
a different
complexion on things.
- Does it?
Might I ask one question?
- Is it important?
- Yes, very.
- Oh, go ahead.
- May I put my coat on?
- Certainly, Mr. Dax.
I wouldn't like to take you down
to the station in
your shirtsleeves.
- This is ridiculous!
Why, Miss Tulip
gave him the rings.
- On half an hour's
acquaintance?
- Yes, I know it sounds absurd,
but then the whole
thing was crazy.
- Certainly was.
She just barged in here
demanding all sorts of things.
And rambled on about
anonymous letters.
- Anonymous letters?
Yes.
She said she'd had some
threatening letters,
and for a time seemed to
think that I'd written them.
- Did she, why?
- Well, how should I know?
- You know, there's something
familiar about this story.
It's rather like one
of your books, Mr. Dax.
- Oh, thank you.
But I can assure you I've
not been imagining things.
Although, Miss Tulip's
whole behavior was unreal.
Asking Kate to lock her
rings up and giving me the.
- Giving you the what?
- Don't tell him, Andrew.
He hasn't even thanked
you for finding her rings.
- But I'm sure he was
very grateful, darling.
- I'm still waiting to hear
what else Miss Tulip gave you.
- Nothing very much, just a gun.
- A gun!
Where is it?
- I can't remember
where I put it.
I chucked it
somewhere around here.
- Was it loaded?
- Why, I didn't look.
- Well, suppose you saw it now?
- You know, I'm
not sure my union
allows me to do the
work of the police.
- Does your union allow you
to be arrested for murder?
- I never asked them.
You didn't see it
in the bedroom, sir?
- No, sir.
- Oh, pity.
Hmm, now let me think.
Oh, wait a minute though.
- Thank you, Mr. Dax.
- Oh, don't mention it.
- Hmm, one shot fired.
Doctor, could that be it?
- I'm not the ballistics
expert, you know.
And also I'd like to say is that
there's no reason why this
should not be the weapon.
- Thank you, Doctor.
Mr. Dax, you any objection
to having your
fingerprints taken?
- No, not at all, if it'll help.
- You'll have to have mine too.
- Why, did you handle
the gun as well?
- No, but if you're
taking Andrew's,
then you might as
well take mine.
After all, I am his wife.
- All right, Sergeant,
we'll have them all down.
You can take a cab over, Willis?
- Certainly, can't
do anything more now.
Simple case, cause of
death, cerebral hemorrhage,
occasioned by a lesion
of the frontal lobe.
- I thought you
said she was shot?
- Same thing, darling.
- Well, then why not say so?
I'm gonna get my coat.
Mr. Dax.
- Don't worry, I'm not escaping.
Archie.
Archie, where are you?
Archie, come on.
Come on.
Archie.
What is it?
T.
Miss Tulip.
- Thank you, Mr. Dax.
Where did you get this?
- Well, just there.
- You didn't drop it?
- No, I didn't.
And look, someone's
been lying here.
- Probably you, Mr. Dax.
- Very funny.
The ground, man, use your eyes.
That accounts for us
not hearing anything.
And the French
windows being open.
She was shot here
and left lying,
while the murderer went to
see if the coast was clear.
- But changed her mind
and walked into the house.
- Now that's impossible.
- Don't be stupid.
Of course, it's impossible.
- No, I didn't mean that at all.
I meant, if she'd
been lying out there...
- I don't care what you meant.
I meant you to keep quiet.
- Very good, sir.
- And stop messing about
with that honeysuckle.
- Wisteria.
- What's that?
- It isn't honeysuckle,
it's wisteria.
- Be careful, Feathers,
be very careful.
- I will, sir, I
never make a mistake
about the names of plants.
Now this particular plant...
- Feathers!
Go and get the others ready.
- Very good, sir.
- Fingerprints, Mr. Dax?
- Andrew, what a funny
little finger you've got.
Would you like mine now?
- No, Ma'am, the Inspector
will see to that,
if it proves necessary.
- Well, I think it is necessary.
After all, we're both in
this thing up to our necks.
- Darling, don't
say such things.
- Could you say what time
Miss Tulip went out or why?
- No, and that's how I
know she wasn't herself.
I've been her only
friend for years.
And if the doctor says
anything to the contrary,
he's a liar.
- You don't like
Dr Willis, do you?
- Like him, nasty, crawly toad.
Always getting around her,
making out she was ill
and giving her medicine.
- According to Mr. and Mrs. Dax,
she'd been receiving
threatening letters.
- Never, or I'd have known.
I always open the post.
Nothing, but bills
mostly from the doctor.
If anyone was after
her money, it was him.
- Mr. Dax says that Miss Tulip
gave him a gun to protect her.
Do you know if she had a gun?
- She had a gun all right.
But it was the doctor's.
- The doctor's?
- Yes.
I heard him say, that
he'd be much happier
if she had something to
protect herself with.
And then I saw him take
something out of his bag.
- What else did he say?
- What?
I don't know he saw
me standing outside,
and he shut the door in my face.
Come in.
- The prints will be
ready in 10 minutes, sir.
- All right, thank you.
- That's it.
Fancy giving a thing like
that to the poor dear.
Nasty, vicious thing.
If you want to
know who done that.
- All right, all right.
Take Miss Judith out, will you?
And bring in Mr. and Mrs. Dax.
- Yes, sir.
- Get Dr Willis on
the line, will you?
Oh, hello.
Ordeal over, Mr. Dax?
I do hope they didn't hurt you.
- Not at all, it's a
pleasure to be fingerprinted.
Makes you feel one of
the family, so to speak.
- Then perhaps you'll take
one of the family chairs.
- Thank you.
- Now, whose idea was it to
come down to Wood Cottage?
- Oh, mine.
You see, Andrew had got
behind in his new book
and Philip, that's
our publisher, was
getting very worried.
You see, they have
to stick to dates.
And Andrew never will.
Oh, nonsense.
- It's no good saying
nonsense, darling.
You know, you
promised to deliver
before you went to America
when you had that
500 pound advance.
- Oh, you had a
500 pound advance?
- Yes.
- And you still
haven't finished the book?
No.
- And you're being
pressed by your publisher.
- Being pressed?
Look, Inspector, publishers
are mean and grasping people.
So, if I don't get in
first and plead poverty
and lack of
inspiration, I get done.
- Now just a minute.
Let's stick to facts.
You owe your
publisher 500 pounds,
and he's asking you to repay it.
- Repay Philip don't be silly.
- What a crazy idea.
- Hello.
Yes, put him through.
Hello, Doctor.
Yes, I'm glad you rang.
I wanted your report
on the time of death.
Not before 10 and not after 12.
You're quite
definite about that?
The revolver Miss Judith
said it belonged to you.
Well, I'd like it cleared up.
Yes, I know she is.
Oh, Miss Tulip's solicitors,
Burton and Travers
on the High Street.
- Was that Dr Willis?
- Yes, why?
- Saying that death
occurred between 10 and 12?
- But, that's ridiculous.
- And your story is
ridiculous too, Mrs. Dax.
According to you, Miss
Tulip was frightened.
Yet, she appealed to you,
perfect strangers,
for protection.
She spoke of
threatening letters,
which Judith said she never had.
Your husband's being
pressed for money.
Yet, she gave you jewelry to
put in a nonexistent safe.
And she gave you the
gun to shoot her with.
I have enough ridiculous
facts to arrest you both.
- Then why don't you, Inspector?
- Perhaps I'm waiting
for the big build-up
in the last chapter, Mr. Dax.
- Or perhaps, it's all just a
little too easy and obvious,
and you don't wanna make
too big a fool of yourself.
- Take Mr. and Mrs. Dax
back to Wood Cottage.
Yes, sir.
- And stop at Burton and
Travers Solicitors on the way.
- What for?
- I want a little legal
advice, any objection?
- You surprise me.
I shouldn't have thought you
wanted advice from anyone.
- Which only goes to prove,
that sometimes even the
police can be wrong.
Goodbye, Inspector.
- Get me Constable
Feathers at Wood Cottage.
- 215 Feathers speaking.
Mr. Thorne.
The body's been removed.
Everything's in order.
And I'm just about to leave.
You'll do
nothing of the kind.
Stay where you are.
- Could you speak a
little louder, sir.
I can't quite hear you.
- Don't let Mr. Dax
out of your sights.
Keep a close watch on him.
- Inside or out?
- That depends on how
tactful you can be.
- You can leave that to me, sir.
- And, Feathers,
watch your step.
We don't want another corpse
on our hands at
Wood Cottage, do we?
- I can't say I'm very keen.
- I don't know that I can
give you the information.
- Look, Mr. Burton,
we only want to know
if either Dr Willis or Miss Gale
are mentioned in the will.
- No.
No?
- Because there is no will.
They were mentioned in some
draft she drew up sometime ago,
but Miss Tulip kept
changing her mind
right up till a week or so ago.
She was coming to see
me but she never came,
so, she died intestate.
- Intestate?
Well, then who inherits?
- No one.
- But surely she must
have some family?
- Miss Tulip was the
last of a very long line.
She and her sister Angela
were the only children.
- Well, what happened to Angela?
- She went to Australia.
- Australia the missing heir.
- She had disgraced her family,
run off with some
young profligate.
Her father was devoted to her.
It took him many
years to forgive her.
And when he did,
it was too late.
She was dead.
The blow killed the old man.
And Miss Millicent
was left alone,
sole heir to the Tulip fortune.
- Then there still
maybe some heir.
Don't you see, if
Angela had a baby.
- There would still
be no legal heir.
The man Angela eloped
with deserted her
without implementing
his promise of marriage.
- Ditched her, did he?
- You men.
- Feathers, they've got him too.
- Oh, no.
- What are you doing here?
- A matter of duty, sir.
- Well, am I to take it
that we're under arrest?
- Oh, no, sir.
- Then may I ask just what
you're doing in my house?
Well, you see
the Inspector said.
- Yes, Feathers.
Well, I can't tell
you it's confidential.
- Then let me guess.
Your orders are to
see that I don't,
to put it vulgarly, do a bunk.
- Exactly.
Well, no, not exactly.
In a manner of speaking,
you see, the Inspector said.
- To blazes with the Inspector!
- Yes, sir, no, sir.
- Well, make up your mind.
- Yes, sir.
- Feathers, you know
as well as I do,
the police have no right
to infest my premises.
- Infest?
- The word was chosen with care.
- I'm sorry, sir, but
my instructions are...
- To make sure that
I don't vamoose.
Feathers, the whole of the
outside world is yours.
- It's a bit chilly
outside, sir.
- Yes, isn't it?
I wish you a hearty good day.
- Thank you, sir.
- Oh, Andrew.
How can you turn poor Mr.
Feathers out into the cold?
Think how you'd feel
if he got pneumonia.
- I know, how I'd feel.
Oh, but then I suppose,
they'd save him.
- Now, you're being very unkind.
I think, he's nice.
Look, how he helped me with
the coffee this morning.
I'm sure if we let him stay,
he'd do the same again.
There's so much to do.
There's the carpet and
stairs to be swept,
and the grate to be cleaned
and all the dusting.
- Well, I don't think
I could very well
do anything like that,
you see, I'm on duty.
- I should have thought
that it was your duty
to give us a hand.
Then, of course, if you
don't like us enough then.
- Well, if you put it like
that, lady, I suppose.
- Kate, I'm worried.
Feathers must've had orders
to stay here at all costs.
Otherwise, he'd have
never allowed himself
to be turned into a housemaid.
- Of course, he would.
He's very nice.
- Well, that's not the point.
The Inspector must
seriously believe
that I killed Miss Tulip.
- But we know you didn't.
- Well, that's not gonna be
much comfort if I'm hanged.
- Well, hanging was never
meant to be very comfortable.
Andrew, don't talk like that.
- Well, it's happened before.
- We must do something.
- Yes, but what?
I have an idea floating around
at the back of my brain.
But, well, it just won't gel.
Don't turn that on.
Otherwise, we shall be drowned.
Anyway, I'm doing the washing.
- Oh, all right.
- Don't use that cloth.
- Why not?
- Well, because Mrs. Jones
left it outside yesterday
and it got soaked.
There's a clean
one in the drawer.
- The rain, of
course, that's right.
It was raining yesterday
and last night.
Kate, I've got it.
- Got what?
- The answer to the riddle
it's all clicking into place.
I may be wrong but, Feathers!
- What you want Feathers for?
- Feathers.
Feathers, come here a minute.
I want you to think
very carefully.
When you examined the body,
were the clothes damp or dry?
- That's just it they were dry.
That's why she couldn't possibly
have laid outside
in the shrubbery.
Not in that storm.
- Well, then why
didn't you say so?
- I tried to, but you
know our Inspector.
Nobody knows anything but him.
Honeysuckle.
- Right now there's
only one chance,
I must get out of here.
- No, you can't do that, sir.
- Of course, I can.
- No, no, the Inspector
rang up definite,
very definite he was not
to let you out of my sight.
- Come on, Feathers.
- I'm sorry, sir, I'd
liked to help if I could,
but orders is orders.
If he hadn't rung up special,
it'd have been different.
- Help, fellas, quick.
Do something.
- All right, ready,
leave it a bit.
I see the trouble this
tap wants tightening.
That's it, plumbing's
my strong suit.
Well, it used to be.
- Do you think we should
turn it off at the main?
- Yes, if you wouldn't
mind, before I get wet.
- Andrew, you heard
what Mr. Feathers said.
Go and turn it off at the main.
- Right, darling,
I won't be very long.
- Went loose again.
I'm afraid, you need
to get a new one.
Still, I'll try and fix
it up for you temporary.
Here we are.
No, we aren't.
Ever been to Trafalgar Square?
Like an English
summer, isn't it?
- Oh, what a shame.
Your beautiful uniform
getting spoiled.
I'm sure, if you just.
- Beginners' luck.
Now I'm soaked to the skin.
- Look, why don't you
take your uniform off,
and we'll dry it in here.
I'll get you my
husband's dressing gown.
- Thank you.
Here, where is he?
- Hmm?
- There, he's gone.
He's hopped it.
- I know, but he'll be back.
- But what about Mr. Thorne?
- Yeah, well, what
about Andrew's neck?
- What about my pension?
Phew.
Get me the police.
- Have you taken
leave of your senses?
What do you think this
is, a fancy dress party?
- Couldn't say, sir.
- It's all my fault, Inspector.
You see, the tap went wrong,
and Mr. Feathers
came to my rescue.
Only, he got awfully wet,
so, we're drying his
uniform in the kitchen.
- And Mr. Dax thinking
everything is in good hands
just went for a walk.
- No, Andrew hates walking.
He took Feathers' bicycle.
- So, you let him
pinch your bike?
Surely, Constable, you
should have given it to him.
- Where are your manners?
- I was being tactful, sir.
- Oh, for goodness sake, man
don't stand about like that!
It makes you look even
sillier than you are already!
Go and put your uniform on!
- Well, it's all wet.
- So, are you go and put it on!
To be taken in by a
smart aleck like that.
- What exactly do you mean
by a smart aleck like that?
- Just what I say, Mrs. Dax.
Your husband.
- Is not a smart aleck.
And if you had one grain of
common sense, you'd know it.
He's gone because he has a clue.
- That's what he's told you.
- Don't be so silly.
Anyone who would
think that you really
believed Andrew was guilty.
- And they'd be right.
I have a warrant for his arrest.
- But you're mad.
Give me one good reason,
why he should want
to murder Miss Tulip?
- I'll give you 10, which
is the number of pieces
of her jewelry, still missing.
- That doesn't prove anything.
- No, but the gun does.
It only has one clear set
of fingerprints on it.
Your husband's.
- But he couldn't
have killed her.
We were together all night.
All night, Mrs. Dax?
- Yes.
- And did you go to sleep?
- Of course.
- Then how do you know
your husband was with you.
- Because the least
noise wakes me up.
Why, I remember when he came
back with milk and biscuits.
- When he what, Mrs. Dax?
- When he went for the milk and
biscuits I woke immediately.
- I think you said,
"When he came back".
- Oh, no, no, when he went.
I know I'm right because
I was thirsty too.
I remember thinking how
lucky it was that Andrew
was out in the cold and not me.
- So, he got you some as well.
- Hm.
- As well or did you drink
out of the same glass?
There was only one glass in
your room this morning, dear.
- I don't remember.
Yes, it was the same glass.
I had a drink from his.
- Mrs. Dax, when your husband
left you, you were asleep.
So, you haven't a clue,
how long he was away,
where he went, or what he did.
But we have.
We say, that while
you were sleeping,
he went down and
murdered Miss Tulip,
and at this moment,
he's on the run.
- Hello.
Hello.
Hello, Exchange.
Get me the police.
- Yes, well, you better split.
Alert all cars.
No sign of him, yet.
He's got to go somewhere,
and it's my bet
he'll come back here.
- But surely, if as you say,
he did have something to
do with Miss Tulip's death,
then the last place
he'd come would be here.
- Perhaps, his superior
knowledge of police methods
will suggest that this is the
place we won't be watching.
- Andrew is not a murderer.
Even if he was he wouldn't be
stupid enough to come here.
So, you might just
as well go back
to your cells and
handcuffs and things
and leave me in peace.
- You underestimate
one factor, Mrs. Dax.
You.
I don't suppose, you've
known many men on the run.
But I have.
There's one thing they all
suffer from, loneliness.
The knowledge that every
man's hand is against them.
I lay a fiver he
comes back here.
- Andrew, the police are here!
The police.
- I wondered if
you could help me.
I'm so silly but
I've lost my way.
- Won't you come in?
- Oh, no, no, no,
I won't come in.
It would only make you late.
- Make me late?
- Yes.
- I'm not going anywhere.
- You're so right, so right.
You wouldn't like it anyway.
It's the summertime, you know.
Gets the clocks all, all upset.
Don't you think?
- Madam, would you kindly
tell me who you are?
- Certainly not, we've
not been introduced.
- Miss Tulip.
- Well, I mustn't
stop your rehearsal.
- We are not play acting, madam.
We are the police.
- Oh, I'm so sorry,
I only use may glasses
when I'm reading.
We've got police in
Australia too, you know.
- Australia, you're Angela.
- Yes, I'm Angela.
- But you're dead.
- I don't think so.
Am I?
She's heard that funny story.
- What funny story?
- About my being killed
in the railway crash.
All the papers had my
name all over them.
The people were so surprised
when I turned up alive.
It was so exciting.
- And your sister knew of this?
- Oh, yes, yes, Millicent knew.
I sent her all the
cuttings to explain.
- When did you get back?
- Oh, I'm not going back.
It would be so silly to go back
having come all this
way here, wouldn't it?
Besides, Millicent, is
meeting me at the station.
- Miss Angela, perhaps,
you'd better sit down.
- How kind of you, thank you.
- I'm afraid, I have
some bad news for you.
- Don't tell me she's
cross with me again?
- No, she won't be
cross with you any more.
You see, she's dead, murdered.
- She should be more careful.
But, she can't possibly
be dead without seeing me.
You see, we'd quarreled,
that's why I eloped
to Australia.
It wasn't till years after
that I wrote home having read
the announcement of my
father's death in the paper.
Then Millicent
wrote and told me,
he cut me out of his will.
- Is that why you killed her?
- I don't understand.
- Mrs. Dax, I must ask you...
- Quiet!
You hated Millicent, didn't you?
For the way she'd opposed you
and made it necessary
for you to run away.
And when you heard
how she cheated you
out of your father's money,
you decided to kill her.
- My dear, you don't
know what you're saying.
- Mrs. Dax, you mustn't make
wild accusations like that.
- They're not wild, but I am,
accusing Andrew of murder.
Anyway, she's been here
before and I can prove it.
- How?
- Because when she came
in, Archie didn't bark.
He knew her, look at him now.
- All animals like me
but that's no proof.
- I wouldn't be
too sure of that.
- Andrew.
- Mr. Dax.
In the
name of the law,
- Why don't you keep quiet
while I talk to the Inspector.
Now, I'm sorry I had to
run out on you, Inspector,
but, well, I've
been doing a little
research on a
story I thought up.
- Yes, Mr. Dax.
- Yes, Inspector.
I have been working very
hard, as a matter of fact.
I've got quite a headache.
And now, I'm on
the last chapter,
the one where we have
the grand finale.
- And the brilliant
amateur solves
the mystery that
baffled the police.
- That's right, yeah.
But it was really Kate
who solved the mystery.
- Andrew, did I?
- Yes, it was when you told me
not to use that damp tea cloth
and reminded me that
it had been raining.
Feathers was onto it, too.
- Feathers?
- Yes.
He saw the snag right away.
You see, although the body
had been laying outside
her clothes were
still quite dry.
That was when the penny dropped.
And as for you, never
again will I say anything
against a woman's intuition.
Your reconstruction of
the crime was masterly.
- Was it?
- Yes.
But not quite right.
She hated her sister all
right, and she killed her.
I mean, it was a clever plot
to drive towards the coast,
stop on the way, commit
the murder and then,
imposing on two
complete strangers,
dump the body in the shrubbery
to establish an alibi,
change clothes with the
corpse during the night
and appear the next day as
her newly arrived sister,
the only surviving member
of the Tulip family,
to claim the estate.
And that, that is
exactly what you did do,
Miss Millicent Tulip.
- Millicent Tulip?
- Hit the jackpot in one.
Splendid, off with the disguise.
You should have found that out.
Elementary!
Go on, back on the beat.
- Millicent Tulip, I arrest you
for the murder of
your sister Angela.
- You're wasting
your time, Inspector.
She's as mad as a March hare.
- It's a lie.
The March hare is
as sane as I am.
Cost me a packet
not to be certified.
- Come along with me, Madam.
- Where are we going?
- To the station.
- Good, I love trains.
Can we get some tea?
- Oh, yes.
- Never drink it.
Well, what are we waiting for?
Let's get cracking!
I know
the way, I know the way.
- Well, how crazy can you get?
Thank heavens that's over.
- Oh, yes.
Now, you'll be able to finish
your book at last, darling.
You're supposed to be
writing one, remember.
- Oh, I'm not gonna finish that.
- What?
- No, I got a much better idea.
- Oh, no.
- Oh, yes.
And the title, "Miss
Tulip Stays The Night."