[intense music]
[music continues]
[screaming]
Headquarters,
send over the homicide squad.
Tenth and Sylvan Avenue.
Attention, car 48,
car 40.
'Go to Tenth and Sylvan ,
report to Inspector Patten'
'at the old Mitchell home.'
This is Mr. Glenn speaking.
Oh good gracious!
I'll run over right away.
This is Dr. Stuart speaking.
What?
We'll be right over.
[engine revving]
Yeah, yeah, I got it right here.
Herbert Wynn, yeah.
Shot? What was it,
murder or suicide?
No-no. Oh, I see.
When did it happen?
At the old Mitchell residence
on Sylvan Avenue, huh?
Oh, yeah-yeah,
I know the old Mitchell estate.
Who found the body?
Body found by his aunt,
Juliet Mitchell
who collapsed, and is now under
care of her personal physician.
Alright, stick on the case.
I'll hold a rewrite man here
in case anymore comes in.
So this is romance.
Three pair of tonsils
and a breakaway kidney.
- All in one day.
- I'm busy too, Adams.
I think,
I'm losing my mind.
Probably it's gone away
someplace with mine.
- 'It wasn't your play.'
- 'It was.'
Well, Russian Bank.
A nice game of Russian Bank,
it just picks me up.
Like a psychopathic ward.
- You got a date?
- Oh, no such luck.
I smell so of chloroform, no one
but a guy with a gas mask
would make a pass at me.
Oh, I'm tired with my board.
I think I'll donate
my body to science
and commit suicide.
Stop. You forgot to put
the nine on the eight.
You can all stop
as far as I'm concerned.
'This place is getting
in your hair?'
It's in my hair, my eyes, my
teeth, my nose and it itches.
I'm beginning
to envy the patients.
Things happen to them,
they live or they die.
Thrills in our routine are
as common as wisecracks
in an algebra book.
(female #2)
'It's your play.'
I'm going to bed.
Oh, why doesn't someone do
something to break the monotony?
You called me
for the same thing.
If we're going to play, please
show a little sportsmanship.
Can either of you
do any acrobatic dancing?
It would be much more
interesting.
[knock on door]
Come in.
Miss Adams, report to
the superintendent at once.
Yeah and snap in to it.
[door closing]
Here's the address,
and ask for Dr. Stuart.
The old Mitchell house.
I know where that is.
Take a taxi.
Something must've happened.
You'll be told.
Do I report back to you?
No, to..
I may as well tell you,
this is an unusual case.
You're really working
for police headquarters.
'Inspector Patten will introduce
himself to you when you arrive.'
'Now, there may be
some excitement.'
'Nervous strain involved in it.'
'If you don't want to go,
I'll send someone else.'
But on the other hand, I think
you're fitted to the job.
If you don't mind a change
from a hospital routine.
Mind a change?
Oh, lady, if you only knew.
[car engine revving]
Here's a dollar.
Keep the change.
- There is no change.
- Then we're even.
Dr. Stuart, please.
There's Dr. Stuart,
right there.
- Miss Adams?
- Yes, Dr. Stuart.
Your patient
Miss Mitchell is upstairs.
Nervous shock case.
She's at a dangerous age.
- What shocked her?
- It's rather serious.
Her nephew shot himself tonight,
and she found the body.
Oh!
This is your room. Your patient
is in the adjoining room.
Thank you.
Sure you didn't
open it yourself?
Positive, sir.
Well, a man might get out
that window with a ladder.
If he did it, he'd leave
footprints a yard deep.
- The nurse is here, inspector.
- Downstairs?
No. In the room
she's been assigned.
Fine, I'll see her
right away.
Now don't stall.
It won't do you any good.
Did you this one?
I didn't touch it, sir.
I swear it on the holy book.
I found it that way.
When Miss Juliet screamed,
and I came running up.
But somebody did it.
That I'll swear to.
He couldn't kill himself,
not the kind he was.
But somebody did it.
And that's where they got away.
Why don't they go away?
Tell 'em,
he was cleaning his gun.
Cowards like him
don't shoot themselves.
There-there, now don't talk
and don't fret.
He's alright, now.
Safe in his savior's arms.
What was that?
How do you do?
Are you feeling better now?
I'm the new nurse.
Adams is the name.
How do you do?
- Who was that?
- That's the coroner.
They were expecting him
for the autopsy.
Autopsy, I won't permit it.
I won't have that--
Now, you must be quiet.
Please.
Let go of me.
Let me go.
Please, please.
(Nurse Adams)
'Dr. Stuart, Dr. Stuart.'
Yes.
Please, hurry.
She's fainted.
Hypodermic of amyl nitrate.
Yes, doctor.
It's ready.
Is she alright?
That's good.
Did you butt in
just to ask that?
Say, listen, there's a cop
around here named Patten
that'll wring your neck
if you mess things up.
No kidding.
The feet fooled me.
No bunion.
I beg your pardon, inspector.
Don't apologize, I liked
the way you dodged the issue.
Sit down.
You've had hospital experience,
police and emergency cases?
Yes along with the rest.
Alright, now tell me something.
If a bullet passes through
a man's head
what's the outstanding result?
A hole, I suppose.
(inspector)
'And in case of suicide?'
Powder burns. Why?
There were no powder marks
on that kid's body.
He cleaned his gun, alright.
But he didn't kill himself
He didn't commit suicide.
- You mean, he--
- I mean, murder.
Who?
That's what
we're gonna find out.
What you're gonna find out.
- Me?
- Sure.
You're working for me now.
Oh, I see.
Well, what's my rank?
- Uh, what?
- My rank, my title.
If I'm gonna be with
the police force, what am I?
A female cop
or a disinfected stool pigeon?
Ah, let's see.
You're a Pinkerton. That's it.
Miss Pinkerton of Scotland Yard.
Oh, that's swell.
Well, what next?
Well, for the moment,
just listen.
Young Wynn was killed
by somebody he knew.
He was unlacing his shoe.
And looking up at the face
of whoever shot him.
[knock on the door]
(Mary)
'Miss Adams.'
Yes.
- You're coming, now?
- Yes, I am.
Oh, then,
I-I won't disturb her.
I'll look in again tomorrow.
Yes, do so. I hope she'll be
well enough to see you.
(Dr. Stuart)
'Oh, inspector.'
Shake hands with Arthur Glenn,
Miss Mitchell's lawyer.
- Just the man I wanna see.
- Anything I can do to help?
Yes, there's one point.
Did young Wynn carry
any life insurance?
He did carry some insurance.
I don't know how much.
I'll look it up.
Much obliged.
Goodnight.
Oh-oh. Excuse me.
- Keep your eyes open.
- Yes, sir.
[wind blowing]
[scratching on door]
Well, hello fella,
come on in. Come on.
Come on in.
You could stay in here tonight,
palsy-walsy.
Come here, you. Get right out.
Come here!
Now, you get right outside.
You can't stay here.
Right out, go on.
Would you please
do me a favor and go to bed.
Do as she says, Mary.
- Goodnight, Miss Juliet.
- Goodnight.
Goodnight.
Shall I take
one of these pillows away?
- No-no.
- Alright.
[wind howling]
Nurse, nurse.
Oh, oh.
I can't breathe.
Yes you can.
Now breathe deeply.
That's it.
Stay here. Don't leave me.
I'm afraid.
Something might happen.
Something terrible.
[clock chiming]
- What?
- Shh.
Your breakfast
is downstairs, miss.
Oh, good morning.
A swell nurse I am.
Need more sleep than my patient.
Slip away from her
and hide this.
She's been watching me
all night.
Don't you worry about her.
[door closing]
In here, miss.
[doorbell ringing]
Is that the doorbell?
Yes, miss. Excuse me.
Morning, Hugo.
You're looking fit this morning.
Thank you, sir.
No one is allowed in here, miss.
I was just looking
for something to read.
At breakfast, miss?
Well, frankly, Hugo
I come from a long distinguished
line of billy goats.
And we always like to gobble
a few chapters of Shakespeare
before we tackle
our corn flakes.
Miss Adams.
- Morning, Miss Pinkerton.
- Adams to you.
Did you get out
on the wrong side of the bed?
I haven't been anywhere
near a bed.
I'm a mattress loving maiden.
I don't belong here.
Neither do I. I oughta be in a
hospital, examining my head.
- Why are you so candid?
- Look at this, will you?
'I don't see anything.
unless for that white spot.'
Is that a defect
in the film?
Defect? Don't let the
photographer hear you say that.
That's the answer to this case.
If only had sense to know it.
That's the corner
of a newspaper.
There was a newspaper
by the body.
What's that
got to do?
It's got everything
to do.
Wynn took out a $100,000
life insurance
before he shot himself.
Glenn, Miss Mitchell's
attorney just told me.
100,000. Then he killed
himself to leave that to the--
That's what he did, alright.
The Mitchell family were broke,
down to the last cent.
He spent all the money
shot his health to pieces.
Well, he was through,
I guess.
But was he smart?
Wait, watch this.
Now, I'm gonna kill
myself, see.
Only insurance companies don't
pay off quickly on suicide.
It's got to look
like a murder or an accident.
Alright, now here's
what I do.
First, I take some oil and rags,
like he did.
The kinda stuff
used to clean a gun.
Then I take the paper
like this.
Kneel down, take my gun,
shoot a hole through the paper.
Once I fall,
the paper falls into place.
When you pick it up,
it's alright.
'What about the powder burn?'
Inside, instead of on me,
smart, huh?
It's been done lots of times.
I must have overlooked.
In the meantime, somebody got
in here and took that newspaper.
- That's what they were hiding.
- Did you see it?
The lady got out, and I caught
her when she sneaked back.
Her feet were
black with dirt.
She hid something
under her pillow.
Morning, Mary went
to the library to hide it.
It might have been
the newspaper.
Probably thrown out by now.
Where do they keep
the newspapers here?
There's an incinerator
in the backyard.
Hugo burns them, I guess.
You wait until dark,
and take a look.
Keep your eyes open.
I'll get down to headquarters.
Maybe, some cop picked it up,
and took it there.
- Gee, I hope so.
- Ah, just my luck.
This is the first case they've
assigned to me all by myself.
And here I go and bungle
it right off the bat.
Probably be walking
the beat next time.
Oh, now stop, will you?
You'll have me crying
on your shoulder.
I've kept your breakfast
on the table, miss.
It's getting cold.
My breakfast?
Oh, yes. Of course.
Could you hear what they said?
No. But she's too friendly
with that inspector.
Don't let her go in there.
'What are you looking for?
Footprints or ladder marks?'
How should I know?
Well, maybe you don't,
but what are you doing here?
After all, you're a nurse,
you'll understand.
I've got to talk to somebody,
or I'll go crazy.
You're a friend of the late
Herbert Wynn, aren't you?
- Oh, yes. He, we--
- Sweethearts?
Yes. Oh, it seems so impossible
that he's dead.
- I know who killed him.
- He shot himself.
No-no, he didn't.
Don't let them tell you that.
He was murdered.
I know who did it.
Come on, we better go in the
house. Someone might hear us.
Wait a minute. I've got to see
how my patient is.
Take everything she'll tell and
hold her till somebody comes.
Yeah.
We'll tail her
if she leaves.
Make it snappy.
Don't be frightened, kid.
Now, what were
you gonna tell me?
I don't know.
Maybe, I better not.
Better get it off your chest.
Alright, first of all,
I was engaged to Herbert Wynn.
They killed him
for his insurance.
They were desperate. The bank
was gonna take the house.
- Who killed him?
- Hugo, I think.
Old lady knew.
She was in it.
They were all in it.
They hated him.
He was afraid. He knew
someone was after him.
One night,
he saw someone in the dark.
After that he always
took his gun along.
He couldn't have
shot himself.
Oh, you must believe me.
I do, only you
ought to tell the police.
But I can't.
My family.
It would be awful
if my name came into it.
I must go now. I don't want
anyone to see me here.
Wait a minute.
What is your name?
I can't tell you, I can't.
It's impossible.
Goodbye, then.
[engine revving]
[screaming]
You must have fainted.
Are you hurt, miss?
Oh.
Hurt? I'm dead.
Something hit you, miss?
No, I tripped.
I saw something
go through that door.
No one got out there, miss.
That door is locked
and bolted.
Always has been.
We never use it.
What were you doing down there?
I, I couldn't sleep.
That is, I heard a noise.
So, I got this,
and went in the parlor.
I watched and then,
I must have dozed.
You say, you heard a noise?
I don't know what,
a kind of knocking
or creeping more like.
Why don't you go outside
and look?
I think, I'll stay down
in the parlor, miss.
Well, just as you say.
Only--
Perhaps, you had better
go to your room.
Okay, but it's a cinch
I won't sleep now.
- Goodnight, miss.
- Goodnight.
'"County Coroner
James A. Klempf'
'"last night wrote finis
to the inquiry'
'started by police into the
mysterious tragic death
"of youthful Herbert Wynn.
Autopsy proves beyond a doubt
that the death was accidental."
It's a great relief, Juliet.
(Juliet)
'In what way?'
In every way.
The poor boy is gone,
and we can't bring him back.
'This means security for you and
I'm most happy for your sake.'
'Now, the insurance
will be paid.'
Oh, no.
But I don't want blood money.
Oh, don't look at it
that way.
Don't you see,
there's no taint on the money.
It's due,
legally and fairly.
It's a Godsend, Miss Juliet.
That'll do, Mary.
It'll help,
I don't deny that.
But I wish it could
have come some other way.
So do I.
So do all of us.
But let's be thankful.
Times are hard, Juliet.
I know they are,
for me at least.
By this indemnity.
(male #1)
'Have you read this?'
Ah, brilliant that coroner.
Sees all and knows nothing.
If he thinks for one minute
he's closed this case,
he's crazy.
[dog barking]
Well, what's the matter, fella?
You still hungry after
all those pork chops.
Right here.
There.
Don't forget
if you meet me in the dark.
I'm your palsy-walsy.
Get out of here.
[dog barking]
You ought to be killed.
Bedtime, Miss Mitchell.
The doctor wants you to drink
this before you go to sleep.
Doctors are all alike.
Even Stuart.
I don't trust any of 'em.
Never did.
[screaming]
Go around on that side.
Come on, Patten.
[Miss Adams screaming]
- What's in there?
- My room.
But you can't open it.
It's locked.
- I don't have the key.
- I can't, eh?
Are you sure
you are alright?
Yes, I'm alright.
He went through that door.
(Patten)
'Quick, boys.
Wynn's room.'
Stand aside.
I'll shoot the lock.
[gunshot]
(Patten)
'Stick 'em up.'
'Come on.'
'Come on out here.'
They don't make doors
like that anymore.
It's solid oak.
Pretty calm, aren't you?
Don't bother,
I haven't a gun.
I'm looking for
a bunch of keys.
How did you
get in the house?
Maybe, I found the doors open.
Riley, take a look around
and see if this fellow threw
a bunch of keys out the window.
- I'm arresting you.
- For what?
Housebreaking?
That'll do until
we find the keys.
And then what?
Suspicion of
first degree murder.
You won't need
the bracelets.
Take him downstairs
to the front door and wait.
I want to see
if Miss Adams is alright.
Alright, come on,
get down here.
Here's some keys, chief.
I found 'em under the window.
'Herbert Wynn's keys.'
Where did you get these?
That would be telling
stories out of school.
Alright, take him down.
Book him for murder.
Wrong again,
Sherlock Holmes.
That boy did not kill Wynn.
Ah, just like a woman.
You mustn't let those
good-looking eyes
and that calm, innocent,
baby-face fool you.
If I wanna be fooled,
I'd put myself in your shoes.
Now, this is no time
to argue.
I've got the murderer,
or at least an accomplice.
- That's certain.
- He didn't do it.
- Who did?
- Wynn killed himself.
Now look. You're so
infernally smart.
'A newspaper?'
What did he break in here
tonight for?
Well, I'm no mind-reader.
Maybe we should call in
a detective on the case.
Well, this paper
doesn't mean anything.
He broke in here that night, and
used the keys to open the door.
- Did the same thing tonight.
- Walked like a ghost I suppose.
He did not walk through
that door like a ghost.
He knew the combination of that
secret door all the time.
Let me see that paper again.
Well, it's ten days old.
Well, don't the powder burns
prove something?
No, not necessarily.
He could've arranged that
ten days ago.
Brought it to make it
look like a suicide.
You are pulling rabbits
out of a hat.
Well, anyway, the handsome young
man will have to give me
mighty good reasons
for having those keys.
You know, all juries
are not made up of susceptible
good-looking blondes
like yourself, Adams.
Remind me to hate you,
will you, Patten?
[bell tolling]
'What was it?
What was it?'
Oh, they caught a fellow named
Elliott, in Mr. Herbert room.
They are gonna charge him
with the murder.
Charlie Elliott?
A young, dark haired boy?
'Yes.'
Oh! Oh!
Oh.
Send for Arthur Glenn
at once.
Well, not now. He's gone home,
and it's getting very late.
Well, then, in the morning.
The first thing.
'I must make a statement.'
A statement?
'Yes, a statement.'
(Juliet)
'Knowing that I have
not long to live.'
'And that I soon
must face my maker.'
I make this statement.
To prevent a great injustice..
...being done.
I make it of my own
free will.
And in full possession
of my faculties.
But I request..
...what I'm about to say
should be kept secret.
Except--
If this is to be
of confidential nature
I better take it down myself.
Would you mind, Miss Adams?
No, of course not.
I think you better
step out too, Miss Lenz.
Certainly.
You might wait in Miss Adams'
room where I can call you.
Alright.
[door closes]
Psst.
- What do you want?
- You've gotta help me.
I'm half mad.
If you think you can create
a sensation
by going crazy,
you are mistaken.
The house is already
full of nuts.
One more night of this,
and I'll lead the parade.
Charlie got arrested
and charged for murder.
It's all my fault.
What? How is it your fault?
- What you gotta do with it?
- It is my fault.
I sent him here last night.
To get something
from Herbert's room.
You left something in there?
Yes. I don't care
what you think of me.
I used to go there
to his room.
Herbert gave the keys to me.
I gave 'em to Charlie last night
and that's how he got in.
Never mind. Tell me what
you want, I'll get it for you.
I can't tell,
until I find it.
My family are strict
and they didn't like Herbert
But please, I can't
tell you anymore.
- I can't.
- Then I can't let you in.
But Charlie's life
may depend on it.
That's a fine thing to say.
If they catch you nosing in--
Oh, you've got to!
Let me in, please.
Well, alright, come on.
I can't make anymore mistakes
than the detectives.
Well, I like your nerve.
Getting powder
all over my things.
Crown you.
So sorry, my dear.
So sorry.
Paula Brent, aren't you?
No accounting
for people's tastes, I suppose.
I'm afraid
I don't understand you.
Indeed. Allow me
to introduced myself.
I am Florence Lenz,
L-E-N-Z.
Oh, I've heard about you.
[knock on door]
So, you're the girl--
- Miss Lenz.
- Yes.
Will you and Ms. Adams step in
and witness this signature.
Certainly.
You understand this statement
is confidential.
Sign here.
(Arthur)
'You are witnessing
simply the signature.'
Now, Miss Lenz.
Thank you. You wish to read
this over now, Juliet?
After I've rested.
Wait downstairs.
You are over-tired,
Miss Mitchell.
- Hello, Arthur.
- Good morning.
A long statement?
Why, she hasn't the strength.
(Miss Adams)
'Oh, doctor.'
Well, exhaustion naturally.
Some uh, amyl nitrate,
hypodermic.
Hmm.
[Juliet moaning]
Miss Adams!
'Yes, doctor.'
What was in that hypodermic?
She's dead.
Get me that hypodermic.
But, doctor, it was
the regular injection.
Get me that hypodermic,
do you hear me?
I've washed it out, doctor.
You've washed it, alright.
Used alcohol too.
- You didn't waste time.
- I'm not trained to waste time.
- Where are the tablets?
- In my room.
It's arsenic.
And five grain tablets too.
One would have been enough.
Oh, but this...this
says amyl nitrate.
Then arsenic was substituted.
That's a very clever deduction.
Do I have to tell you
what this means to you.
It's either a case
of negligence--
Doctor, you don't think
I did it intentionally.
You couldn't!
Nevertheless, this calls
for a investigation.
Having some trouble, doctor?
Oh, you might call it that.
Patten, Miss Mitchell is dead.
- What?
- She died five minutes ago.
No, no, I'll correct
that statement.
She was killed
five minutes ago.
Five grains of arsenic
was substituted
for a regular hypodermic.
And I, uh, I'm due at hospital
on a surgical case.
I'll notify the coroner
from there.
There is one more thing.
'I want this nurse held
on charges of gross negligence.'
'Or a possible complicity
to homicide.'
Goodbye.
Did you fix that hypodermic?
Yes, for heaven sakes--
'No, no, I'm not
suspecting you, am I?'
'Use the brains
you were born with.'
We've gotta work fast.
Now, somebody got here
and switched those tablets.
Who was it?
Who was in this room today,
besides yourself and the doctor?
Florence Lenz and Paula Brent.
'Brent? How did she get in?'
I let her in.
She begged me to.
Wanted to find something
in Herbert's room
and Charlie's
life depended on it.
And you fell for that.
What do you mean?
I believe the kid, that's all.
Detectives are not
supposed to believe.
- Who said I was a detective?
- You aren't. That's certain.
Why'd I let you into this?
Let me into it?
You dragged me into it.
I've lost a lot of sleep.
and scared myself so much.
I'm in shape for an asylum.
Never mind.
Where is Brent?
Up in young Wynn's
room, I suppose.
Look, do me a favor.
Let me go back to the hospital.
Go up and hold her
until I get there.
I must examine Miss. Mitchell's
room before anything is touched.
Now step on it.
Pinkerton.
Did you find it?
- No, I didn't.
- What's this?
- Don't take it, you mustn't--
- I'll take a look at that.
(Patten)
'Married!'
Secretly married to Herbert Wynn
and in love with young Elliott.
Well, this is news.
I want to thank you, Miss Brent
for establishing the motive.
Now I understand, why Elliott
felt that Wynn had to be killed.
- You are wrong.
- I hardly think so.
I'm holding you under arrest
for investigation.
Why? You can't.
- My people wouldn't--
- Take her to headquarters.
But, why? I haven't
committed any crime.
I'm holding you
for investigation
in the murder
of Miss Mitchell
Is Miss Mitchell dead?
Yes. She was murdered
a few minutes ago.
You see.
That finishes the case.
I think I can link
both murders by night time.
It's a cinch.
There is a connection.
I think young Elliott
is the missing link.
Now, listen, young fella.
You are badly mistaken.
Those kids haven't
done a thing wrong.
When I get a hunch
it's usually good.
They are innocent I tell ya.
Oh, you've got yourself all
worked up over this thing.
Your nerves are all shot.
What you need is a good rest.
What I need
is a good shoulder to cry on.
Say, you married?
- No, are you?
- Uh-huh.
[clearing throat]
Inspector, they want
to see you downstairs.
Well, now..
...ah, now, that's better.
That's better.
Uh, ah, alright.
[engine revving]
Hey, who are you?
The Morning Eagle.
The Morning Eagle, eh?
Well, go feather your nest.
I'm sorry you won't
cooperate with me.
I've given you every chance.
I must warn you that
you're hurting your own case.
And his too.
- Bring in Elliott
- Okay.
Charlie.
I'm sorry, honey.
My arms are in use.
[softly]
Take them off.
Take 'em off.
(Charlie)
'Love me?'
'Then that's all that matters
isn't it, honey?'
We won't need you, Miss. Brent.
Move over here.
(Patten)
'I suppose you know
why we brought you here.'
To reenact my hideous
cold blooded crime
for the edification
of you numbskulls, I suppose.
Oh, you'll have plenty of time
to wisecrack in the cooler.
You might as well begin
at the beginning.
Tell us why you came here.
Was it a friendly call?
I told you there's
nothing friendly.
I came to see Wynn and tell him
not to bother my girl.
You mean quit bothering
his own wife.
- I didn't know about that.
- Just what did you know?
Wynn had infatuated her.
I guess he was a smooth worker.
I knew she was in some
kind of mess.
I didn't ask for particulars.
So, I came to Wynn.
I was gonna have a showdown.
- And kill him if necessary.
- No. Sock him, maybe.
I never hated anybody
bad enough to kill 'em.
Go on.
I took the keys from her.
She didn't want me to have 'em.
- We had a tussle over--
- Get the keys to talk to Wynn.
- Juliet could've rung the door.
- I've explained all that.
Wynn knew I didn't like him.
He wouldn't talk,
if I hadn't surprised him.
Oh. I see. What did you do,
when you got inside?
I came upstairs.
I saw light
in Wynn's room and then..
And then what?
I came into the room.
I saw him.
He was on the floor.
He was dead.
I didn't kill him.
He was dead when I got in.
(Patten)
'Did you call the police?'
- 'Did you try and assist--'
- 'You know what I did.'
I heard somebody
coming up the stairs.
I knew it'd look bad,
so I got out.
Out the window.
How'd you get down?
As far as you're
concerned, I flew down.
I got him down
and brought him here.
I was afraid
of what he'd do.
He whistled from the roof.
So, I dragged the ladder
over here and got him down.
That's a mighty
nice story Elliott.
What with your looks
and your manner
you'll get
courtroom sympathy.
But that isn't
all you going to get.
There's just one thing
you left out.
Let's take a look
at this dummy.
This was how Wynn
looked when you saw him.
- No.
- Well, how did he look?
Arrange the body to look exactly
as it was when you saw it.
Nice work. Looks like
a real suicide, alright.
Did you as neat a job
when you fixed the real corpse?
- The real corpse--
- Let's quit stalling.
Your story would
be swell if somebody
hadn't seen you
move the body.
Got the statement, then?
Here it is.
Statement was dictated by
Miss. Mitchell on her deathbed.
I'll read it to you.
Uh, you'll hear it
in court anyway.
I'll tell you what
she said and save time.
She saw you
move the body, Elliot.
That was her
dying testament.
That's a lie. I don't know
anything about it.
She didn't see you shoot him,
but she saw you move the body.
I never touched the body.
He was dead when I got here.
Why make it look
like a suicide?
I didn't. If she
said that, she's lying.
She saw you, alright.
And you got away fast enough.
But you won't
get away this time.
Not through that window or by
someone bringing you a ladder.
'Well, guess
that's all we need.'
'You've cleared things up
quite a bit for me, Elliott.'
- Take him away, boys.
- Come on.
Young Elliott must be in there
telling his middle name.
I wonder why the inspector
wouldn't let us in?
He's afraid we'll
catch the real guy.
Yeah.
Any particulars
from you, chief?
Not now, boys. Carey'll give you
all the dope at headquarters.
Oh, Miss Pinkerton,
don't look like that.
Your face is a mile long.
Remember, this all
was a silver lining.
I don't see one
around this madhouse.
Well, here's one.
Mary has promised
to cook us some late supper.
I could use it.
How about you?
I've been hungry all my life
for one thing or another.
You mean..
I mean, right now,
I'm hungry for...food.
I'll have an ice cream soda
for every time
you've solved this crime.
Oh, now.
Please don't kid me.
You know I'm having
enough difficulty
trying to be intelligent
down at headquarters.
Why can't we talk about
something besides the case
once in a while?
Alright. Let's
talk about you.
You're coming to the movies
with me, aren't you?
- And me, so young.
- Coffee, Miss.
Yes.
As you were saying.
'All we need is one
tiny link to bind Elliott'
'with the murder
of Miss Mitchell.'
'Or at least
a sound motivation.'
Then we can forget clues
murders and confessions
and go places and do
things in the big way.
Um, thanks.
Uh, where's Hugo
tonight, Mary?
I made him
go to bed, sir.
I was afraid he'd
have a collapse.
He's so upset about
Miss. Mitchell's death.
- Cream, sir?
- No thanks.
Hugo was devoted
to the old lady.
There's a great
deal he knows
that he's
not telling.
[door opening]
I'm going
to investigate.
[dog barking]
What is it?
Someone upstairs?
[screaming]
[screaming continues]
Help! Help!
[gunshot]
- We got him, chief.
- I'll be right down.
- Are you hurt?
- Uh, I'm getting used to it.
You screamed loud enough
to bring out the militia.
If you think it's any fun
having a Frankenstein
leap at you every ten minutes
you're badly mistaken.
Look!
Hmm, chloroform.
He's coming
out of it, alright.
Now, listen. Miss Adams
just about saved your life.
I think you better
tell us everything you know.
I'll tell, alright.
Listen. First get Miss Lenz.
Get Florence Lenz
and I'll, I'll tell everything.
(Patten)
'This is your
last chance. Understand?'
It's no use. Lock me up.
I don't care what you do.
I don't know anything about it.
Alright.
Wait. Leave me alone with her.
Maybe I can get something.
Now, stop crying.
Try to. There.
I don't know
anything about it.
You do. You know this
was an insurance swindle.
That Wynn was to fake death
and disappear.
I don't know anything.
Can't you see we're
trying to help you?
We know everything.
Hugo talked.
- Yes. And it involved you.
- Hugo.
He said, the man behind
this case would marry you
after Wynn disappeared.
Hugo was to get a split.
I don't know
anything about it.
How can we help you
like this?
Wynn made a mess of things
when he married Paula.
He couldn't go through with
the suicide so he was murdered.
- With his own gun.
- Suppose he was.
- It has nothing to do with me.
- Only this.
Next to go was Miss Mitchell.
'Cause she got the money.
And name the killer
in her will.
You put the arsenic tablets
in the tube on my tray.
Like the murderer
told you to do.
It's not true.
I didn't know
they were poisoned.
Well, we can't stall around
any longer. Come on.
She's changed her mind.
She'll talk.
Good. Now we know
Miss Mitchell was killed
to make her will
become effective.
Your testimony is what we need
to tie the two murders together.
Are you willing
to make the identification?
Yes.
- Did you want to see me?
- Yes. Stand over there please.
Is this the man?
Now, look here. You said you're
going to make the identification
and you're going through it.
Did anyone in this room
give you tablets?
Poison tablets. And tell to put
them in that medical tube.
Yes.
Do you identify
the prisoner as the man?
- 'Yes.'
- You rotten little liar.
Don't you call me names
you murderer.
You made me one too.
I thought those were
sleeping powders not arsenic.
- Keep your mouth shut.
- Go on. This is good.
Tell me one thing. Did Glenn
manufacture the powder burn
newspaper stunt for an alibi?
Yes. Miss Mitchell
found it and hid it
so she'd get
the insurance money.
She didn't know
it was a murder.
- You're all crazy.
- Oh, but you're not.
You tried killing Hugo
so that he wouldn't talk.
Then the statement
we witnessed was a fake.
Yes. We signed a blank
piece of paper folded over.
Mr. Glenn wrote
the fake statement later.
He thought
it would convict Elliot
and stop further
investigation.
That's all boys.
Take him downtown.
She goes with him.
Don't you worry.
He'll help you. I know he will.
- Thanks.
- Thank you, doctor.
- And that--
- Wraps that up.
What about Charlie Elliott
languishing in yon jailhouse?
He'll be out before
Miss Brent decides which dress
she'll wear
to their wedding.
You're a great
detective.
I sometimes wonder
how far you'll get
if these wicked criminals didn't
go around catching themselves.
Come to think of it,
you've arrested practically
everyone in this cast
except me.
[telephone ringing]
Oh, just as I'm
getting a break.
Oh.
Hello.
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah! Okay.
Has Charlie Elliot confessed and
started the whole thing again?
No. A new case. At The Old Mills
hotel at Caesar Lake.
And they've assigned me to it.
It's a swell double murder.
Bodies found in the lake.
Lots of clues. Wanna come along?
Me? Not for all the tea
in China. I'm going back
to the hospital where
it's peaceful and calm.
I want a change.
I got it and how.
Oh, but this is a big case.
I can smell it.
You can smell
for the both of us.
No, wait a minute, please.
There's something else--
[screaming]
A mouse.
[theme music]