>> Hi, Emily.
Didn't need to be like this,
did it?
[sighs]
Emily Gray.
First class honors, high school.
Graduated, Vancouver.
Everything seems to have gone
on pretty swimmingly until 1995.
Then 1996 comes along and...wow!
You tried to drown a little boy
in the lake...
out of the blue.
You served five years for that.
You're out for only one, and
then this mess.
You want to tell me what's
going on?
I mean, you do, right?
That's...why you confessed.
I'm all ears, Emily.
You got something worth saying,
let's hear it.
What...the hell...happened?
>> What if I told you that I
knew the meaning of life?
>> [eerie music]
>> The thing you have to
understand is...either
everything has meaning or
nothing does.
Look around.
Life is just an accident, man.
Random collision of particles
in space.
Any meaning it has, is only one
we've given it ourselves.
Just like a riddle.
What do the poor have that the
rich want and God fears?
Like death or love or God, the
answer to the riddle all
depends on how you look at
things.
What the poor have, that the
rich want that God
fears...simple...
>> Nothing.
That is so for real.
It's...it's
like everything is just one big
puzzle in your mind.
>> Mmhm.
>> [doorbell ringing]
>> [footsteps]
>> And every mind is different.
>> [Hard rock'n'roll playing]
>> VERN: You were late.
>> SARA: I got sidetracked.
>> [car doors closing]
>> Buildings have alarms but
there's no on-site security.
>> [click]
>> VERN: Go.
>> [dramatic rock'n'roll]
>> What demands an answer but
asks no question?
>> [phone ringing]
>> [running footsteps]
>> MAN: [on phone]
Okay, Sara.
Are you ready for this?
It's in, kind of, a strange
place.
>> Thanks for the tip, Dad.
What's the next clue?
>> [on phone]
You're holding it.
You're one strange puppy.
You know that, lady, for using
that story.
You're the first person I met,
into this shit, that's not a
kid or a freak like me.
>> [on phone]
Well, if you want to see the
world differently, you have to
practice seeing it differently.
>> Whatever rows your boat,
baby.
By the way, you got three
minutes to go.
>> [coins jangling]
>> SARA: "Just keep letters that
win this race and find your
final resting place."
Letters that win this
race...first
letters...
phone number!
J, k, l.
"That win this race."
>> [phone ringing]
>> Come on.
>> [door rattling]
>> Find your final resting
place.
>> [stopwatch ticking]
>> Gotcha.
>> [alarm clock bleeping]
>> [beeping stops]
>> MAN: What is life?
Who are we?
Why are we?
Why do things happen the way
they happen?
Today in our philosophy
discussion we'll be looking at
three key figures.
Aristotle, Descartes and
Nietzsche.
Three different men with three
very different views of the
world.
>> Novak!
Hey, Novak!
I just want to tell you how
moved I was by what you said
the other day in class.
Phew!
All that stuff about the nature
of reality and everything...it
really touched me, you know.
And I thought that maybe you
and I could go out sometime and
discuss it a little more in
depth?
>> Thanks, Curran, but I think
I'll pass.
>> Ooh...I'm serious.
You know Marie, right?
We've got this little study
group going and we both very
much value your input.
But, I have to say that it's
not so much a...metaphysical
thing as it were.
It's really more a hands on,
you know?
So how about it?
Would you be interested in a
group learning experience?
>> Oh, come on!
It was just a question.
>> Curran, have you ever
stopped to wonder why none of
the little games you play ever
work or do you just figure it's
a hygiene problem?
>> Hey, I'm only responding to
all your dirty little signals,
honeysuckle.
>> [laughs]
Well, re-adjust
you radar, Romeo.
>> Okay, so maybe I got you all
wrong.
But at least I'm not the one
lugging some big dark secret
around with me all the time.
Hmm?
You got a secret, Novak.
The whole school practically
knows it.
>> Hmm.
Let me guess...I'm
a closet nymphomaniac?
>> Oh...ah!
Twice a week you drive a car to
school but then take the subway
home at night...and
then back the next morning.
So that means you must be
going somewhere you don't want
your car to be seen--right?
I guess, uh, little miss angel
isn't such an angel after all.
So come on, tell me, where do
you go when you catch the train?
>> [train rumbling]
>> [crowd murmuring]
>> MAN: All right, people.
As most of you know the lousy
bastards that pay our minimum
wage have sprung for the
proceedings this evening--their
way of saying thanks for doing
a good job.
Lads, keep fooling them.
>> [applause]
>> JEFF: Go ahead and open it.
>> Did you manage to fit an
entire security system in here
this time or maybe just a
shotgun?
>> Look and see.
>> You know I took the revolver
back.
There's no way I'd ever use
that thing.
>> It's your birthday.
Will you get on with it?
>> [laughs]
Dad!
It's beautiful.
>> [laughs]
As a police officer I can tell
you mace is effective up to six
feet away.
How the hell's my girl doing
anyway?
Are you doing okay?
>> The usual I guess.
Studying a lot.
>> Are you going out, seeing
people?
>> Mmhm hmm.
>> You know, Sara, when all
your friends went away to
University and you decided to
enroll here I thought, well,
maybe it was for the best.
After all you've been through
it will give you some
continuity and your grades
start to slip and I thought,
well, it's natural.
But to just sit at home and
watch the world slip by...
>> Dad...
>> You have got so much...
>> A man is running late for
work one day.
In his rush he forgets to grab
his umbrella and his raincoat
but he still manages not to get
wet.
How?
Because it never rained.
>> Ah.
I'm assuming you have a point.
>> You always want me to be so
prepared against failure,
burglary.
You have to let me live my life
though, find my own answers.
>> So, while you're looking you
can come over tomorrow night
and see me and Lea...
>> [laughs]
>> We could go to the movies...
>> Get real cozy and play happy
family?
Thanks, but I'll pass.
>> JEFF: Sara...
>> I don't need a replacement
caregiver, Dad.
You married her.
Not me.
I've got an early start
tomorrow.
I should just go.
>> Sara...your real present.
>> Is this mom's?
>> Yeah.
It's good to look for answers.
Sometimes, if you look too
hard, you lose the ones you
already have.
>> I'm okay.
>> PROFESSOR: The curse of
human consciousness is that it
longs to know only that which
is unknowable.
For all our philosophizing, can
the meaning of life ever truly
be understood?
With exams only two weeks away,
let us hope, for your sakes,
that at least some of it can.
>> [sighs]
>> Look, Curran, it's not going
to happen, okay?
Not here, not on a plane, not
in a train.
>> [laughs]
I have my secrets, too.
[laughing]
>> You ever hear stories on TV
sometimes that don't make any
sense?
Maybe a train derails for no
reason or an unexplained fire
breaks out somewhere, you know,
a mystery.
A few years ago police found
out about this invitation
that's been sent around.
Some people got it in their
mail or on their computer, even
painted on the side of their
house.
The invitation was a riddle.
>> What do you mean?
>> All I know is the answer led
you to an abandoned building
somewhere in the City.
If you could work out where it
was, then you became part of a
game and the rules were simple.
You begin receiving
riddles--anonymous ones.
Once you solve them, all you
had to do was return to the
building and write the answer
on the wall.
If you get a certain number of
them right, then one day you'd
be shown "the design."
It's this idea riddle freaks
are into, you know, that all
those unexplainable events out
there that no one can make any
sense out of, they're all just
part of one big riddle we don't
understand.
Well, according to the game, if
you played long enough, one day
you get a chance to see the
answer to that riddle.
This was the calling card of
the game.
Want to tell me where you got
it from?
You really don't want to get
involved.
>> Uh, just a friend.
It was a joke.
>> Funny kind of joke.
>> Yeah, funny kind of guy,
believe me.
So, what happened?
You said the cops found out
about it?
>> Yeah.
That woman a few years ago
tried drowning that boy in the
lake--it was all over the news.
>> Emily Gray?
>> Yeah.
When the cops questioned her
about it, all she would say was
that it was part of "the
design."
>> You're joking me?
>> No.
Your friend's joking, remember?
I'm just hitting on you.
>> When 34-year-old
Emily Gray attempted to drown
her neighbor's child in the
city harbor last year, all of
Toronto was left in a state of
shock.
Tonight, in an exclusive
interview, we get a chance to
speak with Emily for the first
time.
>> [fast-forward audio]
>> WOMAN: He was just
a little boy,
Dennis Reveni, 12-years-old.
Why did you try to kill him?
>> Cyclone hits a tropical
island, kills 45 people.
Train derails in Colombia.
The brakes fail on a school bus
in Calgary.
Why?
What reasons are there for
anything?
>> WOMAN: Near your house,
police found
an abandoned building with
words spray painted all over
the walls.
Did you try to murder this boy
as...part of some game?
>> It was all part of the
design.
When he looks in the
mirror, he knows...
I never sinned.
>> [sirens wailing]
>> [fast footsteps]
>> [train rumbling]
>> When it's ajar.
>> "What has keys but no
lock...space but no room.
You can enter but never go in."
>> [static]
>> You can enter, but never go
in...
A keyboard.
>> [bleep]
>> [thud]
>> Hello?
>> [thudding]
>> [train rumbling]
>> [frantic music]
>> [police radios]
>> Sara!
I just heard!
What the hell is going on?
Someone chased you?
>> It was the cleaner.
He thought I was stealing and I
thought...I overreacted.
>> Novak!
I think we found what scared
you, ma'am.
It was in the computer.
Source of the images.
>> Images?
>> It's nothing.
A practical joke.
[laughs]
>> Sara, was this harassment?
>> Dad.
>> I think we should file a
report, huh?
>> Dad, listen!
I am fine.
Really.
>> At least let me give you a
ride home.
>> Oh, God.
>> Are you all right, dear?
>> I, um...
I have a study thing.
I forgot.
>> Now?
>> Yeah, in the library.
I've got to go, okay?
>> Oh, Sara.
>> I will call you.
>> Sara!
Sara!
>> [rustling]
>> [rock'n'roll playing]
>> Excuse me?
>> Sara.
Curran's friend, right?
>> Yeah.
Do you know where he is?
I need to talk to him.
>> So, the rumors are true I
take it?
You're going through a younger
guy thing.
I've been there.
>> Look, I don't know what
you've heard.
I just need to ask Curran a
question.
>> Well, then...
He was at the Chez "M."
My work.
Curran dropped by last night.
I haven't seen him since.
You know, now you're trying a
few new things out, maybe you
could, uh, drop by too sometime.
I could show you a few
tricks.
We've all got our secrets,
honey.
>> [elevator whirring]
>> SARA: Why did you give this
to me, Curran?
>> [tires screech]
>> If you saw me, then I saw
you.
Okay, Curran.
What's your game?
>> [hip-hop music playing]
>> [hard rock'n'roll playing]
>> Say, Vern, I was just
thinking about that stuff we
were talking about the other
day, you know, life and stuff.
>> Yeah, well, uh, meaning is
what you make it.
It's all in your head.
>> I know.
I know and that is why I've
come up with another one.
You know, a riddle that has
meaning if you look at it just
the right way.
>> All right.
Go.
>> What's a ghost's favorite
color?
Boo!
Yeah.
>> Oh.
>> No, I...I know!
I know!
But think about it.
Okay, think about because if
that's true, then what would be
a ghost's favorite thing to
wear?
Boo jeans, dude!
[laugh]
I know!
That's pretty for real.
>> Yeah.
Look, um, I've gotta grab some
stuff from the back.
>> I'm glad he got that on tape.
>> "Ancient riddles."
"Riddles of the night.
Riddles for the spider."
>> [beep]
What has rivers but no water,"
forests but no trees, cities
but no buildings?"
Fine!
>> [train rumbling]
>> A map...a map.
>> [bleeping]
>> "Find Romeo's girl...and
the word of fear will then be
here.
>> Curran?
Curran?
Okay, so you know where I go
when I catch the train.
What do you want?
It's just a game.
No big deal.
>> [bang]
>> Curran?
Curran?
>> [gasping]
>> Sara?
>> Sara, what are you doing
here?
Oh, fuck!
Sara, come on.
Sara, no!
Sara, stop!
>> The police...
we have to call them!
>> No!
We can't call the police.
>> He's dead, Vern!
>> Sara!
Sara!
You were playing the game.
That's what you were doing
here, right?
And we can't go to the cops.
>> We have to.
>> Someone is setting us up for
this.
Do you understand?
Now, get in the truck.
Go home.
We'll meet tomorrow.
>> [open door]
>> Go home.
>> [alarm clock beeping]
>> [birds chirping]
>> A man lies dead in the
middle of the desert.
All he has with him is an
unopened package.
The unopened package explains
his death.
What's in the package?
>> LEA: What are you mumbling
about in here?
>> Nine across.
Unopened package explains the
man's death...bing!
Parachute!
>> Oh!
I gotta get to work.
>> Oh, honey, do me a favor,
would you, hmm?
Some of Sara's mail came here.
I thought if you return them to
her, it might be a nice excuse
to pop in and say hi.
>> You never give up, do you?
>> Hmm?
>> Oh, for God's sakes, Jeff.
She treats me like a rash.
>> Oh, that's not true, Lea.
>> Isn't it?
>> [doorbell ringing]
>> Tom?
>> Sorry to bother you, boss.
There's been a situation.
>> You lied.
>> I've never seen that before.
>> You were playing the game,
Sara.
Don't you think that's close
enough?
Yesterday someone left a nice
little message for me on one of
my windows.
At the other end of it all was
you...and a corpse.
Now I might be a little slow
here but what the fuck
is going on?
>> About six months ago my car
wouldn't start.
I was running late so I caught
the subway.
It was just like you said, Vern.
Written by the tracks, this
riddle.
I didn't know what it was.
I thought maybe it was for me.
So I answered it.
The answer led me to the
abandoned building.
When I got there the rest of
the game was spray painted on
the floor.
They were easy.
Write your answer to the subway
riddle on the wall of the
building.
That was it.
Then one day, maybe after one
riddle--or a hundred--you'd
finally get to see it.
The reason behind everything we
don't understand, you would
understand somehow.
So, I did it.
I went back to the subway and
they were there and...
>> ...you answered them.
And you had no idea who they
were from.
Real good, Sara.
That's real good.
>> I didn't think anything
would happen.
What do we do now?
>> We?
Look, I take full
responsibility for this, okay?
Really.
I mean, this whole time I was
thinking you were just this
chick into her intellectual
thing, but, you know, normal.
Turns out you're a psycho.
Oh, spare me the Miss Naïve act.
I saw that body, too, remember?
>> What?
You think I did it?
I found him like that!
>> Oh, yeah, out of the blue,
there he was.
>> I was playing...the game.
I was...
>> ...answering
riddles in the subway.
Crawling around in the dark,
you said.
What you didn't say was why.
Come on, Sara.
Good-looking educated girl like
you.
I bet the boys are lining up a
mile long for their piece of
white bread.
But you decided to come down
here instead.
Slum it with the likes of me.
Play your little mind games.
Well, something doesn't smell
quite right.
Why are you doing this?
Why are you playing this thing?
Why are you playing the game?
>> I was in a car crash, okay?
My mother was driving.
It killed her.
I was thrown clear.
There is a reason?
A design?
I guess I just wanted to know
what it was.
>> Sara, it's just a game.
It's not real.
>> What is a game, Vern?
Something where you have to
give the pieces back once your
time's up.
Well, guess what?
It means it's all a game.
Life, everything, one big
game.
>> [doorbell rings]
>> [footsteps]
>> We have to find out more
about this thing.
Who else is playing it.
Any idea where to start?
>> [techno music playing]
>> SARA: Curran's friend saw
him before he was killed.
She works here.
>> [techno music playing]
>> Novak, what the hell are you
doing?
Who's he?
>> Well, you're the one who
knows all about my secrets.
Why don't you tell me?
Everyone's got secrets, honey,
remember?
>> I don't know what you're
talking about, Novak.
>> You and Curran had something
going on, your little swinger's
thing.
Now you're going to tell me
about the rest of it.
What's my secret, Marie?
>> If you're talking about what
Curran said, he told me you
were a stripper, okay?
In another bar around here.
Someone gave him this card,
some kind of VIP pass.
>> VERN: Was this it?
>> What are you?
Her pimp or something?
>> Stripper?
>> Romeo's girl.
Place used to be a strip bar
before it was abandoned.
So who was the person who gave
him the card?
>> Well, I don't know.
He just said some guy.
>> Just some guy?
Nothing else?
>> All he said is he'd been
given the VIP pass for a club
and some kind of password, "I
never sinned".
You know, you say the password,
you get a special treatment.
>> I never sinned?
>> You heard it before?
>> WOMAN: He was just a little
boy, Dennis Reveni, 12 years
old.
Why did you try to kill
him?
>> [fast forward]
>> When he looks in the mirror,
he knows...I never sinned.
>> That's one very mixed up
lady.
>> Something happened to her,
Vern.
Straight A's through college, a
good job, a family.
She was playing this thing and
she went crazy.
>> Well, let's say something
did happen to her.
Some kind of cult thing maybe.
We've got worse things to worry
about here.
Someone wanted us to find that
body for a reason.
>> Well...according
to her public access file,
Emily Gray was released from an
asylum for the criminally
insane last year.
They keep her in a halfway
house just outside Toronto now.
>> Whatever is happening, it
ain't over.
>> [police radios]
>> [on television]
In breaking news, parts of
Toronto University are being
sealed off today as police
investigate a murder.
Known for the attempted
drowning in 1992 of a small
boy, Emily Gray, this morning,
has confessed to killing a
student from the local
university.
>> MALE REPORTER: Why did you
do it, Emily?
>> It's all part of the design.
>> FEMALE REPORTER: Police are
refusing all comments until a
psychiatric assessment has been
made.
>> Still hasn't said anything?
>> Other than her initial
statement...no.
And, of course, her request to
see you.
>> We found the body in the
bushes by the library.
It had been dragged there from
someplace else.
>> OFFICER: It's been
identified.
The victim is who she claims.
>> JEFF: Jeremy Curran.
It was all part of the design.
>> In other words her wheel's
spinning, but the hamster's
dead.
>> What about her lawyer?
>> Oh, he's given clearance for
you to talk to her.
He thinks maybe she's seen you
on TV before.
Is making some kind of
connection.
>> Okay.
Tom, let's get a copy of her
character profile.
Now she phoned it in initially
right?
>> Mmhm.
>> Let's get a recording of
that, too.
Damned if I know why she
wants to talk to me, but I
promise you this, she won't ask
twice.
>> [police radios]
>> I know what's happening.
Buddhist monks knew it all
along.
What is the sound of one hand
clapping?
Where does the room go once you
leave it?
They believed once you opened
yourself up to enigmas, you
began to see the world
differently.
You know who the figure on this
card is?
Well, neither did I.
So, I did some research.
>> VERN: Nemesis.
>> SARA: It's the closest
translation they found for his
name.
He was an Indian monk from
around 400 B.C.
He broke away from his
monastery and studied the way
of enigmas.
Two years later, he was
executed for murder.
You want to know how they
caught him?
He confessed.
>> Emily Gray.
>> Nemesis claimed--just
like all the other mysteries of
life--the
murder and his confession could
be understood through the
contemplation of riddles.
In the years after his death, a
game was developed by his
followers.
The players solved riddles and
wrote their answers on the
temple of prayer.
When, if they were diligent, it
was said they would go to write
their answers on the wall, only
this time they would find a
riddle waiting there
instead--the final enigma.
And if they solved it...
>> ...they would see the design.
>> Those that saw the design
would then leave more riddles
for others to follow.
>> So Emily Gray tries to drown
the boy after she plays the
game.
>> If she had drowned the boy,
my guess is she would have
confessed.
>> But she failed.
So they lock her up.
When they finally let her out,
she tries again.
This time she does kill
someone--your friend.
And then confesses.
>> Just like Nemesis.
>> [sirens wailing]
>> Vern, what are you doing?
>> What I should have done from
the start.
>> What?
You mean the police?
First you want to leave them
out of it, then when someone
confesses you want to get
involved?
>> Sara, if you hadn't noticed,
something's not quite right
here.
According to your stripper
friend, someone tricked Curran
into going to that building.
It wasn't Emily Gray.
It was a man.
Someone you know.
Think about it.
The riddle you found in the
subway wasn't random.
They had to know who you were,
what you were into.
They even know about me, right?
They left the riddle in the
store.
Whatever's going on here, it's
not just about Emily Gray.
>> We can't go to the cops.
>> Yeah, well, watch me.
>> Vern...what if it's real?
What if there's something
happening that we can't explain?
Don't you want to know the
answers?
>> You just don't get it, do
you?
Your mother died.
I'm sorry.
That's messed up.
But if you're looking for some
kind of magic potion for your
problems just because you had a
rough ride, well, guess what?
You're not the only one.
Try watching two of your
friends die in a construction
fire that was you fault.
Try getting over that in a
hurry.
We've withheld evidence of a
murder here.
If we don't tell the cops what
happened, then our credibility
is gone--and
that's all we've got right now.
We've got nothing but our word
here.
Find Romeo's girl and the word
fear will be here.
>> What are you talking about?
>> Nothing.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe we shouldn't go to the
cops.
Go home.
Get rid of anything to do with
riddles, anything to do with
the game.
>> You think we can cover this
up?
>> Just that part of it.
Get rid of everything that
connects you to this thing.
>> What about you?
>> I've got to check something
first.
>> Hi, Emily.
Didn't need to be like this,
did it?
>> [sighs]
Emily Gray.
First class honors, high school.
Graduated, Vancouver.
Everything seems to have gone
along swimmingly until 1995.
Then 1996...wow!
You tried to drown a little boy
in the lake...
out of the blue.
You served five years for that.
You're only out for one and
then this mess.
You want to tell me what's
going on?
I mean, you do, right?
That's...why you confessed.
I'm all ears, Emily.
You got something worth saying,
let's hear it.
What...the hell...happened?
>> What if I told you that I
knew the meaning of life?
That every leaf that falls,
every bee you crush underfoot,
it's all part of a design.
So complex it looks like
chaos, but it's not.
>> Is there a Santa Claus, too?
Okay, you got me.
What's the design?
>> Describe the color red.
Some things you have to see for
yourself.
>> Right.
So, how do I see this design?
Look, Emily, if you want
someone who's going to pant and
beg for what's going on in your
head, you've got the wrong guy.
Either you tell me what this is
all about or I'm out of
here--right?
What's the design?
Okay.
That just about covers it.
Good luck with the padded cell.
>> Have you figured out why it
happened yet?
Your poor wife.
Three days in a hospital, her
ribcage crushed by the steering
wheel.
You haven't been able to make
any sense out of it, have you?
>> Who told you that?
Look, just because somehow you
got a hold of my file, doesn't
mean to say I'm going to roll
over and play dead.
I hate to be the one to tell
you this, lady, but there is no
design.
You're crazy.
>> Am I?
Because I tried to drown a boy?
Because I killed a student?
Is that so wrong?
Is an earthquake wrong when it
kills?
Or a car or a flight of stairs.
Why don't you just admit it?
You don't understand why
anything happens and you never
will.
>> [file drops]
>> Congratulations, Emily.
You're the only one in the
whole wide world who knows the
design.
>> Not the only one, Jeff.
There are many of us.
When I look in the mirror, I
know his name.
Another who has seen the design
as I have.
Look at it in the mirror.
>> Look at what?
>> Ask your daughter.
>> [frantic music]
>> [phone ringing]
>> Hello?
>> JEFF: [on phone]
Sara, I need you to listen to
me.
>> Dad.
>> Do you know anything about a
woman named Emily Gray.
>> What?
>> She claims...you
know something about a design.
She looks in the mirror and she
says she sees a name.
Do you know what that means?
Does this mean anything to you,
Sara?
>> Yes.
>> Listen, I want you to go get
in your car and go to the house.
Do you understand?
I want you to go somewhere safe.
Sara...
>> I...yeah.
Erm, yeah, I'll go.
>> JEFF: [oh phone]
It'll be okay.
I'll see you soon.
>> [suspenseful music]
>> Dennis Reveni.
>> WOMAN: He was just a little
boy, Dennis Reveni,
12-years-old.
Why did you try to kill him?
>> When he looks in
the mirror, he knows...
I never sinned.
>> [computer bleeps]
>> I'm here.
So where's the word of fear?
>> [computer beeps]
>> [computer beeping]
>> All right, I'm here.
This is what you wanted, right?
I was supposed to come here
with the answer.
Well, here I am.
You win, man.
I thought you were the village
idiot, okay?
You win, man.
What do you want from me?
>> [thud]
>> You want to kill me, hmm?
Is that it?
Do you want to kill me, too,
you ghost?
Bring it on.
"What eats to live, but never
drinks?"
>> [clattering]
You want me to answer it?
Is that it?
You want me to come down here
and write the answer to your
riddle on the wall?
What eats to live, but never
drinks?
>> Oh!
Oh.
Sorry.
>> I was just this little boy
and I was playing by the water
and she came up and she tried
to push me under.
She tried to kill me!
And I never understood why...
until I found this riddle.
When I answered it, I suddenly
knew.
It's all part of the design,
Sara.
You un--you understand,
you know.
No matter what we do, Emily
showed me.
There's no right or wrong.
There's only the design.
We kill because there's no
reason not to.
You can't run away from it,
Sara.
We all have our role to play in
this.
I know mine.
Do you know what yours is?
Arrghh!
[gasping]
You'll see it soon.
>> [gun shot]
>> [scream]
>> Tom, is she okay?
>> Whoa, whoa!
Boss, boss, boss...
>> What?
>> Just...just
give her a minute.
>> Well, what happened?
A street kid attacked her.
We got two witnesses inside.
>> Street kid?
>> He died ten minutes after we
got here.
>> Oh!
>> There was a struggle, he had
a gun.
>> Who was he?
>> That's what we're trying to
get from her now.
>> Sara, I need you to think
really clearly right now.
I want you to tell me exactly
what happened.
>> I told you.
I was attacked by a gun man.
His name was Dennis Reveni.
>> What was he doing here?
You knew who he was.
Sara?
When we searched the body, we
found this in one of the
pockets.
It appears he knew who you were.
>> Sara, are you okay?
Baby?
On the phone, you said you knew
something about all of this.
You've got to help us now.
What happened?
Sara, please!
You know, honey, we might never
know why mom died.
But if we knew all the answers,
we wouldn't be human.
Maybe...maybe
not knowing the answers but
going on living, that's what
life's all about.
Tom.
>> TOM: Yeah?
>> I'm going to take her down
to the station myself.
>> You okay?
You want me to come with you?
>> No, we'll be...be okay.
>> All right.
>> Sara!
>> Vern?
Vern, are you in here?
Do you know the answers now?
Do you understand?
Is there really a design?
>> It was all part of the
design, Sara.
>> *