May the force be
with you, spaceman.
Get the fuck out of here.
Dude drives a $50,000
wheel and lays a cuter on me.
I can do better than this cleaning
the crap out of cuckoo clocks.
Eddie: What the hell am I
supposed to do with this anyway?
Take your family
out to dinner with this?
You have the wrong attitude
about this job, Eddie.
You gotta appreciate
the zen aspects of this.
Eddie: Zen aspect?
What's a zen aspect?
Joe, you holding out on me?
No
You doing reefer
for the brothers,
or is the old lady
on her mood cycle again?
Why do you ask
something like that?
Because once a month without
fail you get bullshit philosophical on me.
Yeah, well, that's what happens
when you're married, Eddie.
Didn't that happen to you
when you were married?
No, no, no ways. I'm an
old-fashioned kind of guy.
I'd go to the cubs game and get drunk.
Miss the whole thing.
Yeah, maybe that's why
you're not married anymore.
Angles Ryan again.
Third time today.
Fourth you were in the can
Joe: Isn't that
white fang talking to him?
Yeah, he got the teeth
on a postal rap.
Yeah, the feds are good
about dental work.
Bring it in, come on.
A little more. A little more.
Okay, put it in neutral.
You want the super spray
wax special with the
with the non dissolving lacto
rust-o-protector...
Just a regular wash. Thank you.
Want me to do the ashtray?
I don't smoke. Get out of here.
Going down, Joe, I know it.
If we get them after the exchange, they're
gonna cop possession without intent.
What are you doing?
Joe,
I hope you appreciate the zen
aspects of what I'm about to do.
Oh, Jesus.
Police!
Ryan: What the... what the fuck?
What's the matter with you?
What are you doing?
Eddie: Police! Open up!
Open up! Ryan: Oh my god!
Chicago police department!
Get the fuck out of here!
What are you, nuts?
Joe, get the bag.
Chicago police department!
You're under arrest!
Get your hands of me.
Put it in there!
Get that out of here!
What's wrong with you?
Eddie: You're gonna destroy my interior!
I'll kill you.
I'll fuck you up now, boy!
Eddie: Let go, Ryan! Let go.
This is it.
I give a fuck. Give me the keys!
Fucking, give me the
goddamn keys, Ryan!
Get out of the car!
Let's go!
Let's go! Come on! Come on!
Get out of the fucking car.
Get out of the fucking...
Get them up there!
You got a piece?
Down! Down! Down!
Down!
You fucking move,
and you're dead meat!
It's grass. Rich!
Joe: All we got is grass.
Rat shit.
Three frigging days I'm
out there washing cars.
You disrespect
me with this shit?
We're sending you up.
Hard time, Ryan.
Come on.
It was less than a pound.
That is a felony, dipshit!
You're a three time loser.
Ryan: Take it easy.
Take it easy.
You guys. What's the matter with you?
You are playing it all wrong.
One of you guys is
supposed to be nice.
You know. You're both not
supposed to be hard.
Hard? Hard...
Ryan, you don't know
what hard is.
You're going to the joint
with the brothers.
You know what they're gonna
do to your ass?
Come on, hey, 3
little bit of reefer was
sit down!
Take it easy, will you?
What you guys wanna make a deal?
That's it? All right.
I'll give you something.
Let's see. I got a...
Got a record store. They got hot tvs.
They got stereos.
You give me a two bit fence
after making me wash cars?
You know what the fuck
that does to me?
I can think of
bookies and pimps!
You're a jerk! You're doing
hard time for pushing smoke!
Six years, minimum!
No, wait, wait a minute, eh!
You guys can't put me away. I got
freckles, for Christ's sakes!
Eh, you want something? I got
something for you! I got a hit!
They want me to kill somebody.
Yeah. You?
Who's the target?
I don't know
don't insult our intelligence.
A guy from New Orleans. I swear.
He wants me to whack
some guy out. Real bad.
I'm supposed to
meet him tonight.
This guy from New Orleans,
he knows your face?
This has gotta be
worth something.
Where's the meeting?
Meeting's tonight at
the stockyard inn at 9:00.
He's gonna be with a girl.
A real heart stopper.
She's got a tattoo on her shoulder.
That's all I know.
Ryan: Oh! Hello!
My hat! My cigarettes! Hey!
Why don't we check out that
New Orleans guys ourselves?
Come on, I'm tired.
I wanna go home.
What's so great
about going home...
Rust ferry bongo player in
the rack with your old lady?
She's not like that.
No she's not like that
my wife...
Left a type written note on
the refrigerator door saying
she was leaving
so she could breathe.
Yeah, yeah. Last time it was
on the bathroom mirror.
And the time before that was
on the screen door.
Get your facts straight,
jillette
I don't believe this
I'm trying to share a valuable,
personal experience with you.
You finger fuck me with details.
Don't drink my coffee
from my cup, jillette!
I swear, I met a
better type of cop in vice.
Crabs, big d and gonorrhea,
that's all I had to worry about.
All I did was use your cup,
stemkowski.
Captain stemkowski!
What the hell are you
so mad about?
I was meditating this morning...
Feeling real good about myself.
What happens?
Car washes happen!
They're trying to pass that balloon
robot at office as a work of art!
Captain, we gotta talk to you.
Why should I talk to you after
that chicken shit stakeout?
What do you want? Overtime?
A hundred grand, jillette.
A hundred?
That's what he wants
for that piece of shit.
Guy wants to go to Florida and retire
with a bag of oranges in his lap.
Forget it! Captain?
Come on, let's do it ourselves.
Blow off some steam.
Have some fun.
Aw, you just wanna see
the broad, jillette.
What's wrong with that, Joe?
I don't see any
heart-stoppers here.
These broads still got the price
tag hanging from their nose.
Eddie: Nice, nice.
There he is. He's the dick
Dipper we're looking for.
Joe: Maybe she's his sister.
She's got "born to screw"
tattooed on her forehead.
Don't be bitter. Me, bitter?
- I know the secret to happiness.
- Oh, yeah. What's that?
A girl with freckles
on her tits.
Can I help you?
You got it wrong.
Oh, of course.
Sit down.
Outside.
We're just about to order.
Nice, Eddie. Nice.
You got a hard on for this girl, so
you gotta go and jump on this guy.
You blew it
man comes up to you looking for a Chicago
shooter. What am I supposed to do?
- Swap spit with him, blow in his ear?
- Always works for me.
That's not what your wife says.
Huh? I'd be offended if
you didn't owe me money.
Oh, you're such a romantic.
Ha-ha. No, no, not me. You're
the romantic one, Eddie.
Hence your problem. Yeah.
No. You wired? Huh?
Ever since we walked in to the joint,
I thought we were being watched.
He's clean
Satisfied?
Okay, nothing personal. Right?
Just want to make sure
you're not cops.
Of course.
Get your car and follow me.
I have a problem in New Orleans
I'd like taken care of.
So why not use local?
The man I want you to do
business with is very connected.
He'd know if I used local.
So, why do you want
this guy hit?
Is that important?
Stay out of this, lady.
I don't like the way
you say lady.
What's this gonna cost?
A lot more than her
drop this guy. He's a loser.
You want me to go to a strange
city and make a hit?
I gotta know who the guy is.
What his habits are?
Let this broad go down on you, a
couple of times. She runs your life.
You came up here 'cuz you don't have
the fucking guts to hit him yourself.
You don't have the balls to
keep your woman in her place!
I think we can do business
I don't know, Eddie.
They're not buying it.
She's giving me attitude,
that's all.
This guy's dying to talk.
Think he's smart.
Give me one hour, will you?
Take her back to her hotel
and what am I
supposed to do with her?
What do you usually do?
I don't do anything.
I'm married.
Get the car, Joe.
Wait for me in the room.
Where you staying?
Ambassador east, the penthouse.
You and I should take a ride.
Fine
She's not what you think,
you know.
She's an exceptional woman.
Yeah, sure.
Eddie: So, who's this guy
you want hit?
The man in question
is very dangerous.
Enjoys violence.
Paul: Michel says some women find
him attractive because of that.
Eddie: What does she have to
do with this?
She belongs to him.
I'm lost. What does that mean?
We come from a society which is
very pleasurable to be a man.
You have somebody follow us?
No
Shit! Get out of the car.
Eddie: Get out of the car.
Move it!
Fddie: Get out!
Paul: I can't! I can't get out!
This isn't a job for you.
We can handle it
your friend, maybe. But not you.
Go home to your wife.
What makes you
think I'm married?
I can tell.
You don't belong here.
I'm waiting for Eddie.
Stop it!
I'm a police officer!
Stop the fucking car! Stop it!
Where you going?
It's over
what's over?
Life, my friend.
Hey, hey.
I'm a police officer.
All right, now. Hold it.
Come on,
get out of the elevator.
My partner's
in trouble up there.
Out of the elevator.
I want you to make a call, 911 and
get help over here right away!
Get out of the elevator.
Make the call
make the call!
Police!
Joe?
Joe.
Joe
How you doing?
You okay?
Eddie, what happened?
He was waiting for me.
I was late.
He always tried to
prepare me for this.
It's part of being
a cop's wife, right?
He'd want you to have that.
He loved you.
You look like stale piss.
What were you and
Collins doing with the victim?
He thought we were hit men.
He wanted us to
whack a guy in New Orleans.
Jesus Christ!
Who was this guy?
Paul deveneux. Sent a bag of ashes
to his family in New Orleans.
Real sweethearts
we figured whoever deveneux wanted
to waste, he got him first, huh?
Yeah
So, who was this?
I don't know.
I never got a name.
That's great, jillette.
What were you two doing? Driving
around in the moonlight?
You talk to the cops down there?
You tell them about Joe?
Yeah
they say that's our problem.
My problem.
It's different down there.
You don't know New Orleans.
They don't even talk like us.
I'll make myself understood.
Bitch
- Mr. deveneux, will see you now.
- Hey, thanks.
Detective jillette
Allan deveneux.
I'm Paul's cousin.
I talked to your
superiors in Chicago.
I don't know what more
I can add.
Bernice, Mr. jillette.
Hi
And Susan is Paul's wife.
I know this has been
a very difficult time for you,
but I'd like to
ask a few questions.
Mint julep? No, thanks.
What type of business was
your husband in?
Oh, agriculture, oil,
that sort of thing.
Was he having any financial problems?
“We never discussed them.
Was anything troubling him?
No
Did he have any enemies?
Not that I know of
I knew very little
about Paul's personal life.
You know what he was
doing in Chicago?
No
He hired me to kill somebody.
Susan has been under
terrible strain,
and that kind of inquiry
won't help.
Does Michel mean
anything to you? -No.
She was with him.
Tattoo on her right shoulder.
A tattoo? Huh?
I'm gonna miss Paul.
He was a very amusing man.
Well, I appreciate your coming down here.
I wish I could help you more.
It seems as if your people
don't know a great deal...
Apart from a young lady
with a tattoo.
You find that amusing?
No
I need to see the personal
papers of the deceased
phone bills, credit cards,
address books, everything
well, I don't intend to prolong
this grotesque tragedy.
I hope you understand that.
Oh, I understand.
Goodbye, Mr. jillette.
Good bye.
Now, you should understand me.
I don't play tennis,
I don't drink mint juleps, and
I don't give a shit about you
your family, your horny
bat shit dead cousin.
I'm looking for the bastard
that gutted my partner and
tied his intestines
around his neck.
And with or without your help,
I'm gonna get him.
You've just made
a very big mistake.
About you? About you? Huh?
You? No. Not about you.
Man: The place your
mother warned you about!
Male and female shows onstage.
Disgusting! You'll love this.
And you get in free right now.
Men and women.
They're all real, home grown,
no soy.
See the grisly acts of passion
just as they happened.
Learn the secrets
of the bitches daughter.
See the basement where Angeline
buried her lovers. It's all here.
I just came down here
for the weekend,
and I met this local girl.
Name's Michel.
Blond, blue eyed, about 5'6.
She's got this terrific tattoo right
behind her, her right shoulder.
It's a blue parrot, and I wanna
get one exactly like it.
I think she said she got it at your place.
Does that make any sense?
You don't do parrots.
You know any place that does?
Okay. Thanks anyway.
- Freeze, you motherfucker! Your history.
- Lieutenant hall.
We're police.
Shit.
Someone's been on my tail.
Was it you?
What'd he look like?
I didn't see him.
- You saw somebody you didn't see?
- You're a fucking comedian.
No, you're the comedian.
This is my town, jillette. You check
with me before you piss in my streets.
Make house calls
like you're somebody.
- Deveneux filed a complaint against you.
- Oh, bullshit.
He's got a witness.
Fucking bullshit!
I'm not fucking around with you, boy!
What bullshit
you cross me, and [ll
personally grease the pole
that slides you into
a tub of shit.
Somebody guts my partner, and you're
thinking nasty things about me.
That really,
fucking breaks me up.
I'm sorry about your partner.
But I want you
out of here on the
first plane in the A.M..
Get him out of here.
Algiers? Where's that?
You're on a plane tomorrow
morning, jillette.
That's tomorrow
across the bridge.
Look, you go asking questions
in Algiers...
They'll cut your tongue out
and throw it in the river.
Thanks.
Not really.
Anybody speak english here?
I'm looking for Cara Jones.
Yeah, yeah.
Cara Jones.
A black girl.
Where is she?
Where is who?
Michel
I don't know no Michel
I don't know anything.
What? Day or night?
Is it day or night?
Night.
You see, you do know something.
Don't ever lie to me again.
You a tough guy?
Tough enough.
Hi
Michel here tonight?
Who wants to know?
A friend.
I doubt it
You remember me?
I just read you your rights.
You're under arrest, lady.
This is what's gonna happen.
You and I are
gonna walk out of this joint.
You're gonna keep
your fat mouth shut.
You got it. Huh?
Come on.
Jillette
what? Eddie jillette
Eddie jillette. Say it.
Fddie jillette
if anything else comes out of
your mouth, you're history.
You shoot, they'll kill you.
Think I give a shit about dying?
Eddie: Go! Move!
Fddie: Run!
Oh, no, tough guy! Don't even think
about it! Move over there! Move! Move!
Eddie: Come on! Move it!
Stop the car!
Stop the goddamn car! Get out! Get
out of the car! Get out of the car!
Move it! Get in!
Shit!
Get your head down.
Keep it down!
Ow!
No! I'll tell you when to die.
Yeah. Got a light?
Went in right here.
Yeah, right.
He's gone, man. He's gone.
No!
Michel, where are you?
Not a word,
or you go under. Nothing.
I osado: Call to me.
Try him.
He thinks you're his prisoner.
Jillette!
Fddie jillette
sure, I know your name.
I'll make you a deal.
Fddie jillette
let Michel go.
You don't want her. You want me.
Come out.
Face me.
Just two of us.
You kill me
you go home...
Safe
I guarantee.
But
if you make me come after you...
You die, for sure...
I tke an animal
like your friend.
I cut him open... Eddie jillette
like a pig.
I osado!
Kick. You wanna live,
start kicking.
Michel
Cara: I swear,
I didn't say nothing.
I osado: You talked to him.
No
Yes, my friend.
Sorry to end your
beauty sleep, lady.
You know where we are?
How far did we drift?
How should I know?
Eddie: Jesus Christ!
I can't stand these anymore.
Help me get them off.
You're tough.
Why don't you gnaw it off?
Give me the key.
I can't go anywhere.
I wish I could.
I lost it in the river.
I've got to get them off.
They won't get off.
I have to get them off.
I can't stand it anymore!
- You're just gonna hurt yourself.
- I can't. You gotta them off!
I've gotta get away from youl!
I can't stand it anymore. - Hey!
Hold it hold it! Hold it!
You're gonna hurt yourself!
Now shut up! -Aaah!
You're such a fucking...
Damn boat!
Stupid idiot.
You shut the fuck up!
Well, you lead the way, okay?
You lead the way
and then after you die...
- I have a dead man hanging on my arm!
- I ook! Listen to me.
When I die, it's gonna be on
Chicago concrete. You got it?
Now, fucking move! Walk!
Let go.
Stop! You're hurting me.
I wanna know what happened.
I wanna know why you and your
boyfriend set up deveneux.
I wanna know what you get
for killing a man.
Most of all, I wanna know how
you killed my fucking partner!
He runs Algiers.
Runs Algiers?
What the hell is that?
I belong to him.
No shit what does that mean?
What do you think me?
I think it means losado got himself a
two-bit hooker. That's what I think.
I was 13, my mama took me
to losado.
He gave her a house
and some money.
And I was his. You got that?
I was given to him.
Every hooker's got
a hard-luck story.
That's a real prizewinner,
that one.
If you don't believe me,
you don't matter!
Wrong. I matter a whole lot,
lady.
You're going to jail, and your
boyfriend's gonna stop breathing.
Eddie: Hello?
Hey?
Hey, hey. Hey! Hey!
What are you doing?
Can't you read?
Nothing. Not a crumb.
Come on.
Michel: Great!
What is it?
You never had crawfish before?
Sure, my mom used to put them
in my lunch.
No
Oh, not like that.
I ike that
see, you take them,
and you break the head off.
And suck the juice out of it.
Good?
Yeah, it's good.
Do you have a wife?
Yeah, ex.
Ran off with some guy.
What'd you do?
What do you mean?
Well, did you go after him?
Just left me, that's it.
That's all there was
what's so funny?
You're a tough guy, a cop.
And you didn't do anything?
All right, what happened?
She calls me up
and says, "Eddie...
"I think
"if you and David sat down and had
a beer you'd have like each other"
- so you took him out for a beer?
- Yeah, I really nailed him.
Stuck him with the tab.
You're not from there.
You wouldn't understand.
Hey! Hey, hey, hey.
Don't get excited now.
It's like rain somewhere.
Somewhere pretty.
God, I wish I was far away.
Forget.
Just forget.
Yeah, let's forget.
You're good, lady.
You are... really, really good.
This how you played it with that dumb,
dead jerk in Chicago? Deveneux?
Give some guy a hard-on.
Next thing he knows,
he's getting killed for you.
What the hell, huh?
What the hell!
A whore's a whore. Goes with the territory.
You don't know me.
You don't know anything
about my life.
You think you know everything
but you don't know anything
I know one thing. I do know one thing!
About my life.
Joey Collins is dead
because of you.
And you stood there, and you just
fucking watched, didn't you?
Didn't you? Didn't you?
You don't know what
I've seen in my life.
Do you think that was the worst?
You think that was the worst?
You wanna hear something
about it? Do you?
Losado will kill you.
That's what I'm gonna watch.
I'm not a whore
what?
never been with anyone
except losado.
Yeah, so?
I'm not a whore
Okay. I'm a police officer.
You understand me?
Police officer? A cop?
This 1s my prisoner.
Yeah. Cop.
What are you saying to them?
Keep your mouth shut.
Do you speak any english at all?
You understand this woman's under arrest.
She's my prisoner.
Don't touch her.
Take your fucking hands off!
Don't touch her!
Keep your fucking hands off her!
I osado! I osado!
That's right!
This is losado's woman!
I osado?
Eddie: Yeah, losado.
You understand that?
He'll come here, cut your fucking
hand off and scratch your ass with it
if you touch her.
I osado?
Yeah, losado! Back off!
(Speaking in French
they called losado.
This his operation?
Yeas
he works for him?
Deveneux?
He smuggles them in and sells
them to deveneux. Is that it?
What happened? Deveneux got greedy?
Is that why they whacked him?
Why did you help me?
Why did you say losado's name?
Tub of shit.
Okay.
Turn your head.
Come on.
Get in!
Eddie: No, you don't!
I don't get it.
Losado's in business with deveneux.
Smuggles in cheap labor.
So, what were you doing
with deveneux in Chicago?
And why did he want
to kill losado?
He said it was the only way.
Deveneux promised to help me.
Help you do what?
Get free from losado.
What did you promise him?
I didn't promise him anything.
He was a gentleman.
Jesus Christ, this whole
thing's about you, isn't it?
Get out.
Don't move.
Don't even think about it.
Okay, okay, okay... give it up.
Yeah... wait! Police officer.
And I'm tinkerbell, asshole.
Police officer!
Handcuffs. Keep still.
Jesus Christ!
The next time you send one
of your people down here...
They'd better be advised
to exhibit a better sense
of professionalism and respect.
I don't know how you do things in
Chicago, and I don't intend to find out.
But it doesn't work down here.
Cop to cop.
Your boy has drowned in his own
puddle of mud if you get my meaning.
I wanna know why he's in
this piss-stained rat cage.
They're still
pissed about the war.
Listen here, boy!
Cop to cop...
I want this man out of here.
I want him showered and shaved and
polished up like it's payday...
And south street is filled with
ladies that don't know the word "no"
you get my meaning?
Do it
Thanks.
You come down here, you lose your
gun, your star and your pants.
Got the girl.
With you, there's always a girl.
You better get it together,
jillette
because if they have
their way, you're gonna be
just another piece of maggot shit,
turning big rocks into little ones.
They got the decks
marked and wired.
Life cheats, jillette.
Oh, you're a treasure,
stemkowski.
That's what your
ex-wife says. -My ex?
If you want out of here, you keep
your mouth shut. -
I have Ms. duval's
sworn affidavit
that she did in fact meet
Mr. jillette in Chicago.
That he presented himself
as an assassin for hire.
That he went off
with my cousin Paul.
And that detective Collins went
out of the hotel by himself.
Since you have no evidence
placing miss duval at the hotel
I suggest you drop criminal
proceedings against her.
What I understand she's a
witness against a Mr. I osado.
She maintains she
didn't see anything.
Ask her
thank you for your summary.
The Chicago police department
apologizes for any inconvenience
that we may have caused
this woman.
I'm sure you understand that
in murder of a fellow officer
we're willing to go to extraordinary
lengths to pursue the slightest lead.
I just received word
from Chicago
that we apprehended
a prime suspect in this case.
And that we need detective jillette
back as soon as possible to identify.
This man came into my home.
He threatened me.
He frightened my family.
He destroyed my car.
We've already paid for the car.
You're missing my point. The
man is dangerously unstable!
He has no business
being a police officer.
And I'm gonna see he's put away.
He abducted this woman. He
threatened to kill her. Ask her.
What happened between this man and
me doesn't concern you or the law.
You sign this please, so I
can get rid of these guys.
My client can't read.
Thank you. You're free to go.
Losado: Don't let her out
of your sight.
I don't wanna see
either of you guys.
The plane leaves
in five minutes.
I don't particularly like you,
jillette
I don't wanna hold hands, I don't wanna
take long walks in the moonlight...
And I don't wanna swap spit.
I want
that son-of-a-bitch losado.
What the hell? Lawrence!
Don't forget. I'm very unstable.
I'm a lawyer. I had to say that.
Guys like you...
Always think you can walk away
from things like this, don't you?
Look, can we talk about this?
I don't give a damn about you.
It's losado I want.
I understand that
do you fucking understand?
You're right.
I don't understand that.
Get down!
Aaargh!
Kiss it goodbye.
No!
Please, no!
I'll be in Algiers.
You tell losado.
Second floor. If you wanna guest
towels, it's an extra $10.
If anybody ask for me...
Yeah, I never seen you.
Wrong.
If anybody asks for Eddie
jillette, tell them I'm upstairs.
Who else is staying here?
Well, at the moment, uh...
I'm taking all the rooms.
There's no future in the job.
Go home.
It's still $10
for the extra towel. -
He's not out there
he won't come for you.
He's in the bayou tonight.
He'll come for me.
And that's what you want,
isn't it?
Yeas
if you wanna die so bad...
Why don't you put that gun to
your head and pull the trigger?
Go on.
I didn't come here to die
Eddie, go.
Go.
You can still get out of here.
You can get out right now.
I can't leave.
Please, Eddie.
It's all right.
Say it. Say it.
Say my name.
Say "Michel".
Michel.
Say it.
Michel,
Michel, Michel, Michel.
Did you love her?
Who?
Your wife?
You ask an awful
lot of questions. -
too many?
Maybe.
Did you?
Yes.
Do you still?
Are you a cop?
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
What are you thinking?
How things fade... finally.
Do they?
Or do you just learn to live
with them?
You know, my mama's house
was old and noisy like this.
I used to think it sounded like voices.
Stop.
Right there. Shift your weight.
Okay, take a step to your right.
Okay, good. Right there.
What kind of house
did you live in Eddie?
Like, when you were little.
No houses. Apartments.
All of them dumps.
Take another step.
When I was little
okay, good.
My mama used to put a drop of
perfume in a glass of water.
Then she said, "Michel,
now, drink this right up...
It'll make you
feel pretty inside."
That's it, right there. Good.
Don't.
It's him
Michel, listen to me.
I want you to go.
He'll be here soon.
I want you out of here
by the time he comes. -
no, I'm staying with you.
No, you're not. You're leaving.
I want you to get as far away from
this stinking shithole as you can.
Whatever went down in Chicago's got nothing
to do with you anymore. It's over.
You're free.
Michel, go on. This is your chance.
Get out of here.
Eddie, you have to talk to me. You
have to talk to me right now.
Come on, we've got time.
You have to talk to me.
Just talk to me.
Just for a while talk to me.
You want to help me?
Please get out of here. -Hmm.
I won't let him kill you.
Please.
Together, we have a chance. I want a
chance, Eddie. That's all I want.
I love you. I want time...
I don't care about you!
I want you.
Get the fuck out of here!
You couldn't stop this,
could you?
Then what good are you...
My friend?
Losado: He's a dead man, Michel.
For you.
Losado: All for you.
Don't come any closer unless
you're willing to die with him.
I et him live
and I'll come with you,
like before.
For good.
I always give you
what you want, no?
Come.
Show him that you belong to me.
I osado! I osado!
You'll die, my friend!
You'll die!
Oh, yes. You'll burn, my friend.
You see that, shithead?
I got a one-bedroom apartment.
I don't cook.
I've got a color TV.
I forget to do things. Anniversaries,
birthdays... -
Christmas.
When I'm on a job,
I'm gone for days sometimes.
You understand what I'm saying?
I get drunk.
I yell at the people I love.
So what do you say? Huh?
What do you say?
J» lost and lonely lives
j» floating like waves at sea
> we make it day by day
> watching the world go by
j» in a moment
where time stands still
> from here we look out on
forever
j» darling our love
> One love that never fades away
d our love
j» this love will light
the world on its way
J» shattered broken dreams
d> sifting like grains of sand
> we claim it and here we stay
> watching the world go by
» with the strength
that we spend in this life
j» in the hope
that it goes on forever
» we believe that
as we promise to try
j» that darling our love
> One love that never fades away
d our love
j» this love will light
the world on its way
J» in a moment
when time stands still
> from here we look out on
forever
j» and we can see
all that time will tell
j» 'cause darling our love
> one love that never fades away
d our love
j» this love will light
the world on its way j»