What do you have out here
that you don't have inside?
The moon...
and a few billion stars.
Hmm.
I don't think I can
compete with that...
but I can try.
Go back to bed.
I'll be in soon.
Mivida...
don't worry.
That's my job
when I'm not writing.
Why?
The check might
be here tomorrow...
and you will have
wasted tonight.
The sun will rise...
and bring all good things
with it.
Hmm?
Mm-hmm?
So there's one already.
- Ha ha ha!
- Come on.
Come on, honey.
Let's dance, honey.
No, honey! Mihelado!
Pick your passion--
me or the ice cream.
Oh! No. No, no!
No!
Come on.
Let's go get a drink.
No, it's too early.
Come on, honey.
You already had your treat.
No.
Hey, Jack.
How's it going, buddy?
- Good.
- Good man.
- Two, Bill.
- One.
OK.
- The good stuff?
- Uh, no, not today. No.
Long time between
royalty checks, huh?
Well, you know what they say--
it's a feast or famine business.
Yeah. More like
famine-famine lately.
Ah, don't worry.
Your credit's good...
as long as you got Luz with you.
Heh.
Cómo estás, papita.
Fine, thank you.
And yourself?
Oh, real good right now.
Real good.
How's the wife, Bill?
Too smart to walk
into a dive like this...
with a bunch of losers.
I’m sure she gets
enough of that at home.
Keep the change, Bill.
Come on.
What'd you do,
hock your car? Huh?
Hey, it'll take more than this
to buy you some pride big-time.
- What is your problem?
- Danny, no.
You pathetic lackey!
Oh, yeah, yeah. You just keep
talkin' to the mirror, man.
You know, one more month
without a check, and you are me.
Come on, let's go.
Hey, we got an apron in the back
with your name on it...
just waitin' for you,
Danny boy!
Do you believe that?
What a stupid son of a bitch.
No! You're the stupid
son of a bitch...
for arguing with
a stupid son of a bitch!
Hey, all I wanted was a drink.
You had a hundred bars
to choose from!
You went up there
to punish yourself--
and me, too, maybe.
I don't need this.
What's the matter?
Did you lose something?
Get--
Aah!
Luz!
What happened? Oh, my God!
Luz, are you OK?
Oh, my God.
You're--blood!
Are you all right?
Honey...we've got to
get out of here.
It's all right now.
Honey? It's all right.
It's all right.
Sweetheart...
His face, Danny.
I thought he was...
grabbing at me. I--
So I...
turned to him, you know?
Angry.
And the last face...
he saw before
he left the world...
was angry.
Luz, he was probably
already gone, honey.
No.
Sweetie. Luz.
Luz...
maybe you'd like to go rest
before we go home.
Let's go inside.
I pray for his soul.
It's all right.
Oh. Oh.
- You OK?
- Yeah.
Come on.
E-e-excuse me.
Look...I don’t want
to bother you guys...
but maybe you can help me out.
What is it?
I’m looking for a ride
to the border.
Why don’t you just fly?
Well, I'm a little squeamish
about flying.
Mexican roads aren't any safer.
How'd you get here?
Uh, a yacht, but I wanted
to spend a little time...
and my friends had to get back.
Why the rush now?
I just found out
I have a meeting in Dallas.
Oh, well...bummer.
Tell me about it.
You know anybody with a car?
I’ll pay good money.
I might. How much?
I don't know. Uh...
2, 3,000?
- Oh, I have a c--
- Shh.
Uh, I have a car,
but I'm pretty busy right now.
Time is precious.
How about 4,000? Free some up.
I might be able
to put some work aside, yeah.
Honey, no.
There are asaltantes
on the roads.
Bandits. Uh...
there is that danger.
15 up north,
east in the mountains.
OK, how about I throw in
another grand--hazard pay?
Honey, how much is
your life worth?
5,000, plus expenses?
2,500 in advance?
Yeah, deal...
if we leave tonight.
Well...deal.
We live just a few blocks away.
She looks like
she's clocked more miles...
than a midtown hooker.
Think she'll make it?
Sure, she will.
But just in case...
I have some new plugs
and a spare fan belt in back.
What about a spare transmission?
Uhh. Appearances
can be deceiving.
Yeah, I heard that once.
How long before we leave?
As soon as I throw
some things together.
See? She still puts out.
Danny, mivida.
Huh?
Could I talk to you
for a minute?
Sure, honey.
"Mivida" isn't a good sign.
Coming, honey!
You are not driving
that man to the border.
For $5,000, I'll carry him.
You don't know
anything about him!
You don't even like him.
Let’s just say
he bought my affection.
If you go with him...
I won't be here
when you get back.
If I don't go with him,
we'll be thrown out of here...
and you'll leave me anyway.
Luz, I got to do something.
So write.
You're a writer,
not a chauffeur.
OK. I'll write a book tonight.
I’ll get it published tomorrow.
We should have a royalty check
by next week.
Life is not like one of
your telenovelas, Luz.
Be practical.
You think it's practical...
to drive a complete stranger
to the border...
in the middle of the night?
This is an opportunity
for us, Luz.
It's a blessing, honey.
No. It's some terrible test.
- Oh...
- On a day of bad omens.
I don't have time for
ignorant village hocus-pocus.
OK? Besides,
it'll be an adventure...
give me something
to write about.
Oh, spare me the bullshit, OK?
You've got a typewriter!
That's all you need to write!
Oh, ha ha.
Whew! How much of that
did you hear?
I missed the part about
how you don't even like me.
Ha ha!
She’s just a little upset.
Apparently, you'll be missed.
But not for long.
- You are not going with us.
- Watch me.
Luz, get back in the house.
My father talked
to my mother that way...
but he was
an ignorant villager.
-It's OK with me if she comes.
-It's not OK with me.
Ah, come on. She handles food
and translation.
You drive, I ride shotgun,
eyes peeled for bandidos.
Exactly. It's too dangerous.
No. It will be an event
to remember.
- Luz, I'm serious.
- No!
It's getting late, guys.
The siren's still going.
Yeah. We don't usually have
two people slaughtered...
on the main drag
in broad daylight.
Two white people.
Oh, yeah. That, too.
Think it'll be hard
getting out of town?
Well, there may be a roadblock,
checking people's papers.
Can we avoid that?
Way ahead of you.
Aiming for a back street.
Oh.
Your up-front money, plus, uh...
100 for supplies.
Hide that, honeybunch.
Now, there's nothing
in that bag...
that I don’t want in my car,
is there?
Well... there is this.
Is it OK to take these
out of the country?
Yeah.
McGrane.
When?
Do you have a positive I.D.
on the navy brass?
Reese?
Ohh, man.
That sick bastard.
He really did it.
Ohh.
I’ll be there.
Leave everything. I'll watch it.
I said, I'll watch it.
Yeah, I heard you. Thanks.
Honey, it’s just a few days.
Let's get through it, OK?
- ¿Qué pasa, Victor?
- ¿Wué pasa, Danny?
They've been going all night.
What is it?
An assassination.
That's what I heard.
Really?
Isn’t that right,
Sargento Reyes?
That's what I was told.
Two Americans.
One navy officer...
and a turista
that got in the way.
Two Americans, eh?
You better watch out.
Right.
Any suspects?
We are looking
for anyone suspicious--
like you, maybe.
Are you suspicious?
No.
Listen, Victor,
if I arrest them...
I'll get a promotion.
And you'll get a reward.
Buenas noches.
Cabrón.
You going somewhere?
No, just hungry.
Where did you say we’re headed?
Which border town, I mean?
I haven't decided yet.
Got a map?
Side of the door.
So, um...
what kind of business
do you have in Dallas?
Ah, a little freelance work.
I wasn't, uh,
asking for your resume.
You know...
just making conversation.
Everybody hold on!
Sorry about that.
You OK, honey?
I forgot where I was
for a minute.
Now I remember.
The roads can get
a little bumpy.
Ah, I'm used to it.
You travel a lot
in your line of work?
Yeah, enough.
What brought you
to Puerto Vallarta?
- Running from the cops?
- No.
- I.R.S.?
Ex-wife.
Ha ha ha!
No, nothing that specific.
I’m a writer, so I'm running
from life in general.
Ha ha ha ha!
Danny has written five books.
The last one--
Chicago Crime Syndicate--
won the National
Book Club Award.
Thank you, honey.
She's my press agent. Yeah.
That's impressive.
On paper, maybe. But it's...
it doesn't always pay the rent.
Chicago Crime Syndicate.
Mm-hmm. Ha ha!
You meet any mobsters?
Yeah. Several.
Wow. Sounds dangerous.
Well, it can be.
You know, in about an hour,
I'm gonna need to know...
which border town
you want me to head for.
I haven't decided yet.
I’m thinking...Sonoita.
Sonoita? Where's that?
Let's see, uh...
Route 15 to Santa Ana...
then west, Route 2.
It goes right there.
South of Arizona.
That's gonna leave you
a long ways from Dallas.
Well, you got your money, right?
- Yeah, but, uh--
- Thanks.
I appreciate your concern.
Just when everything
was going so nicely, right?
Sir.
Yep.
You might want to keep
your eyes open on this one.
I beg your pardon, sir?
Did you read the dossier
on the target?
Clayton Price, 5'11"...
gray-brown hair, brown eyes.
Slender build.
OK. He just killed you...
shot you dead
because you're so stupid.
What have we taught you?
You're hunting a man...
one more intelligent than you...
with all your training
and more experience.
He's not the third duck
in the second row...
at the shooting gallery.
In fact, he thinks you are.
Sir, I was just--
Tell me what he's really like...
what his guts smell like.
That's the only way
you're gonna nail him.
I know he was in the Special Ops
in Vietnam, sir.
Did 2 tours. 82 confirmed hits,
over 200 probables.
He was the Babe Ruth of wetwork.
What else?
He started working
for Covert Operations.
They used him successfully
until five years ago...
when he began
to question instructions.
Right. He objected to a hit
in Asia on political grounds.
What else?
He ended up turning rogue...
killing navy brass
in Puerto Vallarta...
and briefing wouldn't
tell me why...
or who he was working for, sir.
Right. That's irrelevant to you.
Yes, sir.
He's a man
with dangerous talents...
and an unstable mind,
and he's roaming free.
Let intelligence
handle the subtleties.
Your job is to kill him.
Yes, sir.
Here.
Do some more homework.
What you learn
might save your life.
That's all
I'm trying to do, son.
Jeez! Look out!
- Danny!
- Oh, my God!
Hold on to something, Luz!
Oh, man! I can't control it!
Danny! Do something!
Danny!
No!
Let go of the wheel!
I'm steering this thing!
I thought gravity was!
Man, now, that's a detour.
You crazy bastard.
You could've killed us.
No, plowing into a wall of cows
would've killed us.
Wall of cows?
Yeah, exactly.
I swerved just in time.
- Yeah, off a cliff.
- I told you, the roads are bad!
Bad? Not as bad as your driving!
Both of you, shut up!
And try to figure out
where in carajo we are!
Guess we're on the road
to San Blas.
Looks like it.
I’m Colonel Benjamin Rivera...
military intelligence,
Mexico city.
Walter McGrane.
This is Neil Weatherford.
Welcome to Puerto Vallarta.
This will be your vehicle.
You're my assigned liaison?
Yes, sir.
My men and I were briefed...
when we arrived last night...
but, of course,
I would appreciate...
any further information
you could provide us.
All information will be
distributed by headquarters...
on an as-needed basis.
We need to know more
about this man.
No, we need to know.
You just need to help us.
Now, if you don't mind,
I want to see where it happened.
How long you want to stay?
I don't know. A couple hours.
Long enough to clean up,
get some shuteye, food.
- OK with you?
- Sure.
What about you, Luz?
Enough time to rest?
Yes, thank you.
You might want to have
your tourist card ready...
just in case.
I don't have one.
Didn’t your boat
go through immigration?
Yeah, but I was below deck...
and I didn’t figure I'd need one
for just two or three days.
Well, how the hell do you expect
to get across the border?
Especially in some little
fleabag town like Sonata...
or whatever you call it.
I don't know. If the border
official is even awake...
I'll just bribe him.
You can't buy everyone
in Mexico, you know.
It's working so far.
Ha ha! Well,
what if the cop stops you?
Jesus. One night together...
and you're already
my goddamn wife.
Let me worry about it, will you?
All right, you wait here.
Luz and I will check in...
and I'll tell them that my idiot
brother is waiting in the car.
You must be
a very patient woman, Luz.
That's the only kind God makes.
Luz?
Honey?
Shouldn’t you be sleeping?
I slept in the car...
between arguments.
Want to swim?
No. I didn't bring
my traje de baño.
Me, either.
What are you avoiding
looking at?
My underwear...
or my scars?
Nothing.
Car accident?
War accident.
But it's OK.
They're not painful...
just ugly.
They are not so ugly.
Thanks.
Danny still sleeping?
Up here.
Well, how about
hitting the road?
How about some food first?
How about some pants...
for both of you?
73.
73 feet.
Expert work.
Small caliber handgun...
target approximately
25 yards away...
all without being able
to take a sight.
The best and the brightest.
What the hell
was Price thinking?
We have an I.D.
The owner of a bodega
on the edge of town...
the night of the killings.
Yeah, and?
The suspect was with another
American, a local resident.
Send out a description
of the American...
along with the photo we supply--
every cop, all military,
every border station.
Yes, sir.
I’ve already done that.
That's great.
Then you can read my mind.
The next time,
you don't give an order...
until you hear it from my lips.
Do you understand?
And I don’t want any engagement.
ls that clear? None.
If they see him, they call you.
You tell me. Got it?
You have instructed us
not to engage.
We will not engage.
Emphasize it.
This is our operation.
I want it handled our way.
I don’t want some local boy
getting macho...
and deciding to play the hero.
Believe me, it'll be
the last decision he makes--
and the bloodiest.
¡Vámonos!
Luz, honey...
I want you to be careful
around this guy.
We don't know anything
about him.
You're the one who decided
to drive him across the country.
I know, but I'm just saying
don't get too friendly.
Did you see those scars?
People don't have scars
like that.
He was in the war.
What'd they do, blow him up
and sew him back together again?
- Danny.
- Don't get all gooey about it...
and don't believe
everything you hear.
He's not a lost puppy.
Keep your distance.
- Ready to roll?
- Yeah, good to go.
OK, let's do it.
- OK?
- OK.
This is what they don't
tell you about...
in the travel brochures.
Yeah, that's the trick.
Hide the poor folk
in the jungle.
Get your hands
on the tourist dollar.
Yep, exactly...
but I sure don't blame
these poor bastards.
I was one of these
poor bastards.
This is like the village
I grew up in.
See that little girl?
She's me, twenty years ago.
Why'd you leave, Luz?
When I was fifteen,
I could've stayed...
and become a farmer's wife
like my mother...
and become an old woman
at thirty...
or go to work in one of
the turista cities.
I chose the city.
Is your family still there?
They're all gone...
like dust.
My two brothers
died of cholera...
my father died of hard work...
and my mother died
of broken dreams.
I was the lucky one, I guess.
Luz worked as a maid at one of
the hotels in Puerto Vallarta...
then as a waitress at Chulo's.
That's where I met her.
- Sad beginnings, happy endings.
- That's right.
And what about you?
Where are your people from?
Brooklyn, New York.
But they left me.
My dad ran away when he was 35.
My mom fell in love
with the bottle...
and sent me packing
to my grandparents in Oregon...
where I grew up.
I’m sorry.
Eh, fuck 'em
if they can’t take a kid.
If we stay on 15...
it's pretty much straight up
all the way.
Danny...
do you think we could go
to Rosario?
It's not too far from here.
Why do you want to go there for?
I want to pay respects
to my parents...
visit their graves.
I’m sorry, honey.
That takes us out of our way
to see dead people.
Maybe we could pay our respects
on the trip back.
We won't stop, I know.
No, if we take this little road
out of Escanaba...
head west towards the sea,
we go right by Rosario.
Well, that’s just
an inch on the map...
but that’s about an hour by car.
I’ll give you another 500 bucks.
I--I don’t want
any more of your money.
I thought you were in a hurry.
I’m trying
to save you some time.
I’m willing to give it up.
I like seeing these back roads,
little villages.
I hope so,
because you might be spending...
a week or two in one of them
if my car breaks down.
I’ll take that chance.
Thank you.
Hey, Poncho,
dos mas tequilas...
ydos mas cervezas, ahora.
Just ignore them.
Ignore them.
Hey, lookit.
Borrachopendejo.
Hey, what are you looking at?
I was just looking
for your balls, man.
Thought maybe
you left them up in there.
Sit down and shut up, Danny.
- No.
- Stop.
Maybe you should listen
to your pussy friend, Danny.
- Yeah, Danny boy.
- Ha ha ha ha!
Come on, stop.
Danny... sit down.
Idiot.
Hey, you got a match?
- Yeah, I do.
- Holy shit. Pussy's got a match.
- What are you doing?
- Just being helpful.
Hey, man, how do you suppose
the pussy and old Danny boy...
ended up with a piece of
first class puta like her, huh?
¡Borracho estúpido!
I guess money talks.
Danny, take Luz to the car.
Hey, toss that over here.
Oh, I can do better than that.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Let me take a look at that.
Hang on, hang on.
You need a light?
No, I don't need a light.
- Sure you do.
- My drink!
You should keep more oil
in your crank case...
and less on your shirt.
It's a real fire hazard.
Hey!
Put it out! Put it out!
I guess America wiped its ass
today, and you two fell out.
Oh, you fucked up now.
Get her in the car.
Start the engine.
No, we have to help him.
Come on.
He doesn't need our help.
That's right.
Come on.
Now, what the hell
was that all about?
Decline of the gene pool.
You didn't have
to set the guy on fire.
No. I could've let him
cut your balls off...
rape your girlfriend.
It never would’ve gone to that.
You spend too much time
with your typewriter, Danny.
In the real world, some people
aren't just fake dangerous.
They're real dangerous.
Oh, yeah, right.
This from the guy...
who has no tourist card,
remember?
Hey, you know what?
Around here, the judiciales...
the federal police,
are a lot more dangerous...
than a couple of biker trash.
Thank you, Luz.
Stop.
- What?
- Stop.
What is it?
It's an ocelot.
What's it doing in the cage?
Oh, it's to sell to a zoo...
or some rich tourist needs
to keep her neck warm.
I don't know.
Ask him how much
he wants for it.
We can't put that thing
in my car.
Yeah, I know.
What are you asking
the price for?
To let it go.
He says $3,000.
He says they are very rare.
3,000.
I don't have that much left.
Look at it.
He should kill the damn thing
or let it go.
Ask him how he'd like to live
trapped in a little cage.
He says he does.
He used his real name.
He's either a hostage...
or the dumbest accomplice
in the world.
He says they paid in cash
for two rooms.
If they used
two separate rooms...
then it's probably not
a hostage situation, right, sir?
Right.
Now stop talking before you ruin
West Point's reputation.
Show me.
He said the man and the woman
stayed in this room...
and the suspect in the other.
What are we hoping to find,
sir, may I ask?
Nothing.
He's too smart
to leave anything behind.
I just wanted to stand
in his space for a moment...
breathe the air he breathed.
Maybe sniff out a clue
in the ether.
You believe in metaphysics,
Weatherford?
No, sir.
Not really.
Me, neither.
He says the suspect went for--
Stop with the Dick Tracy.
His name is Price.
Price...
took a swim in the pool.
Hmm.
Sure. Why not?
There's a dragnet
over half of Mexico...
and he's having
a fucking pool party.
We have the make and the model
of the car, señor.
It’s just a matter of time.
But how much, Rivera?
It's not just that I'm getting
older in this steam bath...
or that Price might
whack a few dozen people
before we find him--
it's also embarrassing.
I mean, where are
all the bright lights...
of the Mexican police
and military...
while he's taking his road trip?
Aren’t you just
a little embarrassed?
We haven’t found him yet,
señor, it's true...
but you created him.
Who should be more embarrassed?
She said she wants to be alone.
Yeah. I’ve said that, too.
I should've come back
to see her more...
before she died.
I lost so many minutes with her.
I know.
You wish you could go back.
Listen a little harder...
look a little more closely
at their eyes...
and speak a few more kind words.
Many more.
If--if you could have...
what would you have said to her?
I would've...
thanked her...
for fighting...
to give me more than she had.
She argued with my father...
to get me to school...
and he beat her for her pride.
She let him beat her...
but she won.
Gracias, mama.
And look at you--
so smart, so beautiful.
She would've been proud.
No.
I wasn’t worth being beaten for.
I’m not a good girl.
- You OK, honey?
- Yes.
I've just been looking
at the map.
You ready to head back
to 15 now or what?
Ah, we're so near the coast.
Let's stay on this road
for a while.
Your dime.
He got all ape shit.
He torched my bro, you know?
Poor guys.
On their way to Club Med,
minding their own business...
and this had to happen to them.
Price must be losing it
if he let these two live.
Look how perfect.
It's timeless.
Eternal.
Aah! God!
Hey, I hate to
interrupt your Zen moment...
but the car's not happy
with this heat.
I don't know
if we’re going to make it.
Sure, she will. She just needs
some encouragement.
You know, you can rub her ass
with Icy Hot...
but I don’t think
it's going to help.
You may have to find yourself
another ride.
Did you hear what I said?
Yeah. Why don’t you use
some of those spare parts...
you were bragging about?
Hey, I got spare parts,
but I'm not the Pep Boys.
Judiciales.
- What'd he say?
- He wants your tourist cards.
Tell him that our papers
are in the car...
and Mr. Fisher had his stolen.
-I speak English.
- OK, great.
Uh...you guys
have badges, right?
Badges? Badges?
- You want to see our badges?
- Please.
See? I showed you mine,
but you can't show me yours.
Well, we all had tourist cards--
Shut up. You talk too much.
- OK.
- Get in the car.
Come on, all of you.
Hey!
Come on, get in the car.
Danny, I don’t want
to go with them.
Hey! Cállate.
Let's not argue with them.
¡Cállate! Sube alcoche.
¡Suelta me!
Luz, move!
Don't get hysterical on me now.
Jesus. They're all dead!
Them or us.
People die every day.
Yeah, when you're around.
He saved us, Danny!
If we’d never met him, we
wouldn't have had to be saved!
Hey, how about
some help over here?
No, I’ve had enough! I'm not
moving your corpses for you!
You gonna stay here
with your thumb up your ass...
waiting to get arrested
for murder?
You killed them, we didn't!
Tell that to a Mexican judge!
Luz, don't!
He is right! We have no choice!
Sorry it went down like this.
Yeah, sorry I killed three guys.
I’m sorry I made you
accomplices to murder.
I’m sorry I ruined your lives!
Danny!
This is where we are--
right here, right now.
Now accept it and make a choice.
What, Mexican justice
or going with you?
No. I'm not leaving you here
to talk to anybody.
Going with me or my justice.
Now come on over here
and grab this guy's feet.
Come on.
Luz, open the trunk.
Luz...
Danny, grab his feet.
Other one in the back.
We'll find a deserted spot
up the road to ditch them.
Here, you drive this car.
I'll take the Jeep.
I’ll take the Jeep.
Yeah, right. Come on, Luz.
Hey, are we your hostages?
No.
You're my sidekicks.
Thanks for helping me
back there.
You were very brave.
Ohh! God!
Shit!
No.
What is he doing?
Oh, my God!
Oh, God!
Oh, no! No!
Hang on.
Please, please, please,
don't hurt him! Please!
Where the hell
do you think you’re going?
I don't know.
You want to get stopped
for speeding...
with three corpses in the car?
No. I'm sorry. Honey--
Shh. Not a problem.
I wasn't running away.
I just--
I--I was trying
to get away from...
You're going to kill us,
aren’t you?
Not if I don't have to.
Put this thing in gear.
Turn off at the next side road.
Luz.
You drive, OK?
OK.
And no cute stuff.
I’m not one of those dumb ass
gangsters you wrote about.
Look...
just get me to the border...
and you'll get your life back.
OK.
We'll take
the Durango turnoff...
and head east
into the mountains.
You killed those men
in Puerto Vallarta, didn’t you?
- You know I did.
- What do you mean?
You saw me.
You were looking right at me.
- No, I wasn't.
- You were looking right at me.
Danny, is that true?
No. I mean, I wasn't sure.
I saw his hand
under his vest and--
You weren't sure?
You agreed to drive him,
and you weren't sure?
You thought maybe he killed
two people, maybe he didn't?
I thought at first,
if it was him...
I could handle it,
but I didn't know, OK?
Well, what about me?
You let me come with you.
Did you think
I could handle it, too?
You insisted on coming,
remember? You just had to come.
I didn't know everything, Danny.
- Well, neither did I!
- You knew more than I did...
and you didn’t tell me.
It's your fault we're here.
Me? What about him?
Boy, those sins of omission
will get you every time.
And you--I was standing
right next to that man.
You could've killed me!
No, I couldn't. I don't miss.
So proud to be
a killer of men...
to steal a human life.
There is a dark spot
on your soul...
for every man you have killed.
Then it must be
pitch black by now.
Yes, it must.
God weeps for you.
What can we expect at the road?
Nothing for a while.
Then Concordia--
that's an inspection station...
and they got guns.
We better get cleaned up.
Luz...not too far.
I won't try to swim
across the border.
May I have a little privacy?
No.
I want you both
where I can see you.
Luz, what are you doing?
What? He wants to see me.
Make sure I'm not carrying
a bomb or a knife or a gun.
When you're a killer,
you think everyone is a killer.
When you're done, let's go.
Shit. A Galil.
What's that mean?
It means
don't do anything stupid.
The kid probably doesn't know
how to use that thing.
He could hose us all down
in a second if he freaks out.
Thanks for helping me
appear nonchalant.
And don’t try acting out
that little drama...
you're playing around
in your head...
'cause I'll be rewriting
the ending, you understand?
Understand?
Yes.
Luz?
I’m just a dumb Mexican chick
in the back seat.
Heh.
All right.
Smile, people.
We’re just one big happy family.
¿Habla español?
Muypoco.
Luz?
The engine.
The rocks on the beach
were slippery, weren’t they?
Oh, Si, Si. Pronto.
Yes.
You should be more careful.
Mexico can be very dangerous...
if you are not...careful.
¿Está bien?
Muy bien.
Gracias.
That--that was pretty easy.
Yeah, maybe too easy.
- How do you mean?
- Nothing.
What's the most direct route
north from here?
- I think we're on it.
- Well, pull off.
Let's try to avoid
the main roads.
Is this heap gonna make it?
If we don't drive it into
the ground, I think so, yeah.
Let's find a little town where
we can rehabilitate ourselves...
and hopefully, the car.
I’m bettin' on the car.
Hey, Luz,
you did good back there.
I did it for us, not for you.
Yeah, well...
thanks anyway.
What is this?
Ricardo Montalban's birthday?
These small towns
are always looking...
for an excuse for a fiesta.
Probably remembering
some local...
who saw the Virgin
in a cornfield or something.
Excuse me. Mexican in the car.
I’m sorry, Luz.
Never mind. It's true.
Better for us.
Easier to get lost.
That looks like a hotel
over there.
You want to check it out?
Yeah.
You two go check in.
Oh...and no secret messages
to the clerk.
No paper airplanes for help
out the window.
Nothing you ever read
or wrote about.
That shit only works
on paper. Clear?
Good.
Because,
whether you know it or not...
you're both better off
with me now...
than you would be
with the authorities.
Really?
Now, what happens to us...
after we ditch you at
the border, assuming we make it?
Hostages, temporary insanity.
I'll think of something.
Let's take care of this life...
before we worry about the next.
Go on.
Room 17.
Meet me in that restaurant
across the plaza.
Ten minutes.
We're in room 18.
Go ahead, honey.
Should we go to the police?
In this town?
Some old man
and his brother-in-law?
They probably
don't even have guns.
By the time the real police
or the judiciales get here...
we could be dead.
We could get in the car,
try to make a run for it.
Not in that car.
But he's right.
Where would we go?
The judiciales
are more scary than he is.
If he hadn't killed
those three today...
we'd both be in jail now.
And I would've been fucked...
by three men, at least.
What should we do?
Now you want my advice?
You think I would've
agreed to drive him...
if I had known
this was gonna happen?
Or let you come with us?
I don't know,
but you should've known, Danny.
I’m sorry, honey.
Don't. I'm too angry
to take care of you.
I’m too tired
to make love to you.
Where the fuck are we anyway?
Somewhere in between--
Never mind.
Surprise me later.
You ever watch any of those
V.D. training films?
Sir, I think
they stopped showing those...
after the Korean War.
Damn shame, too, given all
the disease roaming around here.
You got someone back home?
No, sir.
You?
Nah.
I live with
this middle-aged woman...
who claims to be my wife,
but...
I stopped arguing with her
about it a long time ago.
I just stay out of her way.
I’m married to Uncle Sam.
I’m his bitch, just like you.
No, I don't...
I don't see--
I don't quite see it
that way, sir.
Oh. Ha ha. You will.
Relationships have a way of...
creeping up on you,
then all of a sudden, bam!
You're screwed.
But you’re young.
What are you, 11? 12?
25, sir.
- Get out.
- No.
Old fart.
You guys are all the same.
Iowa?
Rifle team?
Class president?
4-H Club?
No. You're close, sir.
Oh!
Ohio.
And, uh...
I couldn’t join
the 4-H Club, sir...
because my cow died.
Good, Weatherford.
You must've spent
your junior year...
abroad from the academy
growing a sense of humor.
Thank you, sir.
Keep it. You'll need it.
It might save you...
from a razor blade
to the wrists one day.
Gracias.
Let me have the car keys.
If you feel like leaving,
don't let us stop you.
Oh, I wouldn't leave you
stranded here.
That's why you followed us
to the church...
in Puerto Vallarta--
the car.
I did hear the bartender
mention it during the argument.
What if Danny
hadn't agreed to drive you?
I couldn't risk
having him finger me.
He'd already proved
he had a big mouth in the bar.
So, what,
you would've killed me?
Keep your voice down.
You're completely amoral.
Don't throw your boy scout
code of honor in my face.
I’ve been fighting battles
for you for thirty years.
- For me?
- Yeah, that's right.
While you were jerking off
in college...
I was shooting people
and getting shot at...
in Vietnam and Loas
and Cambodia and Panama.
Well, thanks for killing
all those strangers for me.
Don't mention it, you pampered,
ungrateful bag of shit.
How many people have you killed?
300 and change.
300 men?
And women and kids...
and they were all soldiers.
So, you were the good guys?
That's what we thought.
What'd they think they were?
Were they the bad guys
because they weren't paying you?
Well, I guess morality
is pretty subjective.
Look at you.
You sold yourself...
your car, and your girlfriend
for five grand.
And you're the most
self-righteous bastard I know.
-I don't kill people for money!
- Danny.
Don’t tell me!
The fiesta's outside, fellas.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I liked that song, too.
Maybe you could like it
a little more quietly.
Yes, ma'am.
Sit down.
Sit down, Danny.
We'll finish eating
and then take a walk.
We all could use one.
I don't want to take a walk.
I wasn't giving you a choice.
Would you have shot me, too?
No.
Maybe it was the way you looked
when you tripped...
coming down those stairs
out of the church.
You were waiting for us
outside the church?
I walked over to you, remember?
But I mean before that.
You were lying in wait for us?
Forget it. I don't want you
freaking out again.
- Were you or weren't you?
-I didn't do it, did I?
I can't believe this.
You make me sick!
- Hey, keep walking.
- No!
Keep walking.
Don't let it spook you.
We all brush against death...
so many times in our lives
without knowing it.
This was just one
you found out about.
It must feel wonderful thinking
you have all this power.
It’s just business to me.
Yeah. If you'd taken
better care of business...
none of this would've happened.
I mean, come on!
Two guys in broad daylight?
On a crowded street?
A little sloppy,
don’t you think?
I'd been trailing
the civilian for days.
First time he was exposed.
Who was he?
I don't know.
Some guy who’d been selling
something to the Chinese.
Computer technology.
They don’t tell me that stuff.
The U.S. government, that is.
So, then why are you running?
I wasn't contracted
for the other hit--
the navy officer.
You mean that was a mistake?
I was standing
right next to him.
Not a technical mistake.
A personal one.
What do you mean?
I knew the guy.
I wanted to kill him.
Danny?
I’m right here, honey.
Where were you?
Restless.
I got some fresh air.
What are you doing up?
I hear him cry out.
Guilt and remorse.
Should we go to him?
What? No.
Let him live with his ghosts.
He created them.
No use. She's done this before.
- The fuel pump's shot.
- Can you fix it?
Yeah, with a new fuel pump.
Any chance of finding one here?
No way, not in this burg.
I have to take
the old one out...
find a replacement in a bigger
town, like Mazatlán, maybe.
How do you get there?
There are buses going between
these small towns all the time.
I could probably get there
and back in one day.
How far are we from the border?
24 hours
driving straight through.
But even if we could
get this thing started...
she'd never make it.
Ln fact...
we're lucky we found out here.
Oh, yeah. Lucky.
So, do Luz and I go?
You go. Luz stays.
I’ll need her to translate.
Just hold up the old fuel pump.
A picture's worth
a thousand words.
-I’m not leaving her.
- You don't have a choice.
Come on, Luz.
Danny has a fuel pump to remove.
Jeez, man, can’t you wait
till we get to the beach?
Yeah, you left a trail of piss
all the way from Baja.
You must have a bladder
the size of a little girl's.
Yeah, fuck off, both of you.
An iguana's gonna bite
your dick off in there!
It couldn't handle it!
It couldn't find it!
Hey, you guys! Come here!
All right, what now?
Come take a look at this!
What's up, little buddy?
You can't do this yourself?
Aw, fuck.
Don't go down there!
Come on! Come on, you guys!
Come on!
Oh, shit!
Come on, you guys!
OK. There's a bus
out of here in 15 minutes...
and another one in three hours.
Here's your ticket.
Get on that next bus
and meet me in Mazatlán.
What? What about the fuel pump?
There's nothing wrong
with the fuel pump.
I rigged the engine last night
so it wouldn’t start.
Danny, we can't
leave him here alone.
- Really? Why not?
- They'll kill him.
Well, perfect.
Better him than us.
- He's been good to us.
- To you, yeah.
I know he's killed people,
but he seems decent.
There's an American word
for that-- psychopath.
What's wrong with you?
Nothing! It's just not right!
-I can't--
- Yes, you can.
You have to! And you will.
Now, find an excuse to be alone
at 3:00 and get on that bus.
Now, here.
- OK?
- OK.
He's right in front
of the hotel.
- Take that look off your face.
- OK.
Come and see me off
as if nothing's wrong.
OK.
I’m betting on this guy
to win the talent competition.
Maybe he thinks
we're Hollywood scouts, sir.
What's happening, colonel?
Excuse me, colonel.
Colonel?
- Excuse me.
- Not now.
Excuse me!
Well...so much for
the good neighbor policy.
Tell me.
Three men dead--
judiciales.
I’m still in charge. Clear?
My men are dying.
This is our operation now.
No. That doesn't change a thing.
I disagree, señor.
Get in your car.
Here it comes.
Bye, honey.
Adiós, mivida.
Don’t worry. I'll see you soon.
She'll be all right.
Hard saying good-bye.
It shouldn't be.
I’ve been saying good-bye
to Danny since I’ve met him.
What do you mean?
I’m the girl you leave.
The girl you don't marry,
you never take home...
or even across the border.
I’m only fit for someone
living in exile or desperation.
I’m the desperation girl.
I always get left.
The question is when.
You deserve a lot more.
No.
You don't know me well enough.
Yeah, I do.
You want lunch or something?
Something.
Did you ever pray?
Yeah, during the war.
When I was being tortured,
I prayed I'd die.
When I didn't, I gave up on God.
It's a sin to pray for death.
I don’t think God is
even counting my sins anymore.
He is.
But he forgives you.
We are all sinners.
I’m tired.
Do you mind if I rest?
No, not at all.
Luz!
I couldn't leave you alone.
I know.
There's nothing wrong
with the fuel pump.
Danny wanted me
to meet him in Mazatlán.
Yeah, I know. The 3:00 bus.
I saw him buy the ticket.
Then why didn’t you--
I wanted you to stay...
but only if you wanted to.
The first time I was with Danny,
it was for money.
I did work at Chulo's...
but I didn't make enough money
to live on...
or to send home.
So...
sometimes I went with men.
Those bikers
at the restaurant knew.
I am a puta.
They didn't know anything...
except that you're beautiful.
Scum like that
think all women are whores.
But I was.
Danny never throws it
in my face...
never mentions it.
Still, it's always there...
I think...
in the back of his mind.
And now yours.
You had a hard time.
You had to stay alive.
I understand that.
What will he think
when I don't show up?
He'll accept it.
If not now, then later.
Am I a bad girl?
No, no, no.
God forgives you.
We're all sinners.
Bad dream?
Yeah, they're all bad.
I heard you last night.
Same dream, over and over,
since the war.
Lo siento tanto.
Some memories are too
terrible to live with.
I thought they’d stop
after I killed him.
Killed who?
That guy in Puerto Vallarta.
The navy officer.
He left me to die in Cambodia,
in the jungle.
My spotter and I
were trapped there.
He was supposed to lift us out
if things got hot...
and he left us.
He just flew away.
Dios mio.
My friend, my spotter...
was killed right away.
And then I was shot, kicked...
stabbed with bayonets...
and that guy in the chopper--
Reese--
watched it all...
and didn't do a goddamn thing.
What happened?
I was dragged away...
and tortured.
The only thing
that kept me alive...
was hating that fucker Reese.
I wanted to live
just to get him.
Dios castiga.
I’m sure God punished him
long before you killed him.
Not enough.
I got away, escaped.
Floated down...
some river to Thailand.
And after they patched me up
and I got out of the hospital...
I went to work for the CIA...
and I never, ever
forgot about Reese.
But I never saw him again...
till that day
in Puerto Vallarta.
The day I met you.
Do you believe in fate?
More than that.
I believe in miracles.
We're gonna need one
to get out of here alive.
You know that, don’t you?
Yes.
If we do...
will you come north with me?
I have a little place
in the hills...
in Oregon.
Deep in the woods--
very quiet, very beautiful.
It's a good place
to be alone with someone.
I would like to.
We will replace
your bad dream...
with a good one.
Where are you going?
I have a plan.
I don't know if it'll work,
but it's worth a try.
Why can't we just take
a bus to the border?
No, they'll be
looking for me there.
Here. Put this on.
To replace the one I messed up
in Puerto Vallarta.
I saw you looking at it
in a shop window.
Thank you.
Back soon.
Look at what
I’ve been reduced to.
Following these idiots around
like a perpetual motion machine.
Pretty hopeless, isn't it, sir?
Yeah.
You know,
it's my birthday today.
Really, sir?
No, not really.
In a few months.
But it would bolster
my self-pity...
and sense of futility
if it were today.
Yes, sir.
McGrane.
It's Price.
Where the hell are you?
You first.
I’m following some Mexican
intelligence wunderkind...
around the highways and byways
of this dysentery factory...
trying to find your sorry ass.
Now, why would you want
to do that?
So they don't slaughter you.
Better make sure they do.
What would be the point of that?
To eliminate a nasty...
and potentially
embarrassing problem.
Best way to do that
is to get you home.
What about Reese?
What about him?
What's the price for that?
Nothing. It was a mistake.
You know and they know
I don't make mistakes.
Officially, it was a mistake.
You're getting older.
He stepped in your sights.
- It was a terrible--
- And ironic.
Yeah, a terrible
and ironic mistake.
It's more convenient
for everyone...
if you classify it that way.
- Why did my ride pull out?
- He panicked.
- Not your orders?
- No.
Believe me, we just want
to get you out of here now.
Tell me where you are.
I’m in a little town
called Zapata.
It’s just north of Rosario.
Right. Got it.
Where should we meet?
There's an abandoned church
north of town.
It shouldn’t take me more than
a few hours to get there.
I’ll be waiting.
Goody.
Thinks he's going home, sir?
He is...
in a box.
Hang a "U" at the next curve.
Yes, sir.
I’m ready!
Ready for what?
Honey.
Surprised?
I guess you missed the bus.
I told you
I couldn't leave him alone.
No, you told me you'd follow me,
remember?
"Adiós, mivida." All that?
I waited three hours for you
at the bus station at Mazatlán.
I’m sorry.
No. Forget "I'm sorry."
This is bigger than "I'm sorry".
And I spent the whole night
wondering if he'd killed you...
or taken you hostage
or raped you.
Guess he didn't have
to work that hard, huh?
- Danny--
- What?
I love him.
What's the Spanish word
for "psychiatrist"?
You're with this guy,
this murderer...
this serial killer
for one night--
We've been with him
for almost a week now.
Oh, it's a week.
It's a long-term relationship.
I guess a girl could fall
for Charles Manson in a week.
And it was your idea, remember?
- My idea?
- Yeah.
That you’d fall for him?
That'd you leave me stranded?
That you’d fuck him
right under my nose?
Danny--
I guess once a whore,
always a whore.
I’m sorry.
I didn't mean that.
It's all right.
No, it's not all right.
Forget that I said that.
I just--I didn't know
what happened to you.
I didn't know why you didn't--
I thought you would go back...
forget, be safe.
Can you forget, Luz?
Just like that?
Can you?
Looks like we could use
a bigger room.
Yankee Stadium
wouldn't be big enough.
This is what you’ve been after
from the beginning, isn't it?
It just happened.
I think I found a way
out of here.
There's no way out of here.
There are cops and the army
in Concordia...
and on the road in here
to Zapata.
We got to take that chance.
She doesn't.
He's right.
They’re just looking for me.
You can tell them I forced you
and Danny to come along.
They'll believe you.
They already think
I'm out of control.
Think?
Luz...
Luz, stay.
Not for me.
Do it to save your life.
That's what I'm doing.
Here.
What are you doing?
This'll make it more believable.
Give us ten minutes.
Go down to the plaza.
Make a scene about what I did
to you and Luz.
That should be easy.
Your keys,
the rest of the money I owe you.
- You think I could take that?
- A deal's a deal.
Yeah, but I never got you there.
Buy your self a nice headstone.
- Am I going too fast?
- No. Where are we going?
To a place I found where
the jungle meets the town.
-Is that it?
- Yeah.
Someone is going
to meet us there?
I hope so, Luz. Come on.
Wait here.
OK.
This is a mausoleum.
Rich people have themselves
buried in the chapel...
to be closer to God.
We won't be here long.
Here we go.
He's holding her hostage
in the hotel!
Right up there.
What's that?
Our salvation, maybe.
Stay here.
Is that it, sir?
Must be.
And there he is--
all packaged and ready for us.
Are you going to try
and talk to him, sir?
I’ve done all my talking,
and so has he.
Now it's time
for you to do your work.
Yes, sir.
- You with McGrane?
- He's outside.
Let the girl go first.
Why?
Just let her go.
No. We go together.
You're going
to push her aside...
and this'll be over
in two seconds.
Step aside, Luz.
No, no. No, I thought
they came to help us.
Well, they lied to me.
It doesn't have
to go down like this.
Tell him we got away. We'll take
our chances in the jungle.
No, no. No, it's over now.
It's you, or it's both of you.
Now push her aside.
- Get out of the way, Luz!
- Move her aside!
Stop! Don't kill him!
No. Please, no.
They'll lie to you someday.
When you've done
all their dirty work for them.
They'll send a younger version
of you to kill you.
No. Please.
¡Colonel!
The girl was with him.
She was hit
in the line of fire.
- Did you set the blaze?
- Yes, sir.
The place is a huge crypt, sir.
It's filled with bodies.
Appropriate for Price.
I thought the fire
would make it impossible...
to sort out remains...
to complicate matters...
in case the locals
decided to investigate.
I think I underestimated you,
Weatherford.
Yes, sir.
I think you did.
What happened?
Well, Price is dead.
Gunfire ignited the flames.
Where's Luz?
She was caught in the crossfire.
- No!
- Yes.
No!
No! Let go of me!
It's too late. It's too late.
You shot her, didn’t you?
You bastards!
Look, you want to blame someone,
blame Price or yourself...
or her.
We're not stupid enough
to think...
either of you
was completely innocent.
Now, consider yourself
lucky to be alive.
Oh, my God! Oh, God!
Señor.
All right, now.
Calm down, calm down...
before the local boys
use you as the scapegoat.
You'd better get out of here.
That would end things nice
and neat for you, wouldn't it?
Son, things always end
nice and neat for me...
whichever way they go.
3,000 U.S., right?
Here's your money.
- All right, you got it all.
- OK.