- Come on, life sounds. Let's go.
- Okay.
Mike down, mike down.
There you go, now go.
You'd think l'd never done this.
Ready?
Hey, wait a second. Ready.
Five, four, three....
Hi, l'm Angela Vidal.
Come with us tonight
as we travel along with--
- Sorry.
- Okay.
- Ready?
- Yeah, wait a second.
You got a little hair thing. Hold on.
Let me get that.
That right there.
- Okay, there we go.
- Thank you.
Okay.
Hold on.
Okay. Ready.
Hi, l'm Angela Vidal.
Come with us tonight as we paint
the town red on The Night Shift.
Sorry, a little off my A-game.
I'll get there.
That wasn't bad. The second part
just seemed a Iittle pushed, though.
On tonight's Night Shift,
we're in Los Angeles...
...traveling along with that special
breed of hero we like to call...
...the fire department.
We shouId have come earlier.
We could be going with them.
Well, that's cool. You got it?
- Yeah, that's great. That was perfect.
- We'Il wait for them to get back.
- You prefer Bob or Robert--?
- Bob's good.
- Bob, okay, sorry. Ready? Okay.
- Yeah.
Three, two, one.
Tell us, Bob, what's a normaI night
here at the station?
This might surprise most people...
...but 85 percent of the calls
we go out on are medical.
It can be anything from chest pain
to more serious things.
How do you handIe that
with ambulances and hospitals?
Most ambulances you see
are fire department.
- I didn't know that.
- Yeah.
And most firefighters
are also paramedics.
At least,
that's the direction it's going.
One more question, something
I'm sure we're aIl wondering:
Do firefighters still sIide down
those fabulous poles?
We sure do.
No turning back.
Tell my mom l loved her.
- See?
- That's not so bad.
I'm gIad I didn't wear a skirt.
That couId really hurt your legs.
Tell me, Bob, how do you get down
when you're wearing a skirt?
Pantyhose help.
Pantyhose.
That's what they wear under their,
what, their turnouts.
- ExactIy.
- Pantyhose.
- Fire-retardant pantyhose.
- You heard it here.
- Can l do it one more time?
- Sure.
I'll be right back, okay?
- We're going to the dining hall.
- All right.
- Couple of guys l want you to meet.
- Cool.
Hey.
- This is Jake.
- Hey.
- And Fletcher.
- Hi.
- Nice to meet you.
These are the men you'll be
shadowing. Wherever they go, you go.
Cool. Please, oh, please, finish eating.
We'll talk after.
- Well, would you like some?
- Yeah.
- Did you make it?
- We got--
I didn't make it.
Firemen are really good cooks.
- Yeah, that's what l hear.
- ExactIy.
- You should try some of the food.
- Yeah, I'm game.
- Please finish eating.
- We'Il get you a plate.
Great. Sounds great.
Just maybe un-tuck your shirt
and stick it up here.
- Okay. Okay.
- Clip it on your collar.
- You filming this?
- Yeah.
Elliot's been telIing me
I never give him enough B-roll...
...so l'm just gonna shoot it alI.
- Jake? Jake?
- Yeah, yeah.
If you could keep
from rubbing into the mike too much--
- Sorry, yeah.
- Don't worry about the camera.
- Pretend it's not even there.
- Okay.
Can you say something?
Give me a Ievel?
Yeah. Mike check, one--
You can just pretend it's not there.
Just taIk free.
Can you say something
more compelling?
I don't know what to say--
I mean, am l gonna have
this thing on all the time?
Yeah, just watch what you say.
We'll hear everything.
Shit.
You're probably not allowed
to swear on your station.
No. We can cut most of it out.
But it helps
if you're not dropping F-bombs.
Point noted. Filed right here.
So if I was to call this guy
an ass-monkey...
...that wouId be considered
a swear too, right?
It's gonna be a long night.
- So this thing?
- Yeah?
Is this some sort of torture device
when you don't get in your turnouts?
- That's what it is.
- Can you get it?
Yes. This is caIled a hook ladder.
We use this in the--
The firemen would use this--
- We should bring it down?
- Yes.
- Okay.
- All right.
Can you grab the hook?
So this was used
in the '20s and the '30s.
- Oh, my God.
- Yeah.
And as you can see...
...these are the rungs,
and the hook at the end...
...they would grasp onto one window
and then pull themselves up.
And then when they got to that
windowsill, they would hook it again.
- And then puIl themseIves up.
- Okay.
Did you get the hook, Scott?
You see this?
Used in the '20s and '30s.
They stopped using it around--
- HoId it up higher.
- Replaced it--
- That's good, right?
- Good.
Replaced it
with a regular ladder that extends?
Yeah, and rope.
They must have tiny feet.
Those are little rungs.
Yeah. Firemen
were a Iot smaller back then.
The fires were bigger
and they were smaller.
- Don't tell captain we took this down.
- I'm not gonna teIl him l touched it.
I wanna introduce you to somebody.
This is Wilshire. Mark.
- Good boy.
- Hey, Wilshire.
- Say hi.
- Dog right out of the cartoons.
Well, there's a reason
why the DaImatians were in cartoons.
The fire department
has a great sense of tradition.
Yeah, we do.
Dalmatians
got along well with horses.
Important when the fire trucks
were horse-drawn.
Now they're used as mascots.
But what they're trained to do
is run in and stop the traffic.
- Kind of like Fletch.
- Yeah.
That's what l do, I run out there.
Sort of like what a siren does today.
Okay, welI, Wilshire can show you
what to do in case you catch on fire.
- Stop, drop and roll.
- Yeah.
So let's just pretend
you're 5 years old and on fire.
- I'm on fire.
- Wilshire's gonna teach you.
Tell me what to do.
Okay. Wilshire.
WiIshire, mark. Stay.
WiIshire, drop.
Drop. Drop.
WiIshire, roll.
- Good.
- Look at that.
Good boy. Good boy.
- I'm gonna live.
- Report.
You're not gonna be on fire.
So it's stop, drop and roll,
in case you catch on fire. Wilshire.
- Yeah, you know, have some fun.
- You all hang out a lot?
- Yeah.
- You kind of live together.
Yeah, we definitely live together.
Close quarters.
- Okay, good.
- Oh, ready?
So yeah, we have 48-hour shifts...
...so we have everything
we need in this place...
...from, you know,
a small gym to this handball court.
I'll show it to you.
- It's nice, right?
- Yeah.
Sir, you got a call on the office line.
Can you pick up a call
on the office line?
Non-responder.
- Oh, shoot.
- Yeah.
- I was hoping we'd get a call.
Not a big one, a little call
so we can see action.
- Exciting, l guess.
- Yeah.
Gotta be annoying
when trying to finish a game.
Not if you're losing.
Every time, you know,
we go respond to a call...
...the points reset.
Depending on which side you're on,
it's sort of nice.
Works in your favor
from time to time?
Not in my favor.
What are you talking about?
I never lose.
I think I'd roller-skate
if l had access to this.
I can see you doing that. Yeah.
Okay, so this is where the men
store their boots and turnouts.
The pole hole is over here.
- The pole hole.
- Yeah, interesting name, I know.
- You got the locker room here.
- Yep.
You got the dorms here.
Our viewers
always like to see action...
...so maybe we should go
into the locker room.
- Let's go in the locker room.
- You got it.
- Right this way.
- I was kidding, l was kidding.
Okay, toweI up, guys.
We got a female on deck.
- Female on the deck.
- Oh, my God.
That's Griffin.
He can't sing very well.
He's got one major talent,
so come this way.
- He's got a huge talent.
- We're not using this.
Here. We have different hoses at
the station, and this is the Griffin hose.
- Griffin hose.
- What the hell?
You know,
I hope that's a wide-angle lens.
Oh, my God.
Stay in there.
Hey, put that thing away.
This is adding a whoIe new meaning
to the term fireman's hose.
- Hey, hit the floor.
- Oh, my--
I understand
why there are no women here.
- Plenty of female firefighters.
- In this station?
No, not currently.
Okay, l think I can be a firefighter.
- Yeah, it's a lot harder than it seems.
- Keep the door closed.
You know what?
Pick something you're good at.
I bet you $10 l can do it better.
You all can be my witnesses.
- That's too easy. Ten bucks?
- Yeah.
How about my place?
I think we're done here.
We got everything we need.
Here we go. Listen up.
Did you know
you were gonna be on camera?
- Behind the line. Ready?
- Yeah.
- Ten bucks.
- You can't be in the way.
- I know.
- Get on that side.
I'm just saying. You guys ready?
- You know what you're doing?
- Yes.
And go.
- Get in there.
- That's not nice.
That's not fair. She pushed.
- She pushed.
- Haven't got that much time.
- Yes. You owe her 10 bucks, man.
- Ten dollars.
Pay up. Oh, that's embarrassing.
- Oh, this is embarrassing.
- That's really embarrassing.
Okay, rolling.
Just waiting
on something to happen.
You wanna go back outside?
See what they're up to?
Why not?
- Careful.
- Thank you.
We're good.
You good?
I think they're talking about you.
WiIl you turn up his mike?
You didn't catch no eye.
Here, give me some of that.
I'll tell you, all right?
A hundred bucks
says I can bang her by the morning.
- Oh, come on.
- I'lI take that bet.
You're so busted.
Nice mike.
Missed a spot.
- Sorry, what?
- I said you missed a spot.
Oh, l know how to hit the spot.
Don't you worry about that.
I'll hold your camera.
You go kick his ass, okay?
That's how you do pick and roll.
Oh, yeah? Ls that how you do it?
He'lI show you how to do it later.
It's nighttime here...
...and the firefighters take turns
sleeping in these rooms here.
But if the alarm rings, they can be up
and on the truck in under one minute.
Let's check out the room.
Can you get in here?
It's like my college dorm
without the pink.
Attention, 222 Truck 16.
- Watch your back.
- Hey.
Looks like you got your call.
- Just try to keep up.
- You okay?
- We're going to the pole hole.
- Come on, come on.
- Got it?
- What you wanna do?
I can't slide down there.
Come here, come here,
come this way.
Careful, okay?
We have to get on that truck.
- There are Iike 15 stairs.
- I got it.
- You be careful.
- Keep going, keep going.
- It's this way?
- Yeah. Yeah, keep going.
- Be careful.
- Make a quick right.
Make a quick right, baby.
Just jump in the back.
- Jump in.
- Buckle up.
- We're almost in.
- You guys in?
- Yep, yep, yep.
- Yep?
Nice job.
What kind of calI is this?
Probably just a medical.
- Okay.
- We'Il find out when we get there.
You seem to have kept shooting.
Ready?
Ready, set. Ready, set.
Okay, good.
Most little girls wanna be ballerinas
or princesses when they grow up.
I used to tell my mom, "Someday,
I'm gonna grow up and be a fireman."
Tonight, I am truly Iiving the dream.
It's so Ioud,
I don't think we can use any of it.
Scott, l am still living the dream.
Thirty-seventeen, go ahead.
All right, we got a eight at 3 o'clock.
Keep calling out numbers.
What are you doing?
Well, Jake's the engineer.
He's actualIy
a third-generation engineer...
...but l have the most important job.
Navigating?
No,
I'm in charge of the chick-o-meter.
When I see a girl, l rate them.
So if I say
there's a eight at 3 o'clock...
...the guys know
they better look to the right.
You know, it's really funny. L always
thought firemen were so dignified.
Oh, no, no.
I signed up for brave and courageous.
- I don't do dignified.
- Yeah, I think we get that by now.
I see a nine at 2.
- Oh, we got a nine at 2.
- Yeah.
Whoa, that's a dude.
It's called a chick-o-meter,
not a dick-o-meter.
I think we're good.
You're fired. You can't talk anymore.
So where do you think
the problem is?
Do you think it's over there,
around the corner?
Or maybe around there?
You're rotten, you know that?
To the core, baby. To the core.
What are you taking with you?
Tools.
Really anything we might need
to break a lock or open a door.
- You're the one who called this in?
- Yeah.
Come, follow me.
Look at Probie's new turnouts.
I didn't know
they made them that new.
We're almost to the building.
Police are here. Might be more
serious than we thought.
Probably not.
A woman was screaming
bloody murder up there.
- It's Mrs. Espinoza.
- Two cops are up there.
- When did they get here?
- Five minutes ago.
- What's that sound?
- Sound of the building.
It's very oId.
- He insists on fixing everything.
- Wanda, please.
- What apartment number?
- It's up here.
- Go back to your apartments.
- We heard screams.
Well, at least get out of the way.
- Are they with you?
- Yeah. They're shadowing us.
Then they're your responsibility.
I teIl you not to fiIm something,
don't film it.
- I tell you to get lost, you get lost.
- No problem.
Here on the second floor on the right.
It's an oId woman, lives alone.
Probably fell.
Neighbors heard screams, called it in.
What are those peopIe doing?
You wouldn't believe
the way she screamed. It was crazy.
Neighbors say she's weird.
Doesn't talk to anybody.
She hasn't made a sound.
- Who are they?
- They're with Fire.
- I told them not to get in the way.
- Great. That's all we need.
Hello, ma'am, can you hear me?
It's L.A.P.D.
Ma'am, open up the door.
I'm here with paramedics.
We're gonna come in to help you.
If you're near the door,
I need you to move away from it.
- Hey, l got the keys.
- Then get in here, sir. Come on.
- 2A.
- HeIp us out here.
Just a second. Yeah, here we are.
She must have added locks.
- I'm gonna do an intro.
- Yeah, you're good.
Okay. We're standing
outside an elderly woman's apartment.
Neighbors heard screams
and called 911.
The fire department's
about to begin the rescue.
Police say that she lives alone,
she's not very social--
I need you to get back,
brother, please, this time.
Ma'am, we're the police.
We're here to heIp you.
Ma'am? Ma'am?
Ma'am, can you hear us?
- What's her name?
- Mrs. Espinoza.
There's no need to worry, Mrs.
Espinoza. We're here to help you.
Okay, ma'am.
- It's okay.
- It's all right.
Everything's gonna be fine.
Ma'am? We're right here, ma'am.
- It's okay.
- Ma'am.
- Jesus.
- Are you okay?
You okay? Come here.
Ma'am, it's-- We're the police.
- Ma'am.
- We're here to help you.
It's all right, is there anybody else
in the apartment? Any more animals?
- It's gonna be okay, ma'am.
- All right.
It's okay, all right?
It's all right.
Ma'am, ma'am.
It's all right. Lt's all right.
All right. Okay, okay.
Okay, aIl right.
All right. Are you hurt?
All right, are you hurt?
- No.
- Okay, okay.
We're gonna get you
some medical help.
No, no, no. Please, don't.
No, are you okay?
Are you okay, ma'am?
No, no, no.
Okay, okay, okay.
You're gonna be okay.
You're gonna be okay, alI right?
- Okay, just relax.
- Just relax.
- Just calm down.
- Turn that thing off.
- Turn that off.
Give us some room.
- Come on, man.
- Gloves on, Danny.
Where's that blood coming from?
Hey, chief,
we're gonna need an ambulance here.
Copy. On our way.
Mrs. Espinoza,
it's alI gonna be aIl right.
All right,
I just need you to calm down, okay?
It's all right.
Nobody's here to hurt you.
We can't help you
unless you calm down.
- An ambulance is on its way right now.
- All right.
Let's just clear a space.
Danny, get everybody out of here
until the ambulance gets here.
Get her off. Get off. Get her off.
Get him on the floor.
No. We are not moving him.
- We are waiting for the ambulance.
- Do you see an ambulance?
We have to get him downstairs.
- All right. Come on, come on. Okay.
- Grab the arm.
Come on. Come on, l got it.
Come on, lean down.
I got her. I got her.
Let's go.
- Get the fuck out of the way.
- Go, Scott.
Move that camera.
Come on, let's go, let's go.
- Did we get that?
- Move, move, move.
- Let's go, open that door.
- Let's go.
- Be careful down the stairs.
- Hang in there, buddy.
Tape everything, you hear me?
Tape everything.
Move. Move. Move.
- Open the door.
- It's locked.
How can that be?
- Open it, open it.
- Open.
- What do you mean?
- They won't let us out.
- Who locked those doors?
- It's not us.
Something is closing it from outside.
We need an ambulance.
Open the door. Open the door.
Is there a doctor in the house?
- You're a doctor?
- I'm a vet.
- Come on.
- Get over here.
- Put some pressure on that wound.
- Give me that rag.
Get something.
- Back up, back up.
- Cover him up.
Why are they locking
if there's a fire?
There's no fire, Wanda.
There is no fire.
We have an officer down.
I need an ambulance immediateIy.
I need backup.
Does anybody copy?
I have a fucking hurt officer here.
What's going on?
Hey, what's happening?
Why can't we leave?
I know no more
than you do right now.
Back up.
My partner's on the floor bleeding.
- Quiet.
- Please remain calm.
We are working hard
to get you out of the building.
Please follow
the officers' instructions.
This will all be over shortly.
- What will all be over?
- What's going on?
Why are we locked in our building?
Be calm. That's what that means.
Please remain calm and everything's--
Get the camera out of here.
Don't touch the camera.
We have every right to shoot.
- I'm tired of the camera.
- People need to see what's going on.
I'm in charge here. Turn it off--
If you were, you'd be worried
about getting your partner out.
Not whether we're shooting.
You are two steps
from being arrested, okay?
This man will bleed to death.
Everybody stop fighting, okay?
Stop fighting.
We need to get this man out of here.
- What's behind that door?
- That's a fabric workshop.
- What is it?
- Fabric, fabric.
- Is there a way out from there?
- Yeah, through the back. Come, come.
- Keep them back.
- Please, pIease.
You're not helping the situation.
Okay?
My husband's outside.
Said there are cops.
Blocked off the street.
He was getting antibiotics.
We gotta do something--
What the fuck.
- Jesus.
- Oh, Jesus.
- Oh, Jesus, Fletch.
- Oh, my God.
- Oh, Jesus.
- Okay, come on.
- Don't move him.
- No, we have to, we have to.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, okay.
All right, he's stiIl got a pulse.
Shit.
Get the vet over here.
Get the vet now.
- Vet, here, now.
- Get over here.
- Come here.
- Keep an eye on him.
He's still got a pulse.
Take care of him.
Okay, back away.
All right. Come with me, let's go.
Come on, come on.
You two stay here, all right?
Stay here.
Keep an eye on my partner, please.
Come on.
Let's get upstairs.
Come on, let's get upstairs.
I'm coming.
The sound's coming from in there.
Okay.
Move over.
Oh, Scott, don't.
Don't go in there, Scott.
Scott.
- Watch out.
- Oh, my God.
She's dead.
- She's dead.
- What?
What are you two doing here?
Get the camera back.
We need to get you guys out of here.
Ma'am. Ma'am? Ma'am? Ma'am?
Ma'am, listen to me.
Can you hear me, Miss Espinoza?
I need you to stay
right where you are, okay?
All right?
We wanna heIp you here.
Put your hands in the air for me,
Mrs. Espinoza.
Okay? Put your hands in the air.
Oh, my God.
Let's go.
Put the gun down. Let's go.
- She was coming right at us.
- Yeah.
- You saw that, right?
- Yeah, I saw it.
Shit. Okay.
Okay, you saw that, right?
Okay. All right.
Let's just get downstairs.
Let's get downstairs.
Hey, hey, hey.
Easy, easy, easy.
Did you get that?
Yeah.
Show it to me.
- Look, don't worry. L got it.
- I said show it to me!
Okay. Okay, okay.
- What the hell was that?
- I don't know. I think--
Is everything okay?
We shouId probably
just get down the stairs, okay?
I know, I know, I know.
- Oh, my God.
- We just have to get downstairs.
Fire department.
I need you to open up the door.
Fire department. We need everyone
to gather downstairs in the atrium.
Yes, we need you to go downstairs.
- Was there a fire?
- No, it's just a precaution.
Just a precaution for what?
Look,
we just need you to get downstairs.
Does this have anything to do
with the cable being out?
- Come on, let's go.
- What? Wait, wait, wait.
- What if l don't wanna go?
- Then l'd be forced to force you.
Hi. L'm with the fire department.
We need everyone
to gather in the atrium.
Do you speak English?
English? No.
Okay,
we need everybody downstairs, so....
All right, there's people down there,
and we need you two to go there.
You understand?
Fire department.
Ma'am?
Hello, ma'am?
Ma'am, I'm with the fire department.
We need you to quickly and calmly
walk down to the Iobby, please.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Ma'am.
Ma'am,
we need you to get downstairs, okay?
What's wrong with her?
I don't know.
- You wanna give me a hand?
- Yeah.
- I don't know that that's a good idea.
- She needs help.
Just grab her.
Okay. Now lift her up.
Okay.
We're just taking you downstairs,
okay, ma'am?
All right?
Oh, Jesus.
Okay? Okay?
Okay? Yeah.
Oh, she's really sick.
Holy shit. Did you see that?
That rat just totally came after me.
Hey, did you see that?
Come on.
Un-fucking-beIievabIe.
- Oh, my God, look at Elise.
- Somebody grab that chair.
- What's wrong with her?
- Set her down, set her down.
Can't stop the bleeding.
Get him to a hospital. He's gonna die.
Stay here.
I'm gonna check the exit.
No, no, wait.
We are under strict orders--
We're under orders
to stay in the hall. HeIp me.
Fuck your orders, all right?
My friend's dying!
- I'm coming out.
- Do not--
- Didn't catch that. You're breaking up.
- Two people have died.
Two others are in need of medical
care. Police have blocked off the exit.
They've given us no expIanation.
We're trying to find a way out.
- Oh, my God.
- Shit.
- Get away from the window.
- Go, go.
You need to remain in the buiIding.
We have civilians in here.
Briana, don't.
Attention, please.
Do not try to leave the building.
All exits have been sealed.
Just stay calm.
We will send someone in there
shortly to assess the situation.
Thank you for your cooperation.
What are we supposed to do?
- What are we supposed to do?
- Just wait.
There's five there. What happened?
Sir, sir, sir.
Give me your headphones.
No, you're not getting my question.
Not getting my question.
I'm asking
why they're calling this a BNC.
- What's a BNC?
- I don't know.
Hello?
- HeIlo?
- Is somebody there?
Honey, hello?
Why is the phone breaking?
Why is it not working?
- What's a BNC?
- Who said anything about--?
- You. You're stilI miked.
- Wait.
- What?
- Don't jump to--
What's a BNC? What is it?
They're calling this a BNC?
A biological,
nuclear or chemical threat.
- Oh, my God.
- Nuclear?
- What?
- No, don't worry, okay?
- It's more common than you think.
- Supposed to be reassuring?
Our cell phones don't work.
Neither do the TVs or our radios.
- Why are they isolating us?
- I don't know.
My daughter has a fever.
- What does she have?
- They're pointing guns.
You can't keep us trapped here.
- We're all trapped.
- That's right.
We are all trapped in here.
Step over here.
- Here.
- What will they do?
- Step over here, pIease.
- Jake, Jake.
There might be-- From the office on
the second floor, there is an overhang.
Maybe we can use
to jump down to the patio.
- Let's go.
- I show you.
I'm going with you.
Don't turn the light on.
I don't want anyone knowing
we're in here.
Careful.
- When l open the window--
- Yeah?
--Go to the right side and jump.
It's only two and a half meters.
Get away from the window.
- For your own safety.
- No.
- Step away.
- Wait, wait, wait.
- Wait, listen.
Can you see me? Can you see me?
- What are you doing?
- We have a fiIm crew in here.
Tell your boss
we have a TV crew in here.
We are filming this. Please, wait.
People are gonna see
what you're doing to us.
- Why can't we go out?
- People are gonna see this.
Please. Wait.
What are you doing in here?
- You knew about this, didn't you?
- Knew what?
That they're sealing us in here.
What the fuck is this?
- What is going on?
- You tell us.
I don't know anything and don't you
fucking put your hands on me again.
I don't know anything, okay?
Get this fucking camera out.
- Don't touch me.
- Don't touch that camera.
We need to show people
what's going on here.
- Only proof we have.
- Don't you get it?
You're locked in here Iike us.
You think they give a shit about you?
- Step back.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- Let's all just calm down, alI right?
- Shut up.
- Put the gun down.
Go back downstairs now, okay?
Yeah, okay, okay, but--
Shut up!
Damn. Go back downstairs.
This thing is getting to all of us.
No one here
is gonna hurt you, okay?
We're trying to get out.
That's all we're trying to do.
Just put the gun down.
I'm sorry, man.
- I'm sorry, all right?
- Yeah.
I was just freaked out. Let's go.
- We all are.
- Go downstairs, okay?
- All right?
- Yeah, let's get downstairs, man.
Shit.
Fuck.
Grab his legs, okay?
Come on, let's go.
What we'll do
is we'll roll him on his side.
We just have to be really careful.
- What time is it?
- One-thirty-seven.
Five, four, three....
It's 1 :37 in the morning,
and everyone is scared.
They've given us no information,
cut off communication...
...from walkie-talkies and cell phones
to the building's cable and lnternet.
The people trapped here,
myself included...
...can't help but ask why.
How's he doing?
Well, he's not good.
Yeah.
Excuse me. It's Terrence, right?
- No, Lawrence.
- Lawrence, right.
Listen, I've got a ton of Vicodin
in my apartment, if that will help.
Yeah, that's gonna help.
I'll just-- I'll grab a bunch of stuff.
I basically got a pharmacy up there.
You can't arrest me for that,
because of self-incrimination--
Sir, you are the Ieast
of my worries right now, okay?
- All right, I was just asking.
- Go.
Do what you're gonna do, please.
I'm going. L'm going.
You ever seen
anything like this before?
No, I've never
seen anything like this.
Mostly because l'm a vet.
I don't usually treat people.
Dogs and cats, mostly.
All I can really do is l can dress
their wounds and try to comfort them.
How are the injured men doing?
They both lost a lot of bIood,
and the fireman over here...
...he's got a bunch of broken bones
and probable internal bleeding.
ApparentIy, Mrs. Espinoza attacked
and bit them in some kind of a fit.
But honestly,
I find that a little hard to believe...
...that an oId Iady could do
something like this to two grown men.
Ready? Ready to film?
Okay.
- What's your name?
- Briana.
Briana, that's a very pretty name.
How old are you, Briana?
- Five.
- And who do you live with?
With my mom
and my dad and my dog, Max.
Max. L haven't met Max. Where is he?
My dad took him to the vet
because he's sick.
- You sound a littIe sick yourself.
- Yeah.
- She's had it for weeks, it's not like--
- You know what?
If you don't mind, I'd like to keep
you quiet while I interview Briana.
It confuses the audience
when people talk from off-camera.
- Oh, God, l'm sorry.
- No, no, it's okay.
- I'lI interview you afterwards.
- No, that's fine.
- Okay.
- We don't need that.
Okay, thank you.
I don't like being sick.
Yeah, l don't like being sick either.
Briana, you're a very brave girI...
...and l'm really happy
we got a chance to meet.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
She's been fearless
since she was littIe.
She's an incredibly strong child.
Okay? Okay.
Why don't you just start
by introducing yourselves?
Well, I'm Ber-- I'm Bernard.
This is my roommate, Sadie.
And this is Martini.
And how long
have you lived in the building?
I've Iived here six years.
I've been here two and a half years.
And what do you do for a living?
I'm an opera teacher.
Sadie's my best student, my protege.
- Oh, my God.
- Fletcher.
Where's the vet?
Oh, my God.
Where the hell is the doctor?
I got him, got him, got him.
Hold him, hold him.
Hold his neck, hold his neck.
What is that?
- HoId it over, hold his neck.
- Go, go, go.
Oh, my God, is he stilI aIive?
Hold him still, hold him still.
He's gonna go down.
Martini.
Sadie, stay here. Stay.
No, no, stay here, stay here.
No, the dog will come back.
Martini.
Hold him.
- Okay, I have to show you something.
- What?
Have to show you something.
Just a sec.
I think I know what this is.
- Come, come look, look, look.
- Oh, Jesus.
Her tear ducts and saIivary glands
are constantly flowing.
She seems
to be unable to swallow or speak.
She has a fever, she's confused.
She has some degree
of paralysis and delirium.
These are all rabies symptoms.
- Are you sure?
- I'm a vet.
Never seen it in humans,
but I know what rabies look like.
Are you trying to tell me
these people have rabies?
Tears, saliva, fever.
They have what she has.
But here's the thing. Rabies
takes months for symptoms to show.
This is taking minutes.
I mean, rabies never acts this fast.
How does rabies spread?
Through bites?
No, it's passed through anything wet.
Blood, saliva, any mucous membrane.
So if you get their blood on you,
you're okay.
But if you get their blood on you...
...and it gets into a cut,
into your mouth, eyes...
...then you're not okay.
How's it cured?
No, there's no cure.
People get shots in their stomach.
Before symptoms starts showing.
Once symptoms show,
rabies is 100 percent fatal.
Shit.
Yeah, shit.
- Where are you going? Where?
- I'm going up to my apartment.
- What?
- I am going upstairs.
You can't do that.
- Why?
- Come down.
- What do you mean?
- Why can't l go?
- We gonna do this all night?
- You know why?
- Because it's not safe there.
Oh, yeah,
because it's really safe down here.
- You're drunk.
- You know what?
It seems to me, if this is spreading,
maybe we should separate...
...instead of sitting here
in a big group.
You done? You finished?
- You done?
- You know what?
I have a God-given right to protect
myself as I see fit, so you know what?
- I'm gonna go upstairs--
- Step back.
I'm gonna go and l'm
gonna barricade the shit out of it.
- Where do you think they're going?
- You can all sit here and rot.
Oh, you are so close to going to jail.
- Are you some kind of affirmative--?
- You are so close to going to jail.
- Hey.
- Hurry up, hurry up.
- What?
- Where are you going?
Look, this lets out
right next to our apartment.
We wanna see if there's anything
on the news about this.
- But the cable's out.
- Cable?
We still use rabbit ears on our TV.
We're going with you.
Wait, wait, wait, we're going with you.
It's just up here to the right.
You're good?
- Stop. Just stop.
- What?
Go back downstairs.
The door locked behind me.
Just stay there.
Oh, my God. Oh, God.
Hey, look out.
- Oh, my God!
- Look out.
No, no, no!
We can't just open the door. We need
something to hoId the dog back with.
- Find something!
- There's a fire extinguisher.
Oh, my God.
Stop, stop.
Listen.
Turn it off, Scott. Turn it off.
Oh, l forgot something.
- Shouldn't we shut the door?
- Close the door.
- Okay.
- I left the music on.
Folk music.
The TV's back here.
All right.
Okay.
It usually takes
a couple of seconds to....
There we go, all right.
- Fiddle with this--
- Make sure that--
No, I know what I'm doing.
- No, I'm--
- Yeah, I know, all right?
- ...third hour of our coverage.
- There.
- There it is.
- ...receiving conflicting reports.
--Hind me was comp-- Evacuated....
--that the CDC...
Chief.
Tell us why the CDC
is entering the building.
Precaution.
Everyone's been evacuated.
What?
Why would he broadcast that?
Why would he say that?
What the fuck is going on here?
- What happened?
- Power's out.
Oh, Jesus Christ. Jesus Christ.
- What was that?
- Quiet.
Sadie, stay with me.
Sadie, come here.
Sadie, come over here.
Stay with me. Lt cannot be.
- Stay with me.
- You gotta close that door.
Sadie, Iook out.
- Get off me.
- Oh, my God.
Get off of me.
Bernard, stay with me.
Hit her again!
Oh, my God.
Angela, you have blood
all over your shirt.
- Scott.
- What?
Scott.
What do you want?
You okay?
Yeah, l'm just fine.
I mean, l just killed something
with my camera...
...and, you know, l'm just fine.
Yeah.
Scott.
What, Angela? What you...?
I need a moment now.
I'm with you.
- I'm with you, you're with me, okay?
- Okay, okay, okay, we're here.
We're here together, all right?
We get out of here as fast
as we fucking can, you hear me?
- Okay, okay.
- Together?
- That everybody?
- Getting the last one.
All right, keep going.
All right, it's been a long,
exhausting night for all of us...
...but we just got word from outside.
Well, it's about bloody fucking time,
isn't it?
Yes, they told me
they're sending in the CDC.
- CDC?
- What's--?
- Center for Disease Control.
- Why?
Yes, but relax, it's fine.
They're gonna come in.
They're gonna run blood tests
on residents to clarify things.
- Just the residents?
- No, everybody.
Everybody,
so once they check it out...
...make sure everything's okay,
we should be abIe to get out.
- Oh, thank God.
- That won't work.
- What are you talking about?
- That doesn't work, not for rabies.
- Nobody said anything about rabies.
- I did, I told you it was rabies.
How do you test for rabies?
There's only one way.
You gotta get a brain sampIe.
- Come on.
- Man, just shut up.
- What you have to do.
- Let's make sure everyone's here.
A simple "here" will be fine.
So let's get started.
- How many units per floor?
- Three.
- There are three.
- Okay.
Second floor, Unit A,
that's where Mrs. Espinoza lives?
- Yes.
- Who's in B?
- Me and Sadie.
- Here.
Who's in Unit C?
Unit C.
The lawyer.
- Randy.
- Elevat--
All right, third floor, Unit A.
Who's up there?
That's me, my daughter
and my husband, who's been outside--
Yes, yes, yes, we know. Thank you.
- Unit B, please.
- Us.
- My wife and me.
- Who's in Unit C?
- Vacant.
- Why we doing this?
- Nobody's been there--
- Fourth floor, Unit A, who's up there?
- That was Elise. She's dead.
- What?
- She's dead?
- 4B, who's in B?
- It's me, me, here.
- Who's in C?
- It's them.
You two?
They don't understand you.
Them and her father.
- And her father's upstairs?
- Sick, he's paralytic.
Maybe this is all his fault.
- How do you know? You don't know--
- Listen up, all right, let's finish up.
- Okay.
- Somebody knows.
What was I even gonna say?
Who lives in the attic?
A man from Boston. He rents it,
but I haven't seen him in months.
Wait, if her father's upstairs,
should we bring him down?
What if he's the cause?
We can't bring sick people here.
- Your daughter's sick, isn't she?
- She has fever. Hardly the same.
Yeah, so we should bring
her father downstairs.
- Hey, hey.
- Stop, stop it.
- Hey.
- Stop fighting.
- Listen.
- How many times you gonna do this?
Nobody's going.
We're gonna stay here.
They'll let us know
when they wanna move us, period.
Can we finish?
- Fine.
- Thank you.
The cleaning lady.
Yeah, the cleaning lady.
- The cleaning Iady was here.
- I saw her this morning.
She's deceased.
- What?
- What did he say?
- She's gone.
Stand back from the door.
Open the door.
- Show me your hands.
- L.A.P.D.
CDC's now making their way
into the building.
There are security measures in place.
We still have no idea
what's happening.
From the look of the precaution
that they're taking...
...it's something very serious.
I want you
to just keep this area clear.
This is....
This is bIood from my partner here.
He's in the back. This blood
is from the second firefighter.
You, turn it off. Turn it off now.
Now. Turn it off.
Okay, okay, it's off.
Jesus.
Okay, everyone here.
Everybody here is good.
The two guys are in the back.
That's all we can tell you.
- I don't know anything else right now.
- Okay.
Just take me to the injured.
Everyone else stays here.
You heard him. Stay here.
Clear this area.
They tell us to stay caIm,
and they come dressed Iike that?
- It's gonna be all right.
- What? You honestly believe that?
I'm gonna open it.
Can you see?
That's good. That's good.
I'm gonna take samples
from both men.
Up here. Up here.
- Okay.
- Can you get up there?
Yeah, okay, cool.
Hey, hoId this, hold this.
Quiet, quiet, quiet.
You got it?
Okay, give it to me.
Give me the camera, come on.
Give me the camera.
- Can you see?
- Yeah.
What's happening?
- They're handcuffing him.
- Who?
Fletcher.
The other one's got a syringe.
He just gave Fletcher a shot.
- Oh, shit.
- What?
He's got a drill.
- Oh, Jesus.
- What?
I think the vet was right.
I think he's taking a brain sampIe.
- HoIy shit.
- Scott?
Hey, look out.
Angela, run. Run!
The vet's in there.
He's still in there.
- Open the door.
- We can't, he's been bitten.
- Come on, let him out.
- I'm not infected, you're wrong.
I'm not infected. L'm all right.
- They didn't get me.
- What are you talking about?
- Are you sure he's been bitten?
- Yes, and l'm not taking any chances.
Back away tiIl the infected people
have been handcuffed.
Infected with what?
- Would you get that out of my face?
- What happens happens in the open.
They have a right to shoot this,
okay?
- You okay?
- Lawrence.
Lawrence, you okay?
God, this isn't right.
Calm down, calm down. No.
- It's not right.
- It would not be right to let him out--
You telI us what's going on.
- I'm not authorized to tell--
- Bullshit.
You Ieft my friend
because he tried to kill you.
Tell us what you know.
- Tell us what you know.
- Yeah, okay, goddamn, okay.
We got a call from a vet
who had a sick dog brought in.
They ran the routine tests,
it was nothing they'd ever seen before.
Then it started
attacking the other animaIs.
And within an hour,
all the injured animals...
...showed the same kind
of aggression.
Yeah. The dog's collar
led us to this building.
Was the dog's name Max?
Yes.
- She only has bronchitis.
- Bullshit, bronchitis.
- No, don't you dare.
- Kathy.
- Bronchitis.
- We need to find out.
Relax, ma'am. Relax.
We have to be sure.
No, get away from me.
Dog spread the infection
through his saliva.
We just gotta check.
- Let him do a check, ma'am.
- No.
That's all we gotta do.
That's all she has, just bronchitis.
- No.
- Go, go.
Get back. Get back.
Get back. Watch out.
Run, Briana. Run, sweetheart.
- Get the girl.
- No, get away from her.
- HoId her. Hold her.
- Run!
- Run, sweetie, please!
- Get the handcuffs.
- Come on, come on.
- No, let me go.
Don't hurt her. Please!
Please,
you need to get us out of here.
Stop it! Stop it!
- Cuff her.
- No.
Come here. Come.
- Honey.
- She's cuffed.
- Back away.
Back away.
Calm down, calm down, calm down.
- No.
- Father.
- What father?
- Her father's sick in bed.
- Nobody told me that.
We thought everyone was down here.
All right, here. Take this.
Get the girl and inject her with it.
- No, no.
- And you, bring everybody down here.
Bring Briana. Okay.
Kathy, we're gonna get her.
We're gonna bring her down.
- Run, honey!
- Going up.
- We're not gonna hurt you.
- Get away!
Get away from her! Honey.
Briana.
Run!
Honey.
Briana.
Get away from her.
Oh, God.
Slow down, slow down, slow down.
Okay, okay. AIl right.
Briana?
Oh, God.
- Where the hell's the old lady?
- The old lady's gone.
Briana?
Okay. Just take it easy, okay?
Oh, Briana.
- Briana?
Shit.
Shit, I'm sorry.
Briana?
Oh, shit.
Oh, l think she's in here, Jake.
Hell.
She's over there. She's over there.
You all right?
Now, l need you
to give me your hand, okay?
Okay?
What happened to her eyes?
Please don't stop. Please, don't.
Get her off me.
Go, go.
She bit me. Go, Jake!
- Get out of here.
- Go, go, go.
Come on, go. Let's go.
- They're getting out.
They're getting out.
No, no, no.
- Go back.
- They're getting out.
Oh, they're getting out. Run, run!
Don't go. Wait!
They're getting close. Run.
Okay. Run! Run!
Don't leave me.
- Don't leave me.
- I'm not gonna leave her.
- We have to get out of here.
It's not right! It's not right!
- Come on.
- No, no, not that way. This way.
Hurry up, come on.
Where are the others?
Come on, let's go.
Hurry up.
- Lock it, lock it, lock it!
- Hurry up.
Help me, help me.
- Were you bitten?
- No.
- You?
Scott?
- Were you bitten?
- No.
Angie?
No.
- Hey, what about you?
- No, no.
Hey, you.
On the floor.
- Hey, you been bitten?
- No, no.
Jake, did you find the little girl?
Who gives a shit about the little girl?
All right.
We've lost control of the building.
We're fucked.
Damn it.
I don't understand.
They were biting her face off.
I don't know
what the fuck is happening.
- Damn it.
- I don't understand.
We could aIl be infected by now.
We gotta get out of here.
I'm not moving. I'm done.
- I'm not moving.
- Hey, we wait here, we wait here.
- We have to get out of here.
- Listen.
We have to stay here and wait
till somebody come and get us.
They're not gonna come and get us.
- Oh, yes, they will.
- They are not gonna come!
They don't give a shit about us!
They're gonna let us die!
They don't care about us.
Scott, we're gonna die!
- Oh, fuck.
- She's right.
- Who was that?
- It was the doctor.
What?
- I'm gonna kill you.
- I've been bit.
You Ieft us down there.
Piece of shit.
I've been bitten.
He's been bitten.
He's been bitten. Get back.
Close those doors.
Somebody close
those fucking doors.
It won't hold him.
It's not gonna hold him for long.
- Get back.
- She's bleeding.
She's bleeding.
Sadie.
No.
We have to kiIl her.
No, no.
Hey, hey, hey,
you're not gonna fucking touch her.
We gotta get out. Gotta get out.
Gotta get out of here.
Gotta get out of here. Come on.
Help me get out of here.
Let me get out of here, please.
Hey, hey.
Please. Hey!
Hey. Hey.
Please, get me--
Oh, my God.
Sniper!
Scott.
They're not gonna let us out
of here alive, are they?
No.
I don't think so.
- There might be a way out.
- What?
Jake, there might be a way out.
How? How do we get out of here?
Listen, Jake.
There is a drain cover in the basement
that joins up with the sewers.
- We need the key, we need the key.
- The keys are in our apartment.
Come with us.
Come with us!
You have to come with us!
I won't leave him. I can't leave him.
Leave him aIone.
Oh, my God!
We have to get out of here!
We have to get the key.
Key's in Yuri's apartment.
Know where he Iives?
You made the list of residents.
Where does he live?
I can't remember where it's at.
You have to think about it.
Think, think, think.
- I don't know, I don't know.
- Think!
I don't know which apartment.
I don't know which apartment it is.
MaiIboxes, mailboxes.
MaiIboxes.
Yeah, get the hammer.
- Grab the hammer.
- I got it, I got it.
- Go.
- Keep moving.
Oh, keep moving, man.
Keep moving.
I'm coming.
Where is it? Which one is it?
Hurry.
Yuri lvanov, 3B.
Three. Get to the elevator.
- Three. Oh, God.
- Oh, shit.
Get to the eIevator.
But the electricity?
It should run on auxiliary power.
We're good.
She's cuffed. We can get by.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
- Oh, God.
- Get in.
Get in.
Get in. Get in.
Hurry! Hurry. Hurry.
Close the fucking door.
Easy, easy.
But it's gonna stop at two.
We're gonna stop at two!
- The light, the light!
- I'lI get it.
- I'm fixing it, come on.
- The light.
Come on. Come on,
you shouId get that hammer, Jake.
They won't close. They won't close.
It's go-- It's gonna go.
Oh, it's gonna go.
- Oh, shit.
- Scott.
Scott.
Scott!
Get off me.
No!
Get up. Come on.
Get up.
Get up!
Scott, l've been bitten!
- I've been bitten.
- No, you haven't.
No, you haven't. I saw it.
I was bitten!
Angie, Angie, they didn't get you.
You didn't get bitten.
- Come on, Angie. Angie.
- I was bitten!
- Look at me, Angie. Come on, baby.
- No!
- Baby, come on, look at me.
- Man, let's go.
- Get off me. Look at me.
- No.
Let's get out of here.
You did not get bit.
You did not get bit. Look at me.
Trust me. You did not.
- I saw it, l saw it.
- We have to go.
- Let's go.
- No. Let's go, baby.
Come on. Come on! Let's go.
This is 3B right here. Right here.
All cIear.
- Keep the light on my hands, Scott.
- Okay.
- Find them.
- I don't see it, l don't see.
- The light, the light, the light.
- I'm bringing it back to you.
Nothing.
I don't....
No, no, he wouldn't
leave them in there.
Hey, he wouldn't leave them in there.
Come on.
Hurry.
Find the keys.
He's the one that-- Who's--?
Go back to the desk.
- Yeah.
- Find them keys, baby.
Come on.
I got them,
but I don't know which one it is.
- I don't know.
- Take them all.
- Which one is it, Scott?
Come on.
Angela, Angela,
I need you to be quiet.
We need to get three flights of stairs
down to the basement, okay?
I need you to stay tight.
I need you to stay close
and stay fast, okay?
- Are you ready? AIl right, all right.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Ready, Scott?
- Yeah, yeah.
All right, aIl right.
Okay. All right.
- All right, we can do this.
- Got it.
- We can do this, right, Angela?
- Yeah.
Okay, let's go. Let's go.
Come on.
Ready. Come on.
Scott, come on. Come on, Scott.
Angela, Angela, stop.
Hey, we gotta go up. Come on.
Come on, run, run.
Get up there. Come on.
Up. Go.
- Gonna be an old one. Oh, God.
- Go.
- It's gotta be an old one, Scott.
- I know, pick the key.
- Get in there.
- Light, light, light!
- I'm finding it, l'm finding it!
- Come on.
- Go, go, go.
- Scott, l got it.
- I got it!
- Lock it.
- I can't get it.
- Come on.
Scott, l can't!
Just turn the light on.
- Turn the light on.
- It'll come back on.
- I need the Iight on!
- It will come back on.
Oh, please.
There we go, there we go,
there we go. Okay? Okay, listen.
Listen, listen. They went away.
I think they went away.
Oh, damn, damn.
Okay, so this place was locked up.
What that means, probably,
is there ain't nobody in here. No one.
Yeah, let's find a way out.
Oh, God. Come on.
Oh, what is this place, Scott?
- Oh, please, keep the Iight on.
- I got you, I got you.
What is this?
Stay with me. Stay with me.
Come on.
Come on. Come on, now.
- What is this?
- Oh, please.
- I don't know, man.
What is it?
- Oh, what is that?
- Please.
What is it?
What the hell?
Oh, shit.
Oh, God.
Oh, it's all the same kind of stuff.
I don't understand it.
Just stop.
Wait.
Oh, God,
let's get out of here, please.
Okay, come on.
Come on, grab my hand.
Grab my hand, it's me, it's me.
Look at it, look at it.
Just come around this pole.
Let me lead.
Let me lead. L'm right with you.
That's the way, okay?
Okay, come on.
Oh, God, I don't--
Hey, hey, my bad, my bad.
Okay.
Angela?
We're gonna have to go
through that door.
I just need you to open it.
You're gonna let me Iook in first.
- You just open it, okay?
- Yeah.
Just push it and stand back.
Stand back. Okay, okay.
Come on, come on, Angie.
Angie, Iet's go in there.
- Please, get the light on me, okay?
- Come on.
Oh, this is so fucked. L don't know.
Oh, damn.
Oh, shit, stick with me, stick with me.
Come on.
Okay?
- Keep the light on, keep the light on.
- What is it?
Okay.
Okay, good? You gotta--
Shit.
- What is this?
- What?
What is it? What the heIl?
What are you doing?
- Oh, Scott, what is this stuff?
- Okay.
Okay.
Who is this? Who is this?
Oh, what is that?
Is that a fucking...?
Hey, play it.
I don't know what to do with it.
That's it, come on.
Hey, what is that?
What was that?
I'll come to you.
Oh, God, oh, God, oh, God.
Hey, hey, hey.
Come on.
We don't know what's up there.
- Grab my hand, grab my hand.
- Okay.
Okay.
Okay, l'm gonna take the camera.
Listen to me, Iisten to me.
I'm gonna take the camera.
- I'm gonna take a look up there.
- No, no.
- Get up the door.
- No, no, no.
We can't stay the fuck down here.
We can't stay here.
I won't have a light
if you go up there!
- Angie, Angie, stay with me.
- I'lI be in the dark!
Angie, stay with me!
Look, l'm gonna have
to take this light off you.
Here, grab my waist.
Okay, just grab my waist.
Good.
Scott, what happened?
What happened?
- Oh, something hit the camera.
- Don't turn it off, fix it.
- I'm trying. Damn it, l'm trying.
- Please!
I'm trying.
Look, l'm gonna put
the night vision on.
I'll put the night vision on. Hold on.
Just stay there, okay?
- Okay, okay.
- Okay.
Okay.
Okay. Okay, l can
see you now, okay?
Okay.
All right? Okay.
Yeah, yeah. Okay,
I'm gonna stick my hand out, okay?
Okay, okay. Hey.
Relax, relax, it's me.
Hey, it's me, it's me, it's me, okay?
Okay, good. Come on, come on.
Hey, you're doing good.
Come around.
Come around my back. Hold on.
Hold on. We'll be okay, okay?
I just gotta find us a way out of here.
Okay? Okay.
I'll find a way out, l promise.
Just give me a minute.
What's that? Stay still, stay stilI.
Why? Why? Why?
Get down. Get down.
Don't make a sound.
It can't see us.
If it can't hear us, it won't find us.
Okay, get ready.
We're gonna try to get by it.
Run!