When the territories of
the Great West were thrown open...
men of all kinds rushed in.
Most came to settle peaceably,
lured by free land...
gold, cattle.
A man could begin a herd
with a maverick:
An unbranded stray on the public range.
By putting his brand on it,
he owned it.
Cattle barons had started
their great herds with mavericks.
Now they fought each settler
who tried to do the same.
They fought to keep the settlers
off the public lands...
drive them from their homes...
destroy their towns.
Vast ranges became the
battlegrounds of cattle wars.
When the Wyoming big ranchers
found guns were not enough...
they used the Maverick Law:
A law through which they appointed
themselves commissioners...
with power to rule on the ownership
of every maverick branded.
A commissioner's ruling could
declare the settler a rustler...
outlaw his brand,
make his mavericks illegal to sell.
Of course, there was no shortage
of sharp-witted men...
who were quick
to take advantage of this law.
I know what I'm entitled to!
I'm willing to fight for my rights!
And I'm willing to fight for your rights,
but you've got to stand behind me.
You've got to put me
in the Governor's mansion!
You've got to have someone to
represent you, not just Reece Duncan.
Go ahead, Mr Averell.
Don't let me stop you.
What brings you to town?
Your ears burning?
What is this Maverick Law?
The Maverick Law was designed to
protect us all against cattle rustling.
There is nothing in that law
that says new settlers...
can't pick up unbranded cattle
and call them their own.
When a Cattle Commission was appointed
to watch over brands and cattle...
that was for our protection too!
I'd like to ask Mr Duncan one question.
I'd like to ask him
who paid bribe money...
to the Cattle Commissioners
to outlaw your brands?
To see to it that every time you roped
a maverick it was confiscated?
Just hold it still everybody,
real quiet and still.
Put the gun away.
I only aimed to drill his hat, Sheriff.
Just let out some hot air.
Keep it there.
I think Mr Duncan would like
a crack at the governorship himself.
Do you reckon Wyoming
will ever have a Governor...
who'll take a shot at a man
who doesn't wear a gun?
No... or anyone who carries it
under cover either.
- This is a big deal, Sheriff. You ought to step out of it.
- Everybody oughta.
I'm warning you men, this range is taken.
There's no room for squatters.
- You started from scratch yourself, Duncan.
- That was a long time past.
For you! But we're just beginnin'!
And we aim to start with mavericks,
and we aim to stay.
You'll stay just so long
as you stay within the law.
Which means that if I find any one of you
rounding up and branding cattle on my range...
I have the right
to fill you full of lead.
Easy, boys, easy.
A couple of you boys
have asked me if I had any ideas.
Well, gentlemen...
here's one of my
biggest ideas right now.
- Hello, Kate. How are you?
- Same as always, Jim.
Measurements and... memory.
Keep the measurements, forget
the memory. I'm gonna make it up to you.
Folks, the newest and latest
scintillating gem to greet our fair town.
Is there anyone here so young who doesn't
recognize the name of Kate Maxwell?
Hello, boys.
Pleased to meet you."
Boys, I never was any good at keeping
secrets from you, but I sure kept this one.
That place of mine
I've been fixing up...
well, it belongs to Kate
from here on in.
There'll be music, high-kick dancing...
and the straightest card game in Wyoming.
And you'll have money for it too!
Kate's a cattle buyer now.
She aims to buy up every maverick
you can lay a rope on, so bring 'em on in.
Kate's got her own brand,
and not an outlaw brand.
She'll market your mavericks for you,
and there's nothing...
that Duncan and his
Cattlemen's Association can do about it.
What are you up to this time, Jim?
I told you I was gonna make you rich.
I don't suppose I've got to ask
my lawyer if this is legal?
It's legal, Mr Duncan.
I've looked into it.
Miss Maxwell, you've looked into it too?
It's liable to get you in some hot water.
Why, I soak in hot water
every day, mister.
It's good for the... complexion.
"I'm glad you're used to it...
just in case any of those mavericks
"you take in trade come from my range.
I'm just warning you.
No animal on my property,
branded or not, is a stray.
Whatever you pick up
on the open range is yours.
Anything you take from me
has lead coming after it.
Suppose you and me
have a little talk, Mr Averell.
Wait'll you find out
what this is all about.
All right boys, take the coach
and the wagon over to Kate's Place.
Boys, make room for the lady.
Oh, Kate, this is Stan Blaine...
Sweetwater's strong arm of the law.
Pleased to meet you, Sheriff.
Why don't you show me the town
some night before you show me the jail?
You talk like you dress...
but you don't feel that way.
- Play along with him.
- Play?
He's just a drifter. Doesn't make
any trouble, doesn't want any.
- The job was open, so he took it.
- Drifter?
Now, I... am a man with a purpose.
Thank you.
Mind if I give you a hand, miss?
Why I'd be pleasured!
I'll carry you!
This one's a lady.
Why, thanks.
Take a look, Kate. It's all yours.
Not bad. In fact, pretty good.
So why are you giving it away?
Well, honey, I've got a sense of obligation.
I owe you something.
Oh, the world must be coming to an end.
Not only is Jim Averell
giving things away...
but he's paying his debts.
Listen, Kate. A lot of things
have changed since I last saw you.
Since I last saw you...
running out of Abilene like a jackrabbit...
- leaving me holding the sack.
- Did anybody get rough with you?
Why? Will you go back there
and gun them down?
Sorry, Jim, there's no money in it,
just a poor, underpaid judge.
I guess somebody oughta give me
a necktie party for what I've done to you.
Maybe somebody will.
But you came when I called you.
You didn't waste any time.
Birds of a feather.
But that doesn't mean I'll ever feel
the same way about you.
You will, honey. You will.
Believe me, that last sour deal
is way behind me.
I'm going up... up and up right into
the Governor's mansion.
- To ask a pardon?
- To be the Governor!
I'm going to make the whole territory
of Wyoming my own private range.
Think I can't do it? These settlers
would vote me into the White House.
I'm the only one around here
who'll promise them anything.
- And what's in your way?
- Reece Duncan.
I got a big front, but he is big.
Sounds crazy, but it's true. If Duncan goes,
I can be Governor of Wyoming.
You will, of course,
drop in sometime for a drink.
And you'll be with me.
That's what I'm trying to tell you, Kate.
I'm going to make up to you
for everything.
What's this other thing about?
Why am I a cattle buyer?
You don't have to know anything
about cattle. Don't let that scare you.
I know plenty.
I was riding a cow pony before I could walk.
- What's the deal?
- Duncan again, but you don't have to know the details.
You just buy mavericks and sell 'em.
Look.
Here's your brand, registered and legal.
Kate Maxwell.
K-Bar-M.
Honey, it won't be long before people
are calling you "Cattle Kate."
- These three for you, Tex.
- Good! Let's go.
What'll it be, Tex? Chips or cash?
Chips. Watch me double 'em.
That's Duncan's brand, Wally.
Let it go.
Here's a maverick for you, Wally!
It's a clean one.
"For value received, one maverick."
What'll it be?
Chips.
Horses comin', Matt.
It's Duncan! I'll head him off.
- What's the matter with you? That's a rustler!
- Matt Jessup?
- I'm missing branded steers.
- The Jessup boys are taking mavericks.
These weren't mavericks.
They carried the Bar-Double-Check.
I don't say you didn't lose 'em.
There've been reports of strange faces.
Sheriff, there's gonna be
a range war here.
I suggest you make up
"your mind whose side you're on.
I have. I'm on the side
of the first man who gets killed.
- I could knock him off right now.
- Why wait? - Naw.
Save us weeks of work and put that
loud-talking Duncan where Averell wants him.
- I said no!
- Why not?
'Cause Averell said
to let him burn a while.
I told him to come after midnight.
After midnight? He better.
He does what you say. This afternoon
he could've finished Duncan off easy...
but he let him go because
that's what you wanted.
I don't get it, boss.
Abilene taught me something.
To wait.
We set one side against the other.
Prod 'em a little;
first Duncan, then the settlers.
And wait till they kill each other off.
That's the way to get
things done for you.
In fact, that's the way
into the Governor's chair.
How will that help you
to become Governor?
Look, when times are rough, a man can
make himself a reputation overnight...
that'll spread through
the whole territory like wildfire.
That's if he's on the popular side.
And right now I've got these settlers
eating out of my hand.
The way you got it figured,
there won't be any settlers left.
Now, that'd be too bad.
In that case, I'd have to take
the consolation prize...
and all the cattle and
all the land in this valley.
I might become one of the richest, most
important men in the territory of Wyoming.
There's more than one way
to become Governor.
- Does Kate know how you're running the cattle set-up?
- No!
And nobody'll know if you and the boys
keep your mouths shut and do as I tell ya.
Understand?
Yeah, boss.
If I don't stand on 19,
my mind ain't on the cards.
Friend of yours, Kate.
- Take over. I've got to talk to a customer.
- Go ahead.
With Jim, I can at least
keep my eyes on the cards.
Good evening, Sheriff. Drifting?
Mmm! Got a nice, clean shave there.
I bet it was for me.
You're keeping the boys busy,
roping by day and gambling at night.
This is a free country.
They work hard for their money...
and they got a right to spend it
the way they want to.
None of my business.
Just wonderin' where some of 'em
find time to do any rustling.
Duncan's on the warpath.
Somebody's taking his branded stock.
Oh, he's just talkin'.
He's got to say that to stir up trouble.
No, there's rustling going on.
Got it from the other ranchers.
The cows I buy are clean,
unbranded mavericks.
- You ever see a range war?
- There isn't going to be a range war here.
A few rustled cattle--
A few rustled cattle started
the bloodiest killings in Texas.
- I was there.
- Oh, so that's where you hail from, Texas.
Mm-hmm.
- What brought you here?
- Passin' through.
- Oh, drifting.
- You don't like that.
A man knows where he's going.
Take a look at Jim Averell.
- There's a real man!
- I heard him say so.
Kate, you've got a couple more mavericks
in your corral than you had.
- Thanks, Hal.
- Let's have a look.
Is anything wrong with it?
No.
- Don't you ever forget that badge you're wearing?
- No.
Feelin' lucky, Hal?
No, I'd like it in cash. I'm saving.
For any particular reason?
- How'd you know?
- He means it, Kate.
Aw, honey, they all mean it!
Here. One free drink
on the house and then get out.
I need the space for the free spenders.
Since you're on duty tonight, Sheriff,
how 'bout coming out back...
and letting me show you my stuff?
It's a nice moon out tonight.
Bright enough to read a brand.
Well, there they are.
Any of them look stolen?
Nice lookin' stock.
- And mavericks every one.
- Lots of 'em too.
- Is that suspicious, doing business on a big scale?
- No.
Every one of those cows
were taken off the free range.
You don't have to spit fire at me.
My word's good enough for everybody
else, it ought to be good enough for you.
- It is.
- Then don't come with rumours of rustling and range wars.
I'm a businesswoman giving the homesteaders
their first look at cash in two years.
- I don't want trouble!
- There's trouble in the range. You'll be in it along with us.
Not if I'm playing straight
and minding my own business.
My pa minded his own business.
We had a small spread
down near Houston.
When the trouble came,
he said he'd stay out of it.
The range war "you were talking about?
I was up in the barn
when the shootin' started.
By the time I got down and ran for my rifle,
Pa was hanging on the corral fence.
Ma was dead, lying in the front yard.
- They killed my three brothers.
- Who killed them?
Folks, neighbours...
people who just got so mad
they started killin'.
- How old were you then?
- Thirteen.
Thirteen? Your whole family?
Is that when you started drifting?
Drifting's not so bad.
A man sees a lot of country.
Not anything he can call his own.
Why own something if you don't need it?
What about marriage?
Have you ever thought
about getting married?
Some. You?
Kate, need you inside.
We'll talk some more later, huh?
Someone's coming. Put that away.
We'll take care of him.
It's the sheriff. Go get Averell.
You were told not to show up
before midnight.
In this business, you show up when
"you've got the goods.
- How much did he see?
- There's no tellin'.
- Get rid of him.
- For good?
Leave him alone.
Ever since that Abilene business...
every time you get called out of a room,
I get an urge to follow you.
- Now, what's this about?
- Nothing, honey.
This drifter was interfering
in something private.
As a drifter or as the sheriff?
And what jail did you boys break out of?
Do we take him or not?
You leave him alone,
that's what you'll do!
And I hope you're thinking up a good story,
Jim, because I'm getting awfully mad.
Don't.
You'll only come apologizing later.
He's nobody to be skittish about.
Dump him where he'll have
a long walk back.
How do I know they won't kill him?
I wouldn't trust them
as far as I could throw a steer.
They do exactly as I tell them.
Get to it, men.
You like him?
No! There's no money
in that kind of maverick.
All right. Who are those men?
It seems they were running
some cattle into your corral.
- Whose cattle?
- Yours.
Anyway, your brand.
There weren't that many here
a few minutes ago!
That's what I'm trying to tell you, Kate.
Look at this.
Here's Reece Duncan's brand.
Bar-Double-Check.
Now watch. This is clever.
K-Bar-M.
Katie, somebody's apt
to call you a cattle rustler.
- Why you dirty, low-down-
- It takes money to run for office.
You'll never be Governor.
You'll be crow bait on the end of a rope.
I'm no rustler... but you are.
This is your brand,
registered in your name.
I don't share the business with you.
I gave it to you.
You're the one who's been buying and selling
cattle. How do you get out of that?
Wait till I tell Stan about this...
and Duncan!
What if they don't believe you?
Pretty big risk, isn't it?
Jim, what are you up to?
This isn't a big enough
operation for you.
I've told you, we're going to
the Governor's mansion.
It's going to take time
and a lot of money.
And meanwhile,
"you'll keep your pretty mouth shut.
When I'm playing for high stakes,
I get awfully upset if anyone talks.
Hi, Sheriff!
Maybe you can teach
Knuckles how to ride. I give up.
Come on, you stumblebum.
- Where's Kate?
- Went riding.
Come on, Knuckles! You're not going
to throw in the towel, are you?
I'll get a decision over you yet!
Hold on tight, Knuckles!
Come on, ya bum.
Hi, everybody.
You look like you came off second best.
- Third!
- Bet you brought him in, though, whoever he was.
- No, he's still kinda loose.
- But you will!
- I aim to.
- You had a lot of stock in here last night. - Some.
- How many head when we looked at them?
- Why?
How many head this morning
before you got them out in such a hurry?
Putting together that question
and that tin badge...
it looks like I'm accused
of being a rustler.
Two minutes after you left last night,
some cattle came headin' for the corral.
Driven by my boys, of course!
- Too dark to see that.
- But you did see them put cattle into my corral!
- No, I got busy.
- So you've taken such a personal dislike to me...
that without seeing anything,
without any proof...
- you're willing to believe that I'm a rustler!
- I haven't taken a dislike to ya.
Sheriff, I go by actions,
not by words...
and what I feel when you talk to me-
- Why, I just feel as homely as a mud fence!
- Homely? You're the most-
Women!
- What did he say?
- I gave him a line. He won't be any trouble.
That's why he has that job.
That's why I gave it to him.
I took one look at him when he first
came into town and I said to myself...
"That's the kind of sheriff
I need: A drifter."
I've got to hand it to you.
This time you're playing it smart, Jim.
It's nice to hear you say so...
except I know you'd like
to see me break my neck.
That would be nice.
Oh, Katie, you're just ungrateful.
Makes me very unhappy.
I don't like the way you operate.
You don't think of anyone but yourself.
What about the homesteaders
in this thing?
How long will it be before Duncan
starts taking it out on them?
- What makes you think he'd do a thing like that?
- You're hoping he will.
- Why, Kate!
- You want trouble. You want a range war.
You want so much killing that they'd
have to send troops in to keep the peace.
What an imagination!
Duncan killed, arrested,
or any way out of the running.
And the homesteaders just about wiped
out and ready to listen to anybody.
And who steps up to lead them?
- Jim Averell, the poor man's hope.
- It's a good phrase.
I don't want any part of this.
I'm getting out of here.
You can't, Kate.
How far could you get?
It won't take Duncan long
to trace his cattle to your corral...
and the sheriff to wire ahead.
They don't just arrest you
for cattle rustling.
Jim!
This act you're putting on about
not being interested in the sheriff.
- Now you're imagining things.
- I hope so.
I'm jealous, honey.
Can't get angry with me for that.
Sure, I want to be up there where
I know I belong, but I want you with me.
I'm doing all of this for you, Katie.
I'll prove that to you yet.
But these things need time.
Yes, that's what we need... time.
Get some of the boys
and fix that north line fence.
We gotta keep the herds closer in.
Jiminy! Look what's coming.
Good morning, Mr Duncan.
What brings you out in broad daylight?
I wouldn't mind sitting
in the shade for a while.
I'd like to be polite, but
I have a lot of work to do.
My business won't take long.
Not much here to interest a woman.
It's a man's place.
- Oh, that would interest a woman.
- Well, it hasn't.
No wife? No womenfolk?
- I'd have thought otherwise.
- I live alone.
Maybe that's why "you're so successful.
- Everything goes into one big ambition.
- "So far."
Miss Maxwell, you said you had
something to talk to me about.
I have: You.
I think you're making a big mistake.
No, it's your settler friends who are making
the mistake with your encouragement.
Oh, now, Mr Duncan, "you're a fair man.
Why don't you admit you started the
whole trouble by blacklisting their brands?
If you came here thinking that by
being sweet to me and nice to look at...
- I would become a more reasonable man-
- You are a reasonable man.
You've just never been
approached in the right way.
Miss Maxwell...
I came to this territory as a boy,
a ragged trail hand...
without a penny in my pocket
and my boots open at the toes.
In 10 years I owned or controlled most of this
valley. If you think I'm going to sit back now-
Don't holler at me, Mr Duncan.
If I made the mistake of thinking that
"you knew how to play for big stakes...
I apologize.
I was wrong.
- What do you mean?
- I said I was wrong.
I thought you wanted to control
more than just this valley.
Why don't you read the cards,
Mr Duncan?
Before long, the settlers
will outnumber the cattlemen.
It has to be that way.
There's nothing that can stop it.
Cooperate. Give them a chance
to earn an honest living...
and you'll be the most popular man
in the whole territory.
They'll put you in
the Governor's mansion...
not Jim Averell.
What happened, Miss Maxwell?
You have an argument with him?
Let's just say that I want
to be on the winning side.
Suppose this turns out
to be the winning side?
What's in it for you?
The winning side will be the one I tell
the settlers to throw their weight to.
And I think I'll let you
fix the reward.
You sound like
a natural-born politician.
It's all in knowing how to deal.
""Mr Duncan!"
Mr Duncan!
We caught the Jessup brothers
running off with some of our stock.
We got 'em holed up the other side
of town in Pitchfork Canyon.
You expect me to throw in
with a bunch of outlaws?
I'll give you an example
of how a man gets rich.
See that section there?
If I buy that up, I'll control six others
around it because of the water on it.
"It's all in knowing how.
- You hear shooting?
- Yeah. It's over near Duncan's place.
Let's go!
I'm out of shells, Matt.
Looks like we're gonna lose this one.
Blast 'em outta there!
Hold your fire!
Better get down. You don't want
one of your own friends to shoot you.
Drop it.
I said drop it!
You'd better learn to take orders
once in a while, Mr Duncan.
Now start moving!
Stop firin', men.
I keep underratin' you, Miss Maxwell.
I've got to stop that.
Hal! Matt!
Come out reaching!
Looks interesting.
Keep me covered.
- What's the story?
- They was rustling our cattle.
- A lie! We found mavericks.
- They're not mavericks when they're on my land.
- We didn't set foot on your land.
- He was comin' from that way.
Were those mavericks part of
Duncan's stock or weren't they?
- "Where's your proof?"
- I don't need proof.
Them Jaspers were comin' from our herd,
and I know rustling when I see it.
All you know is gunfighting. But if that's
what you want, you can have it now.
- But you'll have a dead boss.
- Simmer down, Wade.
What do you want, Miss Maxwell?
Have you still got your horses?
All right, get on 'em and hightail it.
Don't move... anyone.
What's this all about?
Why, it's Mr Averell!
Glad to see you, Mr Averell.
Miss Maxwell and I were talking
about you just a while ago.
That's nice. What did you say?
Miss Maxwell did most of the talkin';
but I can see she didn't mean a word...
saying she might tell the settlers
to throw in with me against you.
You birds stick together all the way.
I'll send this back to him.
You won't want to be seeing him again.
Evenin', boys. Myra?
We're short-handed.
What am I? A marriage bureau?
Every time I get a dancer trained,
I lose her.
You're sure going to lose this one.
You know what you're doing, Myra?
I want to see a preacher in this, Hal,
or I'm gonna get after you with a.44.
We're gettin' married as soon as
I get more maverick money.
See that you hide it from him
when he celebrates.
- Been here long?
- Settin'.
Can I "set" with you?
Set.
- What do you think?
- Nice team.
- Is there going to be trouble hereabouts?
- Mm-hmm.
- Killing?
- Can't tell.
There's something queer going on.
Got another report of
strange faces in the hills.
Got another complaint from
Duncan about losing cows.
- What'd you see him about today?
- I was trying to make peace.
- How?
- I wanted him to look at this whole thing sensibly.
He thinks he's being sensible right now.
- I thought maybe a woman's approach-
- A woman's approach?
A gun in the back?
- So you know the whole story?
- I know you didn't do peace any good today.
What did you expect me to do? Let him
shoot down the Jessup boys or hang them?
Listen, Jim Averell brought you
out here and set you up in business.
- Everything you do is tied in with him. Duncan hates Averell.
- No, you've-
When you held that gun in his back,
it was being held by Jim Averell...
who's lying to the settlers,
cattlemen, and...
- for all I know, lying to you.
- That's what I want to talk to you about.
Those men are building for a fight...
and it won't take but one wrong move
to touch it off, set the range on fire!
Will you listen to me?
I'm not Jim Averell's woman.
I choose my own man, whoever he is
or whatever he is, kingpin or drifter.
It's a little early to tell anything yet.
He's a bit low.
- Any news?
- We lost him in the dark.
- Spent the whole night combing the hills.
- It's a waste of time!
I know where to go for the bushwhacker.
Duncan or one of his boys shot my brother.
Now it's my turn.
And then it's Duncan's turn,
and whose turn after that?
It's the way feuds get started,
and there's no telling where it will end.
I believe in law and order myself, Sheriff,
but there's also a thing called justice.
And I'm dealing some out.
The law didn't appoint you to do that,
Matt. Don't make me put you in jail.
Stan, you're holding with Duncan.
The boys ain't gonna like it.
You just sit down and cool off.
Don't try to jump a gun. It never works.
Matt can always get another gun, and
Duncan always gives us another reason.
There's a war ahead, Sheriff.
You figure to stop it all by yourself?
- Not if some folks want it.
- I say wipe out Duncan and his whole outfit.
- It's the only thing that makes sense.
- "You talk too much."
It seems to me that all men
want to do is fight...
even when they talk about peace...
like you!
It's with a gun in their hands!
It's high time women took a hand
in running this world.
Duncan and his men run
the Cattle Association.
The homesteaders are mad
because he keeps them out in the cold.
Very well.
Let's form an association of our own!
Sure!
Our own outfit to do business for us!
That's for being the brainiest woman
I've ever met.
Boys, Kate just had a great idea.
It's the answer to everything. We'll form
our own stockmen's corporation.
We'll register our brands with it,
find buyers who'll deal with us.
If the courts try to stop us, we'll have
an organization to fight back with.
Jim, please. You're not a cattle raiser.
This has nothing to do with you.
Of course, this will all take money.
And it'll need leadership.
I'm going to advance you the money.
I want all you people
in this territory to know...
that Jim Averell is with you...
all the way.
Get the boys together.
Better pick your side, Sheriff.
Smartest girl I ever knew.
You make good partners,
"you and Averell.
What one thinks of
is good for the other.
I didn't want him to be part of this.
He took it out of my hands.
Played right into Duncan's.
This is what we needed for a long time.
Kramer, you and Tiny Peterson
start bringing 'em in from the north range.
O'Conners, Stubbs,
handle the west range.
Andrews, Elliot, Lamont-
Hey, Matt, you wouldn't want the men
to ride out in the sun...
without something to line their throats,
would you?
- Where's Averell?
- I don't know. He left ahead of us.
Kinda slow for a man
so anxious to help.
All right, men,
we got plenty of work ahead.
- Got it?
- Couldn't you wait?
Sure.
But not the boys.
They like to be paid as they go along.
It seems to me you go to an awful lot
of trouble just to start a shootin' war.
We could do the same thing by nightfall
by riding out and throwing a little lead.
Mm-hmm. That's why it's a good idea
for you to do exactly as I say...
no more, no less.
- Good coffee.
- Makes the best coffee in the whole dang world.
Learned it from Kate.
There's someone who can cook.
Tell him some more.
I need all the recommendations I can get.
Here comes Averell with the tally book.
Where have you been?
We've been waiting for the tally book.
The horse threw his shoe.
We had to stop at the blacksmith's.
What's the matter, Sheriff?
Don't you believe me?
Just looking at the white stuff.
What about it?
You come by way of Salt Lick Canyon.
Long way around, wasn't it?
I said, what about it?
Nothing about it. Relax.
Here comes the first bunch!
- Duncan showed up yet?
- He'll be here.
Sandy, you just standin' around?
- "I need an extra man to look for strays."
- I work for Jim Averell.
You'll work in this camp
or you don't eat.
There's no grub to spare for gunslingers.
I'll help you, Matt.
I said a man to look for strays!
Oh, I was cuttin' cattle
long before I cut cards!
Get me a horse, something alive!
Tom!
Thank you.
I wouldn't get on that critter, Kate.
It ain't safe!
Kate!
Bet she'd be real handy on a homestead.
- Round-up could be finished before Duncan shows up.
- Not likely.
Trouble is, I hold with the settlers
instead of him.
- Makes it pretty hard being sheriff.
- It'll get harder all the time.
- Duncan's not the kind who gives up.
- Maybe I am.
I didn't figure on this kind of thing
when I took this job.
I didn't figure on being Duncan's man...
running around arresting homesteaders.
Seems to me the best thing I can do
is turn in my badge and move on.
- Where would you go?
- Yonder.
Yonder! Always yonder.
That's no life for a man.
Haven't you ever thought about
sending down roots?
- Staying in one place for a while?
- Reckon so...
when I find what I want.
What do you want?
When Duncan hears how many
mavericks we rounded up...
he's gonna get a real bellyache.
Bar-VRanch, one calf.
Duncan's comin' up Loma Pass!
Get your girls into that tent,
and get in with 'em. Stay under cover.
- But I want to be out here.
- Get into the tent!
Off your horses, boys, and into place.
You know what to do.
Get every horse outta camp!
If there's any trouble,
they'll only be in the way.
Step lively, everybody!
He's on the other side of the hill.
Wade, hold the men up here.
I don't know how far you thought
"you'd go with this fool idea, Averell...
but it comes to an end right now.
Where's that sheriff?
Here's a complaint
signed by Judge Crawford...
to the effect that these men
are defying the Maverick Law.
Serve it.
Seems all regular and in order.
Well, Sheriff, I just happen to have
a Federal injunction...
enjoining these men from interfering
with this round-up...
in any manner, shape or form.
Will you serve it, please?
Looks like a stand-off.
That Jim Averell!
Did anybody ever outsmart him?
If Duncan doesn't win by brains,
he'll win another way.
Here it comes. Keep back.
That's a pretty clever trick,
Mr Averell.
I'm surprised at myself
not figurin'on that.
I've had it in my pocket
for a couple of days...
just waiting for you to show up.
Cancelling out my court order doesn't
cancel out my rights as a rancher.
You don't know of any way
to stop me from stayin' here...
- and keeping an eye peeled for my own stock?
- I wouldn't wanna stop ya.
Get a little nervous, though,
lookin' at all that artillery.
That's why we brought it here.
You won't need it here.
Pick 'em up.
Duncan, tell your boys
to drop their guns off over in Kate's wagon.
I've got an idea they wouldn't do that.
I'm tellin' ya they will.
Never had so many deputies before.
Look over there.
I've got more, but you can't see 'em.
Gentlemen, peace is declared.
What about them?
All right, everybody! Over at Kate's wagon,
and drop off your hardware.
You deputies too!
All right, men,
drop your guns in the wagon.
Hey, Duncan?
Cut out a bunch of your cows a while ago.
You want the calves branded?
I'll take that as a favour.
Where's its mother?
Got separated somehow.
- How do you know this one doesn't belong to me?
- We don't...
Half for you and half for us.
- Can you think of anything better?
- That's fair enough.
- Acts just like you when you won't listen to reason.
- Oh?
If you'd settle down
and talk things over...
- you might find there's room enough here for all of us.
- Could be.
You're the prettiest little maverick
I ever did see!
How 'bout lettin' me
put my brand on ya?
Thanks. I'm wearing one already.
You gotta get used to sudden changes.
Hey!"
Get outta here!
Stop it! Stop it!
What's the idea?
Stampede! Stampede!
Mount up and head 'em off!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Whoa! Whoa!
Duncan!
Get your men together and clear out.
We've had enough trouble here.
Nobody talks to me like that.
That's a Federal court order
talking to you like that.
You better go.
Call the men in.
Tell them I've gone back to the ranch.
- Can you finish this round-up in one more day?
- There's a chance.
Well, then, get movin'.
Well, there's the last one.
Round-up's over.
- How's the round-up?
- It's over. Your men standing by?
Yeah. When do we move?
Averell will give us the word.
Hi, Maverick.
How goes it with law and order?
- Not much change.
- There never is any change with you.
Don't you ever sing or dance,
or feel like kickin' up your heels?
Come on. Dance with me.
I wish I knew what to think about you.
If I ride off, it'll be too late.
Still talking about going away?
About ready to turn in
my badge and saddle up.
What's holding you back?
Nothin', I reckon.
I hope it turns out
to be as green as you think-
the grass on... the other side of the fence."
Hold still, everybody!
Just stay like that and
there won't be any trouble.
I'm takin' you to
the marshal at Rawlins.
- What for?
- For rustling cattle...
- and murdering my foreman, Wade Burrows.
- That's ridiculous!
- What are you trying to start here?
- Keep out of this, Averell.
I'm in this all the way,
and you better have plenty of evidence.
There's enough evidence
to hang her six times over.
Come out to the corral.
Found him out on the range
near my north section...
stretched out near a brandin'fire
with two holes in his back.
They never gave him a chance.
Wade Burrows was a troublemaker.
It just caught up with him.
- What's the connection with Kate?
- I'll show you right now.
Every time I complained to you
about losin' branded cattle...
"you'd talk about strange faces in the hills,
and rustlers nobody ever sees.
I'll show ya some rustlers.
That's my brand, the Bar-Double-Check.
When we picked up Wade,
there was a brandin'iron under him.
I reckon the killers forgot that.
Here's the iron.
And here's what it does.
K- Bar-M.
I'm takin' you in on suspicion
of rustlin' and murder.
The sheriff's office is still filled, Duncan.
Don't try to do my job.
- This woman is goin' to jail!
- "But I'll do the takin'."
I trust you, Duncan, but you got
a vigilante look in your eye.
He'd put a rope around her neck
as soon as they got out of sight.
Don't worry, honey.
I'll get you the best...
legal representation in
the territory of Wyoming.
By the time these charges are heard...
Mr Duncan'll have to eat a lot of words.
- Am I right, boys?
- "You bet."
Your deputies must be tired
after the round-up...
so I know you'll be glad
if I post some of my men at the jail...
to see she doesn't get away.
There'll be more in jail when I found out
which of ya have been takin' orders from her.
You haven't said a word
for the last 15 minutes.
You used to find it easy to talk.
Why not now?
Talking to you never helped me before.
What's the truth, Kate?
Is Averell playin' you,
or are you both playin' me?
Things were bad enough in this town
before you came. They're twice as bad now.
You think I'm a murderer and a rustler?
I don't know what to think.
What's between you and Averell?
Too much.
Keep your eyes peeled for trouble.
Want these gents barbecued
or slow-fried?
Don't get the idea
"you're deputies, boys.
Anything happens to her,
"you'll pay for it.
You might as well catch 40 winks.
- Tomorrow could be a big day.
- I'll stay here.
- You can't help her. She's locked up.
- I'll stay here!
Kinda wondered why he wasn't around.
I wouldn't put it past Reece Duncan...
to kill one of his own men
and pin it on us.
What his second move will be,
I can only guess.
L-I'm too busy thinking about Kate...
sitting over in that jail.
Seems to me we got nothing to go
on but her own word that she's innocent.
- We brought in 300 unbranded mavericks...
- How did it work?
Fine. She was so surprised
she couldn't say a word.
Go back and tell 'em to get set.
You'll see the signal as soon
as it's light enough to see smoke.
There isn't much hay over there.
You'd better drag over another bale.
Go on.
I say Kate had nothin' to do with it.
She's innocent as a newborn babe!
All right. If nobody'll back me up
to bust her outta that jail...
- I'll do it myself.
- I don't think you'll have time.
Boys, I just got some pretty bad news.
Sandy tells me Duncan's calling in
every man he's got.
He's getting set for a fight,
and he'll find a good reason to start one.
I'm going out there
and try and talk him out of it.
- I never heard of Duncan bein' talked out of anything.
- Maybe so.
At least it'll give you men a chance
to get organized for a battle.
See that nothin' happens to her.
As miserable a collection of faces
as ever I seen off a reward poster.
What kind of records did you gents have
before you went to work for Duncan?
Smart aleck! Don't pay him no heed.
All right, men! Come and get it!
That's real cordial, but kinda sudden.
See who's outside.
How do you like that?
They got suspicions.
I've got a good mind
to spill this stuff on the floor.
Quiet outside, but I'm kinda dry inside.
Gimme some of that!
Just a minute.
I kinda changed my mind about you fellas.
- Gimme some of that beer, sonny.
- Sonny?
I'm gonna like this!
Nice work, Knuckles. Pick him up.
You got me covered.
Hey, ain't this somethin'? Ajailbreak!
We're bustin' ya outta here.
- Who organized it?
- We did. The sheriff's outta town.
Jim's ridin' up to Duncan's ranch.
Jim found out Duncan's gettin' ready
for a fight. He's gonna try and stop him.
- Don't you believe it!
- In ya go!
He doesn't want to stop a war.
He wants to start one.
Boys, I think it's about time
"you knew the truth.
I've been covering up
for Jim Averell in one of...
the slickest rustling schemes
Wyoming ever saw.
And the idea back of the whole thing
is to start you...
and the big cattle raisers
to killing each other off.
I told you she mightn't be innocent.
You didn't finish.
We're still listenin'.
Jim's got a bunch of gunslingers
up in the hills.
And one of them, or Sandy, killed Wade
Burrows to pin the whole thing on me...
and start this big range war
that he wants.
He sure did pin it on ya. How many times
that brandin' iron been used?
I don't know, but the important thing is
he wants to start a range war.
Boys, I know Jim Averell and you don't.
He wants to be Governor.
He doesn't care how many people he
walks over to get to the Governor's chair...
or how many he kills to stay there.
I don't believe anything she says,
good or bad.
- Shut up!
- Boys, you've got to believe me.
He's got this whole thing worked out!
- What's he doing at Duncan's?
- Duncan's as big a sucker as any of us.
Jim made him want to fight,
and he's gone up there to push him into it.
I wish somebody would get over
to that case of rifles...
and start protecting me
from what's coming.
- What do you want?
- I'll talk to you inside.
If you came here to talk for Kate Maxwell,
"you're wastin' your time.
Kate doesn't need anybody
to talk for her.
- She's probably out of jail by now.
- I don't think so.
- I left five of my men there.
- Hope they're alive.
Duncan, the settlers are talking fight.
They're gonna end this
by wiping you out.
Wantin' to won't make it easy.
I'd hate to be around
when she sends them out here.
They'll smoke you and your men out,
and knock you over like rabbits.
Maybe, unless I crack down on them first
with a few ideas of my own.
Ned!
- Call the men in.
- Right.
I suppose your story's pretty straight,
Mr Averell.
- Now I'd like to know how straight you are.
- Use your head.
Why are we fighting each other?
Neither of us really have
anything in common with these settlers.
We live in a different world.
We live a different life.
When the chips are down,
whose side do you think I'll be on?
Theirs or ours?
You're a real high-minded citizen
to be looking for the governorship.
- I'm for Jim Averell.
- I see that.
- So after all your big talk, "you're double-crossin' 'em.
- That's not a nice word.
How do I know you're not
double-crossin' me?
You don't. It's a big chance, isn't it?
Which reminds me.
While we're here talking...
- we're giving them more time to get organized.
- That time's about up.
They want a fight,
I'll bring it to them.
You're comin' along, Mr Averell.
If anything goes wrong,
I'll have you right under my guns.
Ned, get all the hands in from the range.
Saddle up. We're ridin'.
- All set.
- All right. Come on.
Get on the horses, boys. Let's go.
- If you try to stop me now, Sheriff-
- I'm not gonna stop ya.
I'm gonna join ya like Averell's done.
How have you managed to keep
"your outlaw friends under cover so long?
- What outlaws?
- Wanna tell him?
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- The outlaws working for him.
- The ones that killed your foreman and stole your cattle.
- That's a lie!
- If it isn't Averell-
- No use arguing now.
We'll find out.
If there's going to be a fight with Duncan's men,
we know we're going into it with clean hands.
But let's keep it clean all the way.
The first shot must come from him.
And if it does, well,
"you boys know how to fight back.
- Here they come!
- Now, remember:
Duncan's boys must be
the first to start.
Duncan, you've got about a minute
to make up your mind.
Throw in with the settlers,
and I think we can prove our friend here...
has been double-crossing
every one of us.
Start battlin', and the outlaws
will wipe out the town.
Seems to me a man of your position,
with all you have at stake...
isn't going to let your thinking be done
for you by a $50-a-month sheriff...
a saddle bum who rode
in here from nowhere.
What's your play, Sheriff?
You didn't spend much time in jail.
Couldn't afford it. Too many chores.
"Glad everybody's in good humour.
- What's it going to be, Stan?
- We're gonna have a party.
A mite different from
the one Mr Averell planned on...
but he's gonna be the host.
- Get off.
- What for?
The man spoke to ya.
Some odd characters in the hills are waiting
for him to tell them we're killing each other.
All right, tell them.
I don't know what you mean.
The smoke signal, Mr Averell.
You're supposed to light that stack of hay as
soon as we start throwin' lead at each other.
Then they come riding in
to take over the town.
- "Light it."
- The wind'll sweep the fire into every building in town.
Hal, get over in the hotel
and keep a bead on him.
If he tries to move anywhere...
- "let him have it."
- Right.
Now light it.
Light it, Jim!
Let's draw 'em in close, boys.
- Let 'em think we're in a free-for-all, and make it good!
-
What are we waitin' for?
All right. Come on!
Rise and shine, Governor!
- Listen to that battle.
- This is where we split up.
Let's ride!
I left five men guardin' you.
Nobody hurt them.
Their pride maybe, but that's all.
You think I'm crooked and no-account.
You'd put more trust in a lead dollar.
- Who killed Wade Burrows?
- Do you think if I had anything to do with that...
I'd have left that branding iron under him
like a signed confession?
Now you're saying that
Averell tried to frame you.
Why should he? You're working together.
If I talk from now till Christmas,
"you'd still only believe what you want.
All right, go ahead.
Believe what you want.
- But make up your mind quickly. There's a fight comin' on.
- ""
You ain't playin' fair, Jim.
You left us no chance for fun.
They're partners, all right!
- I kept trying not to believe it.
- Well?
I've been with ya
since we rode into town.
You-You boys better put up your guns.
- Why?
- Well, I, uh-l-
Well, look here!
Captured ourselves a sheriff!
You boys had a nice little scheme.
Don't talk! Don't shoot! It's a trap.
Not the kind of scheme that'd give
anybody a chance, but I'm givin' you one:
A fair trial if you drop your guns.
- We're covered.
- That's it, boys.
There's a bead on every one of ya.
Let's go!
Get that guy in the hotel window.
He's got me pinned down.
You stay inside!
Jim, grab on!
Leaving?
Pointing a gun at me again, Kate?
I ought to kill you,
but I'd rather see you hang.
- Now, Kate!
- You lying, sneaking, murdering-
They'll be piling in here in a minute, Kate.
You gotta let me go.
Why? For what you've done to me?
For what I used to mean to you.
That was an idea I had.
But you were never like the idea.
Well, uh, the good times we had.
We had good times.
Think about them, Kate.
What are you gonna gain if I die?
You'll never see me again!
You got Stan Blaine, and-
Did I kill him, Kate,
when I had a chance?
When you asked me not to,
Kate, did I kill him?
There's another reason
"you gotta let me go.
Look, Kate. Look at this.
How can I believe anything you've said?
The last time-
- Let's listen to him, boys.
- Thank you.
I think we can
give credit for this to...
Cattle Kate! I've come to realize...
that I've got to consider
"your interests as well as mine.
If you want to make a friend of me,
think of my interests as well as yours.
"The West is gettin'smaller, friends, and I
reckon we've gotta learn to live together.
Now, I'm not the kind of man that'll throw
away the things that I worked hard for.
- Who gave you that?
- He did.
- Where is he?
- Saddling up.
Where to, Maverick?
Could be California,
maybe Oregon Territory.
- Do you still think I was Jim Averell's woman?
- That's how it looked.
Because I cried?
Sure, I cried, but not because I love Jim.
I cried because when I found you
I realized I was all the things...
I never wanted to be, and because-
Oh, what do you know about women
or the way they feel?
There's a piece of bottom land
a few miles down.
Good for homesteadin'.
Let's have a look at it.
Tantico