Okay Pop, hello buddy.
Hello lions. What are you doin'?
What's that rogue,
Togar doin' here?
God Togar, why
today of all days?
Okay, come on. Let's play chase.
The closer we
get, more excited I get.
It should be great seeing him
after three years.
Yeah, I
couldn't believe how fast
he split for Africa
after he got his grants.
And the zoo let him take
the little cubs he raised.
You'd think he'd
take the kids he raised.
Well he
was going to send for us,
but he said it
was too dangerous.
He certainly didn't leave
because he didn't love us.
And you know how
depressed he used to get
with his cats kept in
cages all the time.
I wonder where he is.
Why don't we try to
find our own way there?
You're joking.
Where could he be?
Boy you guys wait 'til my
family gets here tonight.
Are they gonna love you.
Oops, sorry Hank.
And I thought you
came to help me.
I did.
I came to speak for you
with that committee,
and take you to
pick up your family.
Well come on ashore a while.
Are you crazy?
The committee is on their
way here to renew your grant.
Monster.
Come on, you gotta
help me clean the house.
Mmm, not today;
today doesn't seem like
a good day to come in.
Hey where are you going?
Not my jacket!
Throw it here.
Come on over here.
Stay
there. How's she doing?
Look.
This is a madhouse.
No it isn't. It's
just like life.
You get the funny
with the tragic.
It's just with them you get
the gentle and
the ferocious too.
Be careful of the bad,
and enjoy the good.
You aren't careful enough.
Well for my
studies I have to get
as close to them as possible.
You know, actually, the
closer you get to them,
the more they'd like you
and the safer you'd be.
But look! He's
going to jump on us.
No no no no,
they're just playing.
They like to play the
old cat and mouse game.
Here I'll cover ya.
Oh big John.
No, if you just look at
'em, or you run at em.
No look.
What? Oh ah ah ah ah,
you leave him alone.
Oh that's Johnny Lion, you
never have to worry about John.
Are you scaring him?
You know you gotta
watch out for Mark.
No, he's okay. This is Charlie.
And you gotta watch
out for Barry, okay?
It's just playing
I'm tellin' ya.
But you could get killed.
The cats got a little
excited, that's all.
Are you
okay? You're crazy.
Oh Mativo, there's Robbie.
You've never met Robbie.
He's always out
guarding his borders
in the daytime,
and you're always
too afraid to come
and visit me at night.
Now he's the nicest
cat in the world.
And he's also the top cat here.
Yeah. He's the boss.
I work for him.
Hey Rob,
Well come here. I want
you to meet Mativo.
See actually it's Robby
I'm worried about.
Their whole life is
based on dominance.
That's why we have such
a great harmony here,
because Robbie is such a
gentle and loving ruler.
He also knows he has to protect
the others from outsiders.
Right now he's very
worried about Togar.
He's also worried that if the
others see that he's worried
or afraid, that then they'll
start challenging him
like they've been
each other all day.
No matter how afraid
he is at this moment,
he still knows he has
to see this through.
The whole meaning of his
life is before him, Mativo.
That's why you have to help me.
I have to what? Why?
Because I have to
help him, Mativo.
And he could get killed.
Don't worry, I'm gonna help ya.
I don't think you
should count on me.
But Only yesterday
they were so happy.
Now look at them.
Finally on the verge
of finding paradise,
and the only thing
lacking is my family
to share it with me.
And Togar comes in wrecking it.
Here comes trouble.
It's a grand committee,
but Prentiss is with them.
Listen my friend, let me talk.
Good morning everybody.
I would like to
open this meeting
by reminding you all that
Hank's original idea
was a comparative study
of the great cats of the wild.
And while observing
the African cats
in their natural habitat,
he will raise several cats
of each species.
Be they African or otherwise.
And to become almost like
a member of the pride.
Hey it has stripes! It must
be another Tigon or a Liger.
The mother's a lioness,
the father must be a tiger.
Say hello to Henry
the Jaguar, would ya?
Not today.
What are you trying to prove?
That you can have lions
socializing with people?
No, but we can't keep
exterminating them.
We can't keep
eliminating their land.
exterminating everything
that we fear, or that
inconveniences us.
Let the zoos keep them alive.
Prentiss, your actions
aren't necessary.
The government knows
there's a better way.
They're moving the people out of
the migration paths.
I don't know what kind of person
could look in the
eyes of 200 elephants
and put out those lights.
They run frantically in panic
trying to protect
their children--
Do you think your lions
would run and panic?
You better start with me first.
No I'll start with
the tigers first.
That'll teach you for
bringing them to Africa.
I gotta go help your uncles;
they're killing each other.
Stop it! Stop It! Hey! Hey!
Calm down!
Togar!
Togar! Togar!
You stay out of it. You let
Robbie take care of him.
Yeah, you guys are smart;
you stayed out of it.
Oh Craig, hi Tommy, Jimmy.
Oh aw. You hide in here?
I don't blame you, all
those guys are fighting.
Over the
side! This way! Git!
That's my jacket.
Help!
Hank!
Hank get out here!
Hank! Hank!
Get him off me!
Run!
Woah hey.
Come on, go in the house
and get some bandages.
Oh what the hell's
wrong with you?
All you got's a few scratches.
You're lucky Togar
didn't getcha.
I think you should take our bus.
It goes right by there.
Oh no, well I
think we should wait.
No; if you wait until
tonight, and it doesn't come,
there is no other
bus for two days.
And there is no place
for you to stay here.
Well what'll we do?
Will he know where to take us?
Oh come on. I'll
tell him for you.
Hey, she's dry.
Alice has no milk.
Listen, I have to go change.
I'll go back to my boat.
Okay.
Maybe I'll come with you.
If he claws ya--
What do I do now?
just stand up to
them, don't let them
get away with anything.
You gotta let 'em see
how strong you are.
Come on lions. We have to
clean the house for Madelaine.
Come on lions.
Come on Diane. Come on Michael.
Come on Patrick.
Are you sure there aren't
any more big ones in here?
Well hello Gary.
Why didn't you go with your--
Why didn't you go
with your friends?
Come on, you should
go with your friends.
Aw come on.
You really changed this place.
New curtains, new
drapes, new everything.
Come on, go with your friends.
Come on. Oh yes.
You have to go
with your friends.
Come on.
Aw don't worry Davie.
Robbie can handle Togar.
Your father's tougher
than you think.
Come on.
Oh come on, you'll hurt my hand.
See I got a hand hurt.
Come on. Come on Davie.
I think I drove Togar as
far away as 200 miles.
This is the first
time he's come in.
I have a hunch that
Robbie and Togar
could be brothers.
You know Bugsy and Robbie
were both rogue lions.
I found them dying
from battle wounds.
Now if Togar were sick or dying,
these guys'd
probably accept him.
But the way he is now, --
Vicious alright.
Well he can't help that.
As a loner he's too slow to
catch his normal dinners.
And the hungrier he gets,
the more desperate he gets.
The more desperate he gets,
the more ferocious he gets,
because the only way he
can eat most of the time
is by taking his meals
from whole prides of lions.
You gotta be pretty
ferocious to do that.
Sooner or later, he's
gonna get killed.
Come on Gary.
Billy.
Hey, don't try to frighten me.
Leave that alone!
That's my jacket!
Hey Hank, come and help me.
He's got my jacket!
Gimme that Jacket.
That's my jacket!
Hank!
Hank! Help!
Help! Help!
Get back. Come on.
You leave him alone.
Leave him alone.
Hey! Leave him alone.
They almost killed me.
You know you're
not supposed to run.
My head knew it,
but my feet didn't.
Oh. Hi babe. Oh.
Put them out.
They're trying to
stay away from Togar.
Come on.
Why do they have to be in here?
Why this open door
policy you have here
anyway with them?
All the doors are closed except
for here and the bathroom.
There's nothing they can
tear up here or the bathroom.
Put them out.
Mativo this is their home!
What do you think
you're running?
A country club for lions?
Come on, sit down here.
Sit down. You're okay. Oh.
Sit down. You're okay, sit down.
Hey no more fighting.
Come here.
Aww. Sit down. You're okay.
Poor David You are okay.
You are okay.
These stupid lions
are frightening me.
And you want to bring Madelaine
and the children into this?
This'll be great for 'em.
Not boxed in like
back in Chicago.
Hey, wait a minute.
I just thought he had
a cataract starting.
That's Billy. He's great.
They're right. You be on something.
I couldn't last a day.
Expect her to sleep
with the lions are you?
What do you care if
I sleep with my wife?
Mom, did you know that a man
can have as many wives
as he wants to here?
And what is that
supposed to mean?
I mean how could
you be away from dad
for so long?
You know that your father
and I were having problems,
and we thought it would be
better to be apart for a while.
You know, absence makes
the heart grow fonder?
The heart maybe, but what about
the sex glands?
Sex is all you think
about lately young lady.
You'd better watch it,
or you're gonna get
your little tail in trouble.
Some day I hope you'll
understand the beauty
of restraint and self-denial.
Well I hope it wasn't
restraint and self-denial
that drove dad away.
- Hey Mativo.
- Yeah?
You know what my kids used to do
every time I started to sing?
They'd hold their hands over
their ears and say, oh no.
Or they'd turn on the radio.
Hey, hey, don't
let them in the boat.
You're crazy.
I think he said
it's just over the hill.
I can't steer!
I think we are sinking.
Abandon ship!
Hey Mativo. Hey Mativo,
climb out over that way.
Don't swim, they'll get you.
Mom, come here and look.
It's fantastic.
Dad?
Dad.
Hey dad.
Dad?
Hank?
Hello?
Dad?
We're here.
Oh dear.
Hey dad.
Hank?
This is really a nice place.
Come on up.
This place is really wild.
I'd give
anything for some sleep.
I don't understand.
Is that a tarantula?
Huh? You simple minded jerk!
Stop that!
Look.
Oh my god.
Where could he be?
Jerry, run and
open all the windows.
Then we'll dust everything
and surprise your father.
Melanie?
Hey a motorcycle.
I just saw a
thing. I think it was a pelican.
It's a Kawasaki.
Holy mackerel! Look at that!
I don't believe what I'm seeing.
Those can't be Dad's lions.
Oh god. Look
what the cat dragged in.
Melanie?
Mom.
Get in here. Get in here.
Jerry. John!
Where's mom and Mel?
They're downstairs. Come on.
What is going on down there?
Let's go down.
Woah!
Woah Uh!
Go back.
Boy have we got troubles.
Where'd they all come from?
Nice lion.
Oh no!
Oh no, oh no, oh no.
Help? Uhh.
Woah!
Melanie? Are you alright?
Yeah but I'm scared, Mom.
Oh I know honey, so am I.
Oh honey stay here.
I'll go get the boys.
Hey. Hello.
John?
I'm in here.
John are you alright?
Where's Jerry?
Help! Help!
Jerry. Jerry?
Oh god!
Are you alright?
You coulda suffocated!
You coulda died dummy!
Shut
up. I almost died.
What kinda jerk
would hide himself in an icebox?
Okay?
Yeah.
Get me outta here!
Help! Mom! John! Jerry!
In here.
Jerry hurry.
Right here!
Come on.
One, two, three.
Maybe there's some
guns 'round here.
We gotta find a gun.
I think we ought
to split while we can.
Yeah sure with 8,000
lions and tigers outside.
Well if we stay here, we'll
end up being eaten alive.
We're not gonna get eaten.
When Dad gets here, he'll
show us how to handle them.
Until then, we'll just
board up the windows.
Wait a minute.
Who voted you in?
I did. I suppose you
wanna make a run for it?
Right on. I'll take the
motorcycle and go get help.
I know bikes, and I know
the road we came in on.
That's not gonna help;
that's letting you escape,
and leaving us here.
- John! Shoot 'em!
- No!
Give me your handkerchief John.
I wanna go home.
Madelaine's gonna kill me.
It'll go much faster
if you go up there
and borrow some bicycles.
Okay.
I'll take the tigers.
I'll go 'round back
of the village.
Good move.
Don't tell
me, he said, you said.
I'm not interested
in your bickering.
Who asked you to go over there?
I can go on
any property to kill animals
that I deem are a
danger to human lives.
Don't tell me
you care about his family.
I'm telling you there'll be
no culling of cats, elephants,
or any animals ever again.
Well you should
have been at his madhouse
and seen those
cats this morning.
I don't care what you say.
You are not going to go out
there and slaughter his animals.
We cull elephants
if there are too many.
Prentiss, you're
completely out of line.
You are not going
to kill those cats.
You can tell me
what you're gonna do.
And you can tell
me what the rest of
this committee's gonna do, Rick.
But I'll be damned if
you're gonna tell me
what I'm gonna do.
We can't store two tigers.
Well I tried
to make them go home.
How come they are not doing
what you are telling them.
Well they're not trained pets.
They're just friends.
Stay off my back.
Come on. Where are you going?
Come on down.
You go. I'm not going.
You know, you're right.
I can't go to the
airport with them.
They'll go right in with me.
Hey I got an idea for ya.
Hang down off that branch.
- Huh?
- Let your feet
hang down here.
- What?
- Kick your feet.
They'll jump right
up and try to getcha.
Then they'll stay here.
I can sneak away.
No, no. I'm not doing that.
- Listen.
- Uh huh?
Take your shirt off, okay?
And dangle it down.
Hold it by the sleeve.
There you go.
Hurry back!
Why did you bring us here.
We're just gonna die.
No we are not going to die.
Your father is going
to be here soon.
And it'll be all over.
Well why isn't he here now?
He knew we were coming!
You can belly-ache all you
want about him staying away.
But if he's not here
it's because he's dead.
And he's not coming. I know it.
Boy I've been ready to do this
for a long time.
Don't you think we should wait?
We shouldn't load
anything smaller
than a .30-06 for a lion.
Lenny?
Aw Leonard, Leonard, Leonard.
Okay.
Okay, okay.
Come on. Put your
bike in the trunk.
They must be in
the house already.
They took the bus yesterday.
Nikki, get in the car.
Come on. Get in the back.
Come on Greg, get in with us.
Come on Greg.
That's a good boy.
Turn around.
He is trying to
close me in the trunk!
Hey come on, get in.
Hey, well come on. Get in.
Crazy. With them in the back?
They'll bite my head off.
Either get in or
walk, 'cause I'm goin'.
Make them walk.
This is madness.
If somebody sees them
this far from my place
They'll shoot 'em.
These are your friends huh?
And do you know
what your friends
are probably doing to
your family right now?
They are making dinner of them.
They are eating them.
Tivo, shut up.
They are sitting
around eating them,
cracking their bones.
Shut up.
They are licking
their bones clean.
Shut up!
Who are you?
Come on.
Hey! Don't go so fast.
It's too bumpy.
I have to Mativo.
By the way, do they know
that they should not run?
You should have sent them a list
of rules and regulations
before they came.
Aw. Poor Leonard.
Let's get out of here.
Only Melanie was right.
Let's go take the boat.
Jerry okay, you go
first. Go ahead.
Woah. Melanie.
Oh there's a tiger!
Faster!
Go John!
John. John!
John, jump out!
Jerry! You're going
the wrong way!
Go John! Go!
Melanie get in the boat.
Going right into shore.
Jerry watch out.
Go back this way.
Come on, sport.
Boy that was close.
Get away!
Get away from me!
Put her down!
Help me! Help me!
Let go of her!
Help! Help! Help!
Help me!
Aw less then ten
miles to go and we're stuck.
What's wrong?
The jack won't work in the sand.
And the more I dig, the
more the car slides.
I'll have to run.
But you know you're
not supposed to run.
You hold the tigers
back, would ya?
- So they don't tackle me.
- What?
Just use this. Use this.
Use this. Go like that.
Hey Prentiss, did you see that?
Got 'em right through the neck.
- Sooner or later--
- If we're not--
the lions are gonna get us.
he'll be back.
- I'm gonna go for help.
- Why stay here?
Now let's make sure
that all the other doors
in the house are secure.
I hate this place here!
I don't think there's
a good decision.
- John?
- Hey!
I'm gonna get help!
And leave us here?
I'm gonna get help.
I thought it was suicide!
Good luck, son.
Oh no!
Ow. Get out of here.
Open the door. Come on.
Go on. Get out of
here. Leave it!
Go on. Leave it.
Jerry open the door. Come on.
You think I'm crazy?
What kind of jerk
would go off the
roof on a motorcycle?
Get off of her!
Ugh heavy.
No!
Melanie. John, Jerry!
Where are you?
John! Jerry! Hurry!
Melanie! Get up.
No no no!
What's wrong?
Hey what are
you doin' on the floor?
John I can't get my
leg out! Ow ow ow ow!
Come on, hurry.
Get out. I'll hold 'em.
I'll hold 'em.
Melanie come here.
Oh.
Oh my goodness.
Jerry help your sister.
He's just tryin' to kiss her.
Still trying to open the door.
You think
we have enough ammunition?
I've got twenty in this belt,
and thirty in the other.
Remember where all the cheetahs,
leopards, and tigers drop.
We skin them on the way back.
The lions are worthless.
Leave them for the hyenas.
No! Get away.
Go on! Go on! Go!
No!
Come on!
Hey mom, up on the roof!
Mom go over the track!
Come on mom.
See ma? It's another
house. It's completely safe.
It's a good thing,
because I can't
walk another step.
I'm so tired my legs
are gonna buckle under me.
I just have to
sleep for a while.
Oh Donnie Lion!
Come on my friend. Get up.
Let's run again.
Togar! Hey! Ahh!
Togar not that way!
Oh you poor stupid jerks.
Let's try to get 'em outside.
I don't think they're
tryin' to hurt us at all.
Come on. Come on lion.
Come
on lion. Come on.
- Come on. Come on.
- Yeah, faster.
Come on.
Melanie, John,
get away from those lions.
Mom, if they wanted to get us,
they would have done it
while we were asleep.
Come on.
Are you sure it's alright?
Make sure
the mother isn't around.
They're cute.
Oh look at!
You're really friendly.
Oh she's beautiful, isn't she?
John.
Oh look at.
You're really friendly.
Oh she's beautiful isn't she?
Togar! Togar! Togar!
Madelaine!
John.
Hello lion.
Togar! Togar!
Togar! Togar! Madelaine!
Oh hello lions.
Yeah you guys stay
away from Robbie.
Hey kids how are ya?
Oh oh. Woah!
I better go help your ma.
Hey Lynn, get off.
Come on, get up.
Don't hit her Jerry, hug her.
She wants you to hold her.
Are you okay?
I'm just so happy you're here.
You're okay. Don't worry.
Don't worry?
Look at her.
Oh I sure love ya.
Oh I love you too.
Hey. Come on.
Go away. Get away.
Hi little gal.
Listen, don't say anything
about Prentiss, okay?
But he was killing your lions.
I don't want you to say
anything about that either.
Don't spoil the reunion.
I'll tell them later.
Listen I want you
to meet my family.
This is my wife Madelaine.
- Hello Madelaine.
- Mativo.
This is my son, John.
Hello how are you?
Hello, nice to meet you.
This is my daughter, Melanie.
Melanie, Mativo.
- Melanie, how are you?
- Hello.
My son Jerry.
Jerry huh.
Come on this way. I
have a surprise for you.
Boy are we glad to see you.
What are y'all
doin' wearin' my clothes?
Oh no. What happened?
Jerry, get back. Form a line.
They all want to meet you.
We've already met 'em.
Isn't this fantastic?
What do you think?
You guys gonna stay a while?
Sure dad.
I don't have to be back
to Chicago 'til next week.