There's a fire in the
sky in the morning
when the Sun is a
crimson dawning..
And the earth is glowing
like a burning ember.
Who's land is this?
This is my land.
See the shadow of
the eagle in the sunrise
hear the music of the children
in the moon rise
feel the power of the lion
when he roars like thunder
calling who's land is this?
This is my land.
Who's land is this?
Okay Pat, hello girl..
O my, what are you doing?
What's that rogue
Togar doing here?
God Togar, why today of all days.
Okay, come on let's play chase.
The closer we get,
the more excited I get.
It should be great
to see him after three years.
Yeah, I couldn't believe how fast he
split for Africa after he got his grant.
And the zoo let him take
the little cubs he raised.
You'd think he'd
take the kids he raised!
Well he was going to send for us
but he said it was too dangerous.
He certainly didn't leave
because he didn't love us.
You know how
depressed he used to get..
with his cats being kept
in cages all the time.
- I wonder where he is..
- Why don't we find our own way there?
- You're joking!
- Where could he be?
Why, you guys wait till my family get
here tonight. Are they gonna love you!
- Sorry Hank.
- And I thought you came to help me.
I did. I come to speak for
you with that committee..
And take you to pick up your family.
Well, come on shore awhile.
Are you crazy? The committee is on
their way here to review your grant.
Monster..
Come on. You gotta
help me clean the house.
Not today! Today doesn't
seem like a good date coming.
Hey, where you going?
Not my jacket!
Throw it here!
Come on over here.
- Stay there.
- How's she's doing?
This is a madhouse.
No, it's just like life you
get the funny with the tragic.
Just with them you get the
gentle and the ferocious too.
Be careful of the bad
and enjoy the good.
You aren't careful enough.
For my studies I have to get
as close to them as possible.
No actually,
the closer you get to them
the more they like you,
the safer you'd be.
- But look, it's going to jump on us!
- Oh no no no..
They're just playing...
They like to play the
cat and mouse game.
Here, I'll cover you
O, big Joe...
No, if you just look at them...
- Or you run at them, roar
- O god... no look
What?
Na-aah-ah, you leave him alone!
Oh, that's Johnny lion.
You never have to worry about John.
Are you scaring him?
You know you're gotta
watch out for Mark...
No, he's okay.
This is Charlie.
Whoa.
And you gotta watch out
for Barry, okay?
- It's just playing, I'm tellin' ya!
- But you could get killed!
The cats got a little
excited, that's all.
[Mativo] Are you okay?
You're crazy!
Oh Mativo, there's Robbie.
You've never met Robbie...
He's always out guarding
his borders in the daytime.
And you're always too afraid to
come and visit me at night...
You know, he is the
nicest cat in the world.
And he's also the top cat here.
No, he's the boss,
I work for him.
Hey Rob, Wauw Wauw..
Well come here.
I want you to meet Mativo.
See, actually it's Robbie
I'm worried about...
Their whole life is eh...
based on dominance...
That why we have such a
great harmony here.
Because Robbie is such
a gentle and loving ruler.
He also knows he has to
protect the others from outsiders...
Right now he's very
worried about Togar.
He's also worried that if the others
see that he's worried or afraid...
That then they start challenging him,
like they've been each other all day.
No matter how afraid
he is at this moment...
He still knows he has
to see this through.
The whole meaning of
life is before him, Mativo.
- That's why you have to help me.
- Help what?
- Why?
- Because I have to help him, Mativo.
And he could get killed!
Don't worry, I'm
gonna help you.
I .. I don't think you
should count on me...
But only yesterday they
were so happy.
Now look at them.
Finally on the verge
of finding paradise
And the only thing
lacking is my family...
To share it with me and
Togar comes in and wrecking it!
Here comes trouble.
It's the grand committee.
But Prentis is with them.
Listen' my friend,
let me talk for you.
Good morning everybody
I like to open this meeting
by reminding you all...
That eh... Hank's
original idea...
Was a comparative study of
the great cats of the world.
And while preserving
the African cats...
In their natural habitat,
he would raise several cats...
..of each species.
Be they African or otherwise.
And to become almost
like a member of the pride.
Hey it has stripes. It must be
another tiger or a liger.
The mother is a lioness
the father must be a tiger.
Say hello to Henry
the jaguar would ya?
Not today!
What are you trying to prove, that you
can have lions socializing with people?
No, but we can't keep
exterminating them.
We can't keep eliminating their land.
We can't keep exterminating everything
that we fear or that inconveniences us.
Let the Zoos keep them alive.
Prentis, your actions aren't necessary.
The government knows
there's a better way.
They're moving the people
out of the migration paths.
I don't know what kind of person
could look in the eyes at 200 elephants
And put out those lights ...
They'd run franticly and panic...
Do you think your
lions would run in panic?
Well, you'd better start with me first.
No, I'll start with
the tigers first...
That'll teach you for
bringing them to Africa!
I gotta go help your uncle's
they are killing each other.
Stop It..
Stop It!!
Togar!
Togar!!
You stay out of it, you
let Robbie take care of him.
Yeah, you guys are smart,
you stay out of it.
Oh great..
Hey Tommy, Jimmy
Oh you all hiding here
Oh I don't blame ya.
All those those guys are fighting.
That's my Jacket!
Hank!
Come on go in the house
and get some bandages.
No!!
Oh what the hell's wrong with
you, all you got's a few scratches.
You're lucky I told
her, I didn't get ya.
I think you should take a bus.
It goes right by there..
Oh no, I think we should wait.
No, if you wait until tonight
and he doesn't come...
There's no other bus for 2 days and
there's no place for you to stay here.
- Oh what do we do?
- Will he know where to take us?
Hey, she's dry.
Alice has no milk.
Listen, I have to go change.
- I'll go wait in my boat
- okay
Oh. Maybe I come with you?
- What we do now?
- Just stand up to them.
Don't let them get
away with anything...
You gotta let them see
how strong you are...
Come on lions we have to clean
the house of Madelaine.
Come on lions
Come on Diane come on, go.
Come on Patrick..
Are you sure there aren't
anymore big ones in here?
Well, hello Gary.
Whoa, why didn't you go with ... (roar)
Why didn't you go with your friends?
Come on, you should
go with your friends...
Oh, come on.
You really changed this place.
New curtains, new drapes..
New everything!
Come on go with your friends.
Wauw, come on.
Oh yes, ???
Goodbye.
Come on..
Why, don't worry baby,
Robbie can handle Togar.
Your father is
tougher than you think!
Wauw.. Oh come on
you're hurt my hand.
See, my hand hurt.
Come on!
Come on baby.
Wauw!
I've seen that rogue Togar
as far away as 200 miles.
This is the first time he's come in.
I have a hunch that Robbie
and Togar could be brothers.
You know Bugsy and
Robbie we're both rogue lions.
I found them dying
from battle wounds
Now if Togar were sick or dying...
These guys would probably except him
- But the way he is now...
- ??? arrived.
But he can't help that. As a loner
he's too slow to catch his normal diner.
And the hungrier he gets,
the more desperate he'll get.
And the more desperate he gets,
the more ferocious he gets.
Because the only way he
can eat most of the time...
Is by taking his meals
from whole prides alliance.
You've got to be pretty
ferocious to do that!
Sooner or later he's gonna get killed.
Come on, Gary!
♪ Why'd I ever leave Madelaine alone ♪
♪ Make me believe, you'll never leave ♪
♪ It couldn't hurt to pretend ♪
♪ Why'd I ever leave Madelaine alone ♪
Billie!
Whoa, don't try touching me!
Leave that alone!
That's my Jacket...
Give me that..
Hey Hank, come and help me.
Give my jacket!
That's my jacket..
Help!
- They almost killed me
- You know you're not supposed to run.
My head knew it,
but my feet didn't.
Oh, hi babe.
Oh...
- Putt them out!
- They're trying to stay away from Togar.
- Come on.
- Why'd they have to be in here?
Why this open-door policy
you have in here, anyway?
All the doors are closed
except for here..
And the bathroom
There's nothing they can
tear up here or the bathroom.
- Putt them out!
- Mativo, this is their home!
What do you think you're
running, a country club for lions?
Come on, sit down here...
Sit down, you're okay!
Sit down. You're okay.
Sit down.
Hey, no more fighting!
Come here.
Oooh, sit down you're okay.
These stupid lions
are frightening me.
And you're going to bring
Madelaine and the children to this?
This would be great for them
Not boxed in, like back in Chicago.
Hey, wait a minute...
I just thought he
had a cataract start.
Oh, That's Billy he's great
They're right. You must be
on something
I couldn't last a day.
You expect her to sleep with the lions, are you?
What do you care if
I sleep with my wife?
Mom, do you know that a man can
have as many wives as he wants to, here?
And what does that supposed to mean?
I mean, how could you be
away from dad for so long?
You know that your father
and I were having problems
And we thought it would be
better to be apart for a while.
You know absence makes
the heart grow fonder.
The heart maybe,
but what about the sex glands?
Sex is all you think
about lately young lady...
You'd better watch it. You're
gonna get your little tail in trouble.
Someday I hope you'll understand the
beauty of restraint and self-denial.
Well, I hope it wasn't restraint and
self-denial that drove dad away...
♪ ... Isn't it time that we stop ♪
Hey Mativo, you know what my kids
used to do every time I started to sing?
They'd hold their
hands over their ears...
And say oh no!
Or they turn on a radio.
Hey Hank.
Don't let them in the boat
You're crazy!
I think, he said it's
just over the hill.
♪ You will never guess ♪
♪ how many dreams I dreamed about ♪
♪ or just how empty they all seem without her ♪
♪  soooo kiss me once kiss me twice ♪
♪ and kiss me once again ♪
♪ It's been a long ... ♪
I can't steer.
I think were sinking.
Abandon ship!
Hey Mativo...
Hey Mativo climb
out over that way.
Don't swim,
they'll get you.
Mom, come here look...
It's fantastic!
Yeah, Dad!
Hey Dad!
Dad?
Hank?
Hello?
Dad?
We're here...
Oh dear...
Hey Dad??
Hank?
- This is really a nice place.
- Come on up this place is really wild.
Oh, I'll give anything
for some sleep.
Oh, I don't understand...
Is that a tarantula?
- You simple-minded jerk!
- Stop that!
Oh my God!
Where could he be?
Jerry, run it up at all the windows
Then we will dust everything
and surprise your father.
Hey a motorcycle.
I saw a thing,
I think it was a pelican.
it's a Kawasaki!
Holy mackerel!
Look at that...
I don't believe what I'm seeing
Those can't be Dad's lions.
Oh God, look what the cat dragged in!
Melanie?
Mom, get in here...
Get in here.
Jerry?
John!
- Where's Mom and Mel?
- They're downstairs, come on...
What the heck is going on down there.
- Alright we got trouble.
- Where they all come from?
Nice lion.
Nice lion!
Oh.
- Now honey you alright?
- Yeah, but I'm scared mom.
Oh, I know honey so am I
Oh, honey stay here,
I will get the boys.
- Help
- John?
I'm in here.
John, you are alright?
Where is Jerry?
Help!
Jerry..
Jerry?
Oh god.
- Are you alright?
- You could have suffocated!
- You could've died, dummy.
- Shut up I almost died.
What kind of jerk would
hide himself in an icebox?
Get me outta here!
Help, mom!
John!
Jerry!?
- Get me outta here.
- Come on, one - two - three.
Maybe there's some guns around here.
We gotta find a gun...
I think we have to
split while we can.
Yeah, sure with eight-thousand
lions and tigers outside...
Well, if we stay here we'll
end up being eaten alive.
We're not going to get eaten.
When dad gets here he'll
show us how to handle them.
Until then we just
board up the windows.
- Wait a minute who voted you in?
- I did.
I suppose you want
to make a run for it?
Right, I'll take the
motorcycle and go get help.
I know bikes and I know
the road we came in on.
That's not gonna help, that's letting
you escape and leaving us here.
Give me your handkerchief, John.
Oh, I wanna go home.
Madelaine is gonna kill me.
It'll go much faster faster if you go
up there and borrow some bicycles.
- Okay!
- I'll take the tigers out.
Go around the back of the village.
(Mativo speaks the local language
explains tigers are passing the village)
Don't tell me he said ...  you said
I'm not interested in your bitterness.
Who asked you to go over there?
I can go on any property to kill animals
that I deem are a danger to human lives.
Don't tell me you
care about his family!
I'm telling you there'll
be no culling of cats,
elephants or any animal ever again.
Well, you should've been at that madhouse
and seen those cats this morning.
I don't care what you've seen.
You're not going to go out
there and slaughtering animals.
Recall elephants if
there are so many
Prentis, you're completely out of line.
you are not going
to kill those cats.
You can tell me what
you're gonna do...
And you can tell me what the rest
of this committee is gonna do, Rick.
But I'll be damned if you're gonna
tell me what I'm gonna do.
- We can't escort 2 tigers.
- Well, I try to make them go home.
How come they're not doing
what you're telling them?
Well, they're not trained cats
they're just friends.
Stay off my path...
Come on, where you're going?
Come on down.
You go, I'm not going.
You know, you're right.
I can't go to the airport with them,
they'd go right in with me.
Hey, I got an idea for ya...
Hang down off that branch,
let your feet hang down here...
What?
Kick your feet they'll jump right up
and try to get ya and they'll stay here.
- I can sneak away.
- No no, I'll not doing that.
Listen ...
Take your shirt off, okay?
And dangle it down.
Hold it by the sleeve.
There you go.
Hurry back!
♪ You make me feel so alive ♪
♪ make me feel like living on and on ♪
♪ there's more to life ♪
♪ There's so much more
to life than meets the eye ♪
♪ It takes a lot to see,
the forest for the trees ♪
♪ You make me feel so alive! ♪
♪ And I thank you all for showing why ♪
♪ There's more to life
than meets the eye ♪
Why did you bring us here?
We're just gonna die!
No, we are not going to die!
Your father's gonna be
here soon and it'll be all over.
Well, why isn't he here now,
he knew we were coming?
You can bellyache all you
want about him staying away
but if he isn't here
it's because he's dead
and he's not coming, I know it.
Boy I've been waiting
to do this for a long time.
Don't you think we should wait?
We shouldn't allow anything
smaller than a 30.6 for Lions.
Have you seen my wife and children?
No, I didn't see them
I saw a lady and three children.
I told them to catch the bus.
What time?
It was just about 10:30.
Let me borrow your car.
No, I don't have a car.
Leonard?
Oh Leonard...
Leonard ... Leonard.
Okay..
(Leonard gives Hank instructions in their local language)
Come on putt your
bike in the truck.
They must be in the house already,
they took the bus yesterday.
Nikki get in the car.
Come on get in back.
Come on Craig get in with us
Come on Craig that's a good boy.
Yeah, it's a good boy,
turn around.
He's trying to close me in the trunk!
Hey, come on get in...
Hey, well.. come on. Get in!
You're crazy, with them in the back?
They'll bite my head off.
Either get in or walk,
cause I'm going...
Make them walk!
Hank, this is madness.
If somebody sees them this far
from my place, they'll shoot them.
Don't fool yourself!
These are your friends, huh?
And do you know what your friends up
over are doing to your family right now?
they are making diner of them.
- They're eating them!
- Mativo, shut up!
They're sitting around eating
them cracking their bones...
- Shut up!
- They're licking their bones clean.
Shut up!
- Who are you?
- Come on!
- Hey, don't go so fast it's too bumpy.
- I have to Mativo.
By the way
Do they know that
they should not run?
You should've sent them a list of rules
and regulations before they came.
Argh, poor Leonard's...
Let's get out of here.
I think Melanie was right.
Let's go take the boat.
Jerry, you go first, go ahead.
Jerry, you're rowing the wrong way...
Boy that was close..
Get away!
Get away from me!
Help me!
Oh, less than 10 miles to go
and we're stuck!
- What's wrong?
- The jack wont wont in the sand..
And the more I dig the
more the car slides...
- Then I'll have to run.
- But you know you're not supposed to run.
You hold the Tigers back would you?
So that they don't tackle me.
- What?
- Just use this...
Use this!
Look like that..
Hey, Prentis, did you see that?
I got him right in the neck.
Sooner or later the
lions are gonna get us
I'm gonna go for help.
Okay, let's go see if the other
doors in the house are secure.
- John!
- I'm gonna get help.
- And leave us here?
- I tell you it's suicide...
Good luck, son!
Oh no...
Ah, get out here...
Open the door!
Come on!
Go on, get out of here!
Leave it, go on, leave it!
- Jerry, open the door! Come on.
- You think I'm crazy?
What kinda jerk would go
off the roof on a motorcycle?
Get off of her!
Hey what are you
doing on the floor?
John, I can't get my leg out.
Come on help her, I hold 'm.
I hold 'm.
Melanie come here...
Oh.
O my goodness!
- Jerry help your sister.
- He just trying to kiss her.
Do it, open the door!
You think we have
enough ammunition?
I've got plenty in this
belt and thirty in the other.
Remember where all the cheetahs,
leopards and tiger drop..
We skin them on the way back.
The Lions are worthless,
leave them for the hyena's
Mom, go over the tread...
Come on Mom...
See mom, there's another house.
It's completely safe
That's a good thing because
I can't walk another step.
I'm so tired,
my legs just buckle under me
I just have to sleep for a while...
Oh Donny lion...
Oh Donny...
Come on my friend, get up!
I'll make sure they are ???
Togar get away!!
Oh you... poor stupid jerks!
Togar, get away...
Let's try to get them outside.
I do not think they are
trying to hurt us at all.
Melanie, John get away
from those lions.
Mom, if they wanted to get us they
would have done while we were asleep.
Make sure that his
mother is not around.
They are really friendly.
Oh she's beautiful, isn't she?
They're really friendly.
Togar!
Togar!!
Madelaine!
John!
Hello Lion
Togar! ... Togar! ... Togar!!
Madelaine!
Hey you guys stay away for a while..
Hey, kids how are ya?
Wauw oh...oh ...oh
I better go help your mom.
Hey, Lynn get off.
Come on get up.
Don't hit her Jerry, hug her
she wants you to hold her.
Are you okay.
I'm so happy you're here.
You're okay
don't worry.
- Don't worry!
- Oh...
Oh, I sure love you.
Oh I love you too!
Hey... Listen don't say anything
about Prentis okay?
But he was killing our lions
I don't want you to say
anything about that either.
It will spoil the reunion.
I will tell them later.
Listen, I want you to meet my
family. This is my wife Madelaine.
This my son John.
This is my daughter Melanie.
Melanie.. Mativo.
My son Jerry.
Come on this way.
Listen, I have a surprise for you.
Why? We are glad to see you.
Whaddya all do wearing my clothes?
Oh No, what happened?
Get back, they're lively and
they all want to meet you.
We already met them...
Isn't this fantastic!
What do ya think,
you guys gonna stay a while?
Sure dad. I don't have to be back
in Chicago before next week.
(Robert Hawk Florczak - Here We Are In Eden)