♪ I got you
I got you on my mind ♪
♪ And it's time to make you see
What I want ♪
♪ So I'll just make this
a little more obvious ♪
♪ 'Cause I get what I want
and I want you to get with me ♪
♪ Don't think you know ♪
♪ How far I'm going to go ♪
♪ You can't stop this feeling ♪
♪ You can't run away ♪
♪ Baby, I'm what's
on your mind ♪
♪ You can't stop this feeling ♪
♪ There's no escape ♪
♪ No sleep tonight ♪
♪ You won't get
no sleep tonight ♪
♪ You want me ♪
♪ You want me all the time ♪
♪ And you don't need
nothing else ♪
♪ But you seem to be
a little oblivious ♪
♪ So I'll show you the way ♪
♪ If you think that you
need some help ♪
♪ Tell me, baby ♪
♪ Are you coming, with me? ♪
♪ You can't stop this feeling ♪
♪ You cannot run away ♪
♪ Baby, I'm what's
on your mind ♪
♪ You can't stop this feeling ♪
♪ There's no escape ♪
♪ No sleep tonight ♪
♪ You won't get
no sleep tonight ♪
♪ No sleep tonight ♪
♪ Won't sleep tonight ♪
Ahh!
Oh! She shoots,
she scores! Goal!
- What? That's right! Give it!
- Nice kick.
- Very nice kick.
- Give me the ball!
Ow! Justin!
- Drop... Put me down!
- OK. Down like...
Oh, sorry.
- Ooh, goodness.
- Hey!
Mmm.
OK, you are
really getting good.
Aw, you too.
I mean, when we
first started going out,
you couldn't kiss at all.
- I meant at soccer.
- Aww. Really?
Absolutely. You're...
...probably already better
than half the guys on my team.
Mm, probably more
than half.
What do you mean,
I couldn't kiss at all?
Don't worry.
I've taught you well.
I know.
Oww! OK, but
seriously, don't you think
you'd get more playing time
at a school like Michigan?
Yeah, maybe,
but it's always been
about being a Tar Heel
for me.
I'm gonna wear
that Carolina blue.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, baby!
OK, what is the lacrosse team
doing on our field?
- The school cut our team.
- Wait, what?
- Not enough girls signed up.
- So they just cut us?
They can't do that.
OK. This is not over.
Hi, girls.
I heard the bad news.
"Bad"? It's a disaster.
- Now college scouts, they won't even get to see us play.
- Yeah.
I know. If there's anything
I can do, just say the word.
As a matter of fact, there is.
We wanna try out
for the boys team.
Uh, anything besides that.
Coach, come on!
You know that we're good enough.
I don't know that
that's a thing that I know.
What?
All we're asking for
is one shot.
- Yeah.
- Girls,
we have two weeks
before school starts.
Then we open against Illyria.
A rivalry game. We have to win.
And we can help you win.
Hey, baby.
Hey.
What's going on, coach?
Umm, the girls here want
to try out for the team.
- You're not serious.
- All right, all right!
You're all excellent players.
But girls aren't as fast as boys.
- Right.
- What?
- Or as strong. Or as athletic.
This is not me talking.
It's a scientific fact.
Girls can't beat boys.
It's as simple as that.
OK. Well, Justin,
you're the team captain.
What do you think about it?
I think the coach said it all.
Yesterday you told me that I was better than half the guys on your team.
What?
I never said that.
What are you talking about?
Why are you lying?!
Viola! End of discussion.
Yeah, tell her, man.
Fine. End of relationship.
Ohhh!
- Come on, let's go.
- Baby, don't be like that. I...
I just don't want
to see you get hurt.
Aww. You are so full of...
Back to practice.
♪ All alone ♪
Sebastian.
♪ Where are you? ♪
♪ Are we over? ♪
Sebastian?!
♪ Something said... ♪
Sebastian! Jeez!
Oww!
Ew. It's you.
God, you and your
brother look scary alike
from the back.
I think it's
your total lack of curves.
Hah. Hi, Monique.
It's so good to see you too.
Mm. I'm looking for Sebastian.
Where is he?
I don't know.
Just remind your brother how
lucky he is to be in my life.
And tell him to give me a call
if he wants to stay in it. OK?
OK. Does he have your number?
1-800-BEYOTCH?
She will do great things.
I have a surprise
for you!
And this is why
I don't bring friends over.
Mom, not now. I had
a really bad day, so...
This is just the thing
to just perk you up.
- Hold on.
- OK.
- Keep your eyes closed.
Eyes closed, eyes closed,
closed, closed.
They're closed.
All right. Surprise!
Beautiful gowns
for my darling debutante.
Mom, have I not told you
a thousand times?
I have no interest
in being a debutante.
It's totally archaic.
How could I wind up
with a daughter
who only wants to kick a muddy
ball around a field all day?
Well, the world has been set
right, Mom. They cut my team.
- What? No soccer?
- Yeah, that's right. No soccer.
How sad.
Yeah, I can see
you're all torn up.
Well, Justin's
gonna love you in this.
Yet another reason not
to wear it. I dumped him.
What? Why?
I don't wanna talk about it.
He's so handsome and rugged
and chiseled and great.
Then why don't
you date him, Mom?
No, I couldn't
- Hey, Sebastian.
- Hey.
- You OK?
- Uh-huh.
- Monique was looking for you.
- Mmm.
Why do you even date her,
anyway?
She's hot.
It's a guy thing.
Yuck. But she's so awful.
Mmph!
Hey, you know, you
could use the front door.
And Mom can't see me.
She thinks I'm staying at Dad's.
Dad thinks I'm staying at Mom's.
In two days they both think
that I'm going away to school.
That is the beauty of divorce.
Wait, where are you going?
London for a couple of weeks.
As in London, England?
Yeah, my band got a slot
in a music festival there.
OK, what are you
gonna do about school?
Yeah, I was kind of hoping
you could help me with that.
Could you just, like,
pretend to be Mom,
call Illyria,
tell them I'm sick?
Something that sounds like
it would last for two weeks,
like mad cow.
Sebastian, you
just got kicked out
of Cornwall for skipping.
This is not exactly the way
you want to start out.
Hey, I want to be a musician.
Last time I heard, they don't
need to know trigonometry.
Besides, if you want
to chase your dreams,
sometimes you gotta break
the rules, right?
You know the percentage of bands
that make it to the big time?
Probably the same
as female soccer players.
I will see you in two weeks.
- Sebastian.
- Ow!
Sebastian!
Were you talking
with your brother?
No. Yes.
On the phone.
He's at Dad's. Bye, Dad.
Picture this:
We're at the country club,
they call your name,
and you emerge in this.
Ta-da!
Echh. No.
Sorry, Mom. I have
a strict no-ruffles policy.
Sometimes I just think you just
might as well be your brother.
Hmm. You know what?
If you can't join them,
beat them.
You want me to turn
you into your brother?
That's right. I'm going
to Illyria as Sebastian.
I'll make the boys soccer team,
and in 12 days, I'll beat
the Cornwall boys team.
- That's right!
- You've taken way too many soccer balls to the head.
You know I can do it, Paul.
Except for the voice
and the mannerisms
and the breasts
and the mentality and....
Besides, it doesn't matter.
Nobody at Illyria
has even met Sebastian.
They wouldn't know
the difference.
They'll know he's a girl.
Oh, come on, Paul.
Yeah, come on, Paul.
OK. OK.
I'll see what I can do.
Yes!
♪ Who can turn the world on
with her smile? ♪
♪ Who can take a nothing day ♪
♪ And suddenly make it all
seem worthwhile? ♪
♪ Well, it's you, girl
and you should know it ♪
♪ With each glance and every
little movement you show it ♪
♪ Love is all around
No need to fake it ♪
♪ You can have the town
Why don't you take it? ♪
♪ You're gonna make it
after all ♪
♪ How will you make it
on your own? ♪
♪ This world is awfully big ♪
♪ And, girl, this time
you're all alone ♪
♪ But it's time you
started living ♪
♪ It's time you let
someone else do some giving ♪
♪ Love is all around
No need to fake it ♪
♪ You can have the town
Why don't you take it? ♪
♪ You're gonna make it
after all ♪
♪ Oww! ♪
Uh, where are you going?
Mom, I told you! I'm going
to Dad's house for two weeks.
No, you didn't.
And you're not going.
We've hardly spent any time
together this summer.
Now, you just go
upstairs and unpack.
OK, Mom, I thought
about what you said.
And you know Monique is gonna
be there 24/7 with Sebastian,
so, I don't know,
I was just thinking
that maybe she'd
show me the ropes
on the whole debutante thing.
- This is so exciting!
- Isn't it?!
You're gonna have so much fun.
Now, there's the formal ball.
And the luncheon.
And, oh, did I mention
the fundraiser next week?
It's gonna be a carnival!
Look out!
Your brother promised
to be there,
so remind him when you
see him, all right?
Oh, my little girl.
You're finally gonna be a lady!
Are you sure I can do this?!
Oh, yeah. Absolutely.
What's up?
Oh, my God, he knew!
- I wanna go home!
- Relax. He was being friendly!
We're not going home! Stop it!
I did not spend all this time...
- It's your fault! Drive home!
- My idea?! You asked me!
- I did your hair and makeup!
- Reverse!
- I want to go!
- That was not easy! You're being a girl!
- We're not going. Go.
- Come on! Drive!
- He was being friendly.
- All right!
Now, let's run through it
one more time.
Let me hear the voice.
Hey. What's up? I'm Sebastian.
OK. Now show me the strut.
Now, hawk a loogie.
I'm so proud!
- Get off me!
- Remember,
inside every girl
there's a boy.
That came out wrong.
But you know what I mean.
Vi.
Be a good boy.
♪ I've got to, got to, got to ♪
♪ Catch my breath ♪
♪ I've got to, got to
catch my breath ♪
♪ We're getting
closer and closer ♪
♪ And warmer and warmer ♪
♪ My heart is racing
and pacing ♪
♪ Your dad's gonna kill me ♪
♪ Good girl ♪
♪ With such a bad boy ♪
♪ You used to be a good girl ♪
Whoo!
See you guys.
I can do this.
I am a dude!
I am a hunky dude!
I'm a badass hunky dude!
♪ Good girl ♪
♪ Your mom says I'm a bad boy ♪
♪ Got to catch my ♪
♪ Yeah, you used
to be a good girl ♪
♪ But then you met a bad boy ♪
♪ Yeah, that's me all right ♪
Hey!
Hey! What up?
You must be my roommates.
Wha... what's your name?
Sebastian Hastings.
Duke Orsino.
Umm, OK.
OK, OK, OK. Umm...
This is Andrew and Toby.
They live next door.
Yeah. Freshman dorm's
that-a-way, twiglet.
Seriously, how old are you?
I skipped a couple grades.
I'm brilliant.
Shh.
Anyway, do you know
when soccer tryouts start?
Noon. You play?
Absolutely. Center forward.
You know it, bro.
So you play
the beautiful game... bro?
Brothers? Brethren?
Yeah, I'm a striker.
Andrew and Toby are halfbacks.
Schveet.
OK, why do you have tampons
in your boot?
Um...
I get really bad nose bleeds.
So you stick them up your nose?
Yeah.
What? You've never done that?
Oh, my...
Beckham does it all the time.
- Seriously?
- Yes.
- Look. I'll just show you how to do it.
- Ahh!
Take that off and....
...whatever that is.
And you stick it right in.
It absorbs right up.
Are you kidding me?
That's disgusting.
Oh, my God,
your roommate's a freak.
That's so disgusting.
Let's start the season
how we finished the last.
Sharp!
What are you,
the runt of the family?
OK, shirts and skins.
Pardon me, sir.
I have to be a shirt.
- What?
- I'm allergic to the sun.
You're allergic to the sun?
Very, very, very
deathly, deathly allergic.
We like to accommodate
here at Illyria.
So I'll follow you around with
a parasol. All right, Nancy boy?
You're a shirt.
OK, guys, let's go.
One, two, three!
At ease, gentlemen.
I've seen a lot of energy
and commitment out there today.
And that makes a coach proud.
Now, I want to split us up into
first string and second string.
You second-stringers,
don't take it too hard.
You're just as much part of this
team as the first-stringers.
Apart from, of course,
playing the game part.
Schuler.
Haims.
Potensky.
Donner.
Hastings.
Second string.
The rest of you,
congratulations.
First-stringers.
Now, hit the showers.
Shower time.
Shower time?
- Hastings! No shower for you.
- OK.
Principal Gold wants
to see you in his office.
I'm over. It's done. They know.
Sebastian's file.
Sebastian...
Could it be any bigger?
Mr. Hastings.
Horatio Gold...
...headmaster.
So very pleased to meet you.
So very, very pleased.
Hello, sir.
Heard you wanted to see me.
I'd like to say welcome.
♪ Welcome to Illyria ♪
♪ Welcome, welcome, welcome
welcome, welcome, welcome ♪
welcome to Illyria ♪
I just wanted to have you in
to say welcome.
See how you're doing.
Ah... Yeah,
I'm doing great, you know?
Just...
...busy being a guy.
Being a guy. Yeah.
Well, let's take a look
at your file, Sebastian.
And...
Seems to be... stuck a bit.
There we go. All right.
OK. Well...
OK, you're busted.
I know you don't wanna sit here and talk to the headmaster,
but I won't take no for an answer.
Now, have a sit
in the headmaster's chair.
Come on, have a sit.
Sit it.
So, Sebastian Hastings.
How do you like campus?
Beautiful.
You've been inspired
by the charcoal black
and candy apple red?
You know it.
Hey!
Don't touch it. Ever. Ever.
Do not do that.
You know, Sebastian, I was
a transfer student myself...
...once upon a time.
Back when dinosaurs
roamed the earth.
So I keep
a special interest
in the transfer students
that come to this school.
Act as a...
unofficial big brother.
Don't be surprised if I just pop in unannounced
from time to time just to check up.
Yeah, I look forward to it.
Now scoot!
- Ahh!
- Sorry.
- That's OK. Don't worry about it.
- My fault.
What is...?
Ohh. Getting to know
the opposite sex, are we?
Male-female dynamics.
All that sexual tension.
It's all part of the high school
experience. So continue. Please.
But keep it clean, though. OK.
Abstinence is key.
Abstinence is...
The best way to not is to not.
Uh...
Hmm? Yes.
Is he always that friendly?
Are you kidding?
That's him being rude.
Huh.
All right.
Ooh, cute shoes.
You think so? I got them
at Anthropologie.
No way! They have shoes there?
- Oh, yeah. Right by the accessories.
- Huh.
Here are your books.
Thanks.
Well, I guess I'm gonna,
you know, go take care of
some guy stuff.
OK.
There you go.
Have a great apple and sandwich.
Hi! I would love a...
- No.
- But...
Hey, dudes. Mind if I join?
Thanks.
So those soccer tryouts
were bogus, huh?
I mean, second string? Come on,
that's ridiculous. Am I right? Am I right?
So the game against Cornwall,
that should be interesting.
And why would that
be interesting?
Well, my sister goes there,
and she used to date
that tool Justin Drayton.
I know him.
- I made him cry once during a game.
- Wait.
- That was you?
- Absolutely.
- That was so funny.
- Wow.
Is your sister hot?
Uhh... I guess so.
She's got a great personality.
- Ahh.
- Eww.
Incoming.
Oh, yeah! Check out the booty
on that blondie.
- Uh-oh.
- Don't talk about her that way.
Oh. Is that your girlfriend?
He wishes.
She was dating this
college guy, but he dumped her.
I hear she's a total mess
right now, really vulnerable.
Confidence, self-esteem
is way down.
In man words,
it's time to pounce.
Exactly.
I hate that guy.
Did you know bologna
is 38 percent hoof?
Thanks, Malcolm.
Uh-oh. Looks like you
got some competition.
- It's just Malcolm.
- Total geek.
She looks so sad.
It's heartbreaking.
It... it's just...
I can relate, you know?
I mean, I just got out
of a bad relationship too.
I mean, you think
you know someone.
And you realize it's
all been a big lie.
Every touch.
Every kiss.
Plus, you know, you can
never get chicks to shut up.
All right, guys,
catch up with you later.
Empty shower.
Yes!
♪ I get to take a shower ♪
Whoo!
Uh... Malcolm Festes,
dorm director.
Shower shoes are to be worn
in the bathroom at all times
except when
in the actual shower.
Did you not read
your Dorm Life pamphlet?
It was in your cubby.
Ohh!
Wassup, dawg?
Yeah. OK, homey.
Mm. Later.
Hey. You forgot... this, Coolio.
Word, G-Money.
Ahh!
OK, Hastings, you're up!
Hastings, are you deaf?!
Come on, let's go!
Get your butt out there!
Come on!
- Get out!
- Ohh!
Jesus!
Whoa! Ohh!
Come on, baby. Come on.
Ohh!
Rise and shine.
Wait! Let go!
Let go!
Welcome to hell!
Gentlemen! Let me present
this year's soccer newbies!
But first, you
must remove your clothes!
Remove their clothes!
Take your clothes off now!
Hello. My life sucks.
- I'm done!
- What?
Everybody thinks I'm
a huge loser deviant.
I'll never see
the field against Cornwall.
And I smell so bad
I'm convulsing people.
Pick me up, take me home
and make sure I never do
anything like this again.
Look, Vi, I don't know
what to tell you
about the whole
soccer team...
...but as for the social stuff,
I got an idea.
- You do?
- Yeah.
We're gonna show everybody
the man that you really are.
And how are we gonna do that?
Go, Viola.
High five.
Nice.
Aw, man. Look who's here.
Foxy mama.
Uh.. Uh... uh... don't look
at him. Maybe he won't see us.
Spread out so it looks
like we got no room.
- What's up?
Go, Kia.
♪ Hey, sexy lady
I like your flow ♪
Hey, Sebastian. Mmm.
Aw, Kia.
Hey, girl.
How you doing, baby?
- Not the same without you.
- I know. I'm sorry.
New school, new babe pool.
I miss you, Sebastian.
I've been thinking
about you a lot.
- Especially at night.
- Sweet.
- Late.
- Even better.
OK, did she just say that
to Sebastian?
- What just happened?
- Oh, Sebastian.
OK, big, mournful sigh. "Uhh."
Bittersweet farewell.
You're his plaything, baby.
It was really great
to see you, Sebastian.
Call me anytime.
I'd tap that.
Thank you, Kia. You're
gorgeous. And go, Yvonne.
Women.
Yeah.
- Yeah, you know what I'm saying?
♪ Aww, yeah ♪
Sebastian? Is that you?
Hey, what's going on, Yvonne?
- Who's this one?
- Nothing.
I mean, our school lost
its top gun, Sebastian Hastings.
Well, time comes for a man
to move along, Yvonne.
I know, Sebastian.
In the end I wasn't
woman enough for you.
No, you weren't.
That's something
I'll always have to live with.
It just hurts, that's all.
Love is pain.
Just know I'll
never forget you, Sebastian.
Ever! Never!
Needy.
OK. We might need to do
a little reevaluating here.
- Yeah.
- Hey there, pretty lady.
Eww. What...?
What are you, hitting on me?
I was just...
"I was just..."
OK, let me put a stop to that
little brain fart right now.
Girls with asses like mine
do not talk to boys
with faces like yours.
I'm looking for my boyfriend Sebastian Hastings.
Have you guys seen him?
Sebastian?
Not good. Don't let her get
too close, she'll recognize you.
What am I gonna do?
- Keep away from me!
- I beg your pardon?!
Pretty ladies. OK, don't
come any closer, Monique.
- Sebastian!
- It's over!
What are you talking about?!
- I don't want to talk to you, crazy!
- Sebastian, come back here.
You're hot, Monique.
Smoking hot.
Come here. Get! Get! Get!
- But there are plenty of hot girls out there.
- Come back here.
And the truth is,
you have absolutely
nothing else to offer.
And when my eyes are closed, I
see you for what you truly are,
which is ugly!
We're done!
Whoo! That was amazing!
You the man!
What's wrong with you guys?
Make some room for the man.
- Sit down!
- Whoo-whee!
You're officially
my idol now, man.
There he is.
- What's up?
- What's up, brothers?
- Hey, Sebastian.
- Lovelies.
- Holler at your boy.
- Yo! Yo! Sebastian!
Can you get out
of my way right now?
I need your advice.
I got lady troubles.
I'm here for you, bro.
I got a lifetime of knowledge.
How long did you
date that girl?
Too long.
Ball and frickin' chain, man.
♪ I'm a Barbie girl
in a Barbie world ♪
Dude.
Justine. Chick won't stop
dogging me, man.
Oh, my God. Oh, my, God.
She's in our class.
Dude, quit blushing.
That's lame.
Shut up. I'm not blushing.
Everyone, please take a slip
and read off the name
of your lab partner.
"Eunice Bates."
Huh. You got to be kidding me.
- Be nice.
- Yeah.
She got a little
something-something.
Yeah, asthma
and headgear.
"Olivia Lennox."
- You know her?
- I talked to her for a second.
About what?
She gave you the nod.
- She did a good one.
- She gives good nod.
Could everybody
please calm down?
I can't believe you got her
as a lab par... Switch with me.
I can't.
I said her name out loud.
Some guys just walk
in the light, you know?
- Hello again.
- Hello.
I don't think we introduced
ourselves before. I'm Sebastian.
Olivia.
I'm gonna be the best lab
partner you ever had.
Cool.
I gotta be completely honest.
The whole dissecting thing
kind of freaks me out.
So, uh, think you may have
to take the reins on this one.
Wow. Most guys
would never admit that.
Oh, crap, you're right.
No, don't worry.
I think it's refreshing.
- You do?
- No paper near the Bunsen burner.
- Wait.
- What's this? Poems?
Lyrics. They're his...
My... my old stuff.
"Wake up, I've
been waiting for you."
Those are really good.
So honest.
I know. I keep telling him...
me... meself... my... myself...
I write songs too, Olivia.
- Really, Malcolm? Wonderful.
- Check it out.
♪ I see you
through your window ♪
♪ I'm standing
on a tree outside ♪
Aww!
You, you sit.
You, go. Go!
- Did you say anything about me?
- No. Was I supposed to?
Come on. This is perfect.
You get to spend an hour
with her every other day.
You can convince her
to go out with me.
Dude, she had that option
for three and a half years.
I'll tell you what.
You do this,
I'll work with you
on your soccer.
I'll make you good enough
to make first string.
- By the Cornwall game?
- Absolutely.
OK, yeah. You got a deal.
- You're the man.
- Yes, I am.
Ah!
Oh. Right.
Oww! Oh, for the love
of God! It burns!
It just isn't fair, Malvolio.
I wait three years for Olivia,
and then some transfer student
comes in
and suddenly she's
acting like some...
...obsessed
love-struck teenager.
I'm not gonna take that
lying down, Malvolio!
Yeah, I know. I know.
You're absolutely right.
I'll do some digging,
I'll find out what it is,
and I'll nip his chances
with Olivia right in the bud.
What's that? Oh, yeah, sure.
A walk. Sorry. Come on.
You are so smart.
Hello.
- Miss me?
- What's going on?
What's wrong with your voice?
I just have
a little bit of a cold.
So...
I'm still a little phlegmy.
- Did you call my school?
- Yeah.
It's all taken care of.
Just make sure
you're back by the 12th.
It was so cool, Vi.
We went on a couple days early,
and the crowd flipped for us.
They wanted an encore,
so we did one of my songs
acoustically.
- They went nuts for my lyrics.
- Oh, that's so cool.
And you were right
about Monique.
She's history.
She really is, isn't she?
I got to go.
I'll talk to you later.
OK. Bye.
Trouble with your wig,
Hastings?
Uh, no, I actually...
I have a scalp condition.
- No, you don't.
- Yeah, I do.
I really do. It's really
acting up during the...
No, you don't.
You've got
male pattern baldness.
Scoot over, kiddo.
I don't know if you've realized,
but recently I've
started to thin out myself.
I've tried all the creams
and the butters,
and I still can't seem to stop
Mother Nature's vindictive fury,
and neither can you. OK?
There's gonna be a time
when you'll have to come out
of the closet and just accept
yourself for who you are.
A baldy. OK?
But it's gonna be
all right. OK?
Oh, and between you and me,
chicks dig it.
Hang ten. Yeah.
Hi, Olivia. I
don't want you to be worried,
but Malvolio's missing.
- Oh, no!
- Yeah.
If you see him, don't feed him.
He has an irritable bowel.
Yeah. 'Cause that would be
my very first instinct.
To feed the tarantula.
Hmm.
Here's a wild idea.
Have you ever thought about
going out with Duke Orsino?
I see that.
- Duke?
- Yeah.
- No.
- Yeah?
- No!
I mean, he's good-looking
and everything,
but he's just not
the guy for me.
Hmm. I don't know.
Think there may be more
to him than you think there is.
So you're telling me he's
not just another dumb jock
who wants to hook up with me
so he could tell
his friends, but too...?
Insecure to treat you
as an equal?
Exactly.
Tell me about it.
You're the first guy
at this school
who hasn't tried
anything with me.
Trust me,
you're not my type.
Well, why not?
You know, it's just...
...I don't think of you
in that way.
We're friends, you know.
You're actually one
of the few people here
that I feel comfortable around.
I feel the same way
about you.
Good. Then just take my advice.
Go out with Duke.
I'll consider it.
So, uh, what is that exactly?
Um, I think that's the spleen.
Hmm.
- OK, who's your daddy?
- Huh?
I got her to agree to consider
you. You're halfway in.
Uhh! Um, all right, OK.
So should I ask her out?
No. You don't want
to freak her out.
You got to have a casual
conversation first. Hello.
Why do I get the feeling
you don't do this very often?
Man, I just... I'm not
really good at talking to girls.
- Why? You're hot!
- What?
You know,
you're an appealing guy...
Man... guy... guy-man.
Look, I don't know. I just
always say the wrong...
I just always
say the wrong thing.
OK. All right.
Come on. Let's get up.
I want to try something.
I'll act like a girl, and
you're going to talk to me.
Eww. Do I have to?
Yes!
Because I'm Viola.
- Duke? Nice to meet you.
- That was creepy.
You really just sounded
like a girl just then.
I used to imitate
my sister all the time.
I got really good at it.
Come on. And get up!
Come on. Ask me
some questions,
and if the chemistry's right,
things'll just start flowing.
Oh... Um, questions about what?
Anything. Ask me if...
...I like...
...cheese.
Um, OK.
Do you like cheese?
Why, yes I do.
My favorite's Gouda.
- I like Gouda too.
- See?
- See what?
- We're flowing.
We're talking about cheese.
So what? Flow is flow.
What? What's that?
What is that?! It touched me!
It touched me! It touched me!
It's Malcolm's tarantula!
Get it!
- You get it!
- You're the guy!
The bigger guy.
Sorry!
You don't ever, ever do
that girl voice again!
- Freaked me out!
- My bad.
Sebastian, honey,
this is your mother.
I'm calling to remind you
about the carnival tomorrow.
You and your sister promised
you'd both be there. Bye-bye.
Crap! Forgot about that!
Wait, your mom's
in Junior League?
Yeah. How'd you know?
So is mine. I gotta go too.
But I can't deal
with this right now.
I have soccer
to worry about.
Not gonna be that bad.
Olivia's gonna be there.
It's a perfect opportunity
for me to lay some groundwork.
Oh, Olivia's gonna be there.
And my sister.
And Monique. And you.
And my mom.
Great.
♪ Dial up ♪
♪ My number now ♪
♪ Weaving it ♪
Dunk toss.
Hey, dude!
I will cut you, man.
I'll tell you the truth.
I never really liked carnivals.
Hey. I'm working
the kissing booth. Come see me.
I love carnivals, man.
Hey, Duke, where you going?
Where do you think I'm going?
- Uh-oh.
- What's up?
Oh, nothing.
Um, just my psycho ex.
I don't really
wanna deal with her.
So if you guys don't mind,
I'm gonna lay low
for a little while.
- Cool. Catch you later.
- OK.
- Up you go!
- Whoa!
I see a kitten...
...gasping for air.
- Sorry. Pretty urgent.
- Oh...
It's all yours.
- Hi, Mom!
- Oh!
You look like such a lady.
It's a miracle.
- It really is.
- So Monique's getting you
all excited
about being a debutante, huh?
Super-duper excited.
Have a good carnival.
Ohh! Ho, my little petunia.
Where do you think you're going?
You have the next shift
at the kissing booth.
And your brother? He's late
for the cotton candy cart.
I'm gonna go look
for him. Bye.
♪ Here we are
so what you gonna do? ♪
- Ow!
- Sorry.
Excuse you.
- Wait, do I know you?
- No.
Excuse me.
Viola! Hey, hey, hey.
Where you been?
I've been calling and calling.
I miss you. We need to talk.
We've talked, Justin.
All the talking is done.
Look, no one breaks up
over a stupid soccer issue, OK?
Can you just be a girl
for five seconds?
For five seconds?
OK, um, first of all,
it's not a stupid soccer issue,
and you're a jerk.
Oh, look at that! Time's up!
♪ Come on, baby
we ain't gonna live forever ♪
Excuse me. Sorry.
One, please.
♪ You know you
wanna be together ♪
♪ And I wanna spend
the night with you ♪
♪ Come with me tonight ♪
♪ We could make the night
last forever, ohh ♪
♪ Let's pretend you're mine ♪
♪ We could just pretend
We could just pretend ♪
♪ Oh, come on ♪
♪ Just one taste
and you'll want more ♪
♪ So tell me
what you're waiting for ♪
Stay in school.
♪ Come on, baby
we ain't gonna live forever ♪
♪ Let me show you all
the things that we could do ♪
♪ You know you
wanna be together ♪
Sebastian? Sebastian!
- Sebastian! Where are you going?
- Monique's behind me.
- We're on it.
- Sebastian!
Ahh!
Excuse me. No one
over 8 years old
is allowed
inside the Moon Bounce.
But I just saw my boyfriend
go in there.
The correct term
is "ex-boyfriend."
No relationship is over
until I say it is. Understand?
Whatever. You're still not
getting on that Moon Bounce.
Fine.
What's that?
Kia, don't look.
Oh! God!
- She's gone.
- Thank you.
- So are we, uh, having fun?
- Oh, yeah, definitely.
Whoo.
What do you think
it will be like?
Duke, you look at me.
I know it's gonna be
really, really special.
I mean, she's only kissed
like 350 guys at this point.
I just think we need
to acknowledge the moment.
After four years,
Duke is finally
gonna fulfill his destiny.
Life is good.
Life is fair. Life is just.
Hi, um, I'm your relief.
And yet....
Thank God.
I can't catch a break.
Beware of the old guy
chewing gum. It's not gum.
Echh.
- Do I know you?
- No.
- Huh.
- That's just my luck.
No. No, no, no. I mean,
I didn't mean it like that.
It's just, you know,
she's, you know.... No. OK.
I mean, on the other hand,
you're, you know, also...
- I am? Thanks, I guess.
- Yeah.
You don't have to flirt
with her first, genius.
You're paying for it.
Why don't you just...
relax. Um...
Um, maybe I should
kiss you now.
I gave that girl my ticket,
and I waited in line.
Well, it's the least
I can do.
Uh, OK. Here I go.
Um... Uh...
OK, I think that was
one ticket's worth.
No, you get a little bit more.
Excuse me.
The motel's across the street.
Viola, what the hell is this?!
Back of the line, buttball.
Excuse me, doofus. You're
making out with my girlfriend.
Ex-girlfriend.
Whoa, you're Sebastian's sister?
And you're about to die.
Are you gonna drown me
in your tears?
I did not cry during that game.
I had something in my eye.
You know what, guys?
Can we just dial it down?
And just step away, OK?
She's right. I'll see you
on the soccer field,
and we'll settle
this all then.
OK, Duke.
Or we can straighten it out
right here.
Justin! Stop it! Guys!
♪ All right ♪
Stop it! Justin!
Guys! Stop it!
Justin, get off!
Where's my daughter?!
Excuse me. I'm so sorry.
Viola! Stop!
This isn't ladylike.
There is no room
for violence here!
This is a lovely children's
carnival, goddamn it!
Both of you, out! Now!
Where were you at today?
You just disappeared.
Ran into my psycho ex.
Had to bolt.
Oh, my God! Is that a...?
What? Oh. Yeah.
I hope you don't mind. I kind
of borrowed one of your...
Yeah. And you're right, by the
way. These things actually work.
Oh, my God, you're bleeding.
Are you OK?
- Um...
- I mean,
suck it up! Be a man!
Rub some dirt in it!
OK, I'll
rub some dirt on it.
So, what happened?
I got into it
with your sister's ex.
Wait. Really? Why?
He saw me and her kind of
making out at the kissing booth.
Wait. You kissed her?
Yeah, man, I'm...
I hope that's OK.
It was for charity.
Oh, no, I mean, dude, I mean,
if you want to kiss her, you go
right ahead and you kiss her!
I mean, knock yourself out.
I mean, you just...
you take her and then kiss her
and then kiss
the crap out of her!
OK.
So...
...do you like her?
I don't know.
Can we not talk about this?
She's your sister.
It's kind of weird.
No. Right. Right.
Just... You know,
I was just thinking that,
if you liked her then...
...maybe you
should ask her out.
And just, I don't know,
forget about Olivia?
Well, I mean speaking
as a completely objective
third-party outsider
with absolutely no personal
interest in the matter,
I am not sure
that you and Olivia
really mesh well together.
You know? I mean...
But you and Viola...
...I mean...
...be magic.
I don't know.
What does your heart tell you?
- Huh?
- I mean,
which one would you
rather see naked?!
Why do you...? Why?
Why do you always do that?
Why do you always talk
about girls
in such graphic terms? Huh?
You know what?
You... you have issues.
You're a really
sensitive guy, aren't you?
What? No.
No, it's just...
I don't know.
I just think that
relationships should be more
than just the physical stuff.
Don't get me wrong,
that stuff's important,
but, I don't know,
when I'm with someone,
I want to be able
to talk about other stuff.
Like, I don't know,
serious stuff.
Stuff I can't talk about,
you know, with anyone else.
Yeah, like...
...what kind of stuff?
I don't know,
just stuff.
Like, whatever stuff there is.
Like... this kind of stuff?
Yeah.
But what I just told you
is for your ears only.
If you tell anyone,
I'll kick your ass.
Yeah. No.
I got your back, man.
It's cool.
♪ Love me
faster than the devil ♪
♪ Run me
straight into the ground ♪
♪ Drowning
deep inside your water ♪
deep inside your sound ♪
♪ Love me
faster than the devil ♪
♪ Run me
straight into the ground ♪
♪ Drowning
deep inside your water ♪
♪ Drown in
love and memories ♪
♪ Didn't you love me ♪
♪ Faster than the devil ♪
♪ Run me
straight into the ground ♪
♪ Drowning
deep inside your water ♪
♪ Drown in
love and memories ♪
Um, how's your sister?
Ahh! Whoo!
Good. Why?
I don't know.
I kind of was thinking
I might ask if she wanted
to grab dinner
at Cesario's tonight.
You were? Really?
I'd love to.
What?
I'd love to give her
your phone number.
Hastings!
Yeah, coach?
You're first string
for the Cornwall game.
- Really?
- No.
I was joking, you idiot.
Dude, that's awesome.
- Mmm.
- Um... um, dude.
- So you want me to spot you?
- No.
Isn't he cute?
Duke? Yeah.
No. Sebastian.
He's so cool.
But he said
I'm not his type.
- That's impossible. You're everyone's type.
- Not his.
I could tell you what
us mere mortals would do
in this situation.
- What?
- Make him jealous.
So, what do you do? You just
pretend to like somebody else?
Mm-hm. And then
use him shamelessly.
Wow.
So you should call Viola up.
Yeah. I think I will.
Hey, Duke.
Sebastian.
Olivia.
What're you bench-pressing
these days?
225.
Very impressive.
Thanks.
So, Duke, about that call
that you were gonna make.
- You gonna make that?
- Yeah. Thank you.
So how many reps
can you do with that 225?
Like 20... 20.
225 is more than twice
what I weigh.
How many reps
could you do with me?
Forty.
Hello?
Hi, it's Viola.
Sebastian told me to call you.
I'd love to go to dinner.
Um, yeah. What?
Um... can I call you back?
Because I gotta...
...change my feet.
So, uh, do you have
any plans tonight?
Oh! My bad.
What about the thing
that we talked about
that you were
going to do later?
What thing?
I'm thingless.
Great! Then it's a date.
Cesario's, 8:00.
- I'll see you there.
- OK.
Bye, Sebastian.
Later.
Yeah! Mm!
You did it.
♪ I'm goin' out with Olivia ♪
What the hell?! I thought
you liked Viola now!
Dude, come on.
You're a guy.
What would you do
if the hottest girl
in the school
came up to you
and asked you on a date?
I'll be right back.
Olivia? Hi. Can I talk
to you for a second?
Moi? Whatever for?
It's about your date
with Duke.
Oh! I know! I am
so glad I listened to you.
You're right.
He's awesome.
And he looked so good
in those shorts. Whoo!
He's not a piece
of meat, Olivia.
He's a man.
A man with feelings.
And I'm a woman
with feelings.
And my feelings
seem to match his.
You know what?
Speaking as
a completely objective
third-party observer
with absolutely no personal
interest in the matter,
I'm not so sure that you and
Duke are a good idea after all.
Well, thank you
for your concern.
And if you're so worried,
maybe you should come
to Cesario's tonight,
just to keep an eye on me.
We could double.
I bet Eunice is available.
I'm so there, it's insane.
So do you like... cheese?
Hey, you two, what's going on?
You're here...
...with Eunice.
Mind if we join?
- No. Sit down.
- No, no, no.
Lady pterodactyl.
Waiter!
Help.
So...
...I was just telling Duke
how great it is
to meet a real man
at this school.
Uh, you were?
Well, I was just about to.
Isn't it great to have
a real man around, Eunice?
Oh, yes.
A real man
is difficult to find.
So difficult.
Sebastian's with Eunice.
She must be hotter
than I thought.
How come when I wanted to ask out Eunice everyone made fun of me?
Now Sebastian likes her,
and suddenly she's cool?
Screw you guys.
I hate high school.
Eunice! Hands!
You know what?
This has been real fun,
but I have to go...
...shave.
OK.
Well, this has been lovely.
Um, let's do it again sometime.
What?
Soon. Bye.
So, um...
...do you like cheese?
More than almost
any other animal byproduct.
Yeah, check please.
Hey, Monique, it's Sebastian.
I don't know if Viola
told you I'm in London,
but I'm heading home
a day early.
Listen, I've been thinking,
and we really need to talk.
Ladies...
Ladies.
Welcome.
My name is Cheryl Lancaster.
I'm president
of the Stratford Junior League
and coordinator
of this year's debutante season.
Oh, please.
Thank you. Today we're
gonna go over the guidelines
for a graceful, ladylike
entrée into society.
Son of a...
Hello.
Hello there.
- Hi.
- Make sure she's in the back
for the group photo.
Thank you for joining us, Viola.
Now, who's ready to come out?
Kill me.
- Viola? Darling.
- Huh?
Remember, chew like
you have a secret.
Excuse me.
Ladies.
Hi
Hey.
Hey! You're the one
that saved me
in the kissing booth
that one time, right?
- Oh. Hi.
- Hi.
Oh, what a small world.
I'm Viola.
Olivia.
- Nice to meet you.
- You too.
So... Oh.
I know it's none
of my business,
but you went out with
that Duke Orsino guy, right?
Yeah. Once.
- Did you kiss him?
- No, why?
Oh, no. It's nothing,
but... Echh.
Just try to postpone it
as long as possible.
He has this, uh,
salivary gland condition.
Yeah. He doesn't really
like to talk about it,
but it felt like I was
drowning.
- Really?
- Mm.
- Oh, my God, ew.
- I know. It was repulsive.
But, hey, every happiness
to you both.
Uh... No, um, actually,
I don't really like Duke.
Um, I have this huge thing
for his roommate, Sebastian.
And I was just trying
to make Sebastian jealous.
Oh, boy.
Yeah, I know it's really wrong
to use a person this way,
and I feel
really terrible about it.
But I really, really
like Sebastian.
He's so handsome.
He's not the goonish handsome
you see in a lot of guys.
He's a delicate, like, even
refined handsome, you know?
Oh, and when he smiles, I just
can't stop looking at him.
He's just so wonderful.
You know, Olivia...
- It's Olivia, right?
- Yeah.
I'm gonna give you
just a little advice.
- OK.
- Enough is enough!
You are weaving
a really tangled web.
Yeah, like
really, really tangled.
And, um, honey...
...you got to stop!
OK? So you just gotta tell
everybody the truth.
Be very, very honest.
Just let the chips fall
where they may.
- You're right.
- I know.
The next time I see Sebastian
I'll march right up to him.
- You march!
- And I'll tell him how I feel.
You tell him.
Then I'll kiss him
so passionately...
- What?
- ...that even the people he hates will feel pleasure.
Hello, Viola.
Oh, this is not good.
And hello to you,
you little homewrecker.
Uh, who are you?
I am Sebastian's girlfriend.
Ex-girlfriend.
OK, everybody's got
to stop saying that.
Oh, you were the one he dumped in the pizza parlor the other day.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
He did not dump me.
We're just going through
a little bit of a rough patch.
Oh. I heard he dumped you.
He dumped you big.
It was just
like a big, huge dumping.
Ahh!
Are you crazy?!
Are you OK?
Get out!
You are messing
with the wrong man!
Get off me! Get off of me!
Oww!
Ahhh!
Oh!
Whoa! Whoa!
- Get off of her!
- Let go of me!
Ladies! Ladies, stop!
Please!
When debutantes disagree
they say it with their eyes.
Well, Hastings.
Why is it that I always find you
in the middle of a tussle?
Bad timing?
I am convinced
he's hiding something.
Oh, nonsense, Malcolm. He may
be a little lost and confused,
but deep down he's an
all-American, red-blooded male.
- Just like yourself.
- Mom, I will pick out
my own dress.
And no, I will not wear heels.
Because heels are
a male invention
designed to make
a woman's butt look smaller.
And to make it harder
for them to run away.
Malcolm, have you ever tried
to run away in high heels?
- No, sir, I wouldn't...
- Not that easy. Not that easy.
♪ Such a silly game
we play, ohh ♪
Don't forget your guitar,
Mr. Hastings.
Just do it. Just close
your eyes and kiss him.
Sebastian.
"Wake up. I've been waiting
for you to open your eyes
so I can tell you
that I think I'm ready.
I'm ready to free-fall
into the unknown."
I'll see you
at the game tomorrow.
I think I'm gonna
like this school.
Monique, it's Sebastian.
I don't know if Viola
told you I'm in London,
but I'm heading home
a day early.
Listen, I've been thinking.
We really need to talk.
London?
Ooh!
Hey, brother. Dinklage
was looking for you, man.
Dude. Hello!
You know, it's, um, crazy
how wrong you can be
about a person.
Huh, it's crazy.
You know, you think
that they're one thing,
and then they turn out
to be the exact opposite.
- What are you talking about?
- You're gonna sit there
and act like you don't
know what I'm talking about?
OK.
All right. OK.
I wanted to tell you,
Duke, but...
...you have to know...
...I love soccer more than
anything else in the world,
and I had a point to prove.
What?! So you're telling me
that you used me
to help you with soccer,
and then you turn around
and stab me in the back?
Wait, what? Now I really don't
know what you're talking about.
Save it, man.
I saw you with her.
- With who?!
- Who?! Olivia, that's who!
You kissed her
when you got out the cab!
- What cab?!
- We were supposed to be friends!
- We are friends!
- You don't know the meaning of the word!
Olivia never liked you, OK?!
She was just using you
to make me jealous.
But Viola, she's
crazy about you.
She has been since the first
moment that you kissed her.
I bet that's part of your plan.
Distract me so you can move in next to Olivia.
- That is not what happened!
- You... you and your sister have a good life!
"The Hastings twins
couldn't be more opposite."
- Twins?
- Sebastian?
Sebastian?
Sebastian, open up!
It's Monique! You have got
a lot of explaining to do,
followed by a very long night
of groveling!
- He's not here!
- Uhh.
Take his stupid cell phone.
Justine calls every 10 seconds.
This isn't
Sebastian's phone.
God! Sebastian!
- Sebastian! Ew! Ew!
- Can I help you?
- Hello?
- Viola. Hey, baby.
It's Justin. You know,
the big game is tomorrow and...
Viola.
Allow me to introduce myself.
2003, 2004, 2005, 2006, 2007...
Nice night. ...2008.
Hey, Eunice.
Sorry about running out
on our date.
Oh, that's OK. My intensity
scares some people.
Yeah.
Is something wrong?
Got thrown out of my room.
You mean... you need
a place to sleep?
I really do. I mean,
the Cornwall game is tomorrow.
I've never had
a roommate before.
Wow. Vi, you set up
all my stuff.
Thanks.
♪ Hey, hey ♪
♪ See we gotta get it right
but we always get it wrong ♪
♪ And it be the same old thing
and it be the same old song ♪
♪ Tryin' to fight to survive
Tryin' to fight for our lives ♪
♪ See I'm only tryin' to live
I don't wanna say goodbye ♪
And you're absolutely
certain about this?
Yes, sir, we are.
Dude, what are you doing?!
Sebastian, the game's
about to start!
Get out of bed and get
over to the soccer field, man!
The soccer game?
That's what that girl
was talking about.
Sebastian! You're next.
Hurry up.
Come over here,
and I'll do you.
OK, ladies, listen up.
Where's Hastings?
Euni...
Eunice!
Why didn't you wake me?!
You looked so serene.
I made breakfast, darling.
Pardon me. Pardon me.
What is the big emergency?
I canceled my squash game
for this.
I don't know.
All that Principal Gold said
was that we were needed
at Sebastian's soccer game.
Hasn't Viola said anything
to you the past couple of weeks?
How should I know?
She's been living with you.
Hasn't she?
- Excuse me.
- This is so exciting, guys.
Welcome,
ladies and gentlemen.
Today, the biggest rivalry
in our district is afoot.
Illyria versus Cornwall.
It's gonna be something else,
and the atmosphere is crazy!
Afternoon, gentlemen.
Handshake, please.
All right, your call.
Heads.
Heads it is.
We'll stay as we are.
Good game, gentlemen.
How's your jaw?
All right, let's get it on!
Way to go, boys.
Listen to me. We can do this.
Today is the day
- Cornwall beats Illyria.
- Yeah!
I ain't got much to say to you.
Except for, who's gonna bring that blood and pain?!
- Black and red!
This ain't gonna be no game. This is a war!
- Yeah!
Who's gonna bring
that blood and pain?!
- One, two, three!
- Cornwall!
Whoo!
All right, boys,
here we go!
♪ Let me know
that I've done wrong ♪
Hastings! Pass it off!
Pass it off! Hastings!
What in the hell is going on?!
Nice move, moron.
What?
This can't be happening.
Sebastian?
♪ Don't tell anyone, or you'll
be just another regret ♪
Get the ball! Get the ball!
Get up and get back
in there! Get the ball!
Oh, my God, this is my game!
What the hell am I doing here?
This isn't fun.
Christ! You look like
Bambi on ice, boy!
Sebastian!
Can I get a timeout, please?
A pause?
One brief halftime?
- Stopping the clock.
- That's it. Stop the clock.
What the...?
I don't know
the technical lingo.
Armadillos.
Fighting Armadillos, please.
I need... Gather around.
I played soccer once as a young man.
Or was it chess?
Is there a problem, principal?
Yes. Unfortunately there is.
But I think it's only right
that Sebastian Hastings
tell you himself.
Sebastian? Son? Or...
Do you have anything
you'd like to say?
Ahhh...
I'm sorry I'm not
a very good soccer player.
I see.
Well then, please know
that what I say...
...I say with a heavy heart.
Ladies and gentlemen,
esteemed alumni,
friends and family
of Sebastian Hastings,
I am grievously sad...
- Uh-oh.
- ...to inform you that Sebastian Hastings
Is... a girl.
I'm sorry, it's for your own good.
You'll thank me for it someday.
Oh, OK. Certainly. Yes.
Excuse me. I'm not a girl.
Hello! Yes.
In fact, yes, he is.
He's a big girl.
He's actually specifically
his own sister, Viola,
who's been impersonating him
for reasons which
will become very clear
after extensive
psychoanalysis.
Folks.
I'm a boy. I promise.
- Prove it.
- OK.
Oh!
God! I saw it.
Nice work, Paul. Wow.
That's my boy.
Kevin, close your eyes.
Soccer is
the world's favorite sport.
Thank you. Thank you.
Nothing to see here.
No offense.
Folks, please, hang on
for one second.
Just talk amongst
yourselves for a second.
Malcolm!
Can you shed some light
on the current situation?
Not any more than has
already been shed, sir.
OK, lads, listen up now.
Now that we've
established this boy...
...is a boy...
...is it possible
we can get back to our game?
Yes. Oh! Um, enjoy.
That was a skit we...
OK. Yes.
Let's get to it, guys.
Come on.
- I know, let's play.
- Waste of time.
Baby. Baby, baby, baby.
I have missed you so much.
Oh, my God,
we are both so dead.
We're over, Monique. Done.
God! Not again!
Yah!
Good work, Hastings.
Bench.
Good one!
Halftime, gentlemen.
,
Sebastian!
- Vi?
- Yes.
Why do you look like me?!
I pretended to be you
the last two weeks
so I could prove I could
play in the boys soccer team.
- Yes.
- OK. OK, cool.
- No, wait! What?!
- I don't have time to explain! Why are you wearing my uniform?
- I came to find the amazing girl that kissed me last night.
- Who kissed you? What girl?
Check it out. That one.
Olivia?
She was all over me.
She kissed me and then recited my own lyrics.
Vi, this may be
the girl of my dreams.
That's the kiss that Duke saw.
Wait, are those real?
Yeah. I'm growing sideburns now.
No! Please stay hidden
until the end of the game.
And give me my uniform
back right now!
We start the second half.
Illyria, zero, Cornwall, zero.
Nothing but a couple
of goose eggs.
Coach, I'm ready to play.
Is that what you call it?
I've seen little girls in tutus
kick the ball better.
I've changed.
Come on, coach,
give me one more chance.
All right. Go.
Kick. Kill!
- Yeah! Now That's Viola!
- Oww!
♪ Oh, oh, oh
Invincible ♪
♪ Invincible ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
You couldn't score on me
in the first half.
You ain't going to score on me this half, baby!
I'm ninja! Ninja goalie!
♪ Oh, invincible
Invincible, oh ♪
♪ Invincible
You're invincible ♪
♪ Na, na, na-na-na-na
Na, na, na-na-na-na ♪
Come on, guys!
♪ Na, na, na-na-na-na
Na, na, na-na-na-na ♪
♪ Invincible ♪
♪ That crushing, crashing ♪
♪ Atom-smashing
white-hot thing ♪
♪ Invincible ♪
♪ You're invincible
Invincible ♪
♪ Na, na, na-na-na-na
Na, na, na-na-na-na ♪
♪ Invincible ♪
♪ That crushing, crashing ♪
♪ Atom-smashing
white-hot thing ♪
♪ Invincible ♪
Duke! Duke! I'm open!
Give me the ball!
Duke! Hey, over here!
I'm open!
Duke! Get back! Get back!
No!
Yes, Dan-O, way to go, baby!
Whoo!
And Cornwall's right
back in it with a goal.
Whoo-hoo!
What's the matter?!
Sebastian was open!
Rather lose the goal
than let him score?!
Shut up, man.
Duke, I know you're mad at me.
- Don't talk to me.
- I didn't do what you...
- Get out of my face!
- Nothing is going on with me and Olivia!
When the game is
over I'll explain!
But for right now, you don't have to like me,
but I'm your teammate, OK?!
And I want to beat these guys!
I have to beat these guys!
If we're not disturbing you,
we have a soccer game we'd like to finish.
Get back in the net, man.
Or what? You'll hit my
fist with your face again?
Do you want to see me do it?
Come on, let's go!
Duke, come on. Stop it.
- Come on!
- Duke, stop it.
Sebastian!
Duke! Stop it!
Come on!
- Ah!
- OK!
Stop it! Oh, my God!
If you want to roughhouse,
please take it at least 500 yards
- away from the stadium grounds.
- Break it up! Break it up!
OK, tough guys.
You want to box?
You get out of my stadium.
Otherwise, get on
with the game. All right?
Come on, now,
Armadillos of Illyria.
That goes for
the rest of you!
Now get on and play
some real football!
- Like a bunch of girls.
- OK.
The rest of you,
let's play some real football like a bunch of girls.
- All right?
- You suck!
It's not football, it's soccer.
That's what we call it in the States.
- Sebastian! Are you OK?
- Uh-oh.
No, Olivia, Not now.
Try to tell me again
there's nothing going on.
There is nothing going on!
What about last night?
I didn't lie to you, Duke.
I did, but not about this.
Here's the truth.
I love you.
- Huh?
- I beg your pardon?
What? All right... What're you...?
That's just a little weird.
OK, you know what?
I can't do this anymore.
Everybody, I have
something to tell you.
I'm not Sebastian.
I'm Viola.
Wait. You're not Viola.
- Yes, I am.
- No, I know Viola.
- I... I kissed Viola.
- You kissed me.
What are you talking about?
I didn't kiss you.
The girls' team
at Cornwall got cut.
The guys wouldn't let
me go out for their team.
So I've been pretending
to be my brother
while he was in London
for the past two weeks... Ow.
...so I could make
the team and beat Cornwall. Ow.
Whoa!
But my brother
came home early.
And that's who you saw kissing Olivia and that's who played the first half.
Just because you wear a wig
doesn't prove you're a girl.
OK, then.
Merciful Jesus.
Yeah! Whoo-hoo!
- Viola?!
- Is it just me
or does this soccer game
have more nudity than most?
All right,
so everybody understand?
- Yeah. I get it.
- OK.
Wait a minute. If I kissed
your brother, where is he?
Probably halfway to China.
He showed his willis and doodleberries...
- Present.
- Oh. Hi.
What the...?
OK, this is freaking me out.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I hate to say "I told you so," but I just... Ow.
See, Duke?
I didn't betray you.
I'm sorry.
This isn't how
I wanted it to happen,
and I didn't
want to hurt you.
But I just wanted to
prove that I was good enough.
All I'm asking for
is a chance.
Duke?
It's just like what coach says
before every game:
"Be not afraid of greatness.
Some are born great.
Some achieve greatness.
And some have greatness
thrust upon them."
I think the best chance for us to be great here today is to have you play.
- Yeah!
- All right!
Yeah! Yeah! No!
No playing!
You have to forfeit.
There's no girls in this league.
Here. Look in the manual.
What manual?
Listen, pal.
You're in Illyria.
We don't discriminate
based on gender.
All right.
That's gonna bruise.
Fine. You really
think you can beat us
with a girl on your team?
This should be fun.
Go.
I get to say the last word,
not you. Go.
OK, team...
- ...let's go kick! Kill!
- Yeah!
Come on! Come on!
Well, folks,
this is a real nail-biter.
It's a tie score at the bottom of the second half.
,, Come on,
come on! Open up!
What?
Foul? That's not a foul!
He got all ball!
And the penalty kick
will decide the game.
Where you gonna kick it?
Right here?
I know you're
gonna kick it there.
Am I in your head?
You see the goal?
It's getting smaller and I'm getting bigger.
Come on.
I love you.
Concentrate.
Don't kick like a girl.
Guys are better.
It's not gonna happen.
You're a loser!
This is my house!
You're pathetic!
I'm in your head.
Yeah!
- That's my girl!
- Mine too!
It's not fair!
That was a lucky shot!
I never wanna see you again!
You suck!
- You did it, Vi!
- You were so awesome!
- I am so proud of you.
- It's over.
You just scored the game-winning goal.
Say something.
Mom? Dad?
- That was really something.
- Thanks, Dad.
You did all this to play soccer?
I told you,
it's important to me.
If Viola was here
pretending to be you,
- where were you?
- Oh, he was, um...
I was in London
playing my music.
- London?
- It was important to me.
Mom, Dad... Hey!
Why don't we go to dinner?
As a family?
- Maybe tomorrow?
- I suppose I could fit that in.
Would you like to have
my cell phone number?
- Let me give you my email.
- All right.
Yay!
- Good job.
- Thank you.
Oh, wait!
There is somebody I want you to officially meet.
Sebastian Hastings,
Olivia Lennox.
- It's very nice to meet you.
- You too.
So, uh, I heard
you like my lyrics.
- Eunice?
- Toby?
I have something to say.
I think you are...
...amazing.
And I'm not ashamed of it.
I know tricks.
Oh, Eunice.
♪ When you came to me ♪
♪ With your bad dreams
and your fears ♪
♪ It was easy to see ♪
♪ That you'd been crying ♪
♪ Seems like
everywhere you turn ♪
Hey, roomie.
This is for you.
♪ But who really profits
from the dying ♪
♪ I could hold you in my arms ♪
♪ I could hold you forever ♪
"The Stratford Junior League
invites you
to the 38th Annual
Debutante Ball."
- He still could show, you know.
- You didn't see his face.
I found the perfect dress.
Aw, thanks, Mom,
but I don't think I'm gonna
get a chance to wear it.
Nonsense.
You don't need a man
to wear a beautiful dress.
But it doesn't hurt.
Viola Hastings,
it would be my honor
to escort you tonight.
Thanks, Paul.
That's really sweet.
Caterpillars! Caterpillars!
My precious caterpillars.
In 20 minutes you'll all
be beautiful butterflies.
Caterpillars!
Butterflies!
You look beautiful.
I just... I gotta get some air.
I didn't think you'd show up.
It really means a lot to me
that you're here.
Say something.
I gotta turn
the sprinklers on.
Sorry.
Hi.
So, what brings you here?
Well, a few days ago,
I kissed this girl
at a kissing booth.
And now I just can't seem
to stop thinking about it.
Neither can she.
Plus,
I miss my roommate.
I really liked him.
Well...
...he's right in here.
Listen, I know I should've
told you who I was but...
...I was afraid.
- Sorry.
- Well,
you know, maybe if I'd have
known you were a girl,
we wouldn't have talked
like we did
and got to know each other
the same way.
And that would
have been a shame.
Just so you know,
everything you told me
when I was a guy just...
...made me like you
so much more as a girl.
OK, but just
from here on in,
everything would just
be a lot easier
if you stayed a girl.
I promise.
Monique Valentine,
escorted by Justin Drayton.
Justin, you're the man!
Olivia Lennox, escorted
by Sebastian Hastings.
Viola Hastings,
escorted by Paul Antonio.
Viola Hastings.
This is typical.
Well, where is she?
Whoo!
♪ Go ahead as you waste
your days with thinking ♪
♪ When you fall
everyone stands ♪
♪ Another day, and you've
had your fill of sinking ♪
♪ With the life
held in your... ♪
♪ Hands are shaking cold ♪
♪ These hands
are meant to hold ♪
♪ Speak to me ♪
♪ When all you got
to keep is strong ♪
♪ Move along, move along
like I know ya do ♪
♪ And even when
your hope is gone ♪
♪ Move along, move along
just to make it through ♪
♪ Move along ♪
♪ So a day when you've
lost yourself completely ♪
♪ Could be a night
when your life ends ♪
♪ Such a heart that
will lead you to deceiving ♪
♪ All the pain held
in your... ♪
♪ Hands are shaking cold ♪
♪ Your hands
are mine to hold ♪
♪ Speak to me, when all you
got to keep is strong ♪
♪ Move along, move along
like I know you do ♪
♪ And even when your hope
is gone ♪
♪ Move along, move along
just to make it through ♪
♪ Move along
Go on, go on, go on, go on ♪
♪ When everything is wrong ♪
♪ We move along ♪
♪ Go on, go on, go on, go on ♪
♪ When everything is wrong ♪
♪ We move along ♪
♪ Along ♪
♪ When all you got
to keep is strong ♪
♪ Move along, move along
like I know you do ♪
♪ And even when
your hope is gone ♪
♪ Move along, move along
just to make it through ♪
♪ When all you got
to keep is strong ♪
♪ Move along, move along
like I know you do ♪
♪ And even when
your hope is gone ♪
♪ Move along, move along
just to make it through ♪
♪ Just to make it through ♪
♪ When all you got to keep
is strong ♪
♪ Move along, move along
like I know you do ♪
♪ I know you do ♪
♪ And even when
your hope is gone ♪
♪ Move along, move along
just to make it through ♪
♪ Move along ♪
♪ Go on, go on, go on, go on ♪
♪ Right back what is wrong ♪
♪ We move along ♪
♪ Go on, go on, go on, go on ♪
♪ Right back what is wrong ♪
♪ We move along ♪
♪ Go on, go on, go on, go on ♪
♪ Right back what is wrong ♪
♪ We move along ♪
♪ Go on, go on,
go on, go on ♪