Once upon a time,
there was a king named William
who ruled a large and mighty kingdom.
And yet he was sad,
for he was growing old and had
no child to inherit the throne.
Then, happily, a daughter was born.
A princess.
And she was given the name Odette.
Kings and queens came from all around
to offer their gifts to the child.
Among them was the widow Uberta
and her young son, Prince Derek.
It was then that William and
Uberta happened upon the same idea.
Derek and Odette would be brought together each
summer in hopes that they would fall in love
and join their kingdoms forever.
But unknown to all was another plan,
that of the evil enchanter Rothbart.
Odette's birth was of
little concern to him.
For he was preparing to
take William's kingdom
by means of the forbidden arts.
On the eve of his
assault, William attacked,
and Rothbart's powers were
plunged into darkness.
Despite calls for his death,
the enchanter was only banished.
I'm not finished with you yet, William.
Someday I'll get my power back.
And when I do, everything you
own, everything you love
will be mine.
Many feared King William too kind.
But in time, the threat was forgotten.
And all hopes turned to
that not-too-distant summer,
when Derek and Odette would meet.
Here they come. Oh!
Dear Uberta, as lovely as ever.
Oh. A nest. Heh-heh.
And who might this strapping young man be?
Young Prince Derek, no doubt.
Welcome to our fair kingdom, dear William.
And to you, young princess.
Go on, Derek.
Dear, go on.
- Mother.
- Derek.
Hello, Princess Odette.
I'm very pleased to meet you.
Pleased to meet you, Prince Derek.
Ah, ah, ah.
Yuck!
♪ I can't believe I'm stuck with her all summer ♪
♪ I'll bet she doesn't wrestle, hunt or box ♪
- ♪ He looks conceited ♪
- ♪ What a total bummer ♪
♪ If I get lucky, I'll get chickenpox ♪
- ♪ So happy you could come ♪
- ♪ So happy to be here ♪
♪ How I'd like to run ♪
- ♪ This is not my idea ♪
- ♪ This isn't my idea ♪
♪ Of fun ♪
♪ The children seem to get along quite nicely ♪
♪ We'll join our lands if this arrangement clicks ♪
♪ My dear King William
That's my point precisely ♪
- ♪ It's such good parenting ♪
- ♪ And politics ♪
- ♪ So happy we agree ♪
- ♪ I think we've got a deal ♪
♪ Derek's quite a catch ♪
♪ This is my idea ♪
♪ Of a match ♪
Heh-heh. And such fun.
♪ Good heavens, child, don't dawdle
We can't keep Derek waiting ♪
♪ I haven't packed or washed my hair
And, Father, I get seasick ♪
♪ They soon will be arriving
Is that respect you're showing? ♪
♪ If you make me kiss her hand again
I swear I'm gonna be sick ♪
♪ One day Prince Derek will be her intended ♪
Heh-heh. Splendid.
♪ We've tried all summer
But we just can't lose her ♪
- Hey, fellas, wait up!
- Quick, put on some speed.
- ♪ When picking teams ♪
- ♪ Or friends ♪
♪ I'd never choose her ♪
♪ You'd think she'd take a hint and learn to read ♪
- ♪ This really isn't fair ♪
- ♪ We really couldn't care ♪
♪ Boys, it's all or none ♪
♪ This is not my idea ♪
- ♪ This isn't my idea ♪
- ♪ Of fun ♪
♪ Long before they met ♪
♪ Derek and Odette ♪
♪ Were destined to be wedded ♪
♪ However anyone could see ♪
♪ The only point on which they didn't disagree ♪
♪ Was that the very thought of summertime ♪
♪ Was dreaded ♪
♪ She tries to talk me into playing dress-up ♪
♪ She's always flirting with the castle guards ♪
♪ I think you really sort of like her, fess up ♪
♪ I'd like her better if she'd lose at cards ♪
- ♪ Four sevens and a 10 ♪
- ♪ I think I've won again ♪
♪ Every time she's won ♪
- ♪ This is my idea of fun ♪
- ♪ This isn't my idea of fun ♪
♪ We need a royal wedding
I'd love to be invited ♪
♪ At least we'd get a holiday
To rest our plows and axes ♪
♪ Someday these two will marry
Two lands will be united ♪
♪ And with some luck their marriage
May result in lower taxes ♪
- ♪ What if Odette doesn't go for the merger? ♪
- ♪ Urge her ♪
♪ For as long as I remember
We've been told we'd someday wed ♪
♪ Every June until September ♪
♪ All their pushing and annoying hints ♪
♪ I've got bruises with their fingerprints ♪
♪ I can do much better, I am sure ♪
♪ He's so immature ♪
♪ I see him smiling and my knees start buckling ♪
♪ I see inside him and my doubts are gone ♪
♪ She started out as such an ugly duckling ♪
♪ And somehow suddenly became a swan ♪
- ♪ So happy to be here ♪
- ♪ Till now I never knew ♪
♪ It is you I've been dreaming of ♪
♪ This is my idea ♪
♪ What a good idea
Such a charming and romantic notion ♪
♪ This is my idea, such a good idea ♪
♪ Such a powerful and magic potion ♪
♪ This is exactly my idea ♪
♪ Of love ♪
♪ This is my idea ♪
♪ Of love ♪♪
Arrange the marriage.
Wait.
What? You're all I ever wanted.
You're beautiful.
- Thank you. But what else?
- What else?
Is beauty all that matters to you?
Derek?
What else?
I... Uh...
What else is there?
We tried, Uberta.
No one can say we didn't try.
- Say goodbye, Odette.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye...?
- Prince Derek.
- Mother.
- Derek.
Goodbye, princess.
All these years of planning...
wasted!
"What else is there?" She says,
"Is beauty all that matters?"
And you say, "What else is there?"
It was dumb, I know.
You should write a book: How to Offend
Women in Five Syllables or Less.
Heh-heh. Your turn, Prince Derek.
I didn't know what else to say.
- You lost your queen, Derek.
- That's twice in one day.
Think. You must see something
other than Odette's beauty.
Ha! Of course I do, Rogers. She's like...
You know. And how about...?
And then...
I mean, right?
I don't know how to say it.
I'll prove it to her.
I'll prove my love. Checkmate.
Huh?
Today's the day, Willie.
Everything you own,
everything you love will be mine.
I just don't understand.
What else did you want him to say?
I need to know that he
loves me for just being me.
Whoa! Whoa.
Stay inside, Odette.
It's King William's captain.
We...
We were attacked. A great animal.
- Odette.
- Derek, wait!
Odette!
Odette?
King William.
Derek...
Who did this?
It came so quickly. A great animal.
Where is Odette?
Listen to me, Derek.
It's not what it seems.
What's not? Where is Odette?
Odette is...
Odette is... gone.
Odette!
Now, don't let my little
spell make you sad, Odette,
it doesn't even last the whole day.
As soon as the moon comes up...
And that's how it works every night.
You have to be on the lake, of course.
And when the moonlight touches your wings...
Now, look, Odette, this sort of thing
doesn't give me any pleasure.
Well, maybe a teensy bit.
But what I really want
is your father's kingdom.
Take it, then. You have enough power.
Nah, tried that already.
Once you steal something,
you spend your whole life fighting to keep it.
But if I marry the only
heir to the throne...
we'll rule your father's kingdom together, legally.
King and queen. You know.
Never.
Where are you going?
As soon as moonlight leaves the lake,
you'll turn back into a swan,
no matter where you are.
- The musicians are not happy.
- I know, but I have to practice.
Oh, no complaints here.
I think it's going to be loads of... fun.
The great animal is never gonna
give her up without a fight.
You're not still thinking she's alive?
When I find the great animal,
Rogers, I'll find Odette.
Oh, Derek, you've looked everywhere.
She's not coming back.
- The whole kingdom knows that.
- The whole kingdom's wrong.
Odette's alive, and I'm gonna find her.
Ready, Brom?
No peeking.
Animals, assemble!
Lord Rogers, I must object.
We are musicians.
The servants have the day off.
We had to use someone.
- But I'm an artist, not a boar.
- Could have fooled me.
Come on, guys. They're harmless.
♪ We are a band
And not a band of animals ♪
♪ This masquerade
Is more than I can bear ♪
♪ There goes my reputation
It's awful, this humiliation ♪
♪ And I've the lion's share ♪
Down on all fours, please,
and growl ferociously!
Liven it up a bit!
I want you to strike fear into my heart!
Not you, Wesley.
You're a rabbit, for heaven's sake.
Archers. Ready.
Set.
Go!
- Duck.
- Yes?
- Duck!
- What?
♪ Day after day, all the prince ever does ♪
♪ Is practice, practice, practice ♪
♪ Thinking of her and the way that it was ♪
♪ Practice, practice, practice ♪
♪ He's not happy till he has attacked us ♪
Twelve seconds.
♪ Day after day all the prince ever does
Practice, practice, practice ♪
♪ Thinking of her and the way that it was
♪ If we had refused
He would have sacked us ♪
Five seconds!
- ♪ So we face a life of target practice ♪
- Three!
- Two!
- ♪ Practice, practice, practice! ♪♪
Time! Animals, assemble for counting.
Uh-huh. Very good, very good.
You scored plenty of
five-pointers, that's for sure.
Sorry, Hans.
Why don't you take a few days off?
Moose are worth two points.
Sixteen hits, a total of 32.
Ten seven-pointers and 14 three-pointers.
For a total of... 298!
Well done, Derek.
Now, Bromley, let's see. For you...
Zero, and zero, and
nothing, and nil, and zip.
And last but not least,
the elusive 100-point white rabbit...
- I believe that's 300, Rogers.
- Good shooting, Brom.
Well? Write it down. Three hundred to 298.
Oh, but wait just a moment, Rogers.
Sorry, Brom.
You're a great marksman, Derek.
One of the best.
But it takes more than good aim.
It takes courage. That's my forte.
Well, then, how about a quick
round of "Catch and Fire"?
Catch and fire? You mean, me?
You're the only one with enough
c-courage.
- Are you sure you're all right?
- Mm-hm.
Fine, I'm fine.
Oh! Too tight. Too tight.
Whoops. So sorry.
Ready?
He's ready.
Remember now, aim for the heart.
Right between the shoulders.
Oh, please, oh, please, oh, please.
Come on, Brom. Hold it steady.
Oh, please, oh, please. Oh, please.
Now!
Whew!
Fifty-two out of 52! Well done, Derek!
Extraordinary courage, man.
Just think, one inch lower
and that arrow would have...
Don't lose hope, Odette.
Wherever you are, I'm gonna find you.
Quiet! I cannot concentrate.
You've come up with some dumb ideas, Jean-Bob,
but this one is a doozy.
Ha! Go ahead and laugh. I'll get her to kiss me.
And when she does...
And when she does, poof. You'll change into a prince.
I know, I know, you've told me.
Why don't you just give her these flowers?
These are pretty.
Ha! What a love-dunce.
I don't want these flowers, I must have those.
When she learns that I have
risked my life for them,
the kissing will not stop.
- And then you'll change into a prince?
- Precisely.
- Mind if I point out a problem?
- I don't take advice from peasants.
Suit yourself.
Flowers, kiss, concentration.
Just curious, how are you gonna get back?
Hurry, hurry!
Move up! Move up! No, not that.
Close!
Grab me! Grab me! Hold my arm! Hold my leg!
Hold my-- Hold it, hold it, hold it.
Oh, thank you, Odette.
Thank you. Let me have that.
Silence, you savages.
Ha-ha! Ungh!
Are you all right, Jean-Bob?
Jean-Bob?
Oui, oui, oui, Odette. Yes, I'm all right.
- What in the world were you trying to do?
- He thought that if--
Shush! I wanted to get
those flowers for you.
You're being sneaky again, Jean-Bob.
- What sneaky? You deserve a nice bouquet.
- And you deserve a kiss.
Well, all right.
- You know I'm under a spell.
- But my kiss will break the spell.
Give it up, Jean-Bob.
I can only kiss the man I love.
- And then he--
- Must make a vow of everlasting love.
And prove it to the world.
What do you think I was doing with the flowers
and the alligators going chomp-chomp?
- Speed, make him understand.
- I'm only a turtle.
♪ If I could break this spell
I'd run to him today ♪
♪ And somehow I know
He's on his way to me ♪
♪ Derek, you and I were meant to be ♪
♪ For longer than forever ♪
♪ I'll hold you in my heart ♪
♪ It's almost like you're here with me ♪
♪ Although we're far apart ♪
♪ For longer than forever ♪
♪ As constant as a star ♪
♪ I close my eyes ♪
♪ And I am where you are ♪
♪ Sure as the dawn brings the
sunrise We've an unshakable bond ♪
♪ Destined to last for a lifetime and beyond ♪
♪ For longer than forever ♪
♪ I swear that I'll be true ♪
- ♪ I've made an everlasting vow ♪
- ♪ An everlasting vow ♪
♪ To find a way to you ♪
♪ For longer than forever ♪
♪ Like no love ever known ♪
♪ And with your love ♪
♪ I'll never be alone ♪
♪ For longer than forever ♪
♪ Much stronger than forever ♪
♪ And with your love ♪
♪ I'll never be alone ♪♪
Oh!
- You think he's dead?
- No, it's just his wing, I think.
- Strange-looking bird.
- Ooh!
Poor fellow. He must be in a lot of pain.
You'd better hold him.
- Ooh!
- Ready.
Hello. This is your wake-up call.
It takes more than a pair of pond punks
to keep Puffin down. Hiyah!
Wait. I'm your friend.
If you were me friend,
how come you have an arrow in your hand? Huh?
- Yes, the exact kind of arrow I have--
- Heh-heh.
Um...
I took it out while you were laying there.
You mean, you had a chance to
"krkk" and instead you "fft"?
Uh-huh.
Madam, I apologize. Me name is Puffin.
Lieutenant Puffin.
It's a pleasure, Lieutenant Puffin.
I'm Odette, Princess Odette.
And these are my best friends in the whole world.
Mr. Lorenzo Trudgealong...
- Friends call me Speed.
- And Jean-Bob.
I have no friends, only servants.
They call me "Your Highness."
Thinks he's a prince.
Ahem. I owe you, princess.
And I intend on staying until me debt is paid.
I don't think there's much you can do.
He has me under a spell.
What? You mean, a magical...?
Your knight in shining armor has come
to set you free. Heh-heh.
Let me at him. Let me at him. I'll...
Chill.
All it takes is just one little word.
Will you... marry me?
- Every night you ask the same question.
- No, no.
- And every night I give you the same answer.
- Don't!
- I'll die first.
- You're really starting to bug me.
- I should think you'd be used to it by now.
- That's it! Just keep pushing it.
But someday I'm gonna boil over!
Go ahead, then! But I'll never
give you my father's kingdom.
I was hoping you'd say you'd be mine,
but it looks as if you need
another day to think about it.
No.
Princess?
Beautiful. Simply beautiful.
Soon Derek will be married,
and the kingdom will have a king again.
I doubt it. Derek refuses to be king,
unless he finds Odette.
Oh, poppycock. All that will
change at tomorrow night's ball.
They're all coming to the ball. Ha-ha-ha!
Every princess is coming.
Oh, goody, oh, my. Oh, this is wonderful.
You see, Rogers.
One of these is bound to change his mind.
Oh, absolutely... not.
- Do not lose one.
- Oh, no. No. No, no.
Where is Derek?
Oh, never mind, I know where he is,
working on the mystery of the fat animal.
- The great animal, Your Highness.
- Big, great. It's large and has fur.
Listen, Derek, it's not what it seems.
What did King William mean?
It's not what it seems... Of course.
It's not what it seems.
Now I'll find you, Odette.
They're coming, Derek!
Oh, Derek, where are you going?
- To find the great animal.
- Oh, wonderful.
Just make sure you're here tomorrow night.
Tomorrow night?
The ball.
Mother, I can't.
Oh, please, Mother. Don't do the lip thing.
If I leave now,
maybe I can be back in time.
Thank you, darling.
But please, Mother, don't turn it
into one of your beauty pageants.
Oh! No, no, no. It's just a few
friends and their daughters.
I want this to be big.
Every princess must have
her own introduction.
- But you said--
- Forget what I said.
Now, send for the cooks.
And tell the band to start rehearsing.
And I want four footmen
for every carriage. Ha-ha!
Maybe five.
Let me get this straight.
Every night, when the moonlight leaves the lake, you...
Right.
The following night, if I want to turn back into a human,
I have to be on the lake.
Hmph. All she needs is a little moonlight.
Me, I have to be smooched.
No fear. You fly to your prince,
we bring him back to the lake,
the moon comes up,
you change into a princess, and:
Happily ever after.
- How will I find him?
- You don't know where he is?
I don't even know where I am.
- I bet he does.
- Oh, that's a great idea.
Just say, "Monsieur Rothbart, I'd like to leave now.
Do you have a map or something?"
Ah! That's it.
A map.
- Ah!
- Let's do it.
♪ We're off on a mission
We're tough, in good condition ♪
- ♪ We're short ♪
- ♪ But standing tall ♪
♪ No fear! ♪
- ♪ There's danger around us ♪
- ♪ They'd hurt us if they found us ♪
♪ Our backs are to the wall ♪
♪ No fear! ♪
♪ 'Cause we have all the courage we require ♪
♪ Take it from a frequent flyer ♪
♪ Try your luck, our plan will fly ♪
♪ No fear! ♪
It's hanging on the wall
in the upper chamber.
Odette can keep a lookout
while we get the map.
- "We"?
- You're not going to help us?
♪ This plan if applied
Will be simply suicidal ♪
- ♪ You'll be a sitting duck ♪
- ♪ No fear! ♪
♪ Suppose that I do this
Who knows if we'll live through this ♪
♪ How about a kiss for luck? ♪
- ♪ No ♪
- ♪ Fear ♪
♪ Our team is shy
One green webbed-footed volunteer ♪
- ♪ No way, Jose, no chance ♪
- ♪ No choice ♪
♪ No fear ♪♪
No, stop it! Stop it! No!
- All right, quickly.
- Easy for you to say.
Ouch.
Whenever I have to do something quick,
I always bring a turtle.
I think I pulled a muscle.
I'm gonna die! I know it!
I'm on a dangerous mission with a lame turtle.
You're going to get us all killed.
Beat ya.
♪ We will take any dare
That the other side'll dare to dream up ♪
♪ We play tough, we play fair
But we're sure to win because we'll team up ♪♪
- Ah!
- Yikes.
Head for the door.
All right, Jean-Bob goes deep.
Speed gets the hand-off.
Ready?
Break.
Set, hut-hut.
I'm open, I'm open.
- Get that map.
- Ah!
Ha! Uh-huh!
Saved ya.
Ah!
Reach.
Hey, batter, batter, batter.
Oh, the crowd's going wild.
♪ No fear! ♪
♪ If only one of us knew how to steer ♪
- ♪ Get a grip ♪
- ♪ Get set ♪
♪ That's our best bet ♪
- ♪ No brakes ♪
- ♪ No sweat ♪
♪ And no regret ♪
- ♪ We're dead ♪
- ♪ Not yet ♪
♪ Oh, no, no ♪
Save me.
♪ No fear! ♪♪
There's Derek's kingdom. When do we leave?
- It's a mouse.
- The great animal.
Ha-ha. A tad small, wouldn't you say?
Yeah, until it changes into this.
An animal that can change its shape.
A harmless creature approaches,
then suddenly it's too late.
- You mean, it could be anything?
- Anything.
Odette, I apologize for
the way I've been acting.
It's all right, Jean-Bob.
No, no. This Derek is very important to you,
and all I can do is think of myself.
Everyone does that.
Please, Odette, don't make this more difficult
than it already is.
- Accept my apology, please.
- Okay. I accept.
Good. Now we can kiss and make up.
Jean-Bob.
What? What did I say? What? What?
Ten-hut.
It is zero hour, troops.
- Odette, prepare for takeoff.
- Right.
The rest of you have your assignments.
Is everyone ready?
Ready for action, sir.
How about you, Jean-Bob?
Jean-Bob?
- Highness.
- Oui, I am ready.
Take off!
Good luck. Have a nice flight.
Remember, if anything happens to her,
I'll have you whipped, flogged,
put on the rack,
and then have your back
legs fried in butter!
He's in here, Brom. I can feel it.
How will you know the great
animal when you see it?
I'll know.
Better stay close.
If you say so.
Derek? Derek, where are you?
- Shh, shh.
- Oh. Sorry. Heh.
Derek?
Oh! Oh! Oh! Derek!
We'd better keep an eye out for hunters.
At ease, Odette.
I can smell a human a mile away.
- Ah! Where did that come from?
- Derek!
Ah! Derek. He's here.
You will not lose control.
You will follow the plan as outlined.
Acknowledge. Acknowle-- Ah!
Odette!
Odette?
I've got you now. Heh-heh.
Don't give me that innocent look.
Change! Go ahead, change.
I'm not afraid of you.
Ah! Derek.
A swan? A swan.
Of course. It's not what it seems.
Just a little closer.
Come on. Come on.
Derek.
This one's for Odette.
Ah! Odette!
Whew! Hoo. Oh, that was close.
It's working, here he comes.
Hey! Slow down. You're going to lose him.
Slow down.
- He's too close.
- Too close?
He can't even see us anymore, let alone--
Ah! Speed up, girl.
- That boy of yours can move.
- I told you.
He's faster than you thought.
Don't worry, Odette. I've been taught
what to do in this situation.
Well?
Puffin!
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
When the archer has you in his sights,
fly into the sun and use its light.
Follow me!
What did I tell you, Odette?
All we have to do is stay in the sun.
All right, don't panic. Don't panic. Uh...
- Puffin! Into the trees.
- Odette! Hurry!
We'd better think of something quick,
or else we're dead ducks.
Remember what the possum said:
When there's no escape, you have to play dead.
Heh-heh. Gives it the right touch, yes?
Wait till I give you a...
Ha-ha! That'll put some
distance between us.
No sign of them yet.
- I hope that pudgy Puffin knows what he's doing.
- Incoming.
Ha-ha! There they are.
It's almost time, Odette. Look.
- I can't do it.
- Well, you have to.
He'll kill me, Puffin.
You don't do it now,
you've lost your chance for life.
All right.
- I'll do it.
- Go.
What?
All right, come on, come on.
Got ya.
Hello, Derek.
Oh, Derek, I've missed you so.
No one believed me. But I knew.
- You can't stay.
- Can't stay?
No, I'll never let you
out of my sight again.
- Listen to me, Derek.
- Odette.
- Oh, no.
- Who is it? What's going on?
- It's him.
- Who?
- He has me under a spell.
- Who does?
Odette!
- Let him come. I'll--
- No. He has great power, you must go.
- Then you're coming with me.
- I can't.
When the moon sets,
I'll turn back into a swan.
Please, Derek, you have to trust me. Go.
There must be some way to break the spell.
Oh, there is. You must make
a vow of everlasting love.
I make it. It's all I've ever wanted.
- You must prove it to the world.
- How? How?
I don't know.
- Odette?
- Go!
The ball.
Tomorrow night, come to the castle.
Before the whole world,
I will make a vow of everlasting love.
- Odette!
- I'm coming! Go.
- Tomorrow night.
- Yes, tomorrow night.
Now go.
Odette! Didn't you hear me calling?
I... I...
I thought I heard voices.
- Odette, Odette.
- Voices?
- Yes, voices.
- Well, I...
You what?
I've decided to become your queen.
No. You mean...?
Ha-ha. Odette, you've made me so happy.
I'll be a good king, you'll see.
I'll wear nice clothes,
and I'm gonna get my beard trimmed.
Oh, you've made me so happy, Odette.
By the way, you wouldn't happen to know
who this belongs to, would you?
"Come to the ball.
I will make a vow of everlasting love."
Thought you could fool Rothbart, did you?
I will never be yours, you creature!
- I will marry Prince Derek. And you cannot stop me.
- Oh...
I hate to tell you this, Odette.
But you won't be able to attend
the big ball tomorrow night.
If you want to stop me,
you'll have to kill me.
No. I don't think so.
You see, you've forgotten
one very important thing.
Tomorrow night... there is no moon.
No matter what they do,
I'm always one step ahead.
On the other hand,
Prince Derek's vow could ruin everything.
- I'm going to have to deal with him. But how?
- Hmm.
The vow. I'll get Derek to offer
his vow to the wrong princess.
That's it. Ha-ha.
I'll make you look like Odette.
Well, that's gonna take a lot of
work, but it'll be worth it.
Because when he makes his vow to
the wrong girl, Odette will die.
Then I'll finish Derek off myself.
Oh, I love it. I mean,
this is really classy. This is me!
♪ It's such a hoot to see them quaking ♪
♪ When I'm king
They'll treat me with respect ♪
♪ I can't wait to watch
Their poor hearts breaking ♪
♪ So much for politically correct ♪
♪ Up till now I've pulled my punches ♪
♪ I intend to eat their lunches ♪
♪ No more Mr. Nice Guy
Not for me ♪
♪ If you think that I'm hard-hearted ♪
♪ Well, lambie pie, I haven't even started ♪
♪ No more Mr. Nice Guy
No, sir-ee ♪
♪ As soon as my witchcraft has zinged 'em ♪
♪ I'll gain control of the kingdom ♪
♪ As for Odette, well, that's tragic ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm going back to that old black magic ♪
♪ Good behavior, it's so much duller ♪
♪ Time to show my one true color ♪
♪ Baby, Mr. Nice Guy's history ♪
♪ Vengeance is what I believe in ♪
♪ I don't get mad, I get even ♪
♪ Odette can't get to the ball
'Cause I won't bring her ♪
♪ So I'll zap up a date who's a real dead ringer ♪
♪ Up to no good, I love plotting ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm so good when I'm rotten ♪
♪ No more Mr. Nice Guy
Wait and see ♪
- ♪ Wait and see ♪
- ♪ I'll become that nasty, naughty, dirty, spiteful ♪
♪ Wicked, wayward, way delightful ♪
♪ Bad guy I was born to be ♪
One more time.
♪ A lying, loathsome, never tender ♪
♪ Indiscreet repeat offender ♪
♪ No more Mr. Nice Guy
That's not me ♪
♪ Doo, doo, doo ♪♪
Yeah!
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. Ha-ha.
- Mother, have you se--?
- Oh, Derek.
- What are these?
- Roses.
- They're red.
- Of course they're red.
But, Mom, I don't want red roses.
I want white, like a swan.
- Have you seen Bromley?
- No.
Has anyone seen Bromley?
Would you feed this to a swan?
I...
Take it back.
For something light, something fresh.
- No, no, no, Rogers, hold it.
- What's wrong?
Tonight the music must be played rubato.
Soft and graceful, like a swan.
A swan?
- You ever seen a swan, Rogers?
- Of course I've seen a swan.
If you could play a swan,
what would it sound like?
Soft and graceful, Rogers.
- Where is Bromley?
- No one has seen him, Derek.
You're kidding. Who's gonna be my best man?
Best...? You mean...?
You... Oh, Derek.
There you go, Rogers. That's the stuff.
Come on, Mother.
Don't be so secretive, Derek.
Tell me who she is.
It hurts me to lock you up, Odette.
Hurts me deep.
But then, a king's day is
full of tough decisions.
You understand.
Oh... Now you're mad at me again.
Doggone it, I can't do nothing right.
Head full of pudding.
That's me.
I can't leave you like this.
If you're not happy, I'm not happy.
Hmm. I know. If you can't attend the ball,
then I'll bring the ball to you.
Let's see.
The first thing you'll need is a young man.
The prince is busy, of course,
but I think I can arrange a substitute.
No, please. I beg you. Please!
Poor fella. He got lost in the woods.
Help. Help! Don't go.
Oh, I'd love to stay, but if I don't
leave now, I'll be late. That's tacky.
Don't give me that look.
Had to be sneaky, didn't you?
Had to drag your weakling prince into it.
Well, that's fine with me.
Just fine with me!
♪ Every single princess on the planet ♪
♪ Prayed to be invited to the ball ♪
♪ Every Portia, Guinevere and Janet ♪
♪ Would come by coach or boat to be here
Most would swim the moat to be here ♪
♪ Just to be at this historic gala ♪
♪ Girls would walk or run or even crawl ♪
♪ Rumor is that at this joyous scene tonight ♪
♪ The prince will likely choose
His future queen tonight ♪♪
Uh, excuse me. Oh, excuse me.
- Ahem. Excuse me, Your Highness.
- Yes, yes, chamberlain?
- It's getting rather crowded.
- Very well. You may begin the introductions.
- And, chamberlain...
- Yes?
No mistakes this time.
Everything must be perfect.
Oh, no, no, no. Oh, yes.
I mean, oh, no, no, madam.
Everything will be perfect.
Promise me, Derek, you'll tell me who it is
the moment she arrives.
Heh. Don't worry, Mother. You'll know.
Believe me, you'll know.
Ah!
- What?
- It's coming.
- What is?
- An idea. A substantial idea.
- A large, colossal idea!
- Sounds big.
I got it! Water leaks
into the dungeon, right?
Well, if there's a leak,
there must be a hole.
We'll find the hole, make it bigger and...
She's loose. Heh-heh.
I think you're forgetting two things.
- His Majesty's got a point.
- Not to worry. Now, first we need a scout.
Are you crazy?
Who's going to jump into this moat?
- He's got to be a good swimmer.
- I should say so.
He's gotta be small too.
Teeny-weeny, not to be seen.
And it wouldn't hurt if he was green,
for camouflage purposes.
Precisely. Small, good swimmer, green--
Good grief. You're talking about me.
♪ You're off on a mission
You're tough, in good condition ♪
♪ A hero, warts and all
No fear! ♪♪
Oh, thank you.
I know some of you just abhor beauty pageants,
but having been a puff-puff girl myself
way back in '39, I just couldn't resist.
Girls. And a one, a two,
a one, two, three...
♪ Beauty and glamour and breeding
Are matched ♪
♪ Princesses on parade ♪
♪ Lovely, enthralling and all unattached ♪
♪ The hoi polloi and those well-bred agree
Each enjoy a royal pedigree ♪
♪ Born for success ♪
♪ Each possesses a spark ♪
♪ Each a remarkable maid ♪
♪ Boy, oh, boy, these royal highnesses
All have plusses, they've no minuses ♪
- ♪ Gaze upon ♪
- ♪ These princesses on parade ♪
♪ This princess comes from Colchester
Where corn and cotton grows ♪
♪ She plays croquet and harpsichord
And sews her own clothes ♪
♪ Antonia isn't known to take
The path of least resistance ♪
♪ She hails from Southeast Harristan
And came the farthest distance ♪
♪ Griselda lives to help the world
She finds no task too menial ♪
♪ And all the other hopeful girls think
She's the most congenial ♪
♪ Brunhilde is from Stuttgart
Where our swords and armor's made ♪
Gaze upon...
♪ Princesses on parade ♪
♪ This is the likely occasion ♪
♪ When the heir to the throne picks a wife ♪
♪ This may be the day
That Prince Derek will say ♪
♪ "Where have you been all my life?" ♪
♪ Brilliant, beguiling
A smiling brigade ♪
♪ Princesses on parade ♪
♪ Each the pride of her community
Each a golden opportunity ♪
♪ Just the thought that Crown Prince Derek ♪
♪ Will face this choice and he's hysterical ♪
♪ Gaze upon, heap praise upon ♪
♪ These radiant, glamorous, luminous, dazzling ♪
♪ Princesses on parade ♪♪
- Ah!
- Chamberlain.
All who were invited are
present, are they not?
Well, yes. I mean...
- Open the door, heh-heh, chamberlain.
- Who could it possibly be? I checked my list.
It's the milkman. It must be the milkman.
Well, it's not the milkman.
Oh...
Oh, no, it can't be.
Excuse me. Pardon me, please.
I've got to get through.
Oh, yes. She's lovely, isn't she?
Queen coming through here.
Excuse me, excuse me.
- Rogers! Rogers! Who is it? Do you know her?
- I don't know.
Come now, Rogers.
I know he confides in you. Who is it?!
I promise, I've never seen her before.
Although,
she does look a great deal like...
But it couldn't be.
Could it?
- Oh, I was so worried. I almost thought--
- Nothing could keep me away.
Okay, Speed will draw the gators away,
then you'll get a running start
and make a, pshew, for that hole.
If I can find it, and if the alligators
don't chew me before I get there.
Don't worry. Speed will rush to help.
Ah, yes! Mr. Molasses will rush to help.
That's the plan.
- Suddenly, I'm full of comfort.
- All right. Stretch out.
How do I get myself
talked into these things?
All right, to your mark.
Hey, you old leatherheads.
Come and get me. Come on, bug eyes.
Perfect, perfect. All right.
Ready? Get set. Go!
- Faster. Faster.
- Sure, go on, Jean-Bob, race to your death!
- Get moving, slowpoke.
- Slowpoke?
♪ Nah-nah, nah-nah-nah ♪♪
Any luck?
- Jean-Bob!
- To the rescue, mademoiselle.
Oh, there's the signal.
All right, Puffin,
time to brush up on the diving technique.
Yoo-hoo! Those turtles are tough eating.
How about a little white meat?
Ha-ha. Good for the heart.
- We broke through! Let's go.
- Thank you, Jean-Bob.
Oh! And when this is over,
remind me to give you a kiss.
What? What is it? Stay away.
What are you doing?
No. No, get away!
I'll tell you when.
Let's go.
Friends call me Speed.
Go, Odette, go!
Something about you seems--
I don't know. --different.
Don't worry. After tonight,
everything will be perfect.
Yes. Yes, of course.
Rogers, I'm going to make an announcement.
Stop the music.
Kings and queens, ladies and gentlemen.
Mother.
I have an announcement to make.
Today, I have found my bride.
No, Derek! No! It's a trick.
I present her to you as the
future queen of our fair kingdom.
And as proof of my love for her...
I make a vow to break all vows.
A vow stronger than all
the powers of the earth!
- Before you and before the whole world...
- Shh!
...I make a vow of everlasting love...
Derek!
...to Odette.
No!
♪ No more Mr. Nice Guy
No, sir-ee ♪♪
Hello, little prince.
Who are you?
Went and pledged your love to another, eh?
What are you talking about? This is Odette.
No. Odette is mine.
It's you! You have no power here.
I made a vow. A vow of everlasting love.
You made a vow, all right.
A vow of everlasting... death!
No! Odette!
You should have left her to me.
Now Odette will die.
Odette!
- She's fading fast, little prince.
- No!
Something's gone wrong.
If you hurry, little prince,
I'll let you see her one last time.
There she is.
I don't think she's gonna make it.
This way, Odette.
Keep coming, girl. Come on, now.
Odette?
Oh, what have I done to you?
Forgive me, Odette.
Forgive me.
Derek?
Yes, Odette. I'm here.
Derek, I feel so weak.
I think I'm...
No, you'll live, Odette.
The vow I made was for you.
I know.
I love you, Derek.
Odette?
Odette.
I made the vow for her. Do you hear?!
The vow I made was for her!
No need to shout.
Don't let her die.
- Is that a threat?
- Don't you dare let her die.
Ooh, it is a threat.
You're the only one with the power.
Now, do it!
Only if you defeat me.
The great animal.
I'm betting on the animal.
No!
I won't let her die.
The bow. Derek's bow.
- Swim to the bottom of the lake and get the bow.
- Ah!
Throw it, throw it, throw it.
Wake up. Wake up. Hello!
Goodbye.
- Help, please.
- Brom?
Please, oh, please, oh, please.
Forgive me, Odette.
Forgive me.
I only wanted to break the spell.
To prove my love.
I love you. Your kindness and courage.
I always have.
- Derek?
- Odette?
Oh, Derek.
Well, there you have it.
Everlasting love.
Well, Rogers, old man.
I suppose you owe me an apology.
After all, if it weren't for me,
the great animal would still be alive.
- Dear me, no.
- What?
The great animal. It's alive!
- Uberta.
- Rogers.
I don't care if everyone
else does have the day off.
The prince wants a fighting air force,
and it's my job to get you birds in shape.
You're in Puffin's army now.
General Puffin.
I am ready for my kiss, mademoiselle.
Now, don't be too disappointed, Jean-Bob,
if nothing happens.
Finally, after all these years,
I shall return to my throne.
- Don't forget to write.
- You still don't believe me, do you?
The only thing you're gonna turn is red.
Well, I am ready, Odette.
Voilà! Well, Speed,
what do you have to say now?
Uh...
That's what I thought.
And now, if you don't mind,
I've got some schmoozing to do.
- Would you like a kiss too, Speed?
- Nah, heh, I'm happy as a turtle.
Ha-ha! The ladies still fall for me.
Will you love me, Derek,
till the day I die?
No. Much longer than that, Odette.
Much longer.
♪ Far longer than forever ♪
♪ I'll hold you in my heart ♪
♪ Its almost like your here with me ♪
♪ Although we're far apart ♪
♪ Far longer than forever ♪
♪ As constant as a star ♪
♪ I close my eyes ♪
♪ And I am ♪
♪ Where you are ♪
♪ Sure as the dawn brings the sunrise ♪
♪ We've an unshakable bond ♪
♪ Destined to last ♪
♪ For a lifetime and beyond ♪
♪ Far longer than forever ♪
♪ Like no love ever known ♪
♪ And with your love ♪
♪ I'll never be alone ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Far longer than forever ♪
♪ Like no love ever known ♪
♪ And with your love ♪
♪ I'll never be alone ♪
♪ Far longer than forever ♪
♪ Much stronger than forever ♪
♪ And with your love ♪
♪ I'll never be ♪
♪ Alone ♪
♪ Never, never be alone ♪
♪ Never ever be ♪
♪ Alone ♪
♪ Far longer than forever ♪♪
♪ I knew that we belonged together
Long before I knew your name ♪
♪ And the only thing I longed for
Was a sign to prove you felt the same ♪
♪ Somehow I knew your every secret
Just by looking in your eyes ♪
♪ From the very moment I met you
I was thinking of the rest of our lives ♪
♪ Just say to me ♪
♪ I'm gonna love you till the end of time ♪
♪ Somehow two hearts have made a friend of time ♪
♪ Eternity ♪
♪ Eternity is on our side ♪
♪ I'm not afraid to say forever
You have made me feel so sure ♪
♪ Because I know it's everlasting
And I've never had this feeling before ♪
♪ Keep telling me ♪
♪ I'm gonna love you till the end of time ♪
♪ Somehow two hearts have made a friend of time ♪
♪ Eternity ♪
♪ I'll love you for eternity ♪
♪ Caught in a tide ♪
♪ And it brought me to you ♪
♪ Under a spell ♪
♪ And now I know that dreams come true ♪
♪ I'm gonna love you till the end of time ♪
♪ Somehow two hearts have made a friend of time ♪
♪ Eternity ♪
♪ Eternity is on our side ♪
♪ I'm gonna love you till the end of time ♪
♪ Somehow two hearts have made a friend of time ♪
♪ Eternity ♪
♪ Eternity is on our side ♪
♪ I'm gonna love till the end of time ♪
♪ Somehow two hearts have made a friend of time ♪
♪ Eternity ♪
♪ Eternity is on our side ♪
♪ I'll love you for eternity ♪♪