Trouble.
"Uh!
Maggie.
Maggie. Maggie.
Maggie?
Hey.
-Jonathon. ... -Are you still afraid?
I am afraid. I'm afraid of all of them.
They're hard, and they're cruel and one day we'll be found out, and-
Well, we'll just wait for that day.
I love you, Maggie.
I am going to take you away.
There must be some place outside this island where we can find happiness.
[Maggie gasps]
Do you believe me now, Standing?
Your son...
and my wife.
I would never have believed it but for the evidence of my own eyes.
-I can explain, let me talk to you. -You have sinned in the eyes of God.
-You will not go unpunished. -By God?
I am the representative of God here.
My punishment is his.
Amen.
Arrest them.
Get after her!
Come back, girl!
Piranha.
Maggie, no! Maggie, come back!
Maggie, come back!
[Maggie yelping]
No.
[Maggie groans]
A judgment.
Thy will be done.
Thou shalt not commit adultery.
That is the Lord's commandment.
This unhappy woman took no heed of it,
and she was punished by God.
But this man was not punished.
So it becomes our duty to judge him here.
Do you deny the charge laid against you?
Yes. And I claim the right to defend the virtue of a woman
who cannot answer for herself.
[spectators] Aye.
Godfrey Mason, I deny you the right to sit upon that bench.
I am an elect-man of this community.
[Jonathon] You are also my accuser.
What kind of law permits the plaintiff to sit in judgment at the accused?
[spectators] Aye.
Jehovah's an eye for an eye.
[grunting]
-Trial over yet? -No, not yet, Henry.
-They've been in there long. -What about you?
It's devil's work, and Tom and I don't care to witness it.
With that lot on the bench, I pity poor Jonathon.
-God save him. -And all of us.
He's not on trial because he's immoral.
No, it's because he stands for everything that they're against.
The elders are afraid of him.
They'll see this opportunity of using the father to condemn his own son.
Then they'll have it all their own way.
[chattering]
We're waiting for the verdict, Henry.
I'm afraid it's a foregone conclusion.
Your father will have no choice.
It's hard for me to believe that a father could be so harsh
as to convict his own flesh and blood.
Jason Standing is a sick man, Bess.
But he's not beyond all human feeling.
[gavel pounding]
We're waiting for you, Jason.
Jonathon Standing...
you are charged with having broken one of the most sacred laws of God.
Through that sin, you have caused the death
of the unhappy woman who was your partner in it.
You have been found guilty.
And as God's deputy, here in this community,
it is my duty to pronounce the sentence of this court upon you.
Before I do, have you anything to say?
Yes.
I am not guilty.
The cause of Maggie's death was fear.
Fear of her brutal husband.
Yes, fear is your weapon. It's a dangerous weapon.
One day it will recoil on your own heads.
[spectators] Aye!
We've heard enough.
Proceed.
The Ten Commandments...
are the prime laws by which our settlement is governed.
And the penalty for breaking any major one of them can,
as you know, be death.
But because our God is merciful, so we will be merciful.
[spectators] Aye.
Therefore, we have decided that you shall be taken from here,
and tomorrow, transported to the penal colony,
where you will remain for 15 years.
-[Spectators] No! -No!
- No!
[woman] No mercy. No.
[murmuring]
Take charge of your prisoner.
-Shame. -Shame.
Have courage.
[spectators exclaiming]
Do you know what you've done, Father?
You've sent him to die. No one can live in that place.
You've sent Jonathon to die. Your own son.
Can't you see that these men are using you?
Don't, Bess. It's no good. You're only hurting yourself.
Your grandfather would be very proud of you, Jason Standing.
Now, Bess, no crying. I don't wanna remember you like that.
I'm sorry this had to happen, Jonathon.
You did warn me.
It was different this time. I loved Maggie.
You wouldn't understand that.
I'm in love too, Jonathon.
Yes, I know.
Take care of her, Henry.
Try to see that my father comes to no harm.
Whatever he's done, whatever he's become, it isn't for himself.
I'll do what I can when the time comes.
There's got to be some change in this persecuted, tyranny-ridden place.
It will come.
Perhaps not your way, Jonathon, but it will come.
[man] Giddap, there.
[whip cracking]
Get on!
Mr. Jonathon Standing.
We are honored with such illustrious company, Mr. Standing.
And what a fine figure we have.
No wonder the ladies like you.
We'll see to it you don't get too fat.
We'll start you off nice and gently.
Don't forget to thank your lucky stars before you eat it.
Thank yours.
Get out of here!
Keep back! Keep back!
[bird squawking]
Come on, get moving.
[yells]
Get up there, after them!
After them!
Look out!
Run. Run!
[dogs whimpering]
[whimpering continues]
[dogs barking]
[barking continues]
-Straight for the swamp. -Yeah.
[dogs barking]
[birds squawking, chirping]
[gasps]
-Here, help me. -I got you.
-Well, that's one less for us to bury. -Yeah.
Get up.
Get up!
Well, hello, matey. What do we got here?
-What vessel are you from, huh? -I'm not off a ship.
-Maybe an eagle dropped you, eh? -Who fired that shot at you?
-Come on. -Who put these on you?
-Who put them on you, eh? -Answer my questions.
-Come on. -The settlement.
Inland.
I was a prisoner. I escaped.
Oh, well, you'd better come and see our captain.
Aye, he's an expert on punishment.
Thank you, Mr. Hench.
My name is LaRoche.
I understand that you live on this island.
That you have been in a penal settlement,
where you have been undergoing punishments.
Where is the main settlement?
About 50 miles
inland to the north.
We were not aware the island was inhabited.
When was this settlement founded?
Oh, a hundred years ago.
By Whom?
My great-grandfather.
-A refugee? -Yes.
-A Huguenot? -Yes.
The king must be displeased to have that wealth slip through his fingers.
I said nothing about wealth.
No, of course you didn't, no.
Sounds like quite a paradise, this island, doesn't it?
Just the sort of place we've always dreamed of, captain.
Must have been a wrench for you, leaving the settlement.
Well, I'm going back.
You're going back?
-For revenge? -No.
To help my friends.
As they would help you, it seems.
“Do unto others as you would be done by.” Our motto, really.
Our motto without a doubt.
We'll go with you.
With me? What for? There's nothing there for you.
On the contrary, I think there is a great deal for both of us.
I'm prepared to help you, well, shall we say,
get rid of some of the undesirable elements in your settlement?
I'm talking to a pirate. What could be your purpose in wanting to help me?
You underestimate us, Mr. Standing.
Pirates sometimes have other interests besides money.
I will admit that there is another reason
for my wanting to establish friendly relations with your people.
You have apparently existed on this island for many years...
undetected.
Now for me, in my profession,
there's a great advantage in having somewhere that is safe and secure.
Where we can rest between voyages and replenish our stores.
Ours is a very hard life, Mr. Standing,
and you can well understand how very often we long
for a quiet haven of rest like this.
For this,
you would help me to bring a just rule to the settlement?
You have my word.
You need me, I need you.
Strike off this gentleman's chains.
Get him some food and some fresh clothes.
We leave at daybreak.
Come on, matey. We'll look after you.
Oh, you haven't half got something to answer for, matey.
[Sputters]
-Mr. Hench. -Yes, captain?
I intend to reach the settlement by tomorrow nightfall.
Tell the men they must make better time.
Captain, the men haven't rested in six hours.
This isn't a Sunday afternoon picnic, Mr. Hench.
Get a move on there, you lubbers!
The captain wants you to make more speed.
You can tell the captain to go-
Tell the captain what, Brocaire?
[Spits]
All right, you men. Let's move, huh?
Alle, alle!
It's all right for the captain, he doesn't need sleep.
You gotta have sleep.
The captain doesn't need food nor water nor sleep nor nothing.
When he hears you moaning, he won't need you.
I don't need you to tell me.
[shouting]
[shouting continues]
Diamonds, rubies, sapphires.
You're dreaming, man.
This time it may come true.
What are you gonna do with your share, Mr. Hench?
I do not count my chickens before I see them.
And then I wait until the eggs are hatched out.
If the captain is right about this egg, I will have my own ship.
-Brocaire? -For me, no more sea.
Just an island somewhere, like this.
Very peaceful.
Full of beautiful golden women... and no men.
[man] Peaceful? Oh, matey,
you've got a mighty quaint idea of what's peaceful.
Mr. Standing, have you ever wondered what you'd do if you found a fortune?
I've never been near one, I haven't had occasion to think about it.
-You sure about that? -Yes, quite sure.
That's not what the captain thinks.
You seem to set a lot of store by what the captain thinks.
I'm very close to the captain, Mr. Standing.
I understand his mind, I can read him like a book.
He's a great man, the captain.
As strong as a lion, as cunning as a mongoose.
And as vicious as a snake.
A very great man indeed, Mr. Standing.
And he knows every trick of the trade.
He's not like other men, he don't even sweat.
What's he thinking, Mack?
You're so close to him, you must know what he's thinking.
I was daydreaming, Mr. Standing.
You were talking about a fortune.
You shouldn't never take no notice of what a man says in his sleep.
Happy dreams, Mr. Standing.
-Captain LaRoche. -Yes?
We struck a bargain before we started out here.
That's quite correct. The bargain still stands.
I hope you don't share the same illusion as one of your men.
And what is that?
Apart from the natural advantages the settlement has to offer you,
there's nothing else.
There's no fortune, no money and no treasure.
I believe you have made this point before.
The more you stress it, the more convinced I am.
You see, my men are always dreaming about treasure.
I encourage this.
Men who are faced with death almost every day of their lives
must have an incentive.
I suggest you get some rest, Mr. Standing.
Good night.
-Bye, Dad. -Bye, Son.
Giddyap!
Women. What are we waiting for?
[screaming]
Come on, come on.
Come on. Come on here.
No!
Oh, no, no.
[laughing]
Mr. Hench ain't exactly enjoying himself, matey.
Matey!
Up to your usual tricks again, I see, Mr. Hench.
He attacked me when I wasn't looking, captain.
A very strategic maneuver if I may say so.
It doesn't seem to have done him very much good.
-Are these people friends of yours? -They are friends of mine.
This was going to be a peaceful mission.
It was. Unfortunately, human nature is apt to determine
where peace ends and strife begins.
Mr. Hench, you will consider yourself severely reprimanded.
[Laughs]
Reprimanded, eh?
Just like the blooming Royal Navy, ain't we, captain?
We are ready to leave, Mr. Standing.
-Not with me. -Very well.
I think we can probably find our own way to the settlement from here.
-Your purpose in going there? -We made a bargain.
We made a bargain when I didn't know you and now I do.
As you observed earlier, Mr. Standing, we are pirates.
And sometimes we are inclined to harshness.
However, there is one thing I will not tolerate and that is mutiny. Tie him up.
Matey.
With your permission, Mr. Standing, we will now leave.
Dad.
Dad,Dad.
No, Timothy, no.
You can't help him.
Dad, they killed him?
Go and find Uncle Henry and tell him what happened.
Go, quickly. Go.
Uncle Henry!
-Uncle Henry! -What's the matter, Timothy?
Some men killed my father.
-They killed him. Some men- -Wait now, what men?
I don't know, I've never seen them before.
-Jonathon was with them. -Jonathon?
-Are you sure it was Jonathon? -Yes.
-Where are they now? -They went towards the settlement.
-Are your mother and sister all right? -Yes.
Take my horse and go to the settlement.
Warn them they may be attacked. I'll go to your mother.
Get out of here.
[ringing]
God has seen fit to warn us of catastrophe.
Let us, like Noah, take heed.
-Our island has been invaded. -What happened, Father?
Blackthorne has been murdered. Take the children to the great hall.
Get to the stockade, get your guns. Arm yourselves!
The gates! Close the gates!
Come and get the guns!
-What. . . ? -All right, don't push.
Armed with the gun.
All right, take it calm.
You take up positions. Muskets, arrange up on either side of me.
Take the powder.
Right, away you 90-
Load your muskets.
Hold your fire until I give the order.
If you're trying to assess their chances of fighting us off,
you'd do well to look at the men around you.
How many firearms do you suppose your friends have?
Mr. Standing?
If you want to save them from annihilation, go and talk to them.
Tell them that if they resist me, they can expect no mercy.
Tell them to let us in.
So you can rob them of their possessions and slaughter them all?
If I kill, it is to achieve a purpose, not for the sake of killing.
-You have my word on that. -Your word?
Well, Mr. Standing?
As you say, if they resist, the result will be the same.
A wise deduction.
I wish you every success.
Get moving.
There must be 30 at least.
All armed, I imagine.
We've got about 15 muskets between us.
God is on our side.
They come in peace.
God has answered our prayers.
Why, it's Jonathon.
Father, I have a message for you from the leader of these men.
-Who are they? -They are pirates. I am their prisoner.
I've been forced to give you an ultimatum.
Proceed.
They are looking for plunder.
They believe there are riches in the settlement.
They're obsessed with the idea that there's treasure.
-You have told them this is true? -No, how could I when there is none?
They will be convinced only if you allow them to search.
-And if I refuse? -They will attack.
Father, I beg of you, surrender.
It's the only chance of saving the lives of our people.
This is a trick. He's in league with them himself.
Whatever I have done, I'm no traitor. My father knows this.
Allow him to think and speak for himself.
-What is your answer? -This is our answer.
[gunshot]
[Jason] Hold your fire.
Take aim.
Open fire.
The captain wants you.
-Mack. -Right, mate.
Take six men and work around to the back of the stockade.
Round up the women and children.
Tom.
The horses.
Jonathon.
The gates.
Come on!
Those men at the back there, come here and fill these positions.
Mason! Mason!
Jason, stop firing!
Cease fire! Stop!
Stop! Cease fire!
-Cease fire! -Hold.
Hold your fire! Hold your fire!
-Hold! -Hold it!
-Cease fire. Come on. -Hold.
Forby, look after the horses. Brocaire, deal with the settlers.
The rest of you stay with me.
Get them inside.
-Jonathon, Jonat- -Get back.
Get them all back.
[Laughs]
Fortunately for you, I have a reason for keeping you alive.
Which of these men is your father?
I am Jason Standing. Leading elect-man of this settlement.
If your reason for coming here is to find loot or treasure,
you will search in vain.
I am of a different opinion.
Wealthy refugees seldom leave their treasures behind.
Tell us where it is and we will leave.
What is that building?
That is our place of justice and of worship.
Look after our friend and bring the others inside there.
Our terms for leaving you unmolested are very simple.
There is no treasure.
We shall remain here until one of you speaks.
And we shall use whatever means are necessary.
Each day that you remain silent, two of you will hang.
Oh, no. Oh, no.
Starting from now.
Our friends shall draw for the honor of being the first to die.
Come now, me hearties.
Join in old Mack's game of chance. Come, sir, draw one.
And you, my friend, don't be shy. There's only two of you to go.
You, grandpa, you've had a good life. You don't mind going, I'm sure.
Hold them up.
Jason, I-
Captain?
Take them outside.
No!
-And clear this place. -No!
-No! -Oh, no!
No!
You're a lucky man, Mr. Standing. Next time, it may be your turn.
The answer will be the same.
We do not yield to the devil.
A very noble and praiseworthy sentiment.
You may change your mind when you find how persuasive the devil can be.
He fair gives you the creeps, don't he, captain?
I don't think he likes us.
Well, maybe he likes you better than he likes me.
[laughing]
Hello, me old matey.
[Laughs]
Hello, there. Having a good time? Have a drink.
Wait on, mateys, there. Wait for Uncle Mack.
Away, me hearties!
My, she's a hot little beastie, this one.
Hey, a nice slow canter's what I fancy.
Good for the liver.
Come on there. Hey, hey.
My, she's changed her complexion since we first saw her. Forward.
Captain.
[gunshot]
I would have done it but then I haven't had to eat them.
[Laughs]
The first cut's for the captain.
Where are you going, my pretty?
-Leave her alone. -I seen her first, Hench.
Mr. Hench, and I said let go of her.
You are not on board now, Mr. Hench, so this woman stays with me.
All right, Brocaire.
If that's the way you want it, I'm a mate to this crew.
And when I say do something, you do it.
So now I am going to slit your nose,
and then we will see how you get on with the women.
Mr. Hench?
A dispute?
No dispute, captain.
Just a friendly argument.
That's right, captain.
Just friendly.
You, girl...
come here.
Up here.
Are you the cause of all this?
I asked you a question.
Is it you these two men are arguing over?
I don't care. They're both pigs.
[men laughing]
-Answer me, please. -Yes.
Well, Mr. Hench,
we have ways of settling these matters.
Very well, captain.
Mack.
Mr. Hench.
Mateys, clear the way for them, back with the tables.
Jonathon?
Quiet. There are guards back there.
-You all right? -Yes.
-Where have they got our people? -Most of them are in the blockhouse.
Come on.
Five of them. What do these cutthroats want?
-Treasure. A non-existent treasure. -Treasure?
-You're wrong, Jonathon. It does exist. -What do you mean?
My father told me about it before he died.
When our people first came to the island, they were very rich,
and they brought their possessions with them, mainly gold.
There's one man who knows where it's hidden, your father.
[man] I'm going inside to get some water.
Mr. Hench.
Start.
You must stop them.
It's barbaric.
They are fighting over you, you should be honored.
Mate, kill him.
[men laughing]
-Three left. -Bide your time.
-How many horses in the corral? -About 12.
Then we'll release ten of the boys.
With us, that'll make one man for each horse.
I'm staying here.
-You're what? -If we're going to save our people,
somebody's got to persuade my father to give up that treasure.
-Do you think you can do that? -I can only try.
If we do release the men, don't attack the pirates until they're in the open.
They're bound to leave sooner or later, with or without the treasure.
[tapping]
[pounding]
[taps]
Oh, Mama.
You done it!
There you are!
[pounding]
Very good, Mr. Hench. Very good.
All right, girl.
Well, go on. What are you waiting for?
Go on.
[laughing]
You would want to play games?
Bess.
Go open the main gate as quickly as you can.
Silence!
-Silence! -Shut up!
So you're leaving us, captain?
Take the carcass to the ship and put it in my cabin.
And if it answers you back, give it a hundred lashes.
Mr. Brocaire, stand up and salute the captain.
What's this? insubordination?
Captain, there's mutiny aboard the ship.
-What punishment do you prescribe? -That's enough.
But it's mutiny, sir. Mutiny must be punished.
I said that's enough.
Mr. Hench,
give that man 250 lashes.
He's not at all well.
Come here.
Yes, sir. Captain LaRoche.
It's mutiny, sir. Mutiny must be punished.
Correct.
You will learn that no one is indispensable.
Come on, hurry up. Pick up some arms, get the horses.
[gunshot]
Stop firing.
Look to the other prisoners.
No doubt you are responsible for this.
Why didn't you join your friends?
I hoped to serve my people better by staying behind.
Hench?
-Mr. Hench? -He is here, captain.
Where are the men who are supposed to be on guard?
You will find two of them over there with their necks broken.
Deal with those with necks intact.
Double the watch around the stockade. Now get out.
Aye, captain.
There is one way in which you can help your people
and save their lives.
Find the treasure.
Then let me talk to my father.
Your father, does he know where it is?
-Let me talk to him. -Very well.
You have the whole night in which to talk.
Make the most of it.
You wish to speak to me?
Yes, Father.
LaRoche has told me to give you his final warning.
He says that if you don't tell him where the treasure is by tomorrow morning,
he will slaughter every man, woman and child in the settlement.
Oh, Father, have you no conscience?
Conscience?
You dare to speak to me of conscience?
You who have already bartered your soul to the devil?
What value is life on earth at the cost of your soul?
People have a right to look into their own conscience.
They have a right to live.
Father, I beg of you to show them mercy.
Talk to your friend, the devil.
Ask him to show mercy.
If you beg me now till the end of time, the answer will be the same.
You also will die, Father.
Do I fear death when I can face my maker with clean hands
and purity of thought?
What would be his answer?
The answer of a God-fearing man.
You, Jonathon Standing, are a disgrace to our name.
Disciple of the devil.
You would understand none of this.
I curse the very day you were born.
My grandfather's secret will die with me.
From above, he will rejoice in my decision.
His spirit has already entered mine to give me strength.
Yesterday, I ordered the execution of two of your elect-men.
You all know why.
Since then, however, I've made a discovery for myself.
If I'm right about this, we shall leave immediately,
harming no one else.
If I am wrong...
Remove the statue.
No! No!
You mustn't! You can't!
All right, get to work.
We've reached bottom, captain.
There is nothing but rock.
Doesn't seem as if the treasure wants to be found, does it, captain?
Mr. Hench...
you will see to it that no one remains alive.
Get up!
Guard the doors!
No one is to escape!
Make haste there! Make haste!
For the last time, tell them where it is before it's too late.
-No. No, don't touch it! -LaRoche!
LaRoche!
Captain.
Halt!
-There's your gold. -Gold.
Solid gold.
Get back.
Now leave us in peace.
Peace?
Your friends who have escaped, do they want peace?
Get this thing onto the strongest wagon and prepare to leave.
Yes, we shall be taking two hostages with us.
And who will they be?
Father and son.
Very well, release these people and start to move out.
All right, release them!
Get them outside, quickly.
Get on the rope. Pull.
Pull.
They've left the settlement, Henry.
They've taken Jonathon and the old man.
-Which way are they heading? -East.
Making for the mouth of the river, back to their ship.
-What about the treasure? -Well, they had something on a cart.
Looked like the statue of old Simeon Standing, the founder.
That could be the treasure.
If it is, it's mighty heavy.
They're gonna bypass the swamp and take the main track through the bush.
They'll be in Pine Valley about an hour after sunup.
That's where we make our first strike.
All right, boys, go get some sleep.
What will happen to Jonathon and my father?
We'll get them out, Bess.
I'm afraid I'm flying false colors for the moment, Bess.
I'm no man of action.
Perhaps I think too much to be brave.
That's my excuse anyway.
But I don't like fighting and killing. And I don't like what I have to do.
But now the pirates have found the treasure,
why don't you let them take it away?
It isn't as simple as all that, Bess.
The treasure stands for more than just gold.
To us, I mean.
It's a...
A kind of symbol of freedom.
It's what Jonathon's great-grandfather stood for
when he organized a flight from persecution.
And someone thought it fit to commemorate him with a statue.
Somewhere along the line,
greedy, ambitious men have betrayed old Simeon.
But I think he's still watching over us.
And the pirates aren't gonna take him from this island,
not if I can help it.
Now, you'd better get some sleep yourself.
[snoring]
[LaRoche] Mr. Hench?
Get the men moving.
All right, get stirring.
Come on, we're moving out now.
Get up.
And you.
You too.
[stammering]
Don't push us too hard today, Mr. Hench,
if you know what is good for you.
The captain knows what's good for him, all right.
Yeah.
Don't do none of the work, just gives the orders.
“Come here. Do this. Go there.”
Then takes 10 times our share when he's divvying out the gold.
Yeah.
[gunshot]
Take cover!
-Here we go. -Charge.
All of them.
Jonathon, on the back. Come on.
-Father, come on. -Leave him.
Jonathon, leave him.
Get away.
-Get away from me. -Jonathon!
I think you're losing one of your hostages, captain.
Stop! Mr. Hench, get them back here!
Get back here!
The captain wants you all back!
Go on, on the cart.
You too.
Come on.
One, two, three, four, five, six.
There are about seven or eight of them left.
They know this island better than we do.
-How many have we lost? -Six.
Six. That leaves 15.
Fifteen against eight.
They know this island better than we do.
By my calculations, we shall reach the river by tomorrow nightfall.
-And then? -I'm not a prophet.
All right.
Get moving.
-Where's Father? -Look after Henry.
Get some water and fix some bandages for the boys.
Don't take it so hard, Jonathon.
I should have stayed to look after him.
They'll kill him, Henry.
Perhaps that's why he stayed. If the statue goes,
I don't believe your father would wish to live.
Why not?
In his mind, he's protecting the statue, not because it's gold.
He sees the religion and ideals of your great-grandfather
in the process of being destroyed.
Yes, but-
Well, maybe all this has opened his eyes to the truth.
Back in the settlement, he was too weak to fight the men
who have long since forgotten why we came here.
Jonathon, a few months ago, you said to me:
“Try and see that no harm comes to my father.
Whatever he's done, he hasn't done it for himself.”
Well, you were right.
Yes, I understand.
I only hope it isn't too late.
They're following the same trail, Henry.
-We're all ready with the first trap. -Good.
It's too late, matey.
There'll be more of this.
Unleash the statue. We'll carry it the rest of the way.
We'll have to carry it.
Isn't it time we made use of our hostage?
[LaRoche] Yes, he can lead the way.
Standing.
All right, I'll need six of you. The rest of you look to your guns.
Look out, the tree!
Mr. Hench.
Mr. Hench?
What are you waiting for?
The men are going to give trouble, captain.
At least some of them will.
Trouble? To whom?
They are scared. They don't want to go on.
The only other way to go is back.
Perhaps they would prefer that?
What are your plans when you get to the river?
You tell them, captain.
We are only a few miles from the river.
When we get there, we are going to build a raft
and float the statue downstream until we reach the ship.
And who's going with the statue, captain?
Whoever wishes to go.
It'll have to be a big raft to take the statue and all of us.
There won't be as many as there are now.
The islanders will see to that, captain.
What are they gonna be doing while we're building the raft?
I doubt they'll neglect us, but we still outnumber them.
We outnumbered them when the trees fell.
Yes, captain, we outnumbered them
when Baily and Shaw spiked their guts on the bamboo stakes.
-Yeah. -Yeah.
We'll move on, Mr. Hench.
It's all right for him, he has the lion's share.
-I'm all for getting back to the ship. -Yeah, well, me too.
What chance do we have on a raft?
With luck, we shall reach the ship in an hour. Start building the raft.
Captain, this is as far as we go.
That's right, as far as we go.
We are leaving the statue here.
Leave it where it is.
Leave it where it is. Back to the ship.
And who will be next?
Oh, not me, captain.
I'm with you.
Drop the gun...
captain.
We'll build the raft and we'll take the risks,
just like we always do.
But you'll not be coming with us.
Take his gun, Mr. Hench.
I like my wine in my belly, captain, not to drown in.
All right, start felling the trees to make the raft.
Come on, make haste there.
If he gives any trouble, kill him.
If I have a mind, I might do that anyway.
All right.
[horse whinnies]
Look to your guns.
Take cover.
Good girl.
Load this.
I've still got one for you, captain.
[Clicks]
-Powder! -We're out!
Make for the raft.
Bess, look.