Hey, Dee.
You all set?
Mr Kelly?
Good morning, sister.
Sorry, Dee. Wait a bit longer.
I need to speak to your nephew.
I should take off.
This will just take a moment.
I've got a van triple parked.
Please, sit down.
Your check was returned.
That should not have happened.
I had a setback at work.
I'll get you the money & bring it
over tomorrow.
I hope so because we can't keep Dee here
unless you meet your obligations.
This is not the first time this has
happened.
Right. You've been very good.
Are you alright?
What was that about?
It was nothing.
See anything you like?
This is not Victor Kelly's house, is it?
Yeah, when he's here.
Is he here?
- Ahhh, it looks like it, doesn't it?
You gonna let us in then?
I stayed with a friend.
If you were gonna bring him home
you shoulda called me.
No, he's here to see you.
You're Victor Kelly, eh?
Yeah.
I'm your cousin, Michael Kelly.
Is that right?
Yes. Your uncle in Ireland, Frankie,
his son.
Uncle who?
Uncle Frank. Frank Kelly.
Uncle Franco.
I think you've got the wrong place.
He always said to go look up your
Uncle Victor Kelly in New York.
It's a place to stay for a night or two,
a bed.
He made a mistake.
He gave me this exact address, you know.
We're cousins.
He musta took it from the phone book,
'cause I don't know him.
He's a good cook, isn't he?
Yes, he's good.
Well then I'm sorry I bothered you.
You let just anybody walk into the house?
Come on, let's eat.
Dee, do we know anything about an
Uncle Frank in Ireland?
Yes, but I doubt that you or Vic
would.
He was much younger, & your grampa
& him never stayed in touch.
Really?
Why?
Just wondering.
You didn't get very far.
Just on my way.
I'm Miriam, Vic's daughter.
Good to know you.
I'm sorry about that. I apologize.
You're good, your story checks out.
You can come in if you want.
No, I wouldn't want to impose.
Then you shoulda written.
This is where I'm staying?
This is it.
I thought you said it was a mobile home.
It used to be.
That's a caravan.
You don't have to stay if you
don't want to.
Don't get me wrong, man.  It's just
an observation I'm making.
Toilet's in there, key's above the door.
keep it locked.
That's about it.
On my way.
You working on Sunday?
Must be strapped.
Wadda you want?
Nothing. I was just passing by &
saw the van & thought I'd, you know.
So?
You give any more thought to that thing
I was talking about?
No.
Don't come 'round here anymore, Pat.
All right, I won't.
Do yourself a favor, Vic, and think
about it.
Tie game, eh?
What have we here?
Two lemons.
& a pint of milk, like you requested.
Thank you.
I hope you weren't late this morning.
How long has he been here?
He had one drink.  You all right Vic?
I forgot to give him his check,
that's all.
Ted.
Sorry I'm late.  This one's on me.
I like to miss the traffic on the way back,
you know?
Of course.  You wanna go upstairs?
This job took longer than I thought.
I get paid tomorrow.
You should sell your house.
My kid stays there.
Add 15 bucks for bank charges.
Of course.
She doesn't mind your having a
daughter?
Wadda you mean, Ted?
Here you go.
It better be good this time.
Wait a day & it'll be good.
Hey Vic, where you hidin', man?
Arnon, how you doin'?
You still ready to go?
Absolutely, it was done yesterday.
It's got a new carburetor.
Nice paint job.  Looks much better
than it did before.
Should be for what I paid for it.
Thank you.  The receipt's in the
glove compartment.
I'll check it out.
I know that!!
Complete.
I know that.  Go ahead, big guy.
It's you.  Classy, tough,
elegant.
I agree with him.
Meet me back at the precinct.
Start 'er up.
Nice work, Vic.
Bon Voyage.
What the fuck!
Get the extinguisher.
What the hell is this?
- No idea.
You shot the engine, you put no oil in it.
Of course I did. I don't know what this is.
I'm not payin' for this.
I wouldn't charge you.
I want my money back.
- Not yet, I got bills too.
I'll take care of this right away.
You'll get your money when this thing
runs right.
We got a problem?
What a joke.
I don't see anything funny.
This is the last time I do charity
Once a fuckup always a fuckup!!!
I don't know. It blew up with him
standing there.
I got $2000 a day for the renovation.
Come on, we can wait, and then you
pay me back when you've got it.
I can't do that.  Some day.
All right.
Met him last night. He's a chip
off the old block.
Can I get a cup of coffee?
We're closed.
Sorry, just one minute with Vic.
He told me about that situation with the car
and all, sounds like a hell of a jam.
Listen, if you would just do that thing that
we talked about, which you could do blindfolded
It's like money for free.
I told you not to come around here.
OK, if you want to talk to me, he's got
my number.
Mikey.
- Thank you so much, all right.
Thank you so much for the service.
Your uncle Frank gave me that.
Like he was very proud of him.
Says you're an expert.
That's the sort of action that Pat
says is going down again.
And that, my friend, is the sort of action
I'm hunting.
Put it away.
So, is this the cousin I've heard so
much about?
Michael, this is Sally.
- Hello, Sally, nice to meet you.
Hope he's treating you well.
Michael has to take off.
You set? I'll walk you out.
- It was nice to meet you.
Don't ever talk about that in front of my family
or anybody I care about. OK?
How'd you get mixed up in this?
I talked my way in.
You talked to Pat?
Yes, and I listened to Pat.
Now look, Vic, all you have to do is
sit down with the man.
It sounds like a beautiful, sweet little deal,
it's money for free.
Do whatever you want.
So I'll call you about the plan then, eh?
Fuckin' kid, he should have a job.
Vic, please take the money and
make me happy.
I'd love to make you happy.
OK, I'm fine.  Don't worry.
All right, it's a hit.
Tony, I want you to bunt.  These guys,
they cannot field.
You're Vic, right?
Listen, here's some banana bread my wife makes
herself.
Jesus, this is Irish Mike, Vic's cousin.
Hey Tony, I told you to bunt, wadda you doin'?
Pat, we'll talk about this?
- Yeah.
Jesus & I met because we work for a
security company.
They have an account with...
...Arthur Cabs.
You know it?
What they do is come in with the cash
every night & put it in the safe...
...and the next day they go & they
deposit it in the bank.
But we work on the Sunday to Monday, the
graveyard shift...
...from midnight to eight.
The boss comes in at 5 AM, goes in the safe
& walks out with 2 big bags of cash.
They're supposed to keep a record of every
deposit, but they're not doin' it...
They're supposed to take that $$ to the bank.
You see he's helping 'em cheat Uncle Sam.
You should tell the IRS.
This asshole, if he loses his $$ he can't
tell anybody.
It's just like Robin Hood. They have 100 drivers
out there & you know what they pay 'em? Nothing.
These guys are working like 18 hours a day.
Hey, Kevin.
- You got that VCR for me?
I don't have it with me right now, but if you
come by this weekend I'll hook you up.
All right Kevin, I'll see you around.
Kevin, it's very nice to meet you.
Friend of mine from high school, last guy
I thought would be a cop.
Jesus, I'm too old to play Robin Hood.
This is for you.
That's $800, that's all we got.
For your expenses, for anything, OK?
I can check it out.
Do you have a jacket & tie?
No.
How much of that money's for me?
None.
How am I going to eat?
OK, what's the plan?
So have you's lived here long?
No.
You move around a bit, eh?
No, I lived with my mom.
Where's she?
So this is Victor's room.
Yes, shirt, tie, jacket. Beautiful,
that's very nice.
Do you mind if I have a quick look
at everything?  No, go ahead & play.
Most of the up-to-date stuff's at Sally's.
Hey, look at that, beautiful.
What kind of job is it for?
Oh, it's kind of a clerical situation.
A clerical situation.?
Administrative, not exactly sure what it is.
But I've gotta look good for the interview.
Could you work in a bookstore?
People are always leaving, I could ask someone.
A bookstore?  I'll be  honest with you.
No.
No disrespect to ya', but it wouldn't suit,
and Vic set this up.
Vic set it up? Yeah, Vic set it up,
and we'll see how that goes first.
I'll tell you what I'm gonna do. I'm gonna
take the suit. It works very well.
I'll just take 1 or 2 of these things here
and these shoes, and I can move forward.
Thanks very much.
I hope it works out for you.
So do I.
Hey, I don't know how you feel about this 'cause we're kinda related, but...
...you wouldn't like to go out on a date
sometime would you?
You're my father's cousin, it's not
a crime.
So that's a 'yes' then, is it?
Maybe.
Don't wait too long though, alright?
Drive slowly.
If you wanna drive, just tell me.
Open the door for me.
What?
You're supposed to be my driver. Open the door.
Wait here.
Mr Langston?
You're a little early. Mr Ransome will
be here in a minute, though.
I need to make a call.
You wanna use my phone?
I need to call my wife. My kid is sick, so
it's private.
You wanna use his office?
Mr Langston is in there.
Gladys, just don't let anyone in my office.
But he had to make a call.
Just go back to your desk.
Mr Langston.
Hope you haven't been waiting long.
No.  Thanks for the phone.
No big deal.
You're a fan I see.
Yeah, I used to be. It's not the same anymore.
You've got a signed Campinella.
I'm jealous.
I had to pay for it.
I imagine.
So on the phone you said you were opening
a liquor warehouse?
Off the expressway at Flushing. We do business
with hotels, bars, restaurants.
Cash only, so we need somebody with a state
license to make deposits
I'm flattered you chose us.
Could I take a look at the place, it would help me.
We're a small operation. There's
not that much to see.
I got 4 trucks, all maintained.
I got 2 guards on duty 24 hours here.
They're in direct contact with our guys
on the road.
Duffy, get a haircut. I'm not gonna
tell you again.
So, that's about it.
We have great insurance. You have
nothing to worry about.
Where do you lock it up?
In a save, in a secure room, down there.
Could I take a look?
Yeah, sure.
Mr Langston, the law says I gotta report
everything we carry
right down to the bank deposit slips.
But with cash...
...it's sometimes hard to be exact.
This is quite something.
I'm the only one who knows the combination
that has access to the vault.
I had an alarm wired in to keep it up to date.
Look, I don't wanna be rude, but I'm
expecting a phone call.
We're putting a sun room in...
...and the builder's giving me grief.
What are we doing?
Stay here.
Mort, open up.
Wait in the car.
- No, I'm in on this.
It's Vic Kelly.
That's Michael.
I need your help.
How can I help Mr. Goodwrench?
I need some Plessey combinations to
practice on.
I have some tea bags, you want a cup?
No thanks, I have to take back the rental car.
Stay
Can  you make a copy of that?
Why?
I think it's the key to a vault gate.
Take it to the locksmith uptown. It's to
somebody's front door.
Forget that.
Would you put that down!
What about the locks?
Depends on what you're offering.
I can give you 500. It's all I have.
Or something from the take.
What model Plessey is it?
Big, 30 something years, it's got 3 locks.
That's the Imperial. In that case,
I should take this.
It'll be a couple of days.
Go home & visit your family, OK?
We're closing.
Hi, is Vic in?
I need to talk to him, just one minute.
Yeah, alright, come in.
Ted, what's going on?
- $1600 in unpaid rent.
I had a setback at work.
So I heard.
Nothing like word of mouth for business.
Ted, when have you spent a dime on the place?
You can get in line like everybody else
or I could write you a check.
That's funny Vic. Look, you pay by the
weekend or I'm putting your stuff out
and getting another tenant.
Really?
That's a fact.
Well, have a nice day.
He's a total loser.
He owes money everywhere.
Get yourself a nice guy. Goodnight.
Vic, will you stop being such an idiot and
take the money, for god sakes?
I told you I'm not going to do that.
Why not? What's wrong with it?
Not a thing.
You can't just let everything fall apart.
I don't see it. What's falling apart?
Well maybe you should stay at your
place for a while.
What do you mean?
Well you got some kind of scheme, don't you?
No.
Well there are people who rely on you.
And you've been a regular citizen for a while
now and we all got used to you being around.
The regular citizen thing is not
going too good.
Get out.
You mean that?
I'm not gettin' on a bus to go visit
you upstate.
You gonna be that way?
Yes.
Then I'll come back tomorrow, I'll get my
stuff, & I am out the door.
And leave the keys.
Fine.
Do you know what to do?
Yeah.
I go downstairs, find the key, make an imprint,
come back to the van and blink.
Twice.
Yeah, twice is what I meant.
You go upstairs, and if you find it
you come down to me.
Relax.  This is easy.
Yeah, let's start.
Sweetheart.
What.
Go take care of the dog.
Oooohhhh! What is it?
Wadda you got?  Good Boy. Come here.
Good boy, wadda you got?
It's nothing, Honey. It's a car, that's all.
How'd you get out?
You know, Michael, I'm startin' to think
there's something wrong with you.
Mort, it's Vic.
You can't come in. I'm finishing some
business.
That's OK. I need this made. It's the key
I was talking about.
Yeah, meet me at Kent's in an hour.
I'll bring it with me.
You should eat.
No, just coffee's fine.
So the last time you did this you got caught?
What happened?
You got the clipping. What's it say?
But what happened to the money?
I gave it back. I turned myself in.
No, seriously, what happened to it?
My wife, when she found out what I'd done,
took the kid & cleared out, so
I had the money but noone to spend it on,
so I gave it back.
I haven't seen my daughter for 8 1/2 years.
It woulda been more if I hadn't done
what I did.
I got a reduced sentence, I did my time
& now I fuck up cars.
I can appreciated the reasons.
Money isn't everything.
Mort, right on time.
Yeah, how ya' doin'?
It's in there.
How's he doing?
Who?
Him.
Him?
I just hope he doesn't blow it for you,
that's all.
Mort, what're you worrying for?
Me, I got nothin' to worry about.
I'll have it set up for you in a
couple of hours.
I'd stay & chat but I have to go.
You go left past zero 4 times,
the first click here is the first number.
Go right past zero 3 times,
click here is your 2nd number.
You get the routine? It's 3 numbers
for each of the cylinders.
The alarm should give you 6 minutes to get
all 9 numbers. After that, if go past that
The alarm locks you in the building
and calls the precinct.
So are you ready Vic?
You're on.
41.
53.
Time's up.
You got 2 right, which means you got
7 wrong.
You know I think we could try to be
a little bit more positive.
I coach little league, and we like to look
at the glass half full, not half empty.
So you're a family man?
That's right, a wife and two kids.
So what happens to your happy brood if you
go to state for a few years?
Minimum wage it's pretty hard to keep a
roof over their head, you know.
So there's not a lot to cheer about,
right coach?
So why don't you sit the fuck down.
27.
Time's up.
How'd I do?
Not too bad.
Not bad.
Not bad, what? How'd I do?
You got 4.
OK, less than half.
Not too bad.
Do it again. Set it up.
33.
How'd you do?
5 minutes & 42 seconds.
I think we should just get out of this.
No, let's not.  Wait.
He was getting better.
Let's just get out of this.
Calm down.
I'm calm.
Just tell him, 'cause he's your friend.
He's a nice guy...
Just tell him.
No, it was clear...Vic.
Vic, should we still be confident? Cause those
numbers were taking, no offense, a long time.
You're still the coach, you know...
What time's your shift tomorrow?
Midnight, we begin.
We'll be outside.
Body of Christ?
Mr Kelly, you're early today.
For once. I apologize for not coming
when I said I would.
That's all right, I really didn't expect it.
Would you like to take a seat?
We're going to move Dee tomorrow to a
geriatric hospital in Staten Island.
She'll be well taken care of, there'll be visiting
hours & if you wanna take her out for the day you
can make arrangements.
It could be I can straighten this out by tomorrow.
We'll keep our fingers crossed.
If there's a room open we'll be happy
to take her back.
Would you like to come inside?
No, thanks.
You're up early.
I just went to get some breakfast.
Oh, too bad, I got you some.
I'm accepting your invitation.
You wanna go to the cemetery?
Wadda ya' like....Why?
'Cause it's beautiful.
Why isn't Miriam here?
She's late.
You can eat that.
You help me because you think it
makes you feel better.
Paying your pennance.
I'd like to go to Staten Island.
I haven't been there since my friend
Maureen eloped.
You told me that.
Thai's from a box. I didn't have
time to cook.
She'll be here when she gets here.
So wadda you think?
Yeah, big. A big graveyard.
Did you think we were living in a big house
with lots of money?
Miriam, you're standing on the graves.
There we are, get on the path.
Did you?
What?
Think we were living in a big house
with lots of money?
Wadda you mean?
I don't think you're even close to
being related to us.
I found it on the counter in your
little trailer.
Michael Lawler.
At least you kept your first name.
Nice picture.
Give it back. Give it.
I know your uncle Frank, all right?
I grew up next door to him.
Well I don't think that counts as
being related.
I've known Frank all my life.
& he used to tell me about Victor Kelly
over in New York.
Built him up as this kind of big-time
safe-crackin' gangster, good fella.
And you believed him?
Yeah.
I wanted to believe it.
Then you musta been disappointed.
I was. Bitterly disappointed.
But I've nowhere else to go, Miriam.
You're not gonna tell him, are you?
I mean don't tell him 'till after I hear about
this job. He's been very good to me.
We'll see.
I gotta go to lunch.
So what happened to Sally?
I liked it better living here
by myself.
It'll be OK. Dee has to move to some kind
of hospital.
It could be, if I'm not picked, take care
of her for a while.
Why, what's wrong?
I dunno, she doesn't wanna be with the nuns
anymore, I guess.
She doesn't wanna be anywhere.
That' it, she has to move.
OK. What's the matter with you?
Nothing.
Fit as a fiddle.
You keep an eye on her, OK?
How ya' doin'?
Hey man, what's up?
So the trip went ok with Arthurs?
Yeah, fine. Everything went well.
When you gonna get rid of these?
These VCRs?
If I sell those, that all right?
I guess so.
Have a good shift.
Party time.
Don't piss off any dogs.
Why'd you ask about the truck?
I ask him that every week.
Every week--I'm here every week.
You don't listen.
Relax, all right? Just gotta be cool tonight.
I am being cool.
I ask every week.
Yeah.
How you doing, Vic?
So you mind if we watch?
Wadda you want, a box of popcorn?
We'll be out here.
Anything you need.
Good luck.
Good old Mort.
All set?
That's it, you're off, 6 minutes.
Keep me on time.
18.
26.
31.
You're 12 seconds ahead.
22.
Is that a cop?
Yes it is a cop.
It's stopped. How'm I doing?
You've only 3 minutes left.
That's your friend, that's that guy.
- Kevin.
What's he doing here?
He wants a VCR, that's all.
It's all right, it's not a big deal,
all right? I'll just give him a VCR.
No big problem, I'll give him one of these.
Hurry up, let's get outta here, don't talk
to this guy!
It's about time.
You can pay me later, OK.
Watch it, it's fragile.
What's wrong with you, what's the matter
with you? Wait.
My partner wants one too.
52.
One more minute left there, Vic.
4.
40 seconds.
Quiet!
It's Hi-Fi, yes. Surround sound.
With 4 heads?
OK, let me have one of those.
OK, great, just wait right here &
I'll get you one.
I'll go with you.
Bull shit, man!!
My boss is here, know what I mean?
Want me to get fired?
All right, so just stay here.
10 seconds.
Quiet.
That's it, Vic, we're fucked.
You did it. Beautiful.
You sound surprised.
Sweet Jesus, look at this.
Who'd have thought that fucking up a
car could lead to this?
Who'd have thought that fucking up your
Buick woulda led to this?
What do you mean?
Now relax, Vic, alright? Keep it down.
I did not....
It was Pat. I caught him fucking around
with the Riviera.
He said it would force you into doin' this,
and he cut me in to keep me quiet.
But the beautiful thing is, it worked.
Look at this. It's beautiful.
Open the door.
Smart guy, tough guy.
Hey look, there's gotta be a way out.
Now look, here's the button.
NO, DON'T!!!!!
I'm coming back. I'll be back!!
Mr Ransome? I called your home.
Your wife said you were on your way down.
I'm afraid there's been an attempted robbery.
Looks like one of the suspects locked himself
inside your vault. Gotta key?
Yes, yeah.
You just pull inside. My partner will be
right with you.
Thanks. We'll try not to keep you any longer
than we have to.
OK, thanks.
Watch your head.
Mr Ransome?
Yeah, hi.
You were supposed to wait outside.
Yeah, I was looking for yesterday's delivery reports.
Yeah, well technically this is still a crime scene.
Yeah, I got it.
Wanna go see if anything's missing?
That's why I'm here.
Single, Florida Express.
Attn, passengers, the 8:14 Fla. Express is
now boarding at gate 3.
Washington, Richmond, Charlotte,
Charleston, Atlanta, West Palm...
...Ft Lauderdale, Boca Raton
& Miami now boarding at gate 3.
Please have your tickets ready
for the driver.
Hi dad. The detective says they're gonna have
to put a complaint together for the DA, but
you can come home until then as long as you report
back here every day until they get a court date.
Is he going to come?
They moved Dee, so we gotta pick up your van &
take her stuff over to the new place. OK?
Mr Ransome, this is hardly a high-profile case.
Bob. Thanks. I know that.
I'm just tryin' to see how I can help
without hurting my business prospects.++--
Show them out.
You're free to go.
Sorry we missed visiting hours. We got held up.
We brought your stuff.
She's in a ward. I can't take that, but I
can take some of the books.
Why's she in there, she can walk with a cane.
It's the law, she might fall.
I gotta get back before the staff nurse comes.
She's supposed to be taking a nap.
We'll come by to see you next week, OK?
Behave yourself.
Weren't you supposed to return my keys?
I forgot.
You look good. Things are going along
downstairs, I see.
We only just started. I heard you were being
held down at the precinct.
They let me go.
For how long?
I don't know.
Can I borrow that money?
They moved Dee. She won't say it, but I think
she wants to go back with the nuns.
I already paid for the renovation. You left
it too late.
What I was tryin' to do, pay off some bills,
fix things,
without getting you mixed up in it.
You know what I mean.
No, I don't know what you mean. I thought
we had plans
And I don't want to hear it. Don't go blaming
it on me now. You should go.
See you.
OK then.
See you later, alligator.
Go home, Vic.
Put that down!
Take your hands off that!
I've got to find a new tenant.
I told you I move your shit outta here.
You're not going to do this. Take your
hands off that!
I'm not foolin' with you.
Hey, you're doing this too. Shut your mouth.
We're doing this legally, did you see the sign?
If I get 50 bucks for that shit I'll be lucky.
I got to cover my expenses.
[German instructions to helper]
Speak English.
Vic, you're such a big loser.
What have I done to you?
[German disrespectful talk]
Hey, don't talk to me like that.
Let's go.
Let's get out of here. We finish this tomorrow.
And get off my property!!
Jesus, look at you.
I was...I went down to Sally and....
Is that for me, is it...?
You're on the list.
I'm not exactly popular around here any more, am I?
You got it, BINGO.
What's up? Got nobody to spend it on?
I shaved a little bit off for meself.
Money isn't everything.
Here, Cecil. Two sugars.
Dad, you want some?
Come on, back it up.
I am backing up.
Relax.
Hey Vic, what's going on?
Can we take it inside? You might like it.
Yeah, whatever.
What is it?
If it's not what you're looking for,
I'll take it away.
How do you know what I'm looking for?
I should know, right?
Yes.
Vic, it's...
It's vintage, and it works.
It needs some records, but I can fix that.
It's nice.
Something to keep me company while you're
locked up.
That's thoughtful.
If you want, I could get a brush and help out
until they come and get me.
I'll go upstairs...slip into something
more comfortable. I'll be right back.
I'll bet you like the Mets, uh?
Ehhhh, they're OK.
Two dollars.
Thanks.
Bye.
Hi, what can I get you?
I'd like an orange and, uh, a coconut.
OK, two dollars.
And this is for you.
For me?
Yeah, it's from some old friends.
Your highness.
What time are we expected at Sally's
big party?
Who says you're invited?
I think I've got a little special thing
to wear.
Come on, cuddly toys, stuffed animals, pink
pandas, 2 for $25, come on.
I'm not going to say thank you
if that's what you're waiting for.
If you want, I could take you back
to Staten Island.
King of the jungle, big pandas, cheaper
here, 2 for $25.
What's that?
Showing charity.
Knowing Vic, it'll probably explode.
It's going to work.
See wise guy? There. Like poetry.
Hey Vic, these are thristy people.
I remember that Frank always had a sunny
disposition. Is he still...?
He had what?
The hubcaps are an interesting touch.
Do you like 'em? They were Vic's.
Go get him.
You need to come with us.
I'll give you a couple of minutes.
You going to call me?
You'll call.
Yeah.
Where the hell is my Buick?
It's in the back of my house.
There you go. The keys. You can start it.
Aaaahh, don't worry about it.
Take it!
Cop: I don't want to know.
Vic: What about my case?
For some strange reason the guy you tried to rob
doesn't want to press charges.
You lucked out for once.
That's good.
[Subs by Jackmack]