They're heading for beverley manor.
Both of you, wait for me at the
gallows tree, and be ready to travel.
Pablo, get some water and provisions,
and make sure the coast road is clear.
Now, let's move fast.
Edward.
The company commanded by colonel judd
will be here within the hour.
Everything arranged?
Yes, father. Two of my men
will escort the king.
- Who are they?
- Duncannon and fitzroy, sir.
They'll take the coast road
through the forest.
Ah, Jacob. Ask the king
to be ready to leave immediately.
Yes, sir.
- Are you ready to leave with us?
- I'm staying.
- They'll kill you, father.
- It's a chance I have to take.
- We must gain time.
- Have you forgotten that judd is your...
Edward!
Constance.
You will take your
brother and sister with you.
- And you, sir?
- I have made my plans.
Look after her.
And, whatever you do,
keep to the forest.
And remember that you and Philip
were both reported killed at Preston.
The ironsides need never know
your true identity.
Now, go.
But father, what are your plans?
Don't worry about me, my child.
Goodbye, Philip. Edward.
Oh, but please, father!
What'll happen to you?
I'm waiting for colonel judd.
Our distance, captain?
About a mile, sir.
Our friends are a little early.
Yes, sire.
At the halt, by the left,
move column of troops!
Where is Charles Stuart?
Beverley: The king is where you,
and traitors like you,
will never find him.
Hmm.
In the name of cromwell,
I arrest you
for conspiracy against the state.
Bring him inside.
Close the doors.
Why did beverley
call judd a traitor?
When you've been in the troop
a little longer, my friend,
you'll learn that our beloved colonel
fights with the hand that pays him best.
Can't say I blame him.
You'd better search the house, Wyatt.
Detail six men to help you.
Beautiful. Quite beautiful.
Your daughter, is it not,
colonel beverley?
Hmm?
Well, now, are you going to
tell me what I want to know?
If you don't, you'll die.
So will she.
Only more slowly.
Tell me where I can find the king,
and you'll both be granted
a free pardon.
I'm waiting.
What's your answer?
My answer is simple.
I commend you, and the
murdering despot cromwell,
who is your master,
to the bottomless pit of hell,
where you will surely go!
Long live the king!
Thank you, Edward beverley.
And you, Philip.
May god be with you always.
I want to remind you, gentlemen,
that this district is the core
of the strongest royalist resistance
in the country.
It is my duty to stamp it out.
We are to remain here
until the last royalist is hanged.
All right, that's all.
Captain Sylvester, our operations
for the following week
will be for troop a
to cover this area here.
Troop b here, troop c here,
troop d to remain at
headquarters in reserve.
- And Charles Stuart, sir?
- Issue a proclamation.
Cryer: Hear ye!
Hear ye!
To whoever shall bring
information to the state,
leading to the apprehension
of the traitor Charles Stuart,
the state offers a reward
of one hundred guineas.
And to whoever shall
withhold such information,
the penalty is death.
You say you recognised
Charles Stuart?
How?
Well, er... begging your pardon,
your honour,
it was the man who was with him
that gave me the, er... inkling,
as you might say.
Calling him "sire"
and "your majesty".
- Lieutenant hawke?
- Sir.
- Take a troop to the coast road.
- Yes, sir.
All right, you can go.
Er... your honour, ah...
Begging your pardon, your honour...
Well?
I performed my duty as a loyal citizen.
Yes.
Ah, there's the small question
of the reward.
What about it?
Well, er... when will it
please your honour
to permit me to collect it?
If your information leads us
to Charles Stuart
you're entitled to your reward.
Ah, thank you, your honour.
It'll be presented to you...
In public.
Oh, your honour, please,
not in public.
Why not, pray?
Well... the people...
They'd kill me.
Many of them are misguided enough
to retain allegiance to the king.
I... I mean the...
The traitor, Charles Stuart.
If they so much as suspect
what I've done,
I shall need protection!
You'll get your protection.
Thank you, your honour.
Captain Sylvester, make arrangements
for this man to be
confined in the village jail.
- Indefinitely.
- But... your honour!
No-one'll get at you there.
- Captain Sylvester.
- Sir.
- Please show him out, will you?
- Yes, sir.
Your honour, I...
Take him away!
If our friend's information
should prove false,
- you may hang him.
- It will be a pleasure.
I like a man to be
paid in his own coin.
Yes, indeed.
If I had my way with traitors, I'd...
You were saying?
It was of no consequence.
Don't confuse a collaborator
with a so-called traitor.
One is a snivelling coward,
seeking to enrich himself
or to save his own skin.
The other may find himself
ideologically disposed to change sides.
Do you understand?
Every man has a reason
for switching his allegiance.
Only he can adjust
the rights and wrongs of the matter
to his own conscience.
My daughter'll be arriving
in a minute.
She'll be staying here at the manor.
You'd better go and expound
some of your
admirable philosophy to her.
And how is my beautiful Clare?
I'm well, thank you, Tom.
- My father?
- Oh, he's... his usual, shall we say?
- I'm worried about him.
- Oh?
His reputation is spreading
over the whole country.
Everywhere he goes, he leaves
a trail of hatred behind him.
- Well, he's waiting for you now, anyway.
- Wait, Tom.
- Yes?
- Where's colonel beverley?
You'd better ask your father.
Aren't you still in his confidence?
Oh, yes. I'm very much
the blue-eyed boy.
In fact, it may interest you to know
he now looks upon me
in the role of...
Son-in-law.
At least, that's the impression he gives.
- That's a pity.
- Oh. Why?
- I don't enjoy disappointing people.
- Not even your father?
Not even my father.
Judd: Clare.
Sylvester, please excuse us.
Corporal!
Did you make your journey
to see me,
or to ask after the health
of an enemy of the state?
Colonel beverley's only crime
was one of loyalty to his king.
Oh, very touching tribute
to his memory.
His only crime, as you put it, was
sufficient to sign his death warrant.
You didn't lose much time,
did you, father?
My duty lies in
the service of cromwell.
Your duty!
When you first changed sides,
I tried to push your ignoble actions
to the back of my mind.
I tried to delude myself
that you had some reason,
other than greed, for what you did.
But now...
Now, I see you very clearly.
A traitor, a murderer,
cringing to master cromwell for a favour,
or a crumb from his table.
How dare you speak to me like that?
Now, you listen to me
carefully, Clare.
Cromwell has appointed me
officer in charge of the district,
chief intendant of the forest,
and magistrate.
I intend to exercise
those powers to the utmost
in the service of the lord protector,
who recognises my ability.
If I have forgotten
that I was once a royalist,
it is because I now believe
in the new order.
And, whether you
believe in it or not,
you will conform.
Do you understand me?
Yes, father.
I understand you.
Sylvester: Colonel.
We have a very special guest.
Get him to Hampton court.
See to it.
- Sylvester: And the other two?
- Shoot them.
Take him away.
Bring the other two to
the stable yard, wait for me.
Order a firing squad!
Judd: Jacob, leave them.
Remain where you are.
Officer: By the left, halt!
Right turn!
Prepare to load! Load!
Take aim!
Fire!
What's happened?
Father's dead.
Oh, no!
Colonel judd? Yes.
And the king's been taken.
As far as the roundheads
are concerned,
they don't even know we exist.
Jacob has been pressed into
the service of colonel judd,
so, for the time being,
he can come and go as he pleases.
Jacob, you'll bring us
whatever information you can.
Disposition of troops,
movement of transport and officials.
We'll hit them, wherever we can,
with bullets, fire and steel.
These are not haphazard raids.
They're skilfully designed
and executed.
But by whom?
Well?
The man you're looking for, sir,
is known as the Scarlet blade,
but you won't find anyone
in the district to betray him.
You had better look to yourselves.
They are taking more people
for questioning.
Officer:
Squad, halt! Stand at ease!
Stay where you are.
Whichever of you is present,
answer your names,
and stand over by the door.
- Parsons?
- Aye.
Over by the door.
- Fingle?
- Aye.
By the door.
The gypsy, Pablo?
The gypsy, Pablo!
Take 'em outside.
Officer: Squad! Attention!
Forward!
It's all right.
John drury!
Didn't mean to alarm you.
Quick, now, what news of the king?
I... I found a directive
from cromwell to my father.
He's to be lodged for
two weeks at Hampton court,
and then moved to the tower.
We'll try a rescue then.
Meantime, there's work
to be done here,
with getting refugees
away to the coast.
But when they reach the forest,
they must have help: Food, water,
and a place to rest, if possible.
Now, if you can't do this on your own,
you must find somebody
you can trust to help you.
Take this and study it.
It's the place of the next rendezvous.
Twelve men and women will be arriving
at midnight, the day after tomorrow.
Two of them are
personal friends of the king,
they are trying to arrange
for his asylum in France.
Hide quickly!
He's coming in here.
Clare?
My horse went lame. I... 1...
This man assisted me
at the stable.
Thank you for your help.
Would you give him
a few pennies for me, Tom?
A few pennies?
What did he have to do?
Carry the horse?
Get out.
Which leg was it?
Leg?
I thought you said she was lame.
- The near hind leg.
- I see.
You know, horses are no more
to be trusted than women.
This one's an old faker.
I'd have her shot if I were you.
Clare?
I would change my coat
for you any day.
No, wait. Please, trust me.
Who is it?
Good evening, Clare.
I've come to escort you
to dinner.
Allow me.
I'm not ready yet.
Would you wait outside, please?
No, I'll wait in here,
if you don't mind.
Get out, immediately.
You're looking very beautiful
tonight, Clare.
- Will you leave?
- No.
- Who are you ringing for?
- My maid.
If you haven't gone
by the time she comes,
I'll get her to fetch my father.
Do you know something?
I love you even more
when you're angry.
It does something for your complexion.
All I want to do is help you,
and I'm giving you no choice.
Let's put our cards on the table.
You're aiding royalists
to escape the country,
and you've been doing it
for some time.
I also happen to have
a good memory for faces, Clare.
I remember the face of the man
you were talking to in the stable.
Major John drury.
You see, we were in the
same company before the war.
- What do you propose to do?
- Nothing. Help you.
- And if I refuse your help?
- Then call your father.
You can tell him about me, and...
I'll acquaint him about you.
I'm sure the news will do
something for his complexion as well.
It's all right, Mary.
I needed some fresh perfume.
I found it.
Is it a bargain?
- In return for your help?
- Nothing.
I'm merely content
to be around you,
watching you like
a guardian angel.
What greater love
hath man than this?
You know, if you weren't so
overwhelmed by your own charms,
I might grow to like you a little better.
You will.
I promise.
Tom, I want you to
understand one thing.
If we're to work together,
it's for the whole country.
It isn't for us.
Don't change your coat
just for the adventure.
You'll be serving
the king and his people.
Do it with your heart.
Now, shall we go to dinner?
It looks as if we're in for
a hilarious evening, doesn't it?
Judd:
The lord protector, Oliver cromwell.
All: Oliver cromwell.
Two of the men they questioned
this morning died under torture.
- Indeed.
- Glad I wasn't detailed.
Three men were branded.
Another man was tied...
Allow me to compliment you, Wyatt,
on your delicate choice
of dinner conversation.
I'm captain Blake, from the
Garrison at westerly, sir.
This afternoon, we were attacked,
and the station burned to the ground.
- By whom?
- There were about 30 men, sir, against 12...
I asked by whom were you attacked?!
He's in the grounds.
Call out the guards!
Get after him, every one of you.
Sound the alarm!
The Scarlet blade.
- Well?
- He's got away, sir.
Ten officers and a hundred men
on duty in the grounds,
and you let him get away?!
Someone's going to answer for this.
I want a full investigation.
How did he get into the grounds?
How did he slip past the guards?
Mmm?
I think I can tell you.
This man, who calls himself
the Scarlet blade,
knows every inch
of this estate. Why?
Because he was once a
member of this household.
It's quite simple logic.
You still wonder who he is?
I think I can show you.
That's your Scarlet blade.
The late master of beverley himself
was cromwell's most bitter enemy.
He once told me he would fight our
lord protector even from the grave.
That's precisely what he is doing.
Well, gentlemen?
Your logic is indeed
admirable, colonel, but...
But what?
Beverley's two sons were
reported killed at Preston.
I'm aware of that.
They were reported killed.
- Did you see the bodies?
- No, sir.
Most of you fought at Preston.
Did any of you identify the bodies?
By whom were they reported killed?
I can tell you.
By a prisoner of war.
I received the news myself,
and recall a certain feeling of elation,
which overruled
any doubt in my mind.
Subsequently, that prisoner,
whose name was major John drury,
escaped,
and has been a Thorn
in our sides ever since.
- Well, Sylvester?
- Oh, excellent, colonel.
May I compliment you
on the brilliance of your deduction.
We now know who
the Scarlet blade is.
This is indeed revelation.
However, sir, if I, with your permission,
might ask one small question?
- Permission granted.
- How is it going to help us find him?
We will resume dinner, gentlemen.
May the best man win.
I'd like to know what you're thinking.
I'm thinking about the Scarlet blade,
he seems like a lad
after my own heart.
If we can enlist
Edward beverley's help,
we'll have created a link between
this house and a forest escape route.
Go on.
There's a secret passage leads
from the house to the forest edge.
How did you discover that?
The other night, I saw Jacob
enter the passage, so I followed him.
Tom, why would an old servant
of the beverley family use it?
To meet his master.
Wait, you've given me
the germ of an idea.
If you're prepared
to risk Jacob's neck,
I think I know how we can
use him to find Edward beverley.
- How?
- I'll tell you if my plan works.
I've got to go and see your father.
I'm trusting you, Tom.
You'll have to trust me, won't you?
Sylvester: And in the forest,
this traditional place of execution,
known as the gallows tree.
And if, as I suspect,
Jacob is an accomplice
of the Scarlet blade,
then there'll be an attempt at rescue.
We shall be waiting for him.
- It's quite ingenious.
- Thank you, colonel.
I had a letter today
from the lord protector.
In the first paragraph,
he congratulated me
upon securing the arrest of the king,
but in the second,
he deplored the fact
that the Scarlet blade
was still at large.
If your little ruse results
in the capture of this man,
I shall bring your name
to cromwell's notice.
- Thank you.
- Hmm.
- Like a glass of Sherry?
- Please.
We will dispense with
the formalities of a trial.
The old man should be arrested at once,
and notice of his execution posted,
so that the news reaches
Edward beverley in good time.
Execution to take place
at noon tomorrow.
Of course, I could be wrong.
Jacob could be quite blameless.
In which case, we shall have
hanged an innocent man.
That would be most distressing,
wouldn't it?
Still, I fear that is a hazard
we shall have to risk.
Yes, indeed, colonel.
But, of course, we could always
console ourselves with the idea that
Jacob died in a very good cause,
couldn't we?
I've told you. Listen!
It's not only your life
I'm concerned with.
It's the life of the man you serve.
Where can I find him?
You know what'll happen, don't you?
He'll try to save you,
and get cut to pieces
before he gets within
thirty yards of the tree.
Then they'll hang you anyway.
If I wanted to trap Edward beverley,
I'd let him walk into the ambush
they're preparing for him.
If I let this happen, both he
and all his friends will be caught.
Don't you understand this, Jacob?
How can I find him?
Well?
I hope I can trust you.
How can I find him?
- You've heard of the dragon's tree?
- Yes, I know it.
There's a footpath close by.
Follow it.
It takes you deep into the forest.
You will come to an old oast house.
There, you will find Edward beverley.
I'll need something
to prove I'm a friend.
This ring.
Master Edward himself
gave it to me.
Take it.
Why do you want
to help us, captain?
Let us just say
my heart's in the royalist cause.
Your heart?
Your sword fights for cromwell.
How did the two
become disconnected?
My royalist cause
happens to be a lady.
She helped me to see
the error of my ways.
- Who is the lady?
- The daughter of colonel judd.
- Judd?
- And don't condemn her because of her father.
At least she didn't turn traitor.
It's on account of her
that I came to see you here,
and, because of her,
that you can trust me.
As for trusting you,
I shall reserve my judgement.
What is your plan?
This is the gallows tree,
and here, the path leading to it.
They are coming.
“What about the soldiers?
They're waiting for us,
both sides of the gallows tree.
Right. Get to work!
Officer: Troop, dismount!
It's taking them
a long time getting back.
I hope nothing's gone wrong.
They had the element
of surprise on their side.
Don't blame me if they didn't
take full advantage of it.
Here they are now.
Edward!
Pablo!
This is captain Sylvester.
Captain Sylvester,
this is my brother, Philip.
- I'm glad to see you alive, Jacob.
- Thanks to you, sir.
Philip, tell the men
to make themselves scarce,
and double the sentries.
Shall we go in?
Clare, this is Edward beverley.
I'm afraid our hospitality
is a little rough.
I gather some of my father's soldiers
have already experienced it.
Let us get to
the point of the meeting.
You may know I have been helping to organise
escape routes for royalist refugees.
But there are limits
to what I can do for them.
I can direct them to the forest,
I can show them the way
to the coast road, but...
Beyond that, they have to
fend for themselves.
Some of them have been taken because
they lack arms to defend themselves.
I can supply them with arms,
and occasionally an escort.
Good.
Now, this is a matter
which concerns us even more.
The king is being lodged
at Hampton court.
In two weeks, or even less,
he may be moved to the tower.
This'll be our last opportunity
to rescue him.
He'll have an escort
of at least a hundred men.
A well-prepared ambush
will take care of them.
Indeed.
A party of royalist refugees will be
arriving tonight at twelve o'clock.
They'll be waiting
at the beverley crossroads.
Some of them are old men,
women, and children.
- Can you find ponies for them?
- Constance?
- Well, we've got four broken in.
- That'll have to do.
Now I know where to find you.
Goodbye, Edward.
We must be gone.
Edward beverley is being
supplied with information
by someone inside these walls.
How else could he have
countered the trap I set for him?
What have you got to say,
lieutenant hawke?
We didn't stand a chance, sir.
We were attacked by an ambush
that must have been prepared
long before we arrived.
- Heard the news, captain Sylvester?
- Yes, sir.
Ten men killed!
Fourteen wounded,
and the rest put to flight!
That miserable scoundrel
Jacob proust rescued,
and Edward beverley as
far away from capture as ever!
Captain Sylvester, I'm charging you
with the responsibility
of seeking this man out,
and bringing him to justice.
Those are your instructions.
- I'm placing my trust in you.
- Thank you, sir.
I shall endeavour to take
full advantage of it.
All right, dismiss.
- Pablo: What is your name, huh?
- Theresa.
Theresa?
Ah, that is a beautiful name!
My name is Pablo.
You may call me uncle Pablo.
You don't have to be frightened anymore.
You are going on a little boat
with big sails,
to a land where there will be
no trouble for you anymore...
Some of them have been
travelling a long time.
They must get some rest.
Philip will take them on
to the coast tomorrow.
There'll be an escort
to lead them through the forest.
You go ahead. I'll follow.
You realise that, one day,
you'll be caught?
I suppose so.
These people are prepared
to sacrifice their homes,
and risk their lives,
rather than exist under cromwell.
One day, they'll return
to a free country.
I'm glad to help them.
I suppose you think
these are strange words,
coming from colonel judd's daughter.
Having met the daughter,
I don't think the words are strange.
Until a few days ago,
I had only two thoughts in my mind:
To destroy cromwell, and put
the king back on the throne.
And now?
I want to live.
L, also.
I must go.
- It'll all be all right?
- Don't worry.
Do come in.
What kept you?
I had work to do.
You know that.
With Edward beverley?
Tom, you've no right to be here.
I don't like my privacy
intruded upon,
and I don't like you
to question me!
I'm risking my neck for you.
I think I have
every right to intrude,
and to question.
And to make love.
- We made a bargain!
- What bargain?
You said you would help me.
There were to be no conditions.
I once told you what I was.
I'm an adventurer, like your father.
He changed his coat for money,
and I for love.
You touch that cord,
and I'll blow your plans to pieces.
I don't like the woman I love skulking
in the forest with some vagabond.
Tom. “What?
Supposing I were to tell you I've
fallen in love with this "vagabond"?
Are you insane?
No, I'm not insane.
I'm telling you the truth.
I've met the man I love.
A man you've known but a few hours!
And don't protest to me
that love isn't related to time.
Oh, I'm the one that's insane
for setting a trap for myself.
- You offered to help.
- Yes, I offered to help.
And now, I can sit back
and see the course of history
shaped by people
like you and beverley.
Full of noble enterprise,
but lacking the common guts to put
their own cause before their feelings.
I wonder how the king would feel, locked
in his rooms at Hampton court palace,
if he knew about this.
And if your devotion
for the king is so great,
then you use Edward beverley
as you will.
But I don't like to be used.
- I trusted you.
- And I, you.
I still trust you.
Judd: Captain Sylvester!
Will you come in here, please?
Major bell, this is captain Sylvester.
Major bell has been appointed
my deputy, by the lord protector.
I am leaving for London
immediately, to see him.
You will, of course, render major bell
full support during my absence.
Good night, gentlemen.
I have here a list
of the various raids
carried out by beverley
since colonel judd
took command here.
Ten days ago, one of the
lord protector's emissaries
was attacked and killed.
Eight days ago, four wagons
carrying arms were ambushed,
and the escorting soldiers
were killed.
On the same day, a farmhouse, which
served as a barrack for twenty men,
was burned to the ground.
Four days ago,
a man called Jacob proust,
who was to have been hanged,
was rescued.
I understand you were
in charge of that operation, captain.
I was in charge
of the detail, yes.
Oh, you weren't present yourself?
I had other duties
to perform at the time.
Oh, yes, I see. You were engaged in
the purchase of horses at wymington,
where I should have thought
you could have relegated that duty
to a junior officer, under
the circumstances. Hmm?
However, whilst I'm here,
you will personally take charge
of every operation I conceive to
secure the capture of Edward beverley.
I already have an idea I wish to
discuss with you in this connection,
but it can wait till the morning.
- Is that all?
- That's all.
Captain Sylvester, sir.
Ah, ask him to come in.
Good morning, captain.
Have you breakfasted?
Yes, thank you.
Well, be seated.
Now, we'll deal with
routine matters in due course.
But first, the outlaw beverley.
You realise that this man's capture
during colonel judd's absence
would reflect very highly
upon all of us?
Particularly yourself.
I have a plan,
which may well prove successful.
First of all, I should like to point out
that search parties are useless.
This man's too wily a fox to be
caught in his own territory.
Search parties will,
nevertheless, continue.
Now, I understand that
beverley has a sister.
In future, search parties will be
concentrated in the forest area for her.
If we succeed in finding this girl,
we've virtually found her brother.
A life for a life?
Exactly.
We'll hold her,
till he gives himself up.
And you will be in charge
of this operation, captain.
I'll see to it.
I've just had a message
from major drury.
They're moving the king
in three days' time.
Drury's trying to organise an ambush.
- Can you see Edward for me?
- What'll I tell him?
Tell him I'll meet him tonight,
at the oast house.
I can't make it before then.
I think I'm being watched.
I'll see what I can do.
- Tom!
- Hmm?
You will get through
to him, won't you?
I'll do my best.
Halt!
Divide the men into sections.
Spread them so they take in
an area of six miles.
Detail two men with me,
and reassemble here in eight hours.
That'll be after nightfall, sir.
Not frightened of the dark,
are you, sergeant?
Jenkins!
Clare: Tell Edward to make contact
with every available man.
Tomorrow, major drury will return
to give details of the ambush position.
The men must be ready to leave
immediately they get the signal.
Fifty of his men will be
waiting near Hampton court.
- We're badly in need of arms.
- Ssh!
- Who is it?
- Man: Open in the name of cromwell!
Quickly, hide over there.
If you're looking for royalists,
there are none here.
I'll decide about that.
- I'm a loyal citizen.
- I'll decide about that, too.
I am the commanding officer
of this Garrison.
Do you wish to save your life?
On what terms?
Tell me where I can
find your brother.
Never!
I'm giving you the opportunity
of saving your life.
If you refuse to talk,
I'll find him anyway,
and you'll both die.
- You'll never find him through me.
- No?
But if you give yourself up, how do
you know they're going to release her?
You only have their word for it,
and what is it worth?
Someone has betrayed us.
Who?
The only two people
who know where to find us
are captain Sylvester, and...
Clare judd.
I am thinking of Sylvester.
And Clare?
Pablo. Yes?
You've lived all your life
by instinct,
and that's the way you
judge people. Am I right?
- You are right.
- What is your judgement?
I can also use my head.
And it tells me that this girl,
she has done things for your people.
I believe that she loves you.
And in this, my head tells me
what my heart already knows.
But this captain Sylvester,
when I first see him,
I want to kill him!
- Because of his uniform?
- Because of him!
Edward, wait.
If you go, all our plans, all our efforts
to save the king go with you.
There will be no-one
to carry on our work.
- Except you.
- I can go in your place.
No-one knows which of us
is Edward beverley.
Sylvester knows.
How can he say
without betraying himself?
I haven't as much
to lose as you.
Edward, please let me go.
Philip, I am not going to
give myself up.
- Clare.
- I was coming to you.
You know they've got constance?
Yes.
- Where is she?
- In the cellar.
- Be careful. There are guards about.
- Stay here.
Psst!
Come on!
The courtyard!
Keep going!
Colonel judd returns tomorrow.
I intend to cheer his homecoming
by the sight of you,
hanging by the neck
on beverley green.
Take him away.
Whatever you are,
roundhead, cavalier,
adventurer...
Whatever you like to call yourself,
you're still an officer in uniform,
and you can't just stand by
and watch this murder.
Tom, I beseech you.
Go to major bell and ask him
to wait until my father returns.
And when your father returns,
what do you suppose he'll do?
At least it would give us some time.
There might be some way
of saving Edward,
if only we had a little time.
I think you want him to die.
Why should I want him to live?
So that he's free
to take you away from me?
Tom. “What?
Did you betray us?
Did you?
You still love him, don't you?
You did betray us.
Oh, how could you be so vile?
I once told you that
I didn't like to be used.
Remember?
Clare.
This shows the place
of the ambush.
Beverley's men should leave tonight.
Can you get that to him?
Edward's been taken.
No!
I'll try to get it to Philip.
There... there's something else,
major drury.
- Do you remember captain Sylvester?
- Very well.
It was he who betrayed Edward.
He knows about the ambush.
- Has he talked?
- I don't think so.
But he will. Where is he now?
In his quarters. Round that corner,
the first door you come to.
Very well, I'll take care of him.
Guard those plans with your life,
and get them to Philip
as quickly as you can.
Drop the knife.
- I was just about to knock.
- Indeed?
Sylvester: Guard!
Turn out the guard!
Bell: What's happened?
Someone tried to kill
captain Sylvester, sir.
Major drury won't be
troubling us again, sir.
- He's dead?
- As mutton.
Philip: There'll be twenty cavalry
concealed in these woods.
Riflemen over here to the left,
and this is the main road
from Hampton court.
It's well planned, Clare.
It's going to work.
- It'll never work.
- What do you mean?
Sylvester will betray us.
- Philip, how many men have you got?
- More than fifty.
- Pablo, how about you?
- My people do not fight for a cause.
They love no country.
No country loves them.
I give Philip my blessing,
and my help. That is all.
But you'd fight for a life?
For Edward?
That is a different matter.
- Have many of the men left?
- Not yet. They're waiting for me to tell them.
Tomorrow morning, your brother
is due to be hanged.
We can save him, Philip.
Well, if only that were possible.
Oh, it is. It is possible.
With the help of our men,
and Pablo's, we could save him.
The whole district will be
turned out to witness the execution.
Our people and Pablo's
could mingle with the crowd.
There will be only soldiers.
The people have been told
to keep to their houses.
- Then we must make a surprise attack.
- And the king?
There's no chance for the king.
Because Sylvester will talk?
Yes.
Or because you're
in love with my brother?
- Don't you love him?
- Yes, of course I do.
But he wouldn't thank me if I risked
the life of one single man to save him.
But the king stands for the
lives and freedom of all his subjects.
Then you're going to
throw away the lives of fifty men,
because the cause is lost.
The king's as good as dead.
You don't really believe that.
If Sylvester betrays us,
he will have to betray himself.
I love my brother very much.
But I know that he would do
exactly as I intend to do
if he were in my place.
You know I'm right.
Ready.
- Who's the man about to be executed?
- Edward beverley, sir.
Stop the execution!
- Colonel...
- I'm ordering you to stop this execution.
Your orders were to
apprehend beverley, dead or alive.
In my view,
this man is safer dead.
You will refrain from expressing your views
in the presence of junior officers.
You will be good enough
to wait upon me at the manor.
Take the prisoner to the cells.
Captain Sylvester,
I want to know the identity
of everyone concerned
with Edward beverley.
He is to be subjected to
the most extreme forms of persuasion
necessary to loosen his tongue.
- See to it.
- Sir.
- Release the rope.
- Aye, sir.
Take him away.
Guard, dismiss!
Tie him up.
Major bell, do you realise that we are
not dealing with one isolated criminal,
that this man is the leader of a
dangerous royalist underground movement?
- I am aware of that, sir.
- Then why, sir, were you not aware
of the necessity to
extract information from him?
- It was not necessary.
- No?
It might interest you to know that
there is a plot
to rescue Charles Stuart.
Its origin stems from this district.
Beverley is undoubtedly
concerned with it,
and he is not working alone.
I stated that it was not necessary
to extract information from beverley,
because I already know the name
of the principal accomplice.
Indeed?
Before you left for London,
you told me that someone
had been supplying beverley with
information from inside these walls.
I can now tell you
who this person is,
and, for that reason, I saw
no purpose in delaying the execution.
I accuse captain Sylvester.
You have proof?
I have proof.
Request captain Sylvester
to see me immediately.
If your accusations are correct,
Sylvester will know of
the king's imminent removal
from Hampton court to the tower.
An attempt to rescue the king
will be made then.
Go to London immediately, and warn
them of the possibility of an ambush.
I also advise that the king
should not be removed at present.
Carry on.
Captain Sylvester,
you are under close arrest.
- You deny nothing?
- Nothing.
But, I warn you, colonel.
You bring me to trial,
and [I'll seek clemency
by pleading state's evidence.
No doubt that will be considered,
provided you plead now.
I want names.
You may be concerned
with only one for the moment.
That of Clare judd,
your daughter.
That's the name of the woman
that inveigled me into this plot.
Clare judd.
- Your daughter.
- What are you saying?
She managed to ensnare me
under the pretext of love.
She used all her feminine wiles
to trap me.
All this will be
part of my defence.
Maybe none of it
will be taken into account,
but at least you, colonel,
being a staunch
advocate of justice,
will have the satisfaction of seeing
justice handed out to everybody.
Including your own flesh and blood.
Captain Sylvester.
No!
Judd: Captain Sylvester was
shot while resisting arrest.
You will observe that his pistol
is still in his hand.
Get him away.
You've been accused of
assisting in the royalist cause.
Is that true? “Yes.
You've been working
with Edward beverley?
Yes.
Did you ever stop to think
what would happen to your own father
when your traitorous acts
were disclosed?
Did you ever have any
feelings for anyone
other than yourself,
when you turned traitor?
You're the last person
to preach to me!
It's only you
I'm concerned with now.
Fortunately for both of us,
there's now no danger
of the king's rescue taking place,
and, in a few minutes, there will be
no-one left to denounce you.
Except myself.
The king is doomed.
Nothing I or anyone else can do
can help him now.
I am prepared to die
for what I believe is right.
If you refuse to release
Edward beverley,
I'll proclaim to the world
what I've done.
You would never dare.
You don't know me.
You will not only condemn yourself,
you will condemn me.
Whatever your feelings are
towards me,
I am still your father.
Give me your pistol.
Get out.
I've tried to make you talk,
but now... stand up!
Get on your feet.
- Get a horse!
- Edward!
Go on, go on!
They must be almost there by now.
We're too late.
Oh, please. Please!
We're throwing away our only chance,
our lives...
For nothing.
No.
Clare.
Forward!
Philip!
Edward.
Children: Pablo! Pablo!
They're coming!
Quick, Martha, some old clothes!
There are soldiers coming.
Put mud on your faces.
Whoever saw a gypsy
with a clean face, huh?
Make haste. Go with Martha.
Get to your work.
Everybody, get to your work!
Put a bold front on it, my friend.
Get to work, huh?
Will they search the camp?
Everywhere they think
there may be royalists,
they will search.
I advise you gypsies
to keep to the forest.
Forward!
Subtitles by powerhouse films ltd