Aren't you a little old
to be playing with dolls, Michael?
What do you think, Billy, is my kid
gonna love this thing or what?
Sure, he'll love it.
He looks just like it.
Yeah, he is pretty cute,
isn't he?
You know what day it is?
- Tuesday.
- It's October 1st.
It was exactly ten years ago
that I first came to America.
No shit.
Hey, happy anniversary, Billy.
I'll tell you what...
Ten years deserves a celebration.
How bout I take you out
for a drink after work, come on?
I can't be too late.
I'm meeting a girl at nine.
She wants to help me celebrate too.
If you could party
after the graveyard shift,
you got, a lot of stamina.
[You know what I mean?
Shit, looks like the fuckin' Indians
got another one.
We better check it out, Billy.
This is car 17 to dispatch.
We got a code 1022... stripped truck.
Sector H,
right off Longfellow Avenue.
We'll get right back to you.
10-4.
Be careful, Billy.
Michael, check it out.
Jesus!
Christ! Don't... don't shoot me.
Take anything you want,
just don't shoot me.
Relax.
We're caps, okay?
You fellas got one hell
of a friendly city here, you know that?
Just stopped for a red light, and boom!
They got my computers!
Look at my rig! My poor rig!
You stopped at a red light
in the South Bronx
with 2 truckload of computers?
- Where you from, pal?
- Texas.
Figures.
Welcome to New York.
Hey, you're not taking that in, are you?
Can't leave it in the car,
someone steal it.
Don't give me a hard time, get in there.
Hey, that's enough?
- Alright, let's go, let's do it.
- Okay! I'm gonna kick some fuckin' ass.
I'm gonna hit the can.
Another round for my two friends.
You got it.
All right, big man, close that door.
Nobody move!
- Michael, get the back door.
- Hey.
All right, everybody over here,
get over to that jukebox.
Let's go! Move! Move!
All right, I want to see rings,
watches, wallets.
Let's go! You, get over there!
Hurry up! Hurry up!
And that means you too, Bozo! Let's go.
Come on, I said right now.
Hey, open that register real quick,
- Before I blow your fuckin' head off.
- Take it easy, I'll open it.
Hey, Bozo, hurry it up!
I want it.
Hey, man, it's not mine.
It's not mine.
Come on, boy,
you're coming with me.
All right, big man.
Hey, what are you lookin' at?
I'll be out in a minute.
Man,
you shouldn't have done that.
Mike! Go around, Mike.
Duck, Billy!
Michael.
Michael!
Get those fuckers, Billy.
Get 'em.
Call 911, get an ambulance.
- Now!
- Yeah, yeah! Sure!
Hey! Get off my car, you scumbag!
- Freeze!
- What the hell?
You got five seconds
to get off that fuckin' boat!
Move!
Undo that line.
Come on, we got ya.
I need your fastest boat.
- Who the hell are you?
- Police, give me the keys.
Get the hell out of here!
What are you doing?
Give me the fuckin' keys.
- Where's the boat?
- Manhattan Express. Right over there.
Wong! Get the hell out of that thing!
The harbor police will get him.
He killed Michael, Captain!
Billy, I'm ordering you!
That fuckin' China-man don't give up!
Aviation 0-5-zebra.
Officer 1412 in pursuit of a suspect.
I'm in the blue-white speedboat below you.
Can you come up over me?
Roger, 1412.
New York control,
this is 0-5-zebra in pursuit.
We're turning south
at the Brooklyn Bridge,
heading down the river.
That guy's crazy.
Come in closer and drop me a line.
On the count of three,
pull me up as fast as you can.
One, two, three!
Motherfucker!
Is Daddy coming back soon?
You deliberately disobeyed a direct order.
That man killed my partner.
That's no excuse for blowing up
half the goddamn harbor!
- Captain, listen...
- You listen to me, Wong!
I don't like it any more than you do
when a cop gets killed.
But we're not in the revenge business.
The mayor's been up the commissioner's ass
over this one, Wong.
He wants your fuckin' shield,
and if he can't get it, he'll take mine.
I had no choice, Captain.
You could have stood by and let
the Harbor Police pick that guy up.
But, no, you had to be a big hero.
Billy Wong, super cop!
This is it, Billy.
You're back to crowd control.
- But, Captain...
- No fuckin' buts!
That's final!
Maybe next time you'll think twice
before you pull one of your hot-dog stunts.
Now, get outta here!
Nice suit, Garoni,
Billy.
You like it? I'm supposed
to blend in with the crowd.
I heard about your fireworks display
in the harbor.
You always did have a flair
for the dramatic, pretty boy.
- How did you get this shit detail?
- The usual.
Some punk pulled a knife on me,
So I kicked his fuckin' teeth in.
- And he screamed “Police brutality.”
- All the way to the commissioner's office.
- The usual bullshit.
You know, if somebody dropped
a bomb in here,
they'd wipe out half the junior diplomats
in New York.
That's why we're here.
That's Laura Shapiro.
I'd like to work undercover with her.
No, don't tell me.
You guys are cops?
We're that obvious?
You're not so bad,
but that friend of yours,
he sticks out like a sore thumb.
Look, you guys allowed to drink?
- Can I get you a beer or something?
- No, thanks.
Tell you what... if you wait 'til I go
off duty, I'll buy you a drink.
Yeah?
I just might take you up on that.
Um, excuse me, gentlemen.
I have to mingle.
That bum Shapiro probably uses
his own daughter to launder money.
Listen, you lousy Chink bastard,
you keep bugging Mr. Shapiro's daughter,
they'll scrape you off the floor
with a putty knife.
His name's Benny Garucci.
He's an ex-karate champ.
I'd like to bust his fuckin' head open
with a crowbar.
But you're gonna have to hold him...
He's a tough son of a bitch.
I wonder why Shapiro needs
that kind of muscle here?
Are you kiddin'? He can afford to have
the whole fuckin' Marine Corps
standin' by to protect him
if he wanted to.
That fuck owns half of Manhattan, Billy.
I wouldn't mind teaching Garucci
a little lesson in manners someday.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Laura Shapiro Marketing is very pleased
to introduce to New York City
the sensational Edmund Wong
and his fabulous collection
of shimmering cocktail wear.
- Nice dress.
- Nice tits.
Everybody, on the floor!
Don't move! Back off!
No!
New York's finest.
Can't even keep a girl from being snatched
- tight out from under your goddamn noses.
- We had our guns out.
You might as well had your dicks out
for all the good it did.
I'll take my dick out
when I'm going to use it, Captain.
We couldn't shoot
without hitting the girl!
I think you two men
did the right thing.
Well, thank you, sir.
Any word from Shapiro?
He has no idea why
his daughter was snatched.
We've been monitoring his phone
for the past 12 hours.
No ransom demands. No orders. Nothing.
You might find this interesting.
What is it?
A record of all the phone calls made
in the last 12 hours
by Shapiro's hood, Benny Garucci.
Six calls all to the same number.
- Country code 8-5-2.
- Hong Kong.
- How the hell d'ya get this?
- Friend of mine at the phone company.
- The blonde?
- No, the redhead.
What the hell does all this
got to do with Hong Kong?
There's somebody waiting outside
who might just be able to answer that.
Send in Mr. Cantrell, please.
Men, this is Bob Cantrell
from the Justice Department.
Are these the men
who kidnapped Laura Shapiro?
Well, how the fuck should we know?
They were wearing masks.
Excuse me, lady.
What's this all about?
These men all work for a powerful
Hong Kong crime boss named Harold Ko.
Harold Ko.
What, do you know him?
Anybody who knows Hong Kong knows Ko.
- A real snake.
- Yeah, and a tough one to catch.
Now, we've suspected Shapiro and Ko
of running drugs
from Hong Kong to New York for years,
but we've never been able
to pin anything on them.
Why the hell would Ko want
to snatch Shapiro's daughter?
We don't know. Maybe they've had
a falling-out of some kind.
Whatever the reason,
there's a good possibility
that Laura Shapiro's now being held
in Hong Kong.
It's impossible. Nobody could smuggle
a girl into Hong Kong that quickly.
- It's impossible.
- Not for Ko.
He's right. Ko's got most of the island
in his back pocket.
Sir, if Laura Shapiro's in Hong Kong,
we should check it out.
Forget it, Wong.
My Chinatown contacts can give me the names
of some good informers over there.
It might be worth a try.
Garoni could come with me.
He knows Hong Kong from his Vietnam days.
You're way out of line, Wong.
Like it.
If you men could find Laura Shapiro
and pin it on Ko,
you might just be able to shut off
the largest heroin pipeline
to ever come out of the Orient.
Okay, we got nothing to lose.
Why don't you two men go to Hong Kong
as special advisors to the local police
and see what you can come up with.
Yes, sir.
See you, Captain.
Thank you, Captain.
Thank you.
Here's the keys to that Jeep
you asked for.
Thank you.
- You sure you don't want a driver?
- No, we're okay.
Thanks for getting this through customs
for us, Inspector. We really appreciate.
Superintendent Whitehead will meet you
tomorrow afternoon at four.
- You got it, Billy?
- Yeah, thanks, see you tomorrow.
- Thanks a lot, Inspector.
- {Billy] Good night. - Sleep well.
Man, you love it?
We could stay at a better place, you know.
We're on an expense account.
Nostalgia, Billy, my boy. Nostalgia.
Memories of magic nights on R&R.
I remember during Nam,
there was nothing around here
but a bunch of horny grunts, you know?
And the women, Billy...
The women. Madam Mia.
And besides, nobody's gonna look for us
in a dump like this.
- What's that?
- An old Chinese coin.
A friend of mine in Chinatown
gave this to me.
It's sort of a calling card.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Looks like a bunch of shit to me.
I still say it's ludicrous.
The idea that anyone could smuggle
a girl into Hong Kong
without my office knowing about it
is simply impossible.
Improbable, not impossible.
Now, listen to me, you two.
I spoke to your captain,
and he told me
about your Dodge City tactics.
We don't appreciate people like you
in Hong Kong.
I want you to assure me
that you'll behave
with the utmost discretion.
Discretion is my middle name, sir.
Show them out, Inspector.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, sir.
Gentlemen, you must forgive
the superintendent.
He's been trying to nab Ko for years.
Considers it a personal mission in life.
I think he's worried you will succeed
where he's failed all these years.
Don't worry about it, Inspector.
I'm used to pissing' off superiors.
We ran down the phone number you gave us.
Shanghai Massage Parlor.
That's where Benny Garucci called
from New York.
Apparently, it's a rough place.
They, don't necessarily specialize
in giving massages,
if you know what I mean.
You bet your ass I do.
Let's check this place out.
Maybe we can shake Ko's tree a little.
Billy, you're a mind reader.
You two be careful.
One of the reasons Ko has managed to stay
out of prison for so long
is he doesn't mind killing anyone
who threatens him.
If he thinks you're getting too close
to finding Laura Shapiro,
your names will be on the lips
of every assassin in Hong Kong.
It's a friendly little town
you got here, Inspector.
Welcome to Hong Kong.
- This is my favorite part of town, Billy.
- We're supposed to be working, Garoni.
You know what they say...
All work, no play.
Playing around here can get us killed.
- Whoops.
- {man] Sorry.
At least you'd die with a smile
on your face.
- $105, please.
- Thank you.
Thank you. Please come again.
Welcome, gentlemen.
First time here?
We're just a couple of poor lost souls
from New York.
A good friend of ours recommended
this place very highly.
We have many friends in New York.
Maybe you remember our friend...
- His name's Benny Garucci.
- Yeah, Benny Garucci...
Benny Garucci, he really loves this place.
He talks about it all the time.
- Right, Billy?
- Right.
So sorry, we... we have so many friends,
I can't remember them all.
But I'm sure we can make your visit here
very exciting.
- Follow, please.
- All right!
Hey...
keep your eyes open.
Don't worry, Billy boy,
I wouldn't miss this for the world.
Billy, don't let this guy sneak up on me.
Hey, Garoni?
I'm gonna get you.
You know, you're very pretty.
You're very pretty.
My goodness gracious,
what have we got here?
Billy.
Yeah.
- Thank you.
Billy, look at this?
Whichever one you want is yours.
You made the wrong choice.
That's... I'm in love, this is mine.
I'm your friend, you got to take care
of your friends, don't you?
Come on, you're with me!
Whoo! Excuse me.
No.
Call in the other girl, okay?
Go ahead, make the phone call.
Becky, please.
I remember these holes when
they were a little smaller, you know?
What have we got here?
Will come, too?
Will I come too?
This chick loves me.
You love my clothes?
I love your clothes.
You remind me
of someone I knew in Saigon.
You know Saigon.
You're very beautiful-really.
No, you are.
How old are you? 18?
You guess?
- Excuse me.
- {Becky] Yes.
She really knows the way
to a man's heart.
When did you grow a beard?
Yes.
- What the hell?
- Yelling]
Holy shit!
What the hell?
Hold it!
You punk!
Drop it, motherfucker!
No, you drop it,
motherfucker.
Shit, what the fuck's
going on here?
Dress them and take 'em to my office.
I want to talk to them
before we kill 'em.
Hey.
A guy can't take a bath in peace?
- Why did Shapiro send you?
- Shapiro?
- Hey, wait a...
- I think you know why he sent us.
Shapiro?
Why, sure, he's very angry
at you people, very angry.
Shapiro's angry at us?
That's right, yeah.
- But he's the one who...
- Don't say anything!
This man is a New York cop.
Cops?
I ain't no cop, I'm a tourist.
- Maybe he's a cop. You a cop?
- Do I look like a cop?
Well, he doesn't look like a cop.
Take 'em out.
Kill 'em.
Tell Harold Ko we're in town.
His days are numbered.
It's never wise to make threats,
my young friend.
Especially ones you can't keep.
That's not a threat,
that's a promise.
Let's go.
Whatever you say, partner.
Well, you're calling the shots, Billy.
- What do we do next?
- Here.
What is it with this coin?
Tomorrow,
we're gonna cash this in.
If we use it right, it may tell us
everything we want to know
about Mr. Ko.
This Lee Hing, is he an informer?
He used to be.
He's retired, but he's still tapped
into the whole Hong Kong underworld.
Well, what makes you think he'll help us?
He may not, but do you have anything
better to do today?
Well, as a matter of fact,
I could probably think of somethin'.
Can you go to the boat
of Lee Hing Dock N' Shop?
Okay, okay.
What happened to your eye?
It's swollen. I think somethin' bit me.
You better watch out for Hong Kong mosquito
wearing high heels.
Hey, that's the jumbo restaurant!
Boy, do I remember that.
But I don't remember
the rest of this new shit.
It all looks kinda different to me, Billy.
There's Lee Hing's boat.
Looks like
our friend's doing okay.
I bring you greetings
from a friend in New York.
- [Who is your friend?
- His name is Tin Ho.
Tin Ho is a very old and honorable friend.
Well, Mr. Hing, look,
we've just come...
You are police officers from New York.
You have come here looking for a girl
who was kidnapped by Ko.
Gentlemen, there are no secrets
in Hong Kong.
Come, sit and have some tea with me.
If's the least I can do
seeing as how you have come
all the way to see me...
for nothing.
Soo Ling, cha for our guests.
Why is our trip for nothing?
Surely I could.
But I will not.
My father is retired.
Ahoy, Uncle Hing!
I've got a charter in a few hours.
Can I hit you for some supplies?
On credit, I suppose.
At least I'm consistent.
Hey, how ya doin' there, buddy?
I got something for ya, look at this...
- Straight from the mainland. There you go.
- Thank you!
You're welcome.
Mr. Hing, if you know anything
about where Ko is keeping this girl,
- you got to tell us.
- My daughter was quite correct.
I am retired.
But a man like you
must maintain his contacts.
Could you have them find out for us?
Gentlemen, dealing in information
like that is extremely dangerous,
especially when it involves people
like Harold Ko.
Listen, if there's something
you're not telling us,
we can take you in
and let the local cops deal with you.
Are these men bothering you, sir?
That is not necessary, Stan.
These gentlemen are simply tired
and frustrated.
Forgive them.
They are dangerous, father.
Make them leave before they bring trouble.
Don't look now,
but I think they already have.
Damn it,
they must have followed us, Billy.
No.
- Move the boat faster.
- Okay.
Watch out! There's a bike!
- Hey!
Quicker!
You're gonna take me to Ko
right now, asshole.
Shit!
You see? You see the trouble you caused?
- Why wouldn't you leave us alone?
- Hey, give me a break.
Tin Ho has asked a favor of me.
- I must honor it.
- Do you think that's wise, Uncle?
Maybe not.
But sometimes honor is not wise.
Can you tell me where Ko's
holding Laura Shapiro?
Not yet, but my friends will know.
Do you have a picture of the girl?
Right here.
Come back here tomorrow.
Stan will know where to find me.
Well, thanks, we really appreciate it.
Thanks.
What the fuck is this?
- Who's this?
- I hope we can say I'm a friend.
Listen, you creep,
it's not your money we want,
it's your ass.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Goodbye, Mr. Wong.
Danny.
Holy shit, Garoni!
Get the window, Billy. I got downstairs.
I must kill him.
Where are you hiding Laura Shapiro?
[Take me there! Talk, quick!
- Don't move! Raise your hands!
- Don't move!
Sit down.
I spoke to your captain again.
He assured me that a machine gun
is most definitely not standard issue
to New York City police.
I never go anywhere in Southeast Asia
without an Uzi.
Do you know what this is?
This is an initial estimate
of the damage you caused.
Look, at least we know
we're getting close to Ko.
Otherwise, he wouldn't have tried
to wipe us out like that.
You have evidence
that Ko was behind the attack?
Jolly good, let's see it then.
I think it's obvious, don't you?
You want to know what kind of reputation
Harold Ko has in Hong Kong? Read that!
He spent three million
American dollars to purchase that horse.
And he's holding a press conference
this afternoon to announce
that all its race winnings will be donated
to the colony's orphan fund.
He's 3 real fuckin' peach.
I'm warning you two.
I've already wired your commissioner
to ask him to take you off this case.
If I have to set eyes on you again,
there'll be bloody hell to pay!
- Can we go now?
- Get the hell out of here!
This Whitehead's a real schmuck.
- So what are we gonna do next, Billy?
- There's still Lee Hing.
Let's hope he comes up with something.
In the meantime, do you like horses?
I love horses!
{applause]
Ladies and gentlemen,
as you all know, Stolen Fortune,
the most successful horse of all time,
sired only one son
before he was killed in a tragic fire.
The son, Breakaway Threat,
was the horse they said no one could buy.
Thank you.
Stop the car! Stop the car!
It's my pleasure to present
my latest acquisition,
Breakaway Threat,
to the people of Hong Kong.
Mr. Ko, how much money
do you think Breakaway Threat
will be able lo earn for the orphan fund?
We hope to donate
almost two million dollars
Mr. Ko, how soon will Breakaway Threat
be able to race?
Breakaway Threat will be running
one week from Saturday.
{camera shutters]
Hey, Ko!
You left your briefcase
in our hotel room.
I think you are mistaken, sir.
Well, if this isn't your briefcase,
then this isn't your money either.
Excuse me.
Money!
I don't think
this guy Ko likes you, Billy.
That's too bad.
Are you surprised
to see Garucci here?
Not really. Right now, we have
mare important business to take care of.
You follow Garucci.
I'll go see what Lee Hing's dug up.
Whatever you say, kid.
If your father can help us,
we can shut down
one of the worst criminals in the world.
There's no dishonor in that.
Everything will be fine. You'll see.
Cove ahead.
Shit.
No!
No.
Father!
No!
Soo Ling, no! Billy,
for Christ's sake, keep her back!
Soo Ling!
No!
You... you're the cause of this.
You killed my father!
No, I didn't kill your father!
Harold Ko killed your father.
I hate you!
If you hate me, then you must hate Ko.
Help me find him.
Help me destroy the man
who killed your father.
Father!
My father told me to help you.
Even though he's dead, I must obey.
The fortune-teller was a friend
of my father's.
If my father found out anything,
the fortune-teller will know.
You look for a girl
that was taken from New York by Mr. Ko.
- How do you know?
- The I Ching tells all.
Nothing is hidden.
There has been war.
Between Ko and Shapiro?
Yes, but the war is over.
A man has come across the water
to make peace.
- Benny Garucci.
- Yes.
My people tell me
a pact will be made tomorrow night
and the girl will be returned.
- Where's the girl?
- I do not know.
But you must not look for her.
The I Ching is not good.
I see only danger,
death, and betrayal.
Thanks.
Wait a minute.
I must say a prayer for my father
and consult the I Ching.
What do your sticks say?
Is the fortune-teller right?
I ask the questions, Billy.
But I never read the answers.
- Close the gate.
- Thanks.
I trust you found the girl well?
Yes, sir, just as you promised.
When Mr. Shapiro refused to pay
for my last shipment,
I lost much face.
I trust it will never happen again.
It was a simple misunderstanding, sir.
Be assured that Mr. Shapiro remains
your faithful friend and partner.
He wishes no ll feeling towards you.
I'm glad to hear this.
But Mr. Shapiro is worried.
Those two cops from New York,
they're getting too close
to our operation.
Calm your fears.
The girl shall be returned to you tonight.
As for those two police officers,
they caused me great dishonor.
They will be taken care of.
Garucci went to this big container shipyard
before he went to see Ko.
Now, it's my guess
he was checking on the girl
before arranging an exchange
with the big man.
The fortune-teller said the exchange
will be made tonight.
So, we have to break in and get
the girl out before that can happen.
Tall order, man.
The rumors I hear say
the place is Ko's drug factory.
It be heavily guarded.
- Maybe we should call Whitehead, Billy.
- Hold it.
We're not sure it's the drug factory.
We're not sure Laura Shapiro's there.
If we're wrong,
Whitehead will ship us home.
I will go with you.
That's a great idea.
We know you can, Soo Ling.
But someone has to stay behind
just in case we're caught.
That's your job.
He's right, honey.
Now, if you don't hear from us
three hours after we hit the place,
you call Whitehead, understand? Call.
Don't worry, Soo Ling, I'll go with them.
You have experience in this kind of thing?
Yeah, you might say that.
Seals, US. Navy.
As a matter of fact, I just happen to have
some of my old gear with me.
It might just come in handy.
What the fuck is that?
I got that
from an Israeli friend of mine.
That's a portable, six-shot, 20 cannon.
I'll be a son of a bitch.
I ain't never seen anything like that.
Have you, Billy?
No.
The entrance is about four containers in.
It's a gray door.
About four containers on top of that,
there's an air duct
connected to an air conditioner...
That's how we go in. All right?
- All right.
- {Billy] Let's do it.
Okay.
Okay. Take the clothes and leave.
You wait here.
I'll bring down Laura Shapiro.
She better be all right.
Hurry up! Quicker!
Don't you want to go home?
Hold it tight. Quick.
Move it to this side, slightly.
Right, hold it flat.
- That's right. Okay, okay. That's it.
Go in.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
- I'll go first.
- I'll be right behind you, Billy boy.
- You got my back, Jones?
- Got it.
All right, let's go.
Hey, it's so hot in here.
Turn up the air conditioning.
Okay.
Drop your guns.
Billy!
Billy.
I told you, the Japanese make
great bullet-proof vests.
Let's get those fuckers!
Everybody out!
We're gonna blow this joint. Let's go!
- Come on, move it!
- Out!
Am I talking to myself here? Go!
- Come on, let's go!
- Let's move it! Go!
- Hold it! Up, up, up!
- What is it?
- Don't you understand English?
- The guard has the key.
Give me the key,
or I'll blow your dick off!
- Key, key! Come on!
- Key! Key!
What's the matter, you never seen
four naked broads before? Let's go!
Goad to see you again, Laura.
- Yeah. Hell of a way to get a date.
- That's very funny.
Got it?
The other one!
- Hurry! Hurry!
- Go, quickly!
- Jump, jump!
- Go, go!
- Go! Go, quickly!
- {man #2] Let's go!
- What the fuck's going on?
- They're gonna blow the lab up.
Some more.
- Got it.
- You got it?
- Go!
- Okay.
- You got it? You almost ready?
- Yeah.
Come on, Kid,
let's go while I'm pumped!
- Okay, I'm ready.
- Let's go!
- You with me?
- Yes!
This sucker's got keys.
Come on, let's roll it.
Let's get the -
Get him!
Shoot!
- fuzzing]
Where's Laura Shapiro?
The man asked you a question.
Fuck you.
Surely you know we can make you talk.
I got news for you, Ko. You're finished.
You're already dead
and you don't know it yet.
This is all so unnecessary.
Enjoy yourself, Benny.
Hello?
This is Billy Wong.
You've got a problem, Ko.
I've got a problem?
If you don't give me Garoni,
I'm not releasing Laura Shapiro to anyone.
If you kill Garoni, she disappears.
I'm surprised.
I had no idea your partner's life
meant so much to you.
{ believe we can do business, Mr. Wong.
Shall we say, in my shipping yard?
In two hours.
I'll be there.
Stan will take you to Whitehead.
He will get you home.
Look, I don't mind staying in hiding
until you can get Garoni back.
That's okay.
Get Laura to Whitehead.
Tell him to have as many men as possible
at Ko's shipyard at exactly 7:00 AM.
If he's late, there's going to be
lots of dead bodies to pick up.
- You're not going in there alone, are you?
- Yeah.
This is between me,
Benny Garucci, and Harald Ko.
- Open the gate.
- Open the gate!
Raise your hands.
Okay, go in.
Mr. Wong.
How nice to see you.
Where's Garoni?
Where's Laura Shapiro?
My partner first.
But of course.
You bastard.
I've lived up to my part
of the bargain, Mr. Wong.
Now, where is the girl?
She's safe.
She certainly is.
Whitehead!
I warned you, Wong.
Mr. Ko is a very influential man
in Hong Kong.
You son of a bitch.
Yes.
But a well-paid one.
Well, it seems that this affair
will come to a happy ending after all.
There only remains
one last piece of entertainment.
Come on, big boy.
You son of a bitch!
Come on.
This way! Over there!
- Hey! Don't move!
- Stand still! Don't go!
Soo Ling, you help Laura.
I'll take care of Garoni.
Going somewhere,
Superintendent?
Start the engine!
Stop him!
Get me out of here.
No.
Run him down!
Shit.
Jesus Christ.
Give me that fuckin' thing.
Give it to me! Come on.
In recognition of service
above and beyond the call of duty,
which resulted in the forfeiture
of over 2,000 pounds of illicit drugs
en route from Hong Kong to New York,
the Police Department
of the City of New York
is proud to bestow
its departmental Medal of Honor
on Officers Wong and Garoni.
Thanks, Captain. It's good to be home.
What's our next assignment, Cap?
Crowd control.
Congratulations. Well done.
- Well done, Garoni.
- Thank you, sir. Thank you, Mr. Mayor.