Goddamn bunch of cutthroats.
Oh, shit.
Boy, they'd leave me
belly-up out here
if they knew
I was getting ready to run.
- Don't you make a noise when you walk?
- Uh-uh.
Hey, wait a minute.
You got yourself all done up, Ruby.
- What are you up to?
- Here.
Oh, no you don't.
Uh-uh.
Ain't no trading today, Ruby.
And not no more, neither.
You folks gone too far.
Trooper been snooping around.
Air Force been through here twice.
You folks have to go rob a goddamn
Air Force PX for God's sakes.
We're hungry.
No one comes through
back there anymore.
What did you get?
Whiskey and radios.
I ain't got nothing to eat.
I'm sorry, Ruby.
I know you're starving,
but I ain't got
nothing else to trade.
I got no more gas,
no more cartridges, no more food.
And the folks in Corn Creek
have cut me off already.
They even talked of
blocking off this whole section
and marching
the National Guard through,
see what they can find.
You coyotes better watch
your p's and q's for a spell.
- Take me with you.
- What?
So that's it.
You want to get out.
Do you think you could pass out there
with the regular folks?
You don't know a knife and fork
from your five fingers.
And you stink like a horse.
You're getting out.
You take me, too.
Does the pack know you're doing this?
Does Jupiter know?
Why, he'd cut you to pieces
if I told him you were going over the hill.
If my pa knew you was getting out,
he'd rip your lungs out.
- Hello? Anybody around?
- Get in here.
That'll be the State Troopers.
They'll toss you in jail and throw the key
up a wild sow's ass and holler, "Suey!"
Well, I'll take a look around.
I don't see any...
Didn't hear you.
I was just cleaning up.
Fill it up and check the oil and water.
Give you what I got. Ain't got much.
I'm just closing down.
Morning.
Don't you mind them,
they just want to play.
Beauty, get down in there.
Down now!
That's... That's a good girl.
Odd.
I'm telling you,
we're in the middle of nowhere.
Yeah, I wonder how far it is
to the nearest cheeseburger.
We don't usually get folk up this way.
Where you heading?
California. L.A.
Movie stars and fancy cars.
California?
You sure as hell
off the beaten track for that.
Yeah, well, we're just making a stop
around here first.
You know this place around here?
The desert?
Why?
- You got a bathroom around here?
- Yeah, round in back. Round in back.
I need to make a litter dump.
You got a place to throw some trash?
Oh hell. Use the whole damn desert
for all I care.
Oh, I'm sorry, Bob.
Do you have your key?
Good.
How are my two baby girls doing?
Fabulous.
Hey piggy, piggy-
So, anyway, we thought
we'd take a little detour and go see it.
It's supposed to be a real silver mine.
Well, anyway,
that's why I was asking.
You see, it's my Aunt Mildred's gift
to Bob and me on our silver anniversary,
and that's tomorrow.
Lady, they ain't no silver left
back in there.
Besides, the Air Force uses part of this
as a gunnery range.
You folks just forget that foolishness
and go onto California.
- That'll be $6.80.
- OK.
- I've got no change.
- Oh, that figures.
- Detective, huh?
- That's right.
Bob just retired from the police force.
He had to a little early
because of his heart.
Referring to Strike Creek Road.
Do you know where it is?
Look, Mister, don't take your family
back in there.
The silver's been gone 40 years now.
Besides, there's nothing back in there
but animals.
Animals?
You mean nobody lives back there?
Nobody you'd want to meet, lady,
believe me.
See? There's nothing back here.
Jeeze!
Look at this place.
What's the matter'?
See something?
Ugh!
- What?
- Mercury!
I didn't do anything wrong.
I just came to trade.
Grandpa Freddy,
he says he's running away.
Shh! Big mouth.
Let's go,.
Come here. Come here.
Hold it. Come here. Shh!
Come on, Doug.
Come on.
He must have some animals back there.
Shh.
There's nothing, dummy.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
Yeah, you'd better check
your grandchildren there, Mister.
I think one of them's cut himself
on the window back there.
- I'll check it. Thanks.
- That's OK.
You folks go right to California
and have a good trip.
You folks stay on the main road now,
you hear?
Stay on the main road!
Let's get out of here.
What the fuck?
Oh, Lord.
There'll be hell to pay now.
Jupiter. Papa.
Papa Hunter, identify.
Mama. Pluto.
You see a station wagon and a trailer?
That's what Mercury said,
if you can believe him.
They coming.
We're lost. The old creep told you
not to get off the road.
The old bastard probably snuck up here
and ripped off our mine
and that's why
he doesn't want us up here.
We'll be French fries,
human French fries.
We are not going to be French fries.
We're right here someplace
on this little blue road.
Mother, this road is not a blue line.
It's a dotted line if it's on the map at all.
Oh, Jesus.
Nellie Air Force Base Nuclear Testing Site,
closed to the public.
Holy shit, Daddy!
All right, everybody shuts up.
That's it.
Man alive.
We're not on a bomb range
and we're not goddamn lost.
And we are...
Jesus Christ on a crutch,
what was that?
Daddy, slow down a little bit, will you?
Daddy, we're going to lose the trailer.
Daddy, Mum is...!
Bob, watch!
You guys
and your stupid silver mine.
Doug, are you OK?
Open the door.
I think the door is jammed.
Why don't you try unlocking it, creep?
Oh, I got it.
- Are you OK?
- I'm all right.
I feel like I've just been through
my first California earthquake.
- How's the baby?
- She's fine. Mum's got her.
I think we were lucky.
- My finches OK?
- Aren't you even going to ask how I am?
Oh, get out of my life, Bobby.
- Look, I'm wounded.
- What is it'?
It's just ketchup, folks.
Look out.
Oh, you're so stupid.
Twenty-five years I'm a cop
in the worst goddamn precinct
in Cleveland.
Niggers shoot arrows at me
and the hillbillies throw dogs
off the roofs at me.
I'm even shot at on two separate
occasions by my own men,
but none of these bastards
ever come as close to killing me
as my own goddamn wife and her
goddamn road maps and her wrong turns
and her goddamn
hysterical screaming and her...
Watch your language.
You watch your heart, too.
You know what Dr Springer said.
Dr Springer can take his stethoscope
and shove it...
into his little black bag sideways.
It's a turkey buzzard.
It's the janitor of the desert.
Does that mean there's a town nearby?
Like when sailors spot a bird at sea
and know they're near land?
Yeah.
No.
So pretty.
Pretty girl.
Threw the hitch right off the back.
What's the verdict, big fella?
- Well, the goddamn axle snapped.
- Oh no.
Forget it. Forget it.
What do we do now?
We walk, baby.
You know, Marlon Perkins says that
rattlesnakes can reach lengths of 20 feet
and can kill you in eight minutes.
Then you better not shoot
until you see the whites of their fangs, son.
- Or was it eight feet and 20 minutes?
- Oh, Ma.
Thank goodness
the boys at the precinct
presented me with this howitzer
when I retired.
Sure wouldn't want to go looking
for those pythons without it.
If it's all the same to you, Bob Carter,
I'll put my faith in the good Lord
and a little gunpowder
rather than coyotes and rattlesnakes.
This place must be crawling with them.
Well, Katy's taking this all calmly.
You OK?
I hate it out here.
It's just uncomfortable. That's all.
It's more than uncomfortable.
Lynne, honey,
would you get rne my jacket, please?
What is it?
Nothing.
I don't get it.
Why can't we raise anybody on the CB?
Here.
It looks to me like
these hills are full of iron,
and if that's the case, you're not
going to get a radio signal past them.
Would you hold this please?
I'm going to head North,
something on the map that looks like
a military installation here.
OK, fine.
You ought to have a gun too, Doug.
We only have two guns, and I think
one of them ought to stay with you guys.
All right, Doug. You walk out
six or seven miles and get back.
I'll walk out as far as the old geezer's
service station, and...
You can't get there
and back before dark.
It's only 15 miles back.
Sweetheart, I'll get there about sundown.
If the old guy's there, I'll borrow his pickup.
If he's not there, I'll borrow his phone.
But what if the old jerk
doesn't have a phone?
- Then I'll pawn it.
- Daddy, don't.
Look, you stay close to the trailer,
and don't bust Bobby's chops.
- He is in charge.
- That creep isn't in charge of me.
Hey! Another outburst like that,
and I'll confine you to quarters.
All right, men,
synchronise the watches. It's 3:38.
If you're not back by midnight, we'll
have to board the submarine without you.
Can we have a word of prayer first?
- Oh, mother, for crying in a bucket.
- Brenda!
Just to ask the Lord to watch over us all.
Is that too much to ask?
Bob?
Heavenly Father, watch over us
for the rest of this day.
Keep us in thy care in Jesus' name.
Amen.
So long, troops.
Pluto?
They stuck good,
easy pickings now.
Beauty! Come here, girl.
Come on, Beauty.
Beauty.
Come on, girl. Let's go.
Well, at least it's cooler now.
- Oh, bring some plates would you, Bob?
- Sure.
- It is cooler, isn't it?
- Oh, yeah. Fantastic!
Now we'll all freeze to death.
This is a great way to spend the eve
of your 25th wedding anniversary.
Frozen French fries.
A huge clump of human French fries
was found stuck to a camper trailer
this morning by...
But who'd ever find us?
Well, it's kind of a pretty place.
There's certainly plenty of the sunshine
and fresh air.
- This much fresh air's unhealthy.
- Oh, it's good for you.
It makes me want to puke,
if you really want to know.
It gives me the creeps.
I suppose it's my fault we got lost.
Mother, don't be ridiculous.
It was Daddy's idea to go looking
around for this mine without any help.
We'd be in California by now
if we'd stayed on the interstate.
Showers and gin and tonics.
- The beach.
- Fresh clothes.
I wonder what's bugging her?
Maybe there's some rattlesnakes
prowling around.
You know what Freud would say about
your obsession with rattlesnakes, Ma?
I wonder why the beast isn't chiming in.
Beast never barks
until he's ready for the kill.
He likes to catch his victims unawares.
Hey, you know you're right.
Remember that poodle he killed in Miami?
- Do I?
- Oh boy, was that lady ever fit to be tied.
Was Daddy ever mad.
He had to pay vet bills
for a dead poodle.
All right, creep, what's your story'?
Brenda, don't.
Beauty!
Beauty, get back here!
Bobby!
Beauty!
Here, Beauty.
Come here. Come here, girl.
Beauty!
Hey, pig, come here.
Beauty, come here.
Beauty!
Hey, girl.
Bobby!
Do you hear him answer?
No.
Bobby, come down.
Beauty?
You folks
stay on the main road now, you hear?
Stay on the main road.
Nothing out there but animals.
Animals.
Animals. Animals.
Ooh...
- Here.
- Oh, thanks.
It must have dropped 20 degrees
in the last hour.
God, I thought I was out.
Hello. Testing.
Hello'? Anybody there?
Testing, testing.
Maypole, maypole, maypole, maypole.
This is Mama Bear Carter calling.
Do any of you bears have your ears up?
Gosh, I can't seem to remember
how this works.
- It's 'mayday', Mum, not 'maypole'.
- Hmm?
- Mayday.
- Oh.
- Did you put it on battery?
- Mm-hmm.
Well, here, let me.
Mayday, mayday.
This is mobile unit 2345 CB.
We are stranded and in need of help.
Do you COPY?
What the hell was that?
It sounded like some sort of animal.
Yeah, well, animals around here
are smart enough to run radios,
we're up shit creek without a paddle.
You know you never used
language like that
before you moved to New York City.
Where's Bobby and the men, anyway?
Brenda?
Bobby!
Beast, come back here.
Beast.
Bobby'?
Brenda'? You there?
Just a minute, Lynne.
Bobby'?
How does this damn thing work anyway?
Bobby, where have you been?
Bobby, your face...
What happened?
Bobby'?
Get your stupid neck out of that belt,
you jackass.
Should have left you hanging
after you took a shot at me.
Not until you tell me
what the hell is going on.
You're trespassing, that's what.
Give me that.
You always try to stop trespassers
by hanging yourself?
I thought you was somebody else.
- How's your family?
- Well...
The car skidded off the road,
we broke an axle.
They're back at the trailer.
They're all OK.
Like hell they are.
Give me that booze.
There's something
you should know about.
Yeah, well, what is it?
Come on, Beast.
Daddy and Doug back yet?
Not yet.
Didn't you find Beauty?
She must have run off.
Give me that.
Come on, Beast.
Come on sweetheart...
Back in '29,
this place was spanking new,
and me and my wife Martha
had a little baby girl
so pretty and good,
we couldn't believe,
and another kid on the way.
But when Martha had this one,
something went wrong.
This thing she give me,
something happened.
He was so big...
He came out sideways
and almost tore poor Martha apart.
He weighed 20 pounds
and was hairy as a monkey.
When he was 10 years old,
he was big as I was.
Accidents were happening all the time.
Dogs falling in the well.
I even found chickens
with their heads bit off.
Then in August of '39,
I was in town getting supplies,
and the whole damn house
burned to the ground.
My little baby girl was a cinder
when I found her,
but this monster kid
wasn't even singed.
I knew he'd done it.
I hit him with a tyre iron,
and I split his face wide open.
How bad was it?
I thought I'd killed him.
I was afraid they'd come
and take me away,
so I took him out in the desert
and I left him there.
I figured if he wasn't dead,
he couldn't live more than two hours
out there in that heat.
Then it would all be over with.
And you think his ghost
is still trying to track you?
That was a long time ago.
Long enough for him to steal
a whore that nobody would miss.
Long enough to raise a passel
of wild kids.
Long enough for a devil kid
to grow up to be a devil man.
What the hell is this?
That's just some stuff that I...
You want some cheese on this?
There's plenty left.
I don't want anything.
What's the matter,
don't you feel well?
I'm just not hungry.
- Your face still bothering you?
- No.
- Did anybody try to CB while I was gone?
- We tried.
We tried. Nothing...
Well, one time we got something
that sounded an Epstein caller.
What do you mean?
Well, it sounded sort of like
heavy breathing, didn't it, Mum?
It, er... it was static.
İt wasn't.
What was that?
Aw, Jesus.
What's going on?
Mummy!
Daddy!
Help me!
Bogeyman get me!
Daddy!
You son of a bitch!
Faster. Faster.
Mummy, Daddy.
Faster.
Your chest hurt?
Faster. Faster.
Looks like Daddy
going to fall down.
Over here.
Here.
Daddy all gone?
Pluto.
- Papa Jupe?
- Papa Jupe.
We about ready.
Hey-
You mind pointing that thing
somewhere else?
Oh.
Thank you.
It gets cold out there.
Here, I brought you a present.
What's the matter with you?
Well, for one thing,
Dad's not back yet.
Oh, hell.
I wouldn't expect him this early.
He had a lot further to go than I did.
Besides, it's slow-going out there.
Where are the dogs?
Beast broke his chain about
an hour ago and he ran off.
Oh, yeah?
And Beauty...
Well...
- Beauty, sh...
- It's Doug.
Hey!
Doug's back!
I knew when you smelled food
you'd show up!
He-Y, gorgeous.
Get out of here.
- How you doing?
- Did you find anything?
Oh, yeah. Lots of stuff.
There's, er...
I found a tower and a dump
about five miles out of here.
All kinds of good stuff.
Look at this!
Look at all of this. I mean, it's no wonder
we're paying higher taxes.
They're throwing this stuff away.
Did you go any further?
Did you find any people?
Oh, no. There's no people.
And I couldn't go any further
because the road just stops right there.
Just ended right there.
- Is there any food left? I am so hungry.
- Oh, come and get it.
- Come on.
- OK.
Listen, we got to go out there
'cause there's enough stuff
to open an army surplus store,
honest to God.
Ma?
What's the matter?
You don't like dog anymore?
I like it.
Maybe dog's too good
for a runaway slut like you.
The dog's ghost
is talking out there tonight.
Another dog.
Great big stud.
Mama.
Mama?
Let me come inside?
Goodies around here...
...means he ain't around there.
Where?
Never you mind.
Bobby? Come on in.
Don't catch a cold.
- Are you sure you're all right?
- I'm fine.
OK.
Don't lock that too hard, old bean,
we're going out in a second.
- Hey, where you going?
- The sack.
I don't think you should sleep
in the station wagon tonight.
- Why not?
- Look, sleep in here on the floor.
- What are you, nuts?
- Look, Doug, I've got to talk to you.
- All set?
- Yeah. All set.
Hey. I guarantee you
that he'll be back here by 9:30.
Bobby's worried that rattlesnakes
are going to get Big Bob.
- It isn't that.
- Hey.
You better worry about what Big Bob
will do to the rattlesnakes.
Come on, you.
Uh...
Listen. if he's not back here by 11 o'clock,
we'll go out and meet him, OK?
Sleep well.
I'm scared.
Beast?
Beast! Come here, boy!
Come on!
Beast?
Ugh!
Hey, boy.
Come here, boy.
Just...
Come on.
Ugh! Ha...
Stupid...
Jesus!
What do you want?
I mean, the amount of privacy we get
on this trip has been zero.
I'm not the one knocking on windows
in the middle of the night.
All right, this better be good.
- I need your keys.
- Oh, for crying out loud!
I locked myself out.
- Couldn't you wait?
- Goddamnit! Give me the keys, please!
Look, something weird
is going on around here.
Dad's not back yet.
You said that you heard heavy breathing
on the CB,
and now Beast is out there
barking like he's hurt.
Oh, Bobby, it's probably Beauty.
She always sounds like that
when she barks.
- Beauty is dead.
- What?
She's been dead since this afternoon.
Beauty's dead?
What happened?
Why didn't you tell us sooner?
I tried.
When I found her she'd been gutted.
Somebody slit her.
It was pretty bad.
I... I was so scared, I ran away.
OK.
You just hold on right here.
I'll get a flashlight, and we'll take a look.
OK. Hang on.
Come on, come on.
- You stay here.
- I will not stay here.
Do 'u.
Oh, my God!
Oh, God. Ethel!
Help me, Ethel!
Oh, God! Help rne!
- Ethel, don't go out there.
- Let me go!
- Ma!
- Put it out!
Brenda?
Keep an eye on the baby, OK?
Oh, my God!
Ethel!
Help me, Ethel! Help me!
Papa Jupiter.
This here is Mars.
You and Pluto in, Mars?
We in, Papa. We in.
Help me!
God!
Oh, my God!
Ethel!
You son of a bitch!
You wait.
You wait till you get to be a man.
Baby's fat.
You fat.
Fat and juicy.
Oh, that... that's not my Bob.
He needs some water.
Would you get it, please?
That's not my Bob!
Not my Bob!
He wants some water.
No, it's not Bob.
Lynne, Lynne, please,
take her to get some water, please.
I'll take you, Mama.
And some whiskey and blankets too.
- That's not my Bob!
- Whiskey and blankets.
You all right, man?
What... what are you doing?
Where are you going?
You're not my father.
I'm going to get those bastards.
- Bobby?
- I will.
So long, Papa.
Women coming, Mars.
Let's get what we came for and get out.
- Katy!
- What was that?
Oh, Katy!
Where the hell are you going
with my baby?
Get out of my way, bitch.
Get out of here!
You...
Take the baby.
You better move your ass.
I come back for you later, girlie.
It's all right...
It's all right. It's all right.
It's all right, baby. It's all right.
Don't go, baby.
Don't go away.
OK. OK.
Oh, Jesus!
Katy?
Get her inside and see to your mum.
Oh, my God.
Why are you doing this?
What do you want?
Damn you!
Give rne back my baby.
My Catherine.
Please.
Come on.
Yeah, he's still got a gun.
Yeah, I got bullets.
Mercury?
You paying attention, Mercury?
You know how to use that thing?
Huh, Mercury?
Wait a minute.
I see you...
you got something to eat!
We got the goods,
and how, Mercury.
- Is that a baby?
- You be a good, dog, you get some.
Mama Jupi so happy.
Papa Jupi so happy.
Maybe I make a joke like last time
and eat the toes.
You think everybody laugh?
We always laugh at you, Mercury.
Coming through.
OK, Pluto.
What?
I thought I heard something,
rocks falling.
You got rocks in your head, asshole.
Let's go.
- I heard you tried to run away.
- No, Papa, no.
I heard you messing
with Grandpa Fred.
I fixed Grandpa Fred good.
I like fixing people good.
Bobby'?
What you got there?
Is that what I think it is?
Oh, yeah.
About time we got
some powerful food around here.
- We're going to eat it, too.
- Call in Mercury!
- We don't need no watch no more.
- OK, Papa.
We caught us a young
Thanksgiving turkey.
What we going to do?
They got our food, our ammo,
they killed Dad and Lynn
and they got the baby.
And they're going to be back.
What are we going to do?
She hasn't said a word all night.
Mercury don't answer, Papa Ju.
Don't answer?
Maybe you don't know
how to work it right.
I don't think that's it,
I told you I heard something.
- You heard what?
- I'll go find him.
You go do that.
Did you kill them all
like I told you to?
Did you kill them all like I said?
Such a small place, a trailer.
When it's messy, it's so messy.
Yeah.
Daddy back yet?
No, not yet.
Where's the kids, back yet?
Yeah, Brenda's right here
and Bobby's in the kitchen.
Drinking Coke, I bet.
Lynn sleep?
Yeah.
Can I get you anything?
Another blanket, can I have one?
It's chilly.
This will keep you warm.
This will keep you nice and warm.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Oh, no!
- Turn the lights on, please.
- Oh Christ, the battery must be dead.
- Bobby, I'm scared.
- I think the bastards took the lantern.
Coming back for me!
Coming to get me, Bobby!
Shut up, will you?
I hear them outside.
Shh! Shh!
- It's OK.
- Maybe I got that son of a bitch.
Mercury?
Mercury, you all right?
Mercury, where are you?
Cover me.
Hello, Papa? Hello, Papa Jupe?
Hold on Pluto, I'll get him.
The beast?
- That sound like the beast to you?
- I don't think it was.
Yeah, I think it was.
I'm telling you,
they can do the beast perfect.
Bobby, is it all right?
Beast, what are you trying to do?
Oh, get off of rne.
Where have you been?
Huh? Where have you been?
You bring this?
This is Jupiter, what you find?
Mercury's dead, Papa.
He's at the bottom of the cliff.
Mercury's dead? He fall?
He was pushed.
Papa Jupe) Pushed?
Who the hell pushed my boy?
Devil dog.
The big bastards tracks
are right on Mercury's chest.
Good boy!
Pluto! You come back here.
We got some things to do.
You understand what I'm saying?
I'm coming, Papa.
Uh-oh.
Your dog made sport
of my blood, you pig.
I'm going to kill your kids for that.
You come out here
and stick your life in my face.
Stick your fingers in my pie.
That was a bad mistake.
I thought you was smart and tough.
- You're stupid.
- Yeah, you sure are.
You're nothing.
I'm going to watch your goddamn car
rust out, yes I will.
Right, Father. Tell him.
I'll see the wind
blow your dried up seeds away.
I'll eat the heart of your stinking memory.
I'll eat the brains of your kids' kids.
I'm in, you're out. Mars?
Yeah, Papa?
You keep an eye
on that young tenderloin baby.
I want nothing happening to her
unless I say so.
You get me, Papa.
I'm going with you.
I don't care.
Well, you got that cut on your legs,
a blood pipe as big as your thumb.
Good place to cut somebody,
but not so good to get cut there yourself.
Guys!
I got a feeling that tenderloin's daddy
is going to come looking for her.
- You can take care of him then.
- I'll rip his lungs out.
You do that.
- You got bullets for that there cannon?
- All loaded, Papa Jupe.
It's getting light out.
Let's get started.
Wait for me.
Shh!
Bobby'?
Bobby, you read rne?
Shh! Bobby'?
This is a breaker one-niner
for KUY-9532.
Mayday, mayday, mayday.
Goddamnit, mayday.
This is a breaker KUY-195.
Does anybody read this?
This an SOS. Mayday.
This is a breaker one-niner
for KUY-9532.
Does anybody read this?
We need police help.
Mayday,
Look, Brenda,
will you keep it down?
Oh, no.
It's pretty quiet.
- Think they're laying for us?
- Wouldn't be surprised.
Hello, police?
Air Force?
This is KUY-9532
calling mayday, mayday.
Hello KUY,
this is Air Force Rescue.
We have you loud and clear.
What's up?
Thank God.
Hello listen, we're under attack.
I don't know who. They killed three of us,
and they kidnapped a baby.
OK, OK. Now hold on.
What are your defensive capabilities
at this time?
One gun and I only have two bullets left.
We don't have any hunting rifles
or anything.
You've got to help us.
We're sitting ducks.
Stand by.
You've got to tell him where we are.
We are recommending
that until we can get to you,
you stand on your heads.
Stand on our heads?
Um, that's code f...
Just stand on your heads
with your thumbs up your ass.
Oh, Bobby.
"What are your defensive
capabilities at this time?"
Ha! They're just sitting ducks.
We'll go in through that wash.
They'll never see us coming.
Mars, we've seen some signs.
You might have a visitor
snooping around.
You keep your eyes open.
We're almost there.
Bobby, do you read rne?
Bobby'?
They're coming your way.
For Christ's sake, kid,
put your ears on.
Damnit!
Come here, fella.
Come here.
Listen, it's your turn up at the bat, OK?
So you go and get them, OK?
Go, go.
Maybe the real Air Force
will see this and come.
Forget it.
Nobody's gonna help us.
We've got to get out of this ourselves.
Well, if you've got any bright ideas, girl,
just sing right out.
- How strong is this anyway?
- Plenty, why?
Come on, I got an idea.
Come here!
Papa Jupiter!
- Mars.
- Did you get them?
Kill the baby.
- Ruby?
- What do you want?
- Get it out here.
- What?
- You know what.
- Just get it out here.
- What's going on?
Don't do it until I'm away.
I don't want to see it.
Ruby!
Where is she?
Katy!
Ruby!
Hey. you! Give me my Katy.
Let's get out of here!
Wait.
What?
We can't do this.
We've got to do it.
It's the only way to be sure.
Fucking devil dog.
You son of a bitch!
You piece of shit.
I'll kill you bitch.
I'll kill you.
I'll eat your heart, piss licker.
Puke eater!
I'll strangle you with your own guts.
- Take the baby, here.
- Lift this up.
You die, boy!
Jesus, this guy doesn't quit!
Oh, holy shit!
Got yourself trapped
right where they breed, boy!
Mars! Take me!
- Get out of here!
- Take me!
You ain't worth taking, Ruby.
Leave him alone.
Take me.
- Look!
- Ruby!
Mars!
Katy!
Help!
No!
You... son of a bitch!
You bastard!
You got ten seconds to live.
- Ten seconds!
- Please!
Get off! Get off me!
Mars!
Fire it up.
Come on.
Run!
It's working.
Shit!
- Come on.
- He's loose!
Hurry!
Hold your nose. Hold your nose.
Through the window, like I told you!
I'll get you!
Go on. Run!
Come on, open the door.
Come on!
Woo-hoo!
- Where are you going?
- We've got to be sure.
Bobby, don't!
Bobby, no! Wait, don't!
Bobby, don't leave me!
Don't leave me!
Bobby, wait!
Bobby!
Bobby, don't go in there!
Bobby, please don't go in there!
Bobby! No!
Bobby!