( VOICE ) I know you're
here with someone else.
But does he make you happy?
Does he know
about your interests?
I mean, does he
really know about them?
Does he spend weeks raising
a boat from the ocean floor
just for your viewing pleasure?
- Thought it might
make a good photo.
Does he pay someone
to release a watch of
nightingales
at just the right moment?
- What's wrong?
- Nothing...
- Rusty!
Release the birds!
Does he know, neurochemically,
how to make you happy?
- You have modulation of
sensory...
- ...Activation of limbic
system...
- ...Increased oxytocin...
( MOANING )
- ...Orgasm is achieved.
I know how to make you happy.
If we were here together,
I would do all these
things and we would be happy.
Am I crazy to think
we would be happy?
THE INFINITE MAN
( WATCH BEEPING )
- What?
- Didn't you call ahead?
- There was no answer.
- Well, this would be why.
- I don't believe it!
At this time last year we were
playing musical
instruments over there...
Fine dining in there...
Adult activities upstairs...
I didn't know they closed down,
I am so sorry. I am stupid.
- Look, it doesn't matter.
Let's go to the beach instead.
- The beach. I had a dream
about the beach last night.
- Great. Maybe it's a sign.
- No we can't. I've drawn up ths
schedule based on last year,
you see? This was perfect.
- It was. It was also
a year ago, and things change.
Motels shut down,
and people move on.
- I hold in my hands the
blueprint to a perfect weekend,
and if we stay...if we
follow this very precisely,
then...
- That's why we're dressed
in the same clothes as last
year.
- I love you in that dress.
I guess it's a controllable
variable.
- I am taking this stuff to the.
I am taking these clothes off.
I am driving to the beach
and I am going for a swim.
- Lana, please, I mean surely
a...
a deep tissue massage
is preferable to fighting?
- Oh, we're not fighting.
- Are we not massaging?
- No, no, because I didn't
come all the way out here
just to do exactly what
we did on our last anniversary.
- No, of course not.
- It's nuts.
- It is, you're absolutely
right.
I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
- You feel tense.
- Yeah, it's just...
- Please...
- I'll be in the car.
- Do you know where I'll be?
Upstairs with these babies and
some fractionated coconut oil.
Massaging not masturbating!
- Lana! Welcome!
Glad you came back!
I think it scrubs up ok.
I've bypassed the
main switch board.
I found the mattress next door.
Those sheets aren't washed,
don't touch those sheets.
And...the beach.
So...
Now, I had planned
a musical celebration
of your Dutch ancestry
for...about now. But...
( TEARS PAPER )
- You do not have to do that...
- Don't worry, I have copies.
It's a symbolic gesture.
The point is we can do
whatever you like.
- I don't know...surprise me.
( PLAYING ACCORDION )
- My love, Dutch klompens,
should the bass line seize you.
( BOTTLE POPPING )
- Eat! Eat!
The menu might be a year old,
but the food certainly isn't.
( LAUGHTER )
Except for the dolmades
but they last forever.
( SPRAYS MOUTH )
- Lana!
- Yea?
- Sexual congress in five!
- For our last
anniversary I spent months
studying the blue arts...
at least in erotica,
Tantric techniques...
- The Viennese oyster.
Oh! Depressed Elephant.
- I couldn't wait to try it
on someone other than myself,
but when the
moment finally arrived, I...
well I achieved
cosmic consciousness
faster than I would have liked.
- Your cosmic
consciousness was just fine.
- It could have been
more tantric, that's all.
Yes
- What's this?
- This...this is more
stimulating than Tantra.
- Well, Happy Anniversary
indeed.
- Something I've been
developing at the lab.
It is an external limbic system.
So this moment in
time will be encoded in here...
and stored...
in here.
- And this is stimulating?
Intellectually, yes.
The hope is...
that we can retrieve this moment
with complete accuracy.
Every detail, every sensation.
We can return to this moment
in time, over, and over...
and over.
This is your anniversary
present.
- Wow.
I got you a Bunsen burner.
( CAR PULLING UP )
( HORN HONKING )
- Terry!
- Terry?
No!
- You really need to tell him
it's over. You've broken up.
- What are you doing here,
Terry?
- I thought you should know
that you left some
washing on your line.
- You drove
three hours to tell me that.
- I submit these.
Somebody could
have stolen them.
- Hey!
Did she tell you that I threw
javelin at the Olympics?
Yea, I upset the establishment,
with my politics,
and my drug taking.
When they came to
take my medals from me...
I threw them, like a
javelin...off the balcony.
The officials got the medals...
- This has to stop Terry.
We broke up four years ago.
- Yeah, well now I am back.
( INAUDIBLE CHATTER )
- This is unbelievable.
Every time, every time he ruins
it.
- It's a long drive, maybe he jt
needs to stretch his legs
then he'll leave.
- What is he getting from the
car?
- His javelin.
- This is too much!
- And a pack of condoms
and some kind of cattle prod.
- What kind of stretch is this?
- Hey Lana!
Do you still have that
bifurcated dildo?
Or should I grab one from the
car?
- That was for him, not for...
- Okay, that's it!
- Terry! Terry, no,
you will not ruin another
holiday!
( ZAPPING SOUND )
( SILENCE )
( COUGHING )
- This is our chance.
let's just...take these helmets.
Hop in the car.
We'll leave him here.
Find a beach,
some cold beers...
a nice B & B.
- Lana!
Lana!
You can take him,
and you can go to the beach,
but you can't take these.
I never want to see you again.
- What? That's not funny.
- Yeah? What about
self immolation?
- Stop it!
- Is that funny? Setting myself
on fire?
I don't have a lighter,
I need to borrow
someone's lighter.
- Here.
- Don't! Stop it!
- Fire! Fire!
I will do it, I swear I will!
I'm a man with nothing to lose!
- This is insane, Dean, what...
What is that?
What is this stuff?
- It Is ginger wine...
- That's not...
- It's really sticking to my
skin...
( FLICKS CIGARETTE )
- No!
No! Enough!
What the...
( INSULT IN FRENCH )
I don't think you appreciate
the things I do.
And you, you...
( THROWS WINE )
( LAUGHTER )
- This jacket is inflammable.
( ANGRY GROWL )
- Stop it!
Stop it!
- I never want to see
you again, just go.
Go, go on!
Go! Get Out of here!
- Dean...
( CAR DOOR OPENING )
( ENGINE STARTING )
( CAR DRIVING AWAY )
( SOBBING )
ONE YEAR LATER
( LOUD BANG )
( PHONE RINGING )
- Happy Anniversary!
Guess where I am?
Lana? Hello?
Lana, look, I know it's been
a year since we last spoke.
But I need to see you.
I heard you moved to the beach.
Maybe you thought
I'd just forget about you.
Well I haven't.
After you left, I stayed out
here...
I needed some time alone.
Twelve months in our
old room. Thinking about stuff.
Trying to keep busy.
I don't believe I am a jealous
man,but I have been thinking...
about you and him,
and your...position.
I know I drove you away,
but I've been building
something.
I had some things
setup from the lab
and I've been working on
something that I think
might take us back
to how things were.
I think we should give
it one more go, please.
Things will be different this
time.
Look, no need to say anything.
Just give me a sign.
( DIAL TONE )
- Identifying instability
in a closed loop circuit.
Short the voltage source,
open the loop in the fourth
pass.
then apply a test signal
and observe the gain
and phase around the loop.
Make sure the voltage source...
- Dean!
- Hello.
- Hi.
Hello.
You look different.
- Different?
- More stable.
- Oh, I am. I'm very stable.
I want us to try things again.
- Again?
- Please?
- I do not know if I can do tha.
- Why not?
Have you been with
him this last year?
- Isn't that what you wanted?
- What?
No. I...I did so much for you.
We played songs. Dutch songs.
We ate dolmades!
I had planned some
very, very Tantric stuff,
it was going to be
the perfect day, and...
- You threatened to set me on f.
- Yes, but prior to that...
- Then you called me a whore.
- Sounds better in French.
- And all Dutch folk
dancing in the world
isn't going
to change that.
- Well no, that would be...
Why would you even suggest it?
- Because you're wearing clogs.
- The clogs are incidental...
- See? You're doing it again.
It's going to be just like last
time.
- No, not this time.
I am in control of
things now, I can change.
- Stop. I don't want
you controlling everything.
It always feels like your...
controlling me.
- I would never would control
you.
Please, just tell me what I can.
- Nothing.
I made a mistake.
I'm sorry.
If I could change I would, but
I can't, so we both just have
to...
- What if I could?
Just wait here.
- Where are you going?
- To change out of these clogs.
I need shoes
for where we're going.
What about now
are you guys still...together?
- It's complicated.
- Good.
I can work with that.
- Dean!
What are you doing up there?
( MUSIC PLAYING )
- Happy Anniversary.
- Is this why you got me out he?
- There's more.
( SNIFFING )
The ocean.
- I came straight from the beac.
- The beach?
Why?
- I was worried
about you. You just...
- About me?
- Does this mean you're
giving me a chance?
- Yes.
I'm giving you a chance.
- There's something
I want to show you.
- One year ago, we recorded
something onto this drive.
Since then I've been
working a retrieval system.
Something to get
what's on here...
into here.
- And what is on there exactly?
- The past. A point in time.
- Our anniversary weekend.
- This will take us there.
- You still have the
Bunsen burner I gave you.
- I've kept the flame
alive all this time.
- Is that even possible?
- Changing the propane can be
difficult, but...it's
achievable.
( COMPUTER HUMMING )
- It wasn't the best
weekend though, was it?
- No, it wasn't.
- So why do you want to re-live
it?
- I do not want to re-live it...
I want to change it.
( WATCH BEEPING )
- What?
- Didn't you call ahead?
- There was no answer.
- Well, this would be why.
- I don't believe it!
At this time last year we were
playing musical
instruments over there...
Fine dining in there...
Adult activities upstairs...
I didn't know they closed down,
I am so sorry. I am stupid.
- Look, it doesn't matter.
Let's go to the beach instead.
( LAUGHTER )
- This is the past!
This is...this is...
this is...definitely the...the
past!
- This was meant to be,
the perfect weekend and it
wasn't.
- No.
- But this time it will be. It
will be...
perfect.
And when Terry arrives I will
knock him off the balcony
with his own javelin.
You'll stay with me,
and she'll stay with him...
- We traveled
one year into the past
just so you can
hit Terry with a stick?
- No. Well...
Yes, it was one of the reasons.
But why would you
be defending him?
- I am not...
I am not defending him.
- I'll be in the car.
- No no!
- Not this time, please.
Just let me show you
what I have planned.
- Do you know where I'll be?
Upstairs with these babies and
some fractionated coconut oil.
Massaging not masturbating!
- This is a copy
of the original schedule.
Marked up areas of
improvement, here, here and
here.
Then we'll do the
whole thing again but this time,
we will do it right.
There will be better songs,
more champagne
coitus uninterruptus.
And then, see...the beach.
You and me. The schedule.
Now, was it a deep tissue
massage in the old room? Or...
- I don't know.
- Well just look at the
schedule.
- I thought things were
going to be different Dean.
They will be! It's not
going to be like last time.
- Lana!
Welcome! Glad you came back!
I think it scrubs ok.
I've bypassed the
main switch board.
- I found a mattress next door..
- Dean.
- Those sheets aren't washed...
- And...the beach
You came back!
- I found this in the car.
- "Some additional notes
for the weekend, by Dean
Trilby."
- They're just some random thou.
- ''Chapter One..."
"the history of pleasure."
( SCOFFS )
It's hardly a history.
- "Subsection A..."The Dawn of
Man" "
I know how much
this means to you.
So...let's take a look
at that anniversary suite.
( DOOR CREAKING )
( FLIES BUZZING )
- Unfortunately our old
room is a bit of a mess. So...
- It's different.
- Yea, it is...different. Twice.
Sorry, it was meant
to be an improvement.
- Well, what are the other
agenda items?
Musical celebration
of your Dutch ancestry.
- Yea...
- Hey!
- There's supposed
to be Dutch folk music,
and don't even
have a damn rummelpott.
- Shhh.
Can you hear that? Listen...
Where is that coming from?
( ACCORDION PLAYING )
- Shall we eat?
( BOTTLE POPPING )
- Well, what are our options?
Hunting?
Roadkill? Soil?
( SNIFFING )
Wait?
- Is that?
( OPENS DOOR )
- I could swear there's
lobster...
( SHUTS DOOR )
- Lana, Lana!
Wait! Wait!
Lana!
( GASPING )
- It is lobster!
- In a white wine sauce!
I'am going to go upstairs
and go get your
anniversary present.
Just wait here. Love you!
- I love you!
- Dean!
( GASPS )
- What are you doing?
- Waiting for you?
- Where's Dean?
- Upstairs, something about
cosmic consciousness.
Are you planning
to have sex with her?
- What? No!
( GASPS )
- Yes you are!
I remember you said you were
going to get my
anniversary present.
You were going
to have sex with her
and record it on your brain
thing.
That is...I am not
planning to have sex with her.
- Lana?
- Yea?
- Sexual congress in five.
- You said it really tough time.
- Yes, but what about me?
- You both!
- I traveled through time.
- I realize that.
- Well, maybe I should just
go have sex with him.
- Him and her?
- Uh Hm.
- Firstly, that's a paradox.
Second, legally...
like a threesome like that...
- Well, maybe if it's
not to paradoxical
we could have sex.
- Me and you?
- That's part of the...schedule.
- All my Tantra books
are in the other room.
- Oh it doesn't matter.
- Do wish we
had the head pieces..
- We don't need the head pieces.
- It would just be better,
that's all.
- Hey, just forget about the
books,
and the head pieces,
and everything else.
Just close your eyes...
and put it out of your...
( CAR PULLING UP )
( CAR HORN HONKING )
( SIGHING )
Terry.
- Look at him.
Look at his body.
- "The vessel for honorable use.
It's what he calls it.
- You once said he was more...
( SIGHING )
athletic in bed?
- Oh come on!
I am not going to talk about
this.
- Please, we need to talk about
it.
- Just different influences.
Terry's approach to sex is
very...old Testament.
You know, sword and
sandals, blood and guts.
- And what would you say are
my sexual influences?
- Oh, I do not know, do not
know!
Dialectical theater.
German philosophy.
The metronome.
Pythagoras.
- Pythagoras?
- Yea. It's just different.
- You want blood and guts,
I'll give you blood and guts.
- I want you to let it go.
- Twelve months
preparing for this moment.
- Let it go.
Five minutes?
I'll come back.
We'll go for a swim.
We'll catch some rays,
some sun, a few...
Please, just...wait here.
Pythagoras...
- I should say...
that I didn't come here...stric.
on account of your underwear.
I had other business.
- Does this too
involve my underwear?
- Terry!
- Indirectly, yes.
- Terry...
- Your javelin.
- We are working
ourselves into a cycle here.
- I just...want to hold the
javelin.
- This javelin...
It puts me in a line.
A long line...
from Greek gods
to mortal men. Greek men.
Please just give me the javelin.
- Dean. Just let him toss his
damn stick.
- Lana, wait please,
I am doing this for us.
- This has nothing to do with
me.
- Not the window!
( THUD )
( GASPING )
( COUGHING )
- This is our chance.
Let's just take these helmets
Hop in the car.
We'll leave him here.
Find a beach,
some cold beers...
A nice B & B.
- I never want
to see you again!
Go.
Go! Get out of here!
- Dean...
- Lana.
Lana, open up.
Open the door.
Why did you do it? I thought...
I thought things were improving!
Why him? I tried to stop it.
I've tried so hard!
I've traveled through time for
you!
Who else would do that for you?
Who are you?
- Shhh.
Let's walk and talk.
- Tell me. Who you are?
- I'm from the future.
- My future?
- Yes.
You know, I've worked to hard
for you to screw this up for me.
- I want to see her.
- No. She doesn't
want to see you.
- You told her she
doesn't want to see me?
- Definitely implied.
- I do not believe you.
- You should trust yourself.
- There are things
I need to tell her.
- I've all ready told her.
- I'll tell her myself.
- What's the difference?
- Okay, you know what I do?
- Yes, I do.
- I'll go back to the present
I'll...
- No, no you can't,
that's not possible.
- You can't get her forever.
And when you least expect it,
when you've
forgotten I even exist...
That's when I will come.
Because you may have her now,
but I have the element of
surprise.
( MANIACAL LAUGHTER)
- What's that?
- Read it.
- "You can't get her forever.
And when you least expect it,
when you've
forgotten I even exist...
That's when I will come.
Because you may have her now,
but I have the
element of surprise."
- You'll try a few
more times in the next year,
then in twelve months
you will do the sensible thing
and you will
travel back for her.
- Twelve months?
- It worked for me.
( LAUGHTER)
- You know she doesn't love you?
She loves him. Terry.
- Not anymore.
- Why? What did you do?
How did you do it?
- Watch and learn.
- This isn't fair I love her
too!
- Yeah.
Join the queue.
- Just...
It's just...
( SOBBING )
( SINGING )
- Lana?
I need you to listen to me.
You are caught
in a very complicated...
- It was the only way.
- I had no...
- I had to use a toilet.
It's the only way
to keep you from her.
- There are other ways...
- It was the only way.
- What about the lipstick?
- Don't. No.
( CRYING )
( MASTURBATION SOUNDS )
( MOANING )
- Glad you could
meet me out here, Lana.
I have a lot of
things I want to tell you.
You look worried. Don't be.
( SEX SOUNDS )
- Dean!
Dean!
( DOOR OPENING )
( HEAVY BREATHING )
- Traditional initiation
ceremonies...
used to be...
the male who was...
inseminated with...
females emissions.
Mixed with...
with some semen...
from the Guru.
( CRYING )
- Happy Anniversary.
Don't worry, I'm here to help.
- When have you ever helped me?
- Look down there.
( LOUD BANG )
Remember this?
You went to call her.
Asked her to come out here.
- Happy Anniversary!
- What made her choose
someone like you, over me.
- We're not that
different, you and me.
- Then why? Why you?
- I do not know,
maybe it's for your crying.
- Stop it!
Stop it!
- What I'am not crying...
It's just...it's the
steam from the coffee.
- It is quite steamy coffee.
- Just why you...
why you and not me?
- I traveled back for her.
- And what if I went back for
her?
Well, I guess
that would make you...
me.
( COMPUTER HUMMING )
( KEYBOARD TYPING )
- This is unbelievable.
Every time, every time he ruins
it.
- It's a long drive, maybe he jt
needs to stretch his legs
then he'll leave.
- What is getting from the car?
- His javelin.
- This is too much!
And a pack of condoms...
and some kind of cattle prod.
- What kind of stretch is this?
- Hey Lana?
Do you still have
that bifurcated dildo?
Or should I grab one from the
car?
- That was for him, not for me.
- Okay, that's it!
- Dean!
- I should say that I didn't
come here strictly on account...
of your underwear.
I have other business.
- Does it still
involve my underwear?
- Terry!
- Indirectly, yes.
- Your javelin.
- We are working
ourselves into a cycle...
ourselves into a cycle here.
- Terry!
What are you doing here?
Here and there?
- Science.
I used your helmet.
- When?
- In the future.
- Dean. Just let him
toss his damn stick.
- Lana, wait, please.
I am doing this for us.
- This has nothing to do with
me.
- Eros...
and Psyche.
History.
It's all Mediterranean.
- Why did you come back?
- Well, you came back
and she came back,
so I came back.
I won't be excluded.
- Not the window!
( THUD )
- Terry.
Welcome to the future.
( STABBING SOUND )
( GRUNTING )
( HEAVY BREATHING )
( LAUGHING )
( THUD )
- This can not be good.
I've dreamt about this moment.
Many Terry's.
One Lana.
Infinite sexual positions.
- No, there must be
a finite number positions.
No. No there's no finite.
No. I could not be here.
I could be there.
And I could be with her.
Gonorrhea.
- Sorry?
- It is Greek.
It means "flow of seed".
Gonos...rhea.
Does my seed flow?
- No. There can't be more!
- Where's Terry?
- Oh! Thank God!
I thought there were
many, many, many Terry's.
- This is our chance. Let's jus.
take these helmets, hop in the
car,
we'll leave him here.
Find a beach, some cold beers,
a nice B & B.
- Me?
You want to go
to the beach with me?
- I do.
- I'll meet you downstairs.
- Okay.
- I'm so sorry.
- Look at him.
That's the look of a winner.
I've won.
- But he's dead.
You've killed him.
- Still the winner.
( ZIPPING BAG )
- I'm sorry.
I didn't know, I...
I didn't know it was me.
I'll tell you everything.
I tried, more than once.
Sometimes I just get
so angry with myself.
My other selves.
I'm so sorry.
- Hey, I know.
- Plus, there was a second
Terry.
- A second Terry?
- Yeah, he must
have traveled back.
- Why?
- To be with you.
- And where is he now?
- He's dead.
- Dead?
- Well he's not...he's not
going to take this very well.
- We should tell him,
because he has to know...
- No he all ready knows.
He did it himself.
- He killed himself?
- His other self yeah.
- His other self? God.
God it is so typical, it's
so...it's...
It's theater. It's Greek
tragedy. That is what it is.
You know he's not actually
Greek.
- I did...I did not know that.
- What does this mean exactly?
Is he alive or is he dead?
- Well he's alive and dead.
- What...what a sad man.
- Well, it's just us now.
- Lana?
Lana open up.
- I understand every
relationship has it's problems,
but this...this is really...
- I am sorry, just wait
here please I'll go talk to him.
- I've traveled
through time for you.
- Who else would do that for
you?
- Is he watching us?
- He is.
For one whole year
I did nothing but watch us.
- You watched us for a year?
- But we won't...we won't stay
here for a year, I mean...
We can't.
- We did it.
We were here...together.
We were happy.
Why would you
want to change that?
- I don't. I just...I just think
we would be happier...
somewhere else.
- Look. One year from now
he'll finish building the
device.
Everyone will travel back,
and it will be just the two of
us.
Then we can go
where ever we want,
and not have to
worry about these...
people.
I know you like the beach,
just...
Please trust me to get us
through this. I know what to do.
I've all ready seen
us do it and it works.
And I know in the meantime
we can be...happy here.
- Not now.
- It's only one year, and...
and summer always flies
by, so it's like...nine months.
Nine to twelve months.
Twelve months.
Then we can leave.
- And what did we do exactly
for the next...twelve months?
- Do you remember
our first actual date?
- I do
- I was nervous as hell.
You were relaxed, talkative.
Then I found your notes.
Famous quotes, current affairs,
topics of conversation.
- Art, music, science.
- Do you remember
everything about that night?
- Everything.
In fact, I recorded it on tape.
I wanted to review it
after the date,
and make sure
that I sounded natural.
- "Obviously it relies on the
presumption of male
hetrosexual spectatorship.
Does that make
it a bad painting? No."
"And...of course..."
"of course..."
- "Dean, are you okay?"
( FAST FORWARDS TAPE)
- "And of course there's George
Brock..."
Later I edited the tape,
I spliced in a few gags...
Thing's I didn't think of at
the time.
- "Getting Brock the
basics, you might say..."
( LAUGHTER )
- That's not my laugh.
- No, it's the closest I could
find.
- You know what this is?
- What?
- Just...one big revision.
- It's an improvement, it's
not...
- Is this an improvement?
- I would say so, yes.
- Because sometimes it
feels...a little unorthodox.
- No...
This is the modern world.
It's a modern relationship.
- What are you doing?
- Going to the bathroom.
To see if I can lure
a Dean into a cubical.
- See, I would say
that's a little "unorthodox".
- Unorthodox.
I am a man
responding to his environment.
Have you got lipstick?
- I don't want to say
that you're living in the past
- Well obviously,
I am living in the past.
- But, I mean...
You say you fell disconnected.
- Shhh.
- Maybe that's why...
you feel disconnected.
Maybe if you just stop
listening and watching...
- What about you?
- Well, what about me?
- I see the way you look at him.
- It's the same way I look at
you.
- Exactly.
- So I do not want
me to look at you?
- No. Him.
- Who?
- Dean!
- Are you jealous?
- Should I be?
- I do not even know
how to answer that.
- I used to watch us up here.
I used to think we were happy.
- We are happy.
- We could be happier.
- Why do you
hate yourself so much?
- Are you kidding? Look at him!
Sorry. Just forget about it.
Tomorrow everything
returns to normal.
Everyone travels back.
And we're alone. Together.
We can...
go where ever we want.
This is the plan.
We do not touch a thing.
Everyone travels back,
just like they always have...
and then we are alone. Okay?
- Okay
- Good. Okay.
- Happy Anniversary.
Don't worry, I am here to help.
Okay, I was in the
bedroom, testing the amp.
- Dean!
- You called out...
I came down.
The other Lana, where is she.
She should be here by now.
- I do not know.
- Well, this is
how it began, remember?
With her down there.
- Well maybe...
- If Lana doesn't show,
then Dean won't travel back...
and if Dean doesn't
travel back, then...
Things will get very
complicated.
You have to go down there.
- What?
- Yea. Until the other Lana
arrives, you have to go down
there
and say all the things she said.
It has to be exactly the same.
- It's nuts, it won't work!
- It will work. It has to.
It's the only way
- But what if he
takes me back with him?
- That's impossible,
it can't happen.
You'll switch with the
other Lana before then...
they'll travel back
and once they do...
it's just you and me. It's
simple.
- How will I even
know what to say?
- Tape this to your chest.
Put this in your ear.
And I'll tell you
exactly what to say.
- You tell me what to say? No
no.
- Not tell, remind. Your words.
I am just reminding you.
Testing, testing.
It is the only way
to ensure they travel back.
- And how do I know which one
is him and which one is you?
Just listen to your heart.
Also, listen to the
ear piece and will tell you.
- Okay, stop there.
Now call out his name twice.
- Dean!
Dean!
- Ok, good. Now...
He is going to come to you,
just stay there and
repeat what I say.
- This is insane.
This isn't going to work.
- Shhh. Here he comes.
- Hello
- Hi.
- Hello.
- You look...different.
- You look different.
- Different?
- More stable.
- I am. I'm very stable.
I want us to try things again.
- Again?
- Please?
- I do not know if I can do
that.
- Why not? Have you been
with him this last year?
- Isn't that what you wanted?
- What? No!
I did so much for you.
We played songs, Dutch songs.
We ate dolmades!
I had plans for
very, very tantric stuff,
It was going
to be the perfect day...
- You threatened to set me on
fire.
- Yes, but prior to that...
- Then you called me a whore.
- It sounds better in French...
- And all Dutch folk dancing ine
world isn't going to change
that.
- Well no, that would be...
Why would you even suggest it?
- Because you're wearing clogs.
- The clogs are incidental...
- See? You're doing it again.
It's going to be just like last
time.
- No, not this time.
I am in control of
things now, I can change.
- Stop!
- I don't want you
controlling everything.
It always feels like
you're controlling me.
- I would never control you.
Please, just tell me what I can
do.
- Nothing.
I made a mistake.
I'm sorry. If I could change it
I would, but I can't, so...
- What if you could?
- Just wait here.
- Where are you going?
- To change out of these clogs.
- I need shoes for
where we're going.
- What about now
are you guys still...together?
- It's complicated.
- Good.
- I can work with that.
- Lana, where is she?
She should be here by now.
Where are you going?
To change out of these clogs.
I need shoes for
where we're going.
What about now
are you guys still together?
It's complicated.
Dean, what are you doing?
- Dean, what are you
doing up there?
- I'm just trying to...
- Wait, which Dean
are you talking to?
Lana, please. You need to
listen to me. Do not kiss him.
Lana, please!
( MUSIC PLAYING )
No, no, no, you can not travel
back!
Lana, do you hear me?
You can not travel back.
It's not possible.
Lana! It's not possible.
- It wasn't the best
weekend, though, was it?
- No, it wasn't.
- So why do you want to re-live
it?
- I don't want to re-live it.
- I want to change it.
- Lana...
Think! Think, think...
( SCREAMING )
- I met you...at X...
We traveled back...
one year...to Y.
We stayed for one year...
at which point, you met him at
X...
and traveled back one year...
to Y.
( HORN HONKING )
No, not now Terry!
I have to go.
- Can you feel this?
I am in the
business of energy fields.
Man is frequency.
Hologram bracelets.
I have a suitcase full of them.
They are an investment in the
future.
- What are you doing here Terry?
- Terry...
Terry's dead.
I tried to get him to a
hospital, but...
he suffocated in the sports bag.
- I'm sorry.
- I had to bury him...
in a salt pan.
And ever since then,
I've been driving
in my car looking for her.
And, spreading
the word, making some...
Why not, right? I'm on the road.
I miss her.
- I know.
- I love her.
- So do I.
- Sometimes when I masturbate,
I imagine myself as her.
Masturbating...
to a picture of me.
- I'm sorry.
- No, no, these are facts.
I do not want your sympathy.
- She's gone Terry.
- Where?
- Don't know.
She's stuck in
some kind of temporal loop.
She's just going around,
and around,
and around, and around.
- Temporal. Jesus.
How does it work? Your science?
Can you take me to her?
- Why yes.
But you've seen what will
happen?
Is that what you want?
- What I want is for the sun
to exhaust it's full and die.
- But in the short term?
- Even then.
- Well...
if that's what you want.
( KEYBOARD TYPING )
- Before it happens...
I do get to see her again.
Don't I? One more time?
- Yes.
- Okay then.
- I'll just be...over there.
( COMPUTER HUMMING )
( COUGHING )
- This is our chance.
let's just...take these helmets.
Hop in the car.
We'll leave him here.
Find a beach,
some cold beers, a nice B & B.
- Me?
- You want to go to
the beach with me?
- I do.
- I'll meet you downstairs.
- Okay.
- I'm so sorry.
- Look at him.
That's the look of a winner.
I've won.
- But he's dead.
You've killed him.
Still a winner.
( ZIPPING BAG )
- I never want to
see you again. Just go.
Go, go on!
Go, get out of here!
- Dean...
Shit! He has taken the keys.
- Could you drop
me off at the bus station?
- I can take you
all the way if you want.
- Geographically or sexually?
- Does one preclude the other?
- Either way. I'am going
to need petrol money...
- Bus station is fine.
- Lana!
I love you, Lana.
- I know you do Terry...
but we dated for two weeks.
And that was four years ago.
- Well, I think uh...
it was never made clear to me
that we had actually broken up.
- Well, I'm sorry about that.
- Apology accepted.
- Okay, Terry.
( CAR DOOR OPENING )
( ENGINE STARTING )
( CAR DRIVING AWAY )
- Lana!
Lana, wait!
Thank you! Thanks for stopping!
- We didn't stop.
- We ran out of petrol.
- Lana. I am sorry. I was
jealous.
Okay, I thought you were
cheating on me with him.
It sounds silly now, but I did,
and I imagined you in
every conceivable position
The Viennese Oyster,
Congress of the Cow,
Depressed Elephant,
and it drove me nuts.
And I kept coming back to this
place. These positions, and...
then I got jealous of myself,
and I created a very strange
loop.
But I think if we leave now
we can break that loop. You
just...
Just hop in my car.
We'll leave from here.
We'll find a beach...
Some cold beers...
- Depressed Elephant?
- It's when the woman...
- Lana!
- Look, Terry and
I did a lot of things.
- Abstract sexual things.
- We experimented.
- Why not?
You're young, you're free.
- Maybe we did the
Depressed Elephant.
- I can show you evidence.
Photographic evidence.
- It was years ago!
- We're having some time apart.
- It was over!
- Recharging the batteries.
- Finished! Many, many years
ago.
- Even if it wasn't, I am cool..
- Stop trying to please me!
- Done. Stop. I am sorry.
- I am going to walk to the
station.
- Great! I love the station.
( SCREAMING )
- Oh my god my hand!
- Oh jesus! Dean!
Jesus! Dean, Dean, Dean!
- Okay, let me look, let me
look, let me...
Okay. I'll just...
( KNOCKING )
- What is that?
- Nothing.
The wind.
- Inside your boot?
- Yeah.
Anyway, there wasn't even a
sound.
( KNOCKING )
Excuse me.
- Dean, where are you going?
- I am going to the beach!
No. Please, please.
- Lana!
- What?
- I'am going to get him to a
hospital.
- Great! Thank you! Thank you!
See? He is offering help.
- I know. I'm so sorry.
- So he'll go get petrol, and
then we'll get the car started.
Okay, he is insistent, but...
he also has the capacity for
real acts of kind...
( MUFFLED GRUNTS )
- Okay, hey, we need
to get you to a hospital.
- No.
You just get me to
the nearest coastal area.
- Okay
- Thank you.
ONE YEAR LATER
- Happy Anniversary.
- Why are you wearing that
dress?
- I...I thought you liked it.
- No, please, take it off.
- Uhh...you take it off.
( PHONE RINGING )
- It's the phone.
- Yeah, just...forget about it.
- It could be important.
- Happy Anniversary!
Guess where I am?
Lana? Hello?
Lana, look, I know it's been
a year since we last spoke.
But I need to see you.
I heard you moved to the beach.
Maybe you thought
I'd just forget about you.
Well I haven't.
After you left, I stayed out
here...
Think I needed some time alone.
Twelve months in our old room,
thinking about stuff.
Trying to keep busy.
I don't believe I am a jealous
man,but I have been thinking...
about you and him,
and your...position.
I know I drove you away,
but I've been building
something.
I had some things
setup from the lab
and I've been working on
something that I think
might take us back
to how things were.
I think we should give
it one more go, please.
Things will be different this
time.
Look, no need to say anything.
Just give me a sign.
- Who was it?
- I do not know.
I have to go.
- Why?
- I thought we were safe.
It's something I built.
A closed loop system it's...
...it's unstable.
- Dean... It's our anniversary.
Just do it tomorrow.
- I just need to open the loop.
Identify the instability.
And if I find you there...
I'll save you from it.
- But...I'm right here.
- You are, but that doesn't
mean you are not there too.
Lord knows I am
- Wait!
- Identifying instability
in a closed loop circuit.
Short the voltage source...
open the loop in the forth pass
then apply the test signal
and observe the gain
and phase around the loop.
( ZAPPING SOUND )
Short the voltage source...
and open the loop.
- Dean!
Dean!
- Hello.
- Hi.
- Hi. Hello.
- You look different.
- Different?
- More stable.
- I am. I'm very stable.
I want us to try things again.
- Again?
- Please?
- I don't think I can do that.
- Why not? Have you been
with him this last year?
- Isn't that what you wanted?
- What? No, I did so much for
you
We played songs. Dutch songs.
We ate dolmades!
I had planned some
very, very Tantric stuff,
it was going to be
the perfect day, and...
- You threatened to set me on f.
- Yes, but prior to that...
- Then you called me a whore.
- Sounds a lot better in
French...
- And all Dutch
folk dancing in the world
is not going
to change that.
- Well no, that would be...
Why would you suggest that?
- Because you're wearing clogs.
- The clogs are incidental...
- See? You're doing it again.
It's going to be just like last
time.
- No, not this time. I am in col
of things now. I can change...
- Stop. I don't want you
controlling everything.
It always feels like
your controlling me.
I would never control you.
Please. Tell me what I can do?
- Nothing.
I made a mistake.
I'm sorry.
If I could change it, I would,
but I can't, so we
just both have to...
- What if I could?
Please just wait here.
- Where are you going?
- To change out of these clogs.
I need shoes for
where we're going.
What about now are you
guys still together?
- It's complicated.
- Good. I can work with that.
- Dean, stop.
That's enough.
- What are you doing?
- I am going home.
You've lost me! I have no idea
what the fuck is going on.
- I'm just...
I'm just trying to help you!
- This isn't helping. This is...
I don't know.
I don't know what this is...
- Lana wait. Do you feel like
you've been here before?
- Constantly.
- No, I mean this exact moment?
- Dean!
What are you doing up there?
( MUSIC PLAYING )
- Where did she come from?
- She came straight from the
beach.
- The beach.
You followed me from the beach?
- I did.
- Why?
- I was worried about you.
You just...
- About me?
Does this mean that you're me
giving another chance?
- Yes.
- No.
- No?
- I do love you Dean.
- Oh I love you too! I love so
much!
- I know.
But it's not in a way
that I can really see working.
- What? I can make it work
this...
I mean, we've been
through a rough patch, but...
Please...
Lana, please.
- I have to go.
I have to get out of these
clothes.
- I love you in that dress!
- Why do you have to
make things so complicated?
- I was just trying to make it
better.
- Yeah? But what about
flowers, or a box of
chocolates...
- That would have been simpler.
I do love you though.
- But I just can't endure it.
- I understand
You have to go. Yeah...
It's me.
I know it's me.
Here. Inside here I don't think
I ever believed
you really loved me.
- Why? Why would you think that?
- I do not know.
I'm just going
through some stuff. Yeah?
But I'm trying to get better.
And if I do, if I do get better
then I'll come back for you.
- But not now.
- No, not now.
- It might take some time.
- But I'll come back for you.
- Okay.
- Lana!