Mmm.
You know, I thought I
maybe drive into town.
You want something?
No.
A hunter?
No, they would travel
in pairs, I think.
Come on.
Come on!
What's going on?
You have a gun?
Why would you
have a gun?
Jack?
Is he dead?
Jack.
Go to the house
and call the police.
Go!
Yeah?
It's Jack. I'm here.
What do you mean, "here"?
Rome.
There is a bar near the main station.
Caffe Ligeti,
Via Volturna.
Wait there.
Jack.
Pavel.
It's been a while.
Who was the girl?
A friend.
A friend?
Who were the Swedes?
I'm working on that.
It's going to take some time.
Did she set you up?
She had nothing
to do with it.
Pity.
You can't stay here.
I've made arrangements
for you to leave town
while I sort this out.
Take a right
outside the bar.
Then second left.
Via Magenta.
You'll find a dark blue Fiat
Tempra with Pescara plates.
I've marked a small town on the map.
Catelvecchio.
Stay there. Lay low,
till you get my call.
Don't talk to anyone.
And above all, don't
make any friends, Jack.
You used to know that.
Hello.
['Giorno.]
[Buongiorno.]
Where are you from?
America.
Ah, American.
[Ah, l'americano.]
Yes, American.
[Si, il americano.]
No 'il Americano',
L'Americano! L'Americano!
Can I help you?
I'm no good
with machines.
You are American.
Si.
You speak Italian?
A little.
[Poco.]
On vacation?
A working vacation.
Work?
What kind of work?
I'm a photographer.
Fotografia?
Si.
What kind of photographs?
[Che genere di fotografia?]
Pictures of architecture,
landscape...
People?
No people.
Just for publications,
for magazines.
Magazines.
Which magazines?
Different ones.
Uh...
...different publications
All right.
[Va bene.]
You must share a glass
of wine with me.
Come tonight.
Very kind. No.
You want to know
the truth about Abruzzo?
A priest
sees everything.
Yeah?
It's Jack.
You don't answer
the cell I gave you.
I'm no good
with machines.
You don't make this
easy for me, Jack.
I've got
a job for you.
It's a custom fit.
You don't even have
to pull the trigger.
I'll think about it.
The quality of
the brandy is good.
Smooth.
The only good thing
to come from the francesi.
You study our history?
No.
You come to Italy
to make a guide book
and you don't care
about history?
I take pictures.
Of course.
You are American.
You think you can
escape history.
You live for the present.
I try to, Father.
Hello.
[Buongiorno.]
I would like this cheese ...
[Vorrei una formaggiona...]
A wheel of Pecorino?
[Una caciottina del Pecorino?]
Yes, Pecorino.
[Pecorino, si.]
How much?
[Quanto costa?]
12 euro.
Thank you.
[Grazie.]
Here is the change.
Thank you.
[Grazie.]
And I thank you.
Thank you.
[Grazie.]
You are welcome.
[Prego.]
You're welcome.
Here, your coffee.
[Ecco, suo caffe.]
Thank you.
[Grazie.]
What you want, sir?
[Signore, desidera?]
Yes. Long coffee... American coffe.
[Si. Caffe lungo... Caffe americano.]
One american.
[Un americano.]
Yes, thank you.
[Si. Grazie.]
I'm Edward.
Mathilde.
Range?
150-175 meters.
Time?
Five seconds.
Seven at the most.
Targets?
One.
Firing rate?
Rapid.
Magazine capacity?
Large.
Preferably a 5.56.
The weapon must be
fairly light and compact.
How compact?
As compact as possible.
You want an automatic rifle
to fit inside a woman's purse?
A small vanity case
would be permissible.
A small briefcase
would be possible.
Noise?
Silencer.
I can only give you
a suppressor.
It'll dampen
the decibels
and dislocate
the sound source
and reduce
the muzzle flash.
I can't make you silent,
but I can make you invisible
as long as you're willing
to lose some range.
Two o'clock.
Light blue shirt, sunglasses.
Is he with you?
I didn't see him.
In any case,
I'm alone.
Here, one american.
[Ecco, il suo americano.]
Thank you.
[Grazie.]
I can accept
a slight loss of range.
You want a weapon
with the firing capacity
of a submachine gun
and the range of a rifle.
Can you do it?
Clarke.
A package.
[Un pacchetto.]
Clarke.
I'm Clara.
[Sono Clara.]
Thank you.
[Grazie.]
See you tonight.
All the sheep in my flock
are dear to me,
but some are
dearer than most,
especially those that
have lost their way.
Fabio. Meccanico.
''Car doctor.''
But I think his work
is not always legal.
Did you ever want to be
anything but a priest?
Have you ever wanted to be
anything other than a photographer?
I do what I'm good at.
You have the hands
of a craftsman,
not an artist.
You are good
with machines,
yet you told me just the
opposite when we first met.
Hmm?
Journalism...
cannot make you
a rich man.
Perhaps you are
rich already?
A man can be rich
if he has God
in his heart.
I don't think God's very
interested in me, Father.
Fabio.
I've got some damage
to my car.
Sorry, I'm too busy.
I'm the friend of Father Benedetto.
The American?
[Americano?]
Yes.
[Si.]
I'm taking photographs
in the mountains.
Okay, okay.
You need models for you photographs?
Beautiful Italian girls?
No, I need tools for
a broken drive shaft.
You're a mechanic?
It's a hobby.
My garage,
your garage.
Do you want me to take
a look at the bumper?
Yes, thank you.
[Si, grazie.]
How much?
[Quanto costa?]
Nothing!
[Niente!]
Thank you.
[Grazie.]
Is Clara here?
She's not here tonight.
Would you like a drink?
No thanks. Perhaps another time.
Letter from a friend.
Three dead in Dalarna
Hello again, Edward.
Does this place
get many visitors?
This is the only way
to get here.
Did you check it for
footprints and tire tracks?
Three days ago I walked
the river, both sides.
Let's check again.
Rounds?
I prepared two kinds,
10 jacketed, 10 expanding.
I'd like 20 of each.
And 10 explosive.
Not a problem.
Will mercury do?
Mercury will do
very nicely.
I brought my own target.
Right there.
Muzzle velocity?
About 360 miles an hour.
That's including 20 miles an hour
off for the sound suppression.
Ruger?
M14.
I've not had one before.
You'll find it easy.
I've re-balanced it for the
weight of the suppressor.
The fulcrum's two centimeters
forward from the grip,
but that shouldn't matter
if you're firing,
I'm assuming you are,
from a fixed position.
There's no major
recoil issues.
You should be able to hold
any target, even the smallest.
Go to the flower.
Fire into these reeds,
say, two steps
away from me.
Two bursts,
five seconds apart.
The sound suppression
is superb.
I couldn't place
the direction of fire.
I shall require the rounds and the
weapon by the first of next month.
In the meantime,
could you tighten the
adjusting screws on the sight?
They're too loose.
What about the case?
It's a briefcase. Samsonite.
Black. Combination locks.
You have a number
you prefer?
014.
What do you want
done with these?
How thoughtful.
''Asprinio.''
I don't know it.
It's like Moscato,
only frizzante.
It wouldn't look right
if the picnic wasn't touched.
You chilled the wine,
I thought...
Had to be chilled.
Italian cops.
Don't move.
So beautiful.
It's endangered.
You like coming here.
It serves a purpose.
You've never taken a woman
here before?
No.
Perhaps you do not have
a woman in your life?
Thank you, for a lovely day, Mr. Butterfly.
Sergio Leone.
Italiano.
No.
You're acting strange.
Strange?
Yes.
[Si.]
Almost as if...
It's like you can't stop
thinking about something.
Or someone.
Mister Butterfly.
[Signor Farfalla.]
You don't have to act.
Act?
You might have to
with other clients,
but you don't
have to with me.
I want you to be
exactly who you are.
I came here to get pleasure,
not to give it.
Maybe I pretend very well.
You give me more tips
than the other girls get.
I don't sleep
with the other girls.
Hi, Mister Butterfly.
[Ciao, Signor Farfalla.]
How are you?
Good, thank you.
This is my friend Anna.
Hi.
Pleasure, Anna.
[Piacere, Anna.]
Do you want to join
me for some coffee?
We're going to see an American
movie. Anna's learning English.
I would love to
go to America.
But perhaps we can
see each other soon?
On Wednesday I'm free.
Okay, I'll be there.
Where?
Our usual place?
Our usual place.
I forgot.
Where is our usual place?
Let's go someplace new.
You can decide.
Locanda Grapelli?
Great!
Locanda Grapelli,
good food.
Mmm-hmm. Grapelli.
See you there?
I'll see you there.
At 8:00?
At 8:00.
Goodbye, Mister Butterfly.
[Arrivederci, Signor Farfalla.]
Anna, it's nice
to meet you.
Another two prostitutes murdered.
Fuck.
Yeah?
The Swedes found me.
Stay put.
Finish the job.
How the fuck did they know
I was here?
Because you've lost
your edge, Jack.
Good morning.
[Buongiorno.]
You're up early!
I needed some air.
I walk here to meditate.
I thank God for certain
favors he has granted me,
and I ask him to look after those
of my friends who are sinners.
All men are sinners.
Some are greater sinners
than others.
But those who seek peace
have much sinning
in their history.
Maybe.
Forgive me, this is the
priest in me speaking, but
you have done much
sinning, Signor Clarke.
And you still do.
Something happened
here last night.
Everything I've done,
I've had good cause to do.
Do you wish to tell me?
To confess?
Yes.
For what reason?
For your own sake.
Perhaps I can
pray for you?
Perhaps.
I wonder how many bastards
have been made here.
You work in metal.
You were given some steel
by Fabio, the car doctor.
Where was he
conceived, Father?
Fabio, the car doctor.
Why do you ask me that?
You have each other's photos.
You have each other's eyes.
Was he conceived here, under the trees
at night, like all the other bastards?
I do not remember, Signore.
It was many years ago.
In the end it is I
who confesses to you.
Do you want me
to do the same?
For your own good.
You cannot doubt the
existence of Hell. You live in it.
It is a place without love.
Perhaps I have no right
to wear these robes.
But I do have a heart
full of a father's love.
Something close
to his heart!
And for that I am
both grateful and happy.
What do you have,
my friend?
Hi.
[Ciao.]
I was not sure
you were coming.
I wasn't sure
you meant me to.
Of course yes.
[Certo che si.]
Good evening.
[Buonasera. Buonasera. Buonasera.]
Thank you.
[Grazie.]
Here you are. Thank you.
[Prego. Grazie.]
Thank you.
[Grazie.]
Can you bring us a bottle of mineral water,
and Montepulciano d'Abruzzo...
English menu?
No, thank you.
[No, grazie.]
German? Dutch?
Gentleman speaks Italian as good as me.
I repeat, a bottle of mineral water,
and Montepulciano d'Abruzzo.
- Carbonated?
- Non carbonated.
Small town people...
Can I ask you something?
Sure.
Are you married?
No.
I was sure
this was your secret.
Why do I have
to have a secret?
You're a good man,
but...
...you have a secret.
Excuse me.
[Mi scusi.]
No, no, really.
[No, no, davvero.]
Thanks you. No.
[Grazie. No.]
He thinks
we are a couple.
That's okay.
Thank you.
[Grazie.]
Ready.
[Pronto.]
I need some more time.
You're testing my patience.
Just give me
a few more days.
You'll get two days,
then you make a drop.
Hi.
[Ciao.]
Where we go?
Someplace beautiful.
Are we going on a picnic?
A picnic.
Yeah. A picnic.
I have to practice
my English.
Today, we are going
to have a picnic.
It is a beautiful day.
Where we go?
You'll see.
I think it's good
we stay close to the road.
Don't worry. I've been this way
many times taking photographs.
Only you come here?
Yes.
Wow.
Like a paradise, here.
[Come paradiso, qui.]
I'm going to swim
in the water.
You come?
It's cold.
Maybe.
Come!
Come, Mr. Farfalla.
It's beautiful, no?
We make love
in the water?
What's wrong?
We should have our lunch.
Ah! Ah.
Look. It's a bullet.
Maybe the hunters
are here.
I don't think so.
I'm cold.
Edward.
Is that your real name?
Will you put this
behind me?
What?
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Thank you.
[Grazie.]
I just don't understand what the
hell you're doing with a gun.
A friend of mine
give to me.
The two prostitutes were
killed in Pescara, all right?
Did you see what
they do to them?
The police showed me
the photographs.
I want to feel safe
with clients.
Does it make you
feel safe with me?
You're not a client.
Then why is it
in your bag?
Because I work tonight.
There's a processione.
A procession?
Yes. Tomorrow.
In Castel del Monte.
We go to this together?
Maybe.
Really?
And after...
After that,
after tomorrow,
and the next day...
I can't stay
forever, Clara.
It's time to go home.
Take me home with you
I can't.
Stay forever.
Yeah?
I'll make the delivery
and then I'm out.
Pavel?
Okay, Jack.
You're out.
Hello?
Now, you listen
to me carefully.
One coffe.
[Una caffè.]
Two.
[Due.]
I see you've brought
it in with you.
Everything's here
as we agreed.
What's this?
Candy for your trip.
I thought you might
have a sweet tooth.
That's very kind of you.
I guess I'll be reading
about this in the Tribune.
Yes.
I expect so.
I'm just going to
the ladies, wait here.
Okay?
I'm fine. You?
Just fine.
You won't need your gun.
You never know.
Final payment.
Buy yourself
a retirement clock.
Goodbye, Mr. Butterfly.
Hello?
What happened?
There wasn't
the opportunity.
Find one.
I'm following
him now.
Boo!
I was looking for you.
I'm here.
What are you
doing tonight?
I work tonight.
Don't.
If I ask you to come away
with me, would you?
Come away with you?
Why not?
Together?
Together.
Forever?
Forever.
I love you.
[Io ti amo.]
Love you.
[Ti amo.]
I want you to take this
and meet me at the river.
Eduardo.
Go! Go!
Who do you work for?
Who?
Same man
as you,
Jack.
I'm sorry, Father.
Eduardo!