Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Let's go, ladies.
You're useless.
Move it!!
What the fuck?
Stop the ambulance!
My son.
Don't be sad for his death.
The spirit of your father is free
from the bars that confined him.
This is the last gift from Papa before he died.
You're a man now. You're finally
ready for what needs to be done.
You must bring honor and respect
back to our family.
Your father hid millions of dollars
before he was locked up.
Here are the coordinates where you can find them.
We'll take back what's ours.
With this money we can finally get revenge.
The people who destroyed our family
will know how it feels to be hunted.
He dies last.
Stay calm.
It's ours.
That was fast.
We got a new base of operations too.
You've spent so much time on the other
side you sound like a gringo.
I made it clear. Lowrey dies last.
I'm the one up here.
I've learned how to handle things, all right?
You've had me training my whole life.
The cop was a threat. The others are nothing!
Do you listen to me or not?
I wanted him to see the others die.
Just finish it.
Never disobey me again!
Everything for you, Papa.
He didn't die.
Isn't that what you wanted?
Santa Muerte wouldn't let him die
before he suffered as we have.
Don't kill him until I tell you.
He will suffer.
A little something for your fans...
I had him.
I had him right there.
I don't understand, Mama.
A bullet is mercy for this son of a bitch
who took your father from me.
He needs to suffer.
Then he dies.
You understand?
Yes.
Mama, they're all gone. It's time?
Yes, kill him.
But before you do it, look in his eyes
and tell him something for me.
What, mama?
Forget about me! Kill them both!
Kill them both!
Move!
The traitor is coming.
Get prepared.
We will.
Let's go!
Or should I call you Mike?
Not very thorough.
There was a time when touching
me would have melted you.
This used to be our place.
I wanted you dead...
but you survived.
Perhaps I made you too strong.
Or perhaps...
Santa Muerte is telling us something.
We were fated to meet one more time.
I've taken care of that.
It's just us now.
Why didn't you tell me I had a son?
What would you have done?
Taken care of him.
Like you took care of me?
Is it true what he says?
It doesn't matter. He's nothing to you.
Who is he?
Is he my father?
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org