Gentlemen, cock your pistols.
Gentlemen!
Barry's father had been bred,
like many sons of genteel families...
to the profession of the law.
There is no doubt he would've made
an eminent figure in his profession...
had he not been killed in a duel...
which arose over the purchase
of some horses.
Barry's mother,
after her husband's death...
lived in such a way
as to defy slander.
Many a man who had been smitten
by the charms of the spinster...
renewed his offers to the widow.
But she refused all proposals
of marriage...
declaring that she lived
only for her son...
and the memory of her departed saint.
First love! What a change
it makes in a lad.
What a magnificent secret it is
that he carries about with him!
The tender passion gushes out
of a man's heart.
He loves as a bird sings...
or a rose blows from nature.
Killarney.
Now, what shall it be?
Turn around and face the wall.
The object of Barry's attention...
and the cause of his early troubles...
was his cousin,
Nora Brady by name.
I have taken the ribbon from around my neck
and hidden it somewhere on my person.
If you find it, you can have it.
You are free to look anywhere for it.
I will think little of you
if you do not find it.
I cannot find it.
You haven't looked properly.
I'll give you a hint.
I feel the ribbon.
Why are you trembling?
At...
At the pleasure of finding the ribbon.
Liar.
Company, forward march!
Company, eyes left!
About this time the United Kingdom
was in a state of great excitement...
by a threat generally accredited
of a French invasion.
And the noblemen and people of condition...
showed their loyalty by raising regiments
of horse and foot
to resist the invaders.
Their scarlet coats and swaggering airs
filled Barry with envy.
Company, eyes right!
Brady Town sent a company to join...
the Kilwangan Regiment,
of which John Quin was the Captain.
The whole country was alive
with war's alarms...
the three kingdoms ringing
with military music.
At ready!
Present!
Fire!
Redmond, what is the matter?
Nora, were you obliged to dance
five times with Captain Quin?
I don't care a fig for Captain Quin.
He dances prettily to be sure,
and is a pleasant rattle of a man.
He looks well in his regimental stool.
He asked me to dance.
How could I refuse him?
But you refused me.
I can dance with you any day.
To dance with your own cousin looks
as though I could find no other partner.
Besides Redmond, Captain Quin is a man.
You're only a boy and you
hadn't a penny in the world.
If ever I should meet him again, you will
find out who is the best man of the two.
I'll fight him sword or
pistol, Captain as he is.
Redmond, don't be so silly!
I mean it Nora.
But Captain Quin is already
known as a valiant soldier.
It is mighty well of you
to fight farmer's boys...
but to fight an Englishman
is a very different matter.
You best have your
Englishman take you home.
Redmond!
Barry resolved never to see Nora again.
But such resolutions,
steadfastly held for a whole week...
are abandoned in a few
moments of bleak despair.
No, Nora, no, except for you
and four others...
I vow before all the gods my heart...
has never felt the soft flame.
Ah, you men, you men, John...
your passion's not equal to ours.
We are like some plant I've read of.
We bear but one flower and then we die.
You, you, you mean you...
never felt such an inclination for another?
Never, my John.
How can you ask such a question?
Oh, darling Norelia!
Nora was chaperoned
by her brothers Mick and Ulick...
whose interests would be affected...
by the favourable outcome
of her affair with Quin.
Redmond, how nice to see you.
Redmond!
How could you do this to me?
Redmond, in the name of
heavens, what's the matter?
What are you talking about?
I think this might be an opportune moment
to return something to you.
I...
Thank you, Redmond.
I must have forgotten it.
Yes, you did, Nora.
Captain Quin, may I have the honour of
introducing my cousin, Redmond Barry.
Miss Brady, it would appear...
you both have something to
discuss in private with this young man.
Perhaps it would be
best for me to withdraw.
Captain Quin, I have nothing
to discuss with my cousin in private.
Miss Brady, it would appear you have
a great deal to discuss in private.
Good heavens, Captain Quin, he is but a boy and
don't signify any more than my parrot or lapdog.
Indeed!
Are you then in the habit of giving...
intimate articles of your clothing
to your parrot or lapdog?
Mayn't I give a bit of ribbon
to my own cousin?
You're perfectly welcome, miss.
As many yards as you like.
When ladies make presents to gentlemen,
it is time for other gentlemen to retire.
I have the honour to
wish you both a good day.
Jack Quin!
What's the matter here?
I'll tell you what it is, sir.
I've had enough of Miss Brady here
and your Irish ways.
Ain't used to them, sir.
What is it?
We'll accustom you to Irish ways,
or we'll adopt English ones.
It is not the English way
for ladies to have two lovers.
And so, Mr. Brady, I'll thank you
to pay me the sum you owe me.
And I resign all claims
to this young lady.
If she has a fancy with schoolboys,
let her take 'em, sir.
Quin, you're joking!
Ha. I never was more earnest.
John, wait.
Hiya for a meddling brat!
Your hand is in everybody's pie!
What business had you to come quarrel in
here with a gentleman who has 1500 a year?
Redmond, me boy, take a seat.
Mrs. Brady and ladies, if you please.
This is the sort of toast that is drunk
a great deal too seldom in my family...
and you'll please to receive it
with all the honours.
Here's to Captain and Mrs. John Quin
and long life to them.
Go on.
Kiss her, Jack,
for faith you've got a treasure.
Come on, Jack. Come on.
There's the man!
Here's to a long and happy life together.
A long and happy life together.
Thank you.
Redmond!
Here's my toast to you,
Captain John Quin.
Redmond, how dare you behave like that
in my house!
Mrs. Brady, take the children out.
Captain Quin, my dear
fellow, are you all right?
In heaven's name,
what does all the row mean?
The fact is, sir...
the young monkey's
fallen in love with Nora.
He found herself and the Captain
mighty sweet in the garden today.
And now he's for murdering Jack Quin.
And I tell you what, Mr. Brady, I've been insulted grossly
in this house.
I'm not at all satisfied
with these ways of going on.
I'm an Englishman, I am!
And a man of property!
And as for this impudent young swine...
should be horsewhipped!
Mr. Quin can have satisfaction
any time he pleases...
by calling on Redmond Barry,
Esquire of Barryville.
I'll see the boy home.
A pretty day's work of it
you made, Master Redmond.
Knowing your uncle to be distressed
for money...
and trying to break off a match which
will bring £1,500 a year into the family...
Quin has promised to pay off the £4,000
which is bothering your uncle so.
He takes a girl without a penny...
a girl that's flinging herself at the head of
every man in these parts, these 5 years past.
And missing them all!
And you, a boy who ought to be attached
to your uncle as to your father...
And so I am.
And this is the return
you make for his kindness?
Didn't he harbour you in his house
when your father died?
Hasn't he given you and your mother
rent free, a fine house of value to wander?
Mark this, and come what will of it...
I will fight the man who pretends
the hand of Nora Brady.
I'll follow him if it's into the church
and fight him there.
I'll have his blood, or he'll have mine.
Faith, and I believe ye!
I never saw a lad more game in me life.
Give me a kiss, me dear boy.
You're after me own soul.
As long as Jack Rogan lives, you
shall never want a friend or a second.
Will you take my message to him?
Will you arrange a meeting?
Well, if it must be, it must.
Look here, Redmond, me boy,
this is a silly business.
The girl will marry Quin, mark my words.
And as sure as she does,
you'll forget her.
You're but a boy and Quin is willing
to consider you as such.
Isn't that right, Quin?
Oh, mm-hm.
Now, Dublin's a fine place.
If you've a mind to ride there
and see the town for a month...
here's ten guineas at your service.
Will that satisfy you, Captain Quin?
Yes, if Mr. Barry will apologize
and go to Dublin...
I will consider the whole affair
honourably settled.
Say you're sorry, Redmond.
Come on, you can easily say that.
I'm not sorry.
And I'll not apologize.
And I'd as soon go to Dublin as to hell.
Well then. There's nothing else for it.
God bless you, me boy.
This isn't one of my pistols.
It's all right, it's one of mine.
Yours will serve, if it's needed,
for the next round.
Good luck, Redmond.
Gentlemen...
cock your pistols.
aim your pistols.
One.
Two.
Three.
Is he dead?
Quite dead.
This has been a sad day's work
for our family, Redmond Barry.
And ye've robbed us of 1,500 a year.
Now you'd better ride off
before the Police are up.
They'd wind of this business
before we left Kilwangan.
Come on, Redmond, I'll go home with you.
How different Barry's fate
might have been...
had he not fallen in love
with Nora...
and had he not flung the wine
in Captain Quin's face.
But he was destined to be a wanderer.
And the battle with Quin set him
on his travels at a very early age...
as you shall soon see.
The boy must go into hiding
for a short time, anyway.
Dublin is the best place for him to.
He can stay there
'til matters have blown over.
But the child has never been
away from home before.
Wouldn't he be as safe here?
I wish that were true, Aunt
Belle, now you know I do.
But I'm afraid the Bailiffs may be
already on their way from Kilwangan.
Now, Dublin is five days' ride
away from here.
There's not a soul who'll know him there.
I don't want to harp on
unpleasant matters, you know that...
but you do know what can happen
to him if he's taken.
I'll be all right.
I'll be all right in Dublin, Mother.
No lad who has liberty
for the first time...
and 20 guineas in his pocket...
is very sad.
Barry rode towards Dublin
thinking not so much of...
the kind mother left alone,
and of the home behind him...
but of tomorrow
and all the wonders it would bring.
Excuse me, miss.
Would it be possible to have
a drink of water?
Yes, sir.
Good day to you, young sir.
Good day.
Will you join us in a drink?
No, thank you.
Would you like something to eat?
That's very kind of you,
but I have to be on my way.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Uh, excuse me, sir.
Good morning again, young sir.
Don't even think about it.
Get down off that horse.
Raise your hands high
above your head, please.
Come forward.
Stop.
How do you do? I'm Captain Feeney.
Captain Feeney!
Captain Feeney, at your service.
The Captain Feeney?
None other.
May I introduce you to my son... Seamus?
How do you do?
To whom have I
the honour of speaking?
My name's Redmond Barry.
How do you do, Mr. Barry?
And now I'm afraid we must get onto the more
regrettable stage of our brief acquaintance.
Turn around and keep your hands
high above your head, please.
There must be 20 guineas
in gold here, Father.
Well, well, well.
You seem to be a very well set up
young gentleman, sir.
Captain Feeney, that's all the money
my mother had in the world.
Mightn't I be allowed keep it?
I'm just one step ahead
of the Law myself.
I killed an English Officer in a duel, and I'm
on my way to Dublin until things cool down.
Mr. Barry...
in my profession
we hear many such stories.
Yours is one of the most intriguing
and touching I've heard in many weeks.
Nevertheless, I'm afraid
I cannot grant your request.
But, I'll tell you what I will do.
I'll allow you to keep
those fine pair of boots,
which in normal circumstances
I would have for myself.
The next town is only five miles away.
And I suggest you now start walking.
Mightn't I be allowed to keep my horse?
I would like to oblige you...
but, people like us we must be able
to travel faster than our clients.
Good day, young sir.
You can put down your hands now,
Mr. Barry.
Gale's Regiment of Foot, commanded
by Lieutenant General Charles Gale...
which has so gloriously distinguished
itself during the recent troubles...
wants several men to supply
the places of those veterans...
who have deserved to be pensioned
as lettermen, at one shilling a day.
All clever young fellows
who are free and able...
and are ambitious of becoming
gentlemen by bearing arms...
are hereby invited to step up
and meet the Recruiting Officer...
who promises that they shall meet
with every encouragement...
that merit and good behaviour
can entitle them to.
Those meeting the qualifications
will immediately receive...
His Majesty's Royal Bounty
of one and a half guineas...
with complete clothing, arms
and accoutrements.
King George and Old England forever.
Left, left, left, right, left.
For a young man in difficulty...
who had killed a man in a duel and
was anxious to find refuge from the Law...
the opportunity to earn distinction
in the European wars...
seemed a great stroke of good fortune.
And King George was too much in want of men
to heed from whence they came.
Hey, lad! Lad!
Lad!
Can I have a new beaker?
This one is full of grease.
Covered in grease! Give the gentleman
a towel and a basin of turtle soup.
If you want to vex him,
ask him about his wife...
the washerwoman, who beats him.
Mr. Toole, is it a towel
of your wife's washing?
They say she wipes your face
often with one.
Ask him why he wouldn't see her
yesterday when she came to the camp.
Mr. Toole, why did you hide so yesterday
when Mrs. Toole came to visit you?
Afraid of getting your ears boxed?
Gentlemen, gentlemen, you may fight it out
with fists if you choose.
We'll form a square for that purpose.
Gentlemen, step this way, please.
Both shake hands.
Shake hands.
Take your stance.
No biting, kicking or scratching.
The last man to remain standing
is the winner.
Gentlemen, commence fighting, now!
Barry's training continued
at Dunley at the camp.
And within a month he was transformed
into a tall and proper young soldier.
During this time the Regiment's strength
was steadily increased...
by the arrival of other troops...
in preparation for joining
their gallant armies fighting in Germany.
One occasion...
brought the welcome appearance of no
other than his second in the fatal duel...
Captain Grogan.
It would have been better for all of us
if we'd known what had become of you.
Didn't you think of writing
to your mother?
Of course.
But the shame I felt of losing
her money...
my father's sword and pistols...
I couldn't tell her.
Your mother wouldn't care
a pin about those things.
You are her only concern.
Now you must sit down tonight
and write her a proper letter.
And tell her that you're safe and well
and merry to brown Bess.
I will.
Is Miss Brady well?
There are only six Miss Bradys now.
Has something happened to Nora?
She took on so about your going away...
that she was obliged to
console herself with a husband.
She is now Mrs. John Quin.
Mrs. John Quin?
Was there another John Quin?
No.
The very same one, me boy.
He recovered from his wound.
The shot you hit him with was not likely to
hurt him, for it was only made of tow.
Tow?
Do you think the Bradys would let you kill
1500 a year out of the family?
The plan of the duel was all arranged
in order to get you out of the way.
For the cowardly Quin could never
be brought to marry...
from fear of you.
But hit him you certainly did, me lad.
With a fine thick plugget of tow.
The fellow was so frightened,
that he was an hour in coming to.
Are you in want of cash?
You may draw on me. For I got a couple
of hundred out of your uncle from my share.
While they lasts, you shall never want.
It would require a great philosopher
historian to explain the causes...
of the famous Seven Years' War
in which Europe was engaged...
to in which Barry's regiment
was now on its way to take part.
Let it suffice to say,
that England and Prussia were allies...
and at war against the French,
Swedes, the Russians and the Austrians.
Barry's first taste of battle...
was only a skirmish against
a small rearguard of Frenchmen...
who occupied an orchard
beside a road...
down which a few hours later the
English main force wished to pass.
Though this encounter is not recorded
in any history books...
it was memorable enough
for those who took part.
I've only a hundred guineas
left to give you...
for I lost the rest at cards.
Kiss me, me boy,
for we'll never meet again.
It is well to dream of glorious
war in a snug armchair at home.
But it is a very different thing
to see it first-hand.
And after the death of his friend, Barry's thoughts
turned from those of military glory...
to those of finding a way
to escape the Service...
to which he was now
tied for another six years.
Gentlemen may talk
of the Age of Chivalry...
but remember the ploughmen,
poachers and pickpockets whom they lead.
It is with these sad instruments
that your great warriors and kings...
have been doing their murderous work
in the world.
A young man could hardly have fallen
into worse circumstances...
than those in which Barry found himself.
But fate did not intend he should
remain long an English soldier.
An accident occurred...
which took him out of the Service
in a rather singular manner.
Freddie, I hope you won't be too angry
with me, but...
I've got something to tell you
which you won't be happy about.
Oh? What is it?
First, you've got to promise me
you'll keep your temper.
Jonathan, don't be such a silly ass!
You're making a great big mystery of it.
What is going on?
I I'm afraid I shall have to go away again.
Only for about a fortnight.
Oh, my God, you're not serious?
Yes, I'm afraid I am. There's
nothing I can do about it.
Where are you going to this time?
I'm going to Bremen, carrying important
messages and dispatches to Prince Henry.
But Jonathan you promised me last time it
would be once and for all and never again.
Yes I know. And promise you I've
kept my part of the bargain, but...
Pontersby insists I'm the only one on his
staff who can be entrusted with the trip.
Here was the opportunity
to escape from the Army...
for which he had been searching.
It was only a few miles through the forest to
the area occupied by their Prussian allies...
where this Officer's uniform
and papers...
should allow him to travel
without suspicion...
and stay ahead of the news of his
desertion which would be sure to follow.
Then, we'll have little time together.
Are you cross with me?
Damn you. Damn you, you know I
can't stay cross with you for long.
Oh, Jonathan...
It's times like this that I realize
how much I care for you...
and how impossibly empty
life would be without you.
Frederick!
Barry was glad to see the blue and
white uniforms of the Prussian Infantry.
They showed him that he was out of
the land occupied by his own countrymen.
His intention was to make for Holland...
almost the only neutral country
of Europe, in those times...
and thence to get a passage home, somehow.
As he rode away...
Barry felt once more that
he was in his proper sphere.
And determined never again
to fall from the rank of a gentleman.
Excuse me, miss.
Yes.
Good day.
Do you speak English?
I'm speaking little.
I have not eaten anything all day, no food.
Is there an inn nearby
where I might have a meal?
No... I don't think so.
There is nothing to eat
something since Grünberg.
Do you live near here?
Yes.
Would you... feed me? Something to eat.
I'd be happy to pay you.
I think so.
Is it a little boy or a little girl?
A boy.
And what's his name?
Peter.
How old is Peter?
He's one year sold.
Where might Peter's father be?
You mean, where he is?
Yes.
He's in the war.
And how long has he been gone?
Sorry... I didn't understand.
What?
How long has he been gone?
Oh! A long time.
Since springtime.
It must be hard for you to be alone.
It is.
It must be very danger
for you to be in the war.
I'm an officer and must do my duty.
You are sometimes...
lonely?
Sometimes.
What did you say. What's your name?
Lieutenant Fakenham.
No, I mean...
what is the name before Fakenham?
- My first name?
- Yes.
Jonathan.
Jonathan?
Would you like...
to stay with me?
For a few days, or sometimes?
That would be very nice.
Goodbye, my beautiful Lischen.
Goodbye, Redmond.
I love you.
Look after yourself.
God be with you.
A lady who sets her heart
upon a lad in uniform...
must prepare to change lovers
pretty quickly...
or her life will be but a sad one.
This heart of Lischen's was like
many a neighbouring town...
and had been stormed and occupied
several times before Barry came to invest it.
During the five years which
the war had now lasted...
the great and illustrious Frederick had
so exhausted the males of his kingdom...
that he had to employ
scores of recruiters...
who would hesitate at no crime,
including kidnapping...
to keep supplied those brilliant
regiments of his with food for powder.
Good evening, sir.
I'm Captain Potzdorf. May I ask to
whom have I the honour of speaking?
Good evening. I'm Lieutenant Fakenham,
Gale's Regiment of Foot.
Pleased to meet you.
Can we be of some
assistance to you, Lieutenant?
Thank you Captain, but I must continue
on my way. I'm carrying urgent dispatches.
May I ask your destination?
I'm travelling to Bremen.
To Bremen? Then you're
obviously lost, Lieutenant.
Because Bremen is in
the opposite direction.
Are you sure, Captain?
Yes.
Wouldn't you know it!
My departure was so hastily organised that
my orderly forgot to prepare proper maps of the area.
Of course I understand.
Please, do not be offended, Lieutenant...
but may I ask whether you are
carrying your identity papers?
Yes, of course I am.
Would you allow me to see them?
Of course.
Here you are.
Thank you very much.
Thank you very much, Lieutenant, I hope
I haven't inconvenienced you in any way.
Not at all.
Now that we are riding
in the same direction...
I'd be very honoured if you'd allow me to
offer you a meal and a bed for the night...
and a proper map to be
drawn up for the journey?
That's extremely kind of you, Captain,
and I'd be honoured to accept your invitation.
Barry was treated with great civility...
and was asked a thousand questions
about England,
which he answered as best he could,
inventing a thousand stories.
He described the King and Ministers...
boasted that the British Ambassador
in Berlin was his uncle...
and even offered Captain Potzdorf
a letter of introduction.
His host seemed quite satisfied
with these stories.
But at the same time
he led Barry on
with a skilful combination of
questions and flattery.
You will have to pardon me, I know
so little about your country of England...
except that you are
the bravest nation in the world...
and that we are really fortunate
to have such allies.
Lieutenant Fakenham...
let us drink to the friendship
of our two great nations.
To our two great nations.
Aren't you lucky,
going to Bremen tomorrow?
I know one of the loveliest women
in Europe there.
May I ask you to take a letter to her?
Certainly.
By the way, to whom are you carrying
your dispatches?
General Williamson.
General Williamson?
Yes.
General Percival Williamson?
Yes, the same.
Sergeant.
This man is under arrest.
Under arrest? Captain Potzdorf, sir...
I'm a British Officer.
You are a liar. You're an imposter.
You're a deserter.
I suspected you this morning and your
lies and folly have confirmed this to me.
You pretend to carry dispatches to a
General, who has been dead these ten months.
You say your uncle is the
British Ambassador in Berlin...
with the ridiculous name of O'Grady.
Now, will you join and take
the bounty sir, or be given up?
I volunteer.
The Prussian Service
was considerably worse than the English.
The life that a Private Soldier led
was a frightful one.
Punishment was incessant.
And every Officer had the right to inflict it.
The gauntlet was the most common penalty
for minor offences.
More serious ones were punishable
by mutilation or death.
At the close of the Seven Years' War
the army...
so renowned for its disciplined valour,
was officered by native Prussians.
But it was composed for the most part...
of men from the lowest levels
of humanity...
hired or stolen
from almost every nation in Europe.
Thus, Barry fell into the worst
of courses and company...
and was soon very far advanced in
the science of every kind of misconduct.
Help!
Get me out of here.
Help.
The Colonel's speech declared that
the King had expressed his satisfaction...
with the conduct of the Regiment
at the Battle of Audorf...
and with the bravery of Corporal Redmond
Barry's in rescuing Captain Potzdorf...
was to be specially rewarded
with the sum of two Frederick d'or.
Corporal Barry, eight paces forward...
march!
Corporal Barry.
You're a gallant soldier, and have
evidently come of good stock...
but you're idle and unprincipled.
You've done a great
deal of harm to the men.
And for all your talents and bravery,
I'm sure you'll come to no good.
I hope the Colonel Guideau is
mistaken regarding my character.
I have fallen into bad company it is true,
but I've only done as other soldiers have done.
And above all, I never had a kind friend
or protector before...
to show that I was worthy
of better things.
The Colonel may say I'm a ruined lad,
and send me to the Devil.
But be sure of this. I would go to the
Devil to serve the Regiment.
Corporal Barry, fall in.
The war was soon ended and Barry's
regiment was garrisoned in the Capital.
He had, for some time now, ingratiated
himself considerably with Captain Potzdorf...
whose confidence in him
was about to bring its reward.
Good morning, Redmond.
Good morning, Captain Potzdorf.
I should like you to meet my uncle,
the Minister of Police. Herr from Potzdorf.
Good morning, Herr Minister.
Redmond...
I've spoken to the Minister regarding
your services and your fortune is made.
We shall get you out of the Army...
appoint you to the Police Bureau,
and, in time...
we'll allow you to move in a better sphere than
that which fortune has hitherto placed you.
Thank you, Captain Potzdorf.
Redmond, your loyalty to me and your service
to the Regiment has pleased me very well.
And now there is another occasion on
which you may make yourself useful to us.
And if you succeed...
depend on it...
your reward will be secure.
I'll do the best I can, sir.
There's lately come to Berlin a gentleman
in the service of the Empress Queen of Austria.
He calls himself
the Chevalier de Balibari.
He appears to follow the
profession of a gambler.
He's a libertine:
Fond of women, of good food...
polished, obliging.
He speaks French and German indifferently.
But we have some reason to fancy
that this Monsieur de Balibari...
is a native of your country of Ireland.
And that he has come here as a spy.
Naturally your knowledge of English...
makes you an ideal choice
to go into his service...
and to find out for us
whether or not he is a spy.
Does this assignment interest you?
You may be certain, Herr Minister, I'm interested
in anything that can be of service to yourself...
and to Captain Potzdorf.
Of course you will not
know a word of English.
And if the Chevalier asks as to the particularity
of your accent, say you are a Hungarian.
You served in the war.
You left the army on account
of weakness in the loins...
you then served Monsieur de Quellenberg
for two years.
He's now with the Army in Silesia, but
you'll have a certificate signed by him.
Good morning, Your Honour.
So you are the young man
recommended by Seebach.
Yes, Your Honour,
here are my credentials.
Your name is Lazlo Zilagy?
Yes, Your Honour.
Monsieur de Quellenberg
recommends you highly.
Monsieur is a very good man.
It was very imprudent of him...
but when Barry saw
the splendour of the Chevalier's appearance...
the nobleness of his manner...
he felt it impossible to
keep disguise with him.
Those who have never
been out of their country...
know little what it is to hear
a friendly voice in captivity...
and as many a man who will
not understand the cause...
of the burst of feeling which
was now about to take place.
You seem the right one to me.
Thank you, Your Honour.
Are you ill?
Sir...
I have a confession to make to you.
I'm an Irishman.
And my name is Redmond Barry.
I was abducted into the
Prussian Army two years ago.
Now I've been put into your service...
by my Captain Potzdorf
and his uncle, the Minister of Police...
to serve as a watch
upon your... actions...
and to give information to the same court.
The Chevalier was as much affected as Barry...
at thus finding one of his countrymen.
For he too was an exile from home.
And a friendly voice, a look...
brought the old country
back to his memory again.
He goes to church regularly.
He's very religious.
And after hearing mass he
comes home for breakfast.
He then takes an airing in his carriage.
Barry presented his reports
regularly at the Minister's office.
The details were arranged between
him and the Chevalier beforehand.
He was instructed, and it
is always far the best way...
to tell as much truth as his story
would possibly bear.
It would be seen that the information
he gave was very minute and accurate...
though not very important.
But who does not acknowledge him.
Wine or punch, Your Honour?
Wine.
It was agreed that Barry
should keep his character of valet.
That in the presence of strangers,
he should not know a word of English.
And that he should keep
a lookout on the trumps
when serving the
champagne and punch about.
And having a remarkably fine eyesight...
and a natural aptitude...
he was speedily able to give
his dear patron much assistance...
against his opponents
at the green table.
If, for instance, he wiped
the table with a napkin...
it was to show the enemy was strong in diamonds.
If he adjusted a chair it meant ace king.
If he said, "Punch or wine, My Lord?"...
hearts were meant, and so forth.
The Prince of Tübingen...
was a nobleman who had intimate connections
with the Great Frederick...
was passionately fond of play
as indeed were the gentlemen...
of almost all the Courts of Europe.
You owe 15,500 Frederick d'or.
Chevalier...
though I cannot say how...
I believe you have cheated me.
I deny Your Grace's accusation...
and beg you to say
how you have been cheated.
I don't know.
But I believe I have been.
Your Grace owes me
15,500 Frederick d'or...
which I have honourably won.
Chevalier...
if you will have your money now
you must fight for it.
If you will be patient...
maybe I will pay you something
another time.
Your Grace, if I am to be so tame
as to take this...
then I must give up an honourable
and lucrative occupation.
I have said all there is to be said.
I am at your disposal
for whatever purposes you wish.
Good night.
Was the Prince cheated?
In as far as I am able to tell of
such things, Herr Minister, no.
I believe the Chevalier
won the money fairly.
What are the Chevalier's intentions?
I'm not sure.
The Prince told him quite clearly that if he
wished to have his money he'd have to fight for it.
A meeting with the Prince of Türbingen is impossible.
The Prince has left him only that choice.
Now.
Will you be able to return here tomorrow
without arousing suspicion?
I know they won't allow a meeting
with the Prince.
But if I say that, do you know any reason
why he'll pay me the money he owes me?
You must tell them I intend
to demand satisfaction.
Don't look so downcast, my boy.
There's no harm they can do to me, my friends
in the Austrian Embassy will see to that.
The worst they can do is send me
out of this dreary country of theirs.
And if they should, make your mind easy...
you shall not be left behind.
Have no fear of that.
The King has determined to send
the Chevalier out of the country.
Has he already demanded satisfaction?
Not yet, Herr Minister,
but I believe he intends to...
possibly today.
Then this must be done tomorrow.
All the arrangements are made.
Redmond.
You said he takes a drive in his carriage
after breakfast every day.
Yes, sir.
Is there any reason to believe
that he'll do any different tomorrow?
No, sir.
Good.
When the Chevalier comes out
to his carriage in the morning...
two officers will meet him
and escort him to the frontier.
His baggage will be sent after him.
Excellent.
At ten o'clock the next morning...
the Chevalier de Balibari...
went out for his regular morning drive.
Where is my servant, Lazlo?
I will let down the steps for Your Honour.
What is the meaning of this?
Please get inside.
Am I under arrest?
We're going to drive to the frontier.
To the frontier? But I'm on my way
to the Austrian Ambassador's house.
I'm sorry Your Honour, but my
orders are to escort you to the frontier...
and see you safely across the border.
But, I'm not going to the frontier.
I'm going to the Austrian Ambassador's house.
I have very important business there.
My orders are to take Your Honour to the
frontier by any means which may be necessary.
But if you come along willingly...
I'm to give you this purse
on behalf of the Prince of Tübingen...
containing 2,000 Frederick d'or.
All Europe shall hear of this.
And so, without papers or passport...
and under the eyes
of two Prussian officers...
Barry was escorted across the frontier
into Saxony and freedom.
The Chevalier himself had uneventfully
crossed the frontier the night before.
And by these wonderful circumstances,
Barry was once more free again...
and began his professional work
as a gamester...
resolving, thenceforward and forever,
to live the life of a gentleman.
The four wins.
Soon there was no court in Europe where
he and the Chevalier were not received...
and they were speedily in the very
best society where play was patronized...
and professors of that science
always welcome.
The seven.
Why not the seven?
All... all, yes.
No more bets.
Number seven...
loses.
Place your bets.
Chevalier, will you give me
credit for 5,000 Louis d'or, please?
Of course, Lord Ludd.
Five thousand.
Now, everything on the four.
Yes, I know, everything on the four.
No more bets.
The four loses.
Another game?
It is not important.
Now, I'm weary.
I would like dinner. Shall we?
Excuse me, Lord Ludd.
If you don't mind.
Not at all.
They always played on credit
with any person of honour or noble lineage.
They never pressed for their winnings...
or declined to receive
promissory notes in lieu of gold.
But woe to the man who did not pay
when the note became due.
Redmond Barry was sure to wait upon him
with his bill.
And there were few bad debts.
Saluez.
It was his great skill
with the sword, and readiness to use it...
that maintained the reputation
of the firm, so to speak.
En garde!
I will pay you today, sir.
Thus, it will be seen, that their life...
for all its splendour,
was not without danger and difficulty...
requiring talent and determination
for success.
And one which required them to live
a wandering and disconnected life.
And if the truth be told, though they were
swimming upon the high tide of fortune...
and prospering with the cards,
they had little to show for their labour...
but some fine clothes
and a few trinkets.
Five years in the Army, and some
considerable experience of the world...
had by now dispelled any romantic notions
regarding love...
with which Barry commenced life.
And he began to have it in mind,
as so many gentlemen had done before him...
to marry a woman
of fortune and condition.
And, as such things so often happen...
these thoughts closely coincided
with his setting first sight upon a lady...
who will henceforth play a
considerable part in the drama of his life.
The Countess of Lyndon...
Viscountess Bullingdon of England...
Baroness Castle Lyndon of Ireland.
A woman of vast wealth and great beauty.
She was the wife of the right
honourable Sir Charles Reginald Lyndon...
Knight of the Bath...
Minister to George III
at several of the Courts of Europe.
A cripple, wheeled about in a chair...
worn out by gout
and a myriad of diseases.
Her Ladyship's Chaplain, Mr. Runt...
acted in the capacity of tutor to her son,
the little Viscount Bullingdon...
a melancholy little boy,
much attached to his mother.
Samuel, I'm going
outside for a breath of air.
Yes, My Lady.
To make a long story short...
six hours after they met...
Her Ladyship was in love.
And once Barry got into her company...
he found innumerable occasions
to improve his intimacy...
and was scarcely out
of Her Ladyship's sight.
Good evening, gentlemen.
Good evening.
Sir Charles.
Good evening, Mr. Barry.
Have you done with my Lady?
I beg your pardon?
Come, sir. I'm a man who would rather
be known as a cuckold than a fool.
I think, Sir Charles Lyndon,
that you've had too much to drink.
Ha, ha, what?
As it happens, your Chaplain, Mr. Runt,
introduced me into the company of your Lady...
to advise me on a religious matter,
of which she is a considerable expert.
He wants... to step into my shoes.
He wants to step into my shoes.
Is it not a pleasure, gentlemen, for me,
as I am drawing near the goal...
to find my home such a happy one...
my wife so fond of me, that she is even
now thinking of appointing a successor?
Isn't it a comfort to see her
like a prudent housewife...
getting everything ready
for her husband's departure?
I hope you're not thinking of
leaving us soon, Sir Charles?
Not so soon, my dear, as
you may fancy, perhaps.
Why, man, I've been given
over many times these four years.
And there was always
a candidate or two...
waiting to apply for the situation.
I'm sorry for you, Mr. Barry.
It grieves me to keep you
or any gentleman waiting.
Had you not better arrange
with my doctor...
or have the cook flavour my omelet
with arsenic, eh?
What are the odds, gentlemen,
that I live to see Mr. Barry hang yet?
Sir, let those laugh that win.
Gentlemen.
I'll get a surgeon.
Have some brandy, Sir Charles.
From a report in the St. James' Chronicle,
"Died at Spa in the kingdom of Belgium...
"The Right Honourable
Sir Charles Reginald Lyndon...
"Knight of the Bath,
Member of Parliament...
"and for many years...
"His Majesty's Representative
at various European Courts.
"He has left behind him a name
which is endeared to all his friends."
"Dearly beloved...
"we are gathered together
here in the sight of God...
"and in the face of this congregation...
"to join together this man
and this woman in holy matrimony."
A year later,
on the fifteenth of June...
in the year 1773...
Redmond Barry had the honour to lead
to the altar the Countess of Lyndon.
The ceremony was performed by the
Reverend Samuel Runt, Her Ladyship's Chaplain.
"And therefore is not in any way
to be enterprised...
"nor taken in hand unadvisedly...
"lightly or wantonly...
"to satisfy men's carnal lusts
and appetites...
"like brute beasts
that have no understanding.
"But reverently...
"discreetly...
"advisedly...
"soberly...
"and in the fear of God.
"Duly considering the causes
for which matrimony was ordained.
"First...
"it was ordained for the procreation
of children to be brought up...
"in the fear and nurture of the Lord,
and to the praise of His holy name.
"Secondly...
"it was ordained for a remedy
against sin, and to avoid fornication...
"that such persons..."
Barry had now arrived
at the pitch of prosperity...
and by his own energy had raised
himself to a higher sphere of society...
having procured His Majesty's
gracious permission to add the name...
of his lovely Lady to his own.
Thenceforth, Redmond Barry
assumed the style...
and title of Barry Lyndon.
Redmond, would you mind not smoking
for a while?
Redmond?
Lady Lyndon was soon
destined to occupy a place in Barry's life...
not very much more important
than the elegant carpets and pictures...
which would form
the pleasant background of his existence.
My Lord Bullingdon,
you seem particularly glum today.
You should be happy
that your mother has remarried.
Not in this way.
And not in such haste.
And certainly not to this man.
I think you judge your mother too harshly.
Do you not like your new father?
Not very much.
He seems to me little more
than a common opportunist.
I don't think he loves my mother at all.
And it hurts me to see her
make such a fool of herself.
At the end of a year
Her Ladyship presented Barry with a son.
Bryan Patrick Lyndon, they called him.
♪ None of those ancient heroes
E'er saw a cannon ball ♪
♪ Or knew the force of powder
To slay their foes withal ♪
♪ But our brave boys do know it
And banish all their fears ♪
♪ With a tow, row, row, row, row
To the British Grenadiers ♪
Her Ladyship and Barry lived,
after a while, pretty separate.
She preferred quiet, or to say the truth,
he preferred it for her...
being a great friend to a modest
and tranquil behaviour in woman.
Besides, she was a mother,
and would have great comfort...
in the dressing, educating
and dandling of their little Bryan.
For whose sake it was fit,
Barry believed...
that she should give up the pleasures
and frivolities of the world...
leaving that part of the duty
of every family of distinction...
to be performed by him.
Lady Lyndon tended
to a melancholy and maudlin temper...
and, left alone by her husband,
was rarely happy or in good humour.
Now she must add jealousy
to her other complaints...
and find rivals even among her maids.
Samuel, what would the time be?
Twenty-five minutes past eleven,
My Lady.
Shall we make this the last game, ladies?
Yes.
Good morning, ladies.
Good morning, sir.
Would you mind excusing us?
I'd like a word alone with Lady Lyndon.
I'm sorry.
This coat is made of the
finest Littlefield velvet...
all cunningly worked, as you see,
with silver thread.
No finer velvet has ever been woven,
and you will see none better anywhere.
Pardon me, gentlemen.
- Good morning, dearest.
- Good morning.
We're taking the children for a ride
to the village. We'll be back for tea.
Well, have a nice time. I'll see you then.
Goodbye, little Bryan.
Lord Bullingdon.
Take good care of your mother.
Come now, give your father a proper kiss.
Lord Bullingdon...
is that the way to behave
to your father?
Lord Bullingdon,
have you lost your tongue?
My father was Sir Charles Lyndon.
I have not forgotten him, if others have.
Lord Bullingdon,
you have insulted your father!
Madam, you have insulted my father.
Dearest, would you excuse Lord
Bullington and me for a few minutes?
We have something
to discuss in private.
Gentlemen.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Lord Bullingdon...
I have always been willing
to live with you on terms of friendship.
But be clear about one thing:
As men serve me, I serve them.
I never laid a cane on the back
of a Lord before...
but, if you force me to, I shall
speedily become used to the practice.
Do you have anything to say for yourself?
No.
You may go.
Barry believed, and not
without some reason, that it had been...
a declaration of war against him
by Bullingdon from the start...
and that the evil consequences
which ensued...
were entirely of Bullingdon's creating.
I shall make you into
a real magician now, Bryan.
I shall show you the knot that never was.
As Bullingdon grew up to be a man...
his hatred for Barry
assumed an intensity...
equalled only by his
increased devotion to his mother.
Very good, Bryan. A little bow.
Put it on the table for me.
Thank you.
For Bryan's eighth birthday the
local nobility, gentry and their children...
came to pay their respects.
The inside is quite empty.
The outside is quite empty.
Wave your hand over the top, Bryan.
Is there anything there?
Yes? Oh!
Wonderful! Wonderful, colourful
silk handkerchiefs!
Take a bow, Bryan,
you did that beautifully.
Very good indeed.
Let's see if you have something
behind your ear.
Yes, you have. Ha, ha.
A little ball. Let's make it vanish.
It's gone, Bryan.
Here it is! Here it is, behind my elbow.
I want you you to wave your hand
over my green silk handkerchief...
and see whether we can produce
a magic flower. I wonder if we can?
Here it comes. Look at that.
We have the colours of the rainbow.
You know all the colours of the rainbow
produce but one colour, Bryan.
Nothing in my magic cabinet.
They produce the colour... white.
And there is my own...
beautiful white rabbit.
Bryan, you did that very well.
A little bow.
We crept up on their fort,
and I jumped over the wall first.
My fellows jumped after me.
You should have seen the look on the Frenchmen's
faces when 23 rampaging he-devils...
sword and pistol, cut and thrust,
pell-mell, came tumbling into their fort.
In three minutes we left
as many Artillerymen's heads...
as there were cannonballs.
Later that day we were visited
by our noble Prince Henry.
"Who is the man who has done this?"
I stepped forward.
"How many heads was it", says he,
"that you cut off?"
"Nineteen," says I,
"besides wounding several."
Well when he heard it, I'll be blessed,
if he didn't burst into tears.
"Noble, noble fellow," he said.
"Here is nineteen golden guineas for you,
one for each head that you cut off."
Now what do you think of that?
Were you allowed to keep the heads?
No, the heads always become
the property of the King.
Will you tell me another story?
I'll tell you another story tomorrow.
Will you play cards with me tomorrow?
Of course I will. Now go to sleep.
Will you keep the candles lit?
No Bryan, big boys don't sleep
with the candles lit.
But I'm afraid of the dark.
But my darling, there's nothing
to be afraid of.
But, I like it with the candles lit.
It's all right, you can sleep
with the candles lit.
Thank you, Papa.
Good night.
Ah, Redmond!
It's a blessing to see my darling boy
has attained a position I always knew was his due.
And for which I pinched myself
to educate him.
Little Bryan is a darling boy...
and you live in great splendour.
Your lady wife knows
she has a treasure...
she couldn't have had,
had she taken a Duke to marry.
But, if she should tire
of my wild Redmond...
and his old-fashioned Irish ways...
or if she should die...
what future would there be
for my son, and my grandson?
You have not a penny of your own...
and cannot transact any business
without the countess' signature.
Upon her death, the entire estate
would go to young Bullingdon...
who bears you little affection.
You could be penniless tomorrow...
and darling Bryan at the mercy
of his stepbrother.
Shall I tell you something?
There is only one way for you
and your son to have real security.
You must obtain a title.
I shall not rest
until I see you Lord Lyndon.
You have important friends.
They can tell you
how these things are done.
For money, well-timed
and properly applied...
can accomplish anything.
And to be sure, Barry was acquainted with someone...
who knew how these things were done.
This was the distinguished Barrister
and former Government Minister...
Lord Hallam...
whose acquaintance he had made, as he
had so many others, at the gaming table.
Do you happen to know Gustavus Adolphus,
the Thirteenth Earl of Wendover?
I don't believe I do.
Well sir, this nobleman is one
of the Gentlemen of His Majesty's Closet...
and one with whom our revered Monarch
is on terms of considerable intimacy.
In my opinion, you would be wise
to fix upon him...
your chief reliance for the advancement of your
claim to the peerage which you prefer as to get.
When I take up a person, Mr. Lyndon,
he, or she, is safe.
There is no question about them any more.
My friends are the best people.
I don't mean they're the most virtuous...
or, indeed, the least virtuous,
or the cleverest...
or the stupidest,
or the richest or the best born.
But, the best.
In a word, people about whom
there is no question.
I cannot promise you how long it will take.
You can appreciate
it is not an easy matter.
But, any gentleman with an estate,
and 30,000 a year...
should have a peerage.
And there standing behind me
was a total stranger.
So I looked at him, and he said to me:
"Excuse me, sir, could you tell me,
is Lord Wendover alive or dead?"
I was so astonished,
I couldn't think of what to say.
Then I became a bit angry,
and said to him, "He's dead."
The striving after this peerage was one of
Barry's most unlucky dealings of this time.
He made great sacrifices
to bring it about.
He lavished money here,
and diamonds there.
He bought lands
at ten times their value...
purchased pictures and articles
of virtue at ruinous prices.
He gave repeated entertainments
to those friends to his claim...
who, being about the royal person,
were likely to advance it.
And, I can tell you, bribes were
administered. And in high places, too.
So near the royal person of His Majesty
that you would be astonished to know...
what great noblemen condescended
to receive his loans.
This is by Ludovico Cordi...
a disciple of Alessandro Allori.
It's dated 1605...
and shows,
"The Adoration of The Magi".
It's beautiful.
Yes.
I love the use of the colour blue
by the artist.
Yes indeed, that is very beautiful.
What, may I ask, is the price of this one?
Well, this is one of my best pictures.
But, if you really like it, I'm sure
we can come to some arrangement.
Count Andrachier.
Mr. Henry Drummond.
Mr. Drummond.
Sir Gilbert Elliot, Your Majesty.
Sir Gilbert.
Lord Wendover, Your Majesty.
I'm glad to see you here today,
Lord Wendover.
And tell me, what news of Lady Wendover?
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Lady Wendover is much better.
Good, good! Present my compliments to her.
Say we miss her company here.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
And what of those excellent boys
of yours?
They're very well. Charles has gone to sea under
the protection of Captain Geary on the Ramillies.
And John has gone to Oxford to be taught
how to preach and pray.
Good, good!
- Your Majesty, may I present Mr. Barry Lyndon.
- Your Majesty.
Mr. Lyndon. We were very fond
of Sir Charles Lyndon.
And how is Lady Lyndon?
She's very well, Your Majesty.
Mr. Lyndon raised a company
of troops and sent them to America
to fight the rebels
against Your Majesty's crown.
Good, that's right Mr. Lyndon. Raise
another company and go with them, too.
Sir Christopher Neville, Your Majesty.
Sir Christopher.
Peregrine Cavendish.
Mr. Peregrine.
Barry was one of those born
clever enough at gaining a fortune...
but incapable of keeping one.
For the qualities and energies
which lead a man to achieve the first...
are often the very cause of his ruin
in the latter case.
Now he was burdened with
the harassing cares and responsibilities...
which are the dismal adjuncts
of great rank and property.
And his life at this period...
seemed to consist of little more than drafts
of letters to lawyers and money-brokers...
and endless correspondence
with decorators and cooks.
Gentlemen, I'm going to leave you on your own for
a few minutes. You may carry on with your work.
Yes, sir.
Bully.
Mm-hm?
What does...
"strenuous" mean?
Bryan, I'm trying to work.
But what does it mean?
It means "an effort requiring strength".
What does "quadrangle" mean?
A quadrangle is a four-sided figure
like a square or a rectangle.
Now, please be quiet, Bryan,
and let me get on with my work.
Bryan, please be quiet!
Have you seen my pencil?
No, Bryan, I haven't.
Bryan, please stop making so much noise.
That's my pencil. Give it...
No, it isn't.
It is. It's my pencil!
I've had this all morning.
It's my pencil!
Listen, will you be quiet!
I'll teach you a lesson.
What the devil's going on in here?
I told you never
to lay a hand on this child.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Will that be all, Mr. Redmond Barry?
Yes, that will be all.
Well then, look you now.
From this moment, I will submit
to no further chastisement from you.
I will kill you if you lay hands
on me ever again.
Is that entirely clear to you, sir?
Get out of here!
Don't you think he fits my shoes
very well, Your Ladyship?
Dear child...
what a pity it is I'm not dead,
for your sake.
The Lyndons would then have
a worthy representative...
and enjoy all the benefits...
of the illustrious blood
of the Barrys of Barryville.
Would they not...
Mr. Redmond Barry?
From the way I love this child, My Lord...
you ought to know how
I would've loved his elder brother...
had he proved worthy
of any mother's affection.
Madam!
I have borne as long
as mortal could endure...
the ill treatment of the insolent Irish
upstart whom you've taken to your bed.
It is not only the lowness of his birth and the
general brutality of his manners which disgust me.
But the shameful nature of his conduct
toward Your Ladyship...
his brutal and ungentlemanlike
behaviour...
his open infidelity...
his shameless robberies and swindling
of my property, and yours.
And as I cannot personally chastise
this low-bred ruffian, and as I cannot bear...
to witness his treatment of you...
and loathe this horrible society
as if it were the plague...
I have decided to leave my home
and never return.
At least, during his detested life...
or during my own.
Good day, My Lord.
Good day, Barker.
Will anyone be joining
Your Lordship?
No, I shall be alone.
Thank you.
The roast beef's very good, My Lord.
Hello, Neville. How are you?
Ah, Barry. Hello.
I see you're alone.
Why don't you come over join me?
Oh, thank you, Barry,
you're very kind, but...
I'm expecting someone to join me soon.
What a shame! Lady Lyndon and I
have missed your company lately.
Please give my respects to Lady Lyndon...
and say I've been very busy of late
and not been able to go about much.
I shall.
By the way on the eighth of next month we're
having some guests over for cards...
we'd love to have you
and Lady Wendover join us.
I'll check my diary, but I think
I'm engaged on that evening.
Well, I hope you're not engaged.
We'd love to see you again.
I'll write and say if I'm free or not.
I look forward to hearing from you.
It's nice to see you again.
If he had murdered Lord Bullingdon...
Barry could scarcely have been received
with more coldness and resentment...
that now followed him
in town and country.
His friends fell away from him.
A legend arose of his cruelty
to his stepson.
Now all the bills came down
on him together.
All the bills he had been contracting
for the years of his marriage...
and which the creditors sent in
with a hasty unanimity.
Their amount was frightful.
Barry was now bound up in an
inextricable toil of bills and debts...
of mortgages and insurances,
and all the evils attendant upon them.
And Lady Lyndon's income was hampered
almost irretrievably...
to satisfy these claims.
Do you think that's good?
Excellent.
Who's this?
It's a peacock on the wall.
What's it say?
I saw this bird yesterday.
Who's that?
Mama in her coach.
Is she going to London?
I don't know.
Parry.
Very good.
Barry had his faults...
but no man could say of him
that he was not a good and tender father.
He loved his son with a blind partiality.
He denied him nothing.
It is impossible to convey
what high hopes he had for the boy...
and how he indulged
in a thousand fond anticipations...
as to his future success
and figure in the world.
But fate had determined that he should
leave none of his race behind him...
that he should finish his life...
poor, lonely...
and childless.
Papa.
Yes, Bryan?
Will you buy me a horse?
Will I buy you a horse?
Yes, Papa.
But you already have little Julia.
But July's only a pony,
I want a real horse.
Then I can ride with you on the hunt.
You think you're big
enough for the hunt, do you?
Oh, yes, Papa!
Jonathan Plunkett is only a year older
than I am and he rides with his papa.
I'll have to think about it.
Please, say yes, Papa. There's nothing I
want in the whole world more than a horse.
I'll think about it.
Oh, thank you, Papa. Thank you!
How much are you asking for him?
One hundred guineas.
He's a nice little horse, but I don't
think he's worth a hundred guineas.
Seventy-five seems
more like the right price.
I'll accept eighty guineas,
and not a shilling less.
Five guineas should never keep two
gentlemen from their drink. Eighty it will be.
Done, sir.
Take the horse to Doolan's farm.
Tell him he needs a bit of breaking in.
And say it's for Master Bryan's birthday
next week, and I want it to be a surprise.
And remember that yourself.
Yes, sir.
Papa.
What is it, lad?
Did you buy the horse?
Horse? What horse is that?
The horse you were going
to buy me for my birthday.
I know nothing about any horse.
But one of the stable boys told Nelly
you'd already bought it...
and it was at Doolan's farm
where Mick the groom was breaking it in.
Is that true?
Bryan, when is your birthday?
Next Tuesday.
Well, you'll have to wait till then
to find out.
Then, it's true! It's true!
Oh, thank you, Papa.
Bryan?
Yes, Mama?
Promise me you will not ride that horse
except with your father.
Yes, Mama, I promise.
And I promise you a lordship of good flogging...
if you even go to Doolan's farm
to see him before your birthday.
Yes, Papa.
You understand?
You promise me?
Yes, Papa, I promise.
All right, eat your food.
Come in.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning, Reverend.
I'm sorry to trouble you
with this, Mr. Lyndon...
but I believe Master Bryan
has disobeyed you...
and stolen away to Doolan's farm.
On going to his room this morning,
I found his bed empty.
One of the cooks said she saw him
cross the yard at daybreak.
Didn't you see him go?
He must have passed through my room
while I was asleep.
Oh, my God! What has happened here?
I noticed the lad riding
across the field, sir...
and having trouble with the horse,
which was playing up a bit.
Suddenly the animal plunged and reared,
and the poor lad was thrown.
Oh, Bryan, why did you disobey me?
I'm sorry, Papa.
You won't whip me, will you?
No, my darling.
I won't whip you.
William, you take my horse and
ride like the devil for Doctor Broughton.
Tell him whatever he's doing
he must come at once. You understand?
Yes, sir.
The doctors were called.
But what does a doctor avail in a contest
with the grim, invincible enemy?
Such as came could only confirm
the hopelessness of the poor child's case.
He remained yet with his parents
for two days.
And a sad comfort it was to know
he was in no pain.
Papa.
Am I going to die?
No, my darling, you're not going to die.
You're going to get better.
But I can't feel anything,
except in my hands.
Does that mean I'm already dead
in part of my body?
No, my darling, that's where
you were hurt by the horse.
But you're going to be all right now.
Papa, if I die, will I go to heaven?
Of course you will, my darling...
but you're not going to die.
Mama, give me your hand.
Papa, give me your hand.
Will you both promise me something?
Yes.
Promise me never to quarrel so.
But to love each other.
So that we may meet again, in heaven...
where Bullingdon said
quarrelsome people will never go.
We promise.
Will you tell me the story
about the fort?
Of course.
We crept up on the fort.
And I jumped over the wall first,
and my fellows jumped after me.
And you should have seen the look...
on the Frenchmen's faces when
23 rampaging he-devils, sword and pistol...
cut and thrust, pell-mell
came tumbling into the fort.
In three minutes time...
we left...
"'I am the resurrection
and the life,' saith the Lord.
"'He that believeth in me,
though he were dead...
"'yet shall he live.
"'And whosoever liveth
and believeth in me...
"'shall never die.'
"I know that my Redeemer liveth...
"and that He shall stand
at the latter day upon the earth.
"And though after my skin
worms destroy this body...
"yet in my flesh shall I see God.
"Whom I shall see for myself
and mine eyes shall behold...
"and not another.
"We brought nothing into this world...
"and it is certain
we can carry nothing out.
"The Lord gave,
and the Lord hath taken away.
"Blessed is the name of the Lord."
Barry's grief was inconsolable.
And such solace as he could find,
came only from drink.
His mother was the only person in his
misfortune who would remain faithful to him.
And many a night, when he was
unconscious of her attention...
saw him carried off to bed.
"O blessed Lord...
"the Father of mercies
and God of all comforts.
"We beseech Thee, look down
in pity and compassion upon this...
"Thy afflicted servant.
"Thou writest bitter things against her...
"and makest her to possess
her former iniquities."
Her Ladyship,
always vapourish and nervous...
plunged into devotion...
with so much fervour that you would have
imagined her almost distracted at times.
In the doleful conditions
which now prevailed at Castle Hackton...
the entire management of the house,
and of the Lyndon estate...
fell to Mrs. Barry,
whose spirit of order...
attended to all the 10,000 details
of a great establishment.
Come in.
You wish to see me, madam?
Yes, Reverend. Please sit down.
I have some matters I would like
to discuss with you later, Graham...
but just now, perhaps you would go
to Her Ladyship...
and have these papers signed by her.
Yes, madam.
Reverend Runt...
I need not tell you
that the recent tragedy to this family...
has made the services of a tutor
no longer required at Castle Hackton.
And as we are in some
considerable difficulty about money...
I'm afraid I must ask you,
with the greatest reluctance...
to resign your post.
Madam, I'm sensible
of your predicament...
and you need have no concern about my wages,
with which I can willingly do without...
but it is out of the question for me to consider
leaving Her Ladyship in her present state.
I'm very sorry to say this to you...
but I truly believe you are largely responsible
for the state of mind she is in.
And the sooner you leave,
the better she will be.
Madam, with the greatest respect...
I take my instructions
only from Her Ladyship.
Reverend Runt...
Her Ladyship is in no fit mind
to give instructions to anyone.
My son has charged me with managing
the affairs at Castle Hackton...
until he recovers from his grief and
resumes his interest in worldly matters.
And while I am in charge...
you will take your instructions from me.
My only concern is for Lady Lyndon.
Madam...
your only concern is
for Her Ladyship's signature.
You and your son have almost succeeded
in destroying a fine family fortune.
And what little remains for you...
depends on keeping Her Ladyship
prisoner in her own house.
Reverend Runt...
this matter bears
no further discussion.
You will pack your bags
and leave by tomorrow morning.
God, help. Help!
In the midst of these great perplexities...
Her Ladyship made an attempt
to kill herself by taking poison.
Though she succeeded only in
making herself dangerously ill...
due to the very small amount
which she swallowed...
this, nevertheless, caused
an intervention from a certain quarter...
which was long overdue.
Oh, my God!
If my mother had died...
it would've been as much
my responsibility...
as if I had poured
the strychnine for her myself.
For to the everlasting disgrace
of my family name...
I have, by my cowardice
and my weakness...
allowed the Barrys
to establish a brutal...
and ignorant tyranny over our lives...
which has left my mother
a broken woman...
and to squander and ruin
a fine family fortune.
My friends profess sympathy,
but behind my back...
I know I am despised.
And quite justifiably so.
However...
I know now what I must do.
And what I shall do.
Whatever be the cost.
Good morning, My Lord.
Good morning.
Is Mr. Barry Lyndon here?
Yes, My Lord, he's inside.
Thank you.
Mr. Redmond Barry.
The last occasion on which we met...
you wantonly caused me injury
and dishonour.
In such a manner, and to such an extent as
to which no gentleman can willingly suffer...
without demanding satisfaction...
however much time intervenes.
I have now come to claim
that satisfaction.
Mr. Lyndon...
these are a matched pair of pistols,
and as you have seen...
your second has loaded one,
and I have loaded the other.
But as they belong to Lord Bullingdon,
you may have whichever one you wish.
Lord Bullingdon.
Now, gentlemen, to determine
who will have first fire...
I will toss a coin in the air.
And again as the offended party, it is
Lord Bullingdon's choice to call the toss.
Is that agreeable to both of you?
Yes.
If Lord Bullingdon calls correctly
he will have the first fire.
If incorrectly, Mr. Lyndon
will have the first fire.
Is that clearly understood?
What is your call, Lord Bullingdon?
Heads.
It is heads.
Lord Bullingdon will have the first fire.
Lord Bullingdon...
will you take your ground?
One... two... three...
four... five... six...
seven... eight... nine... ten.
Mr. Lyndon, will you take your ground?
Mr. Lyndon, are you ready to receive
Lord Bullingdon's fire?
Yes.
Lord Bullingdon...
cock your pistol...
and prepare to fire.
Sir Richard, this pistol must be faulty.
I must have another one.
I'm sorry, Lord Bullingdon,
but you must first stand your ground...
and allow Mr. Lyndon his turn to fire.
That is correct, Lord Bullingdon.
Your pistol has fired,
and that counts as your shot.
Mr. Lyndon, are the rules of firing
clear to you?
Yes.
Lord Bullingdon...
are you ready to receive
Mr. Lyndon's fire?
Yes.
Very well, then.
Mr. Lyndon...
cock your pistol...
and prepare to fire.
Are you ready, Lord Bullingdon?
Is your pistol cocked, Mr. Lyndon?
Yes.
Then prepare to fire.
One...
two...
Lord Bullingdon, in view of Mr. Lyndon
having fired into the ground...
do you now consider
that you have received satisfaction?
I have not received satisfaction.
Mr. Lyndon, are you ready?
Yes.
Lord Bullingdon...
cock your pistol
and get ready to fire.
One...
two...
Barry was carried to an inn
nearby and a surgeon was called.
Right, I'm nearly finished.
I'm sorry to have to tell you this,
Mr. Lyndon.
I'm afraid you'll have to lose the leg...
most likely below the knee.
Lose the leg?
What for?
The simple answer to that
is to save your life.
The ball has shattered the bone
below the knee and severed the artery.
Unless I can amputate, there's no way
that I can repair the artery...
and prevent further haemorrhage.
Graham.
Yes, My Lord?
As soon as we arrive at Castle Hackton, I want
you to inform Mrs. Barry of what has happened.
Don't go into any unnecessary detail.
Just tell her where he is
and that he has been wounded in the leg.
She will naturally want to go to him.
See that she is out of the house and on
her way to London as quickly as possible.
And that in no event...
is she to be allowed the
opportunity to see my mother...
or create any disturbance at the house
before she leaves.
Yes, My Lord.
Ah, Mrs. Barry, how do you do?
How nice to see you, Graham.
Come in.
Thank you.
You, uh... You received my note?
Yes, we were expecting you.
Oh, good, good, I didn't want
to call unannounced.
Mr. Lyndon, how are you feeling?
I'm feeling much better,
thank you, Graham.
Won't you sit down?
Thank you, Mrs. Barry.
Would you like some tea?
Oh, no! No, thank you, Mrs. Barry.
Not just now.
How's the world treating you, Graham?
Oh, not too bad.
And, uh...
Are you comfortable here?
Most comfortable.
Good, good!
Well, uh...
Shall, uh...
Shall we get down to the matter at hand?
By all means.
Yes.
Well...
Mr. Lyndon...
Lord Bullingdon has instructed me...
to offer you an annuity...
of 500 guineas a year for life.
Specifically on the condition of your...
leaving England...
and to be stopped...
the instant of your return.
Lord Bullingdon has also asked me
to point out to you...
that should you decide to remain here...
your stay would infallibly plunge you...
into jail.
As in view of the present circumstances
there will soon be...
innumerable writs taken out
against you for...
debts long-outstanding...
and your credit is so blown that...
you could not hope...
to raise a shilling.
Utterly baffled and beaten...
what was the lonely
and broken-hearted man to do?
He took the annuity and returned
to Ireland with his mother...
to complete his recovery.
Sometime later he
travelled to the continent.
His life there, we have not the means
of following accurately.
He appears to have resumed
his former profession of a gambler...
without his former success.
He never saw Lady Lyndon again.