Is this the last one?
I don't know.
There's no ether, either.
Jesus Christ.
You there!
Is this the last one?
God, what a mess.
At least there's no gangrene.
There will be
if it doesn't come off.
I can't saw if
I can't keep my eyes open.
I'm sorry.
Let's coffee up.
He can wait a few minutes.
- Is that Tucker's men?
- Yes, sir, I think it is.
How long has it been like this?
We just found them this morning.
They been here for 2 days.
Is that you, Lieutenant?
Hey, come on,
you better take cover.
These boys are shooters.
Go under cover.
You went to hospital?
It was no good.
What's going on here?
What's going on here...
is the question all right.
See, you could ask the major.
But he don't know, he's busy.
He's figuring out why
the officer's mess ran out
of ice cream.
And of course you got the general.
He came to see the show.
All he knows is there ain't no show.
The major is looking at
the general,
thinking: "I better do something".
You know what that means.
I don't want to be
the first across this field.
They're supposed to be
beat up like us.
Tucker's men are as tough as cobs.
Only thing killed so far
is three milking cows.
But that's about to change.
You son of a bitch.
Some of the boys are saying,
if we ain't gonna fight,
we could settle all this
with a little high-stakes poker.
Wouldn't that be a sight? A bunch
of fellows sitting in this field,
drawing cards.
What is it?
Looks like a suicide.
Tucker!
What'd you say to him?
I didn't say nothing.
Come on back, you son of a bitch!
Come on back!
- You won't make it a second time!
- All right by me.
Forgive me, Father.
- Ray!
- I got him.
No...
Don't take off my foot.
Rest easy. You'll keep your foot.
I swear you'll keep it.
- Bring up my ambulance.
- Sir?
Bring up my ambulance
and my surgeon with it!
We got an officer
who's worth something here.
The strangeness of life
cannot be measured,
In trying to produce my death,
I was elevated to a living hero,
I was awarded Cisco, the mount
I rode across the field that day,
On recovery, I was given transfer
to any station I desired,
The slaughter continues in the east
as I arrive at Fort Hays,
an island of men and material
surrounded by prairie,
Lieutenant John J. Dunbar.
Lieutenant John J. Dunbar?
Yes, sir.
"Yes, sir".
Indian fighter, huh?
Excuse me?
You're posted to the frontier.
Frontier is Indian country.
I deduce you're an Indian fighter.
- I didn't get promoted being stupid.
- No, sir.
"No, sir".
It says here...
- you've been decorated.
- Yes, sir.
And they posted you here?
I'm here at my own request.
Really? Why?
I've wanted to see the frontier.
You want to see the frontier?
Yes, sir.
Before it's gone.
A smart lad coming to me.
Sir Knight,
I am sending you
on a knight's errand.
Report to Captain Cargill
at the furthermost outpost
of the realm.
Fort Sedgewick.
My personal seal will assure
your safety through many miles
of wild and hostile country.
- I was wondering...
- Yes?
How will I be getting there?
You think I don't know?
- No, sir.
- You think I don't know.
- It's just I don't know.
- Hold your tongue.
I'm generous and will grant
your boon. See that peasant?
He calls himself Timmons.
He's going to Fort Sedgewick.
You can ride with him.
He knows the way.
That is all.
Sir Knight.
I just pissed in my pants.
And nobody can do
anything about it.
To your journey!
To my journey!
The king is dead.
Long live the king.
What you got?
Somebody back east is saying,
"Why don't he write?".
Stupid bastard.
What's that?
What is that?
What the hell is that?
Why don't you put that
in your book?
If not for my companion,
I'd be having
the time of my life,
He means well,
but he is possibly the foulest man
I have ever met,
Get up, Timmons.
Timmons.
Get up.
Come on, get up.
Did you poke me in my butt?
Goddamn it!
I'm gonna have a welt.
Why haven't we seen any buffalo?
You can't figure
the stinking buffalo.
Sometimes you won't see any
for days.
Other times, they'll be thick
as curls on a whore.
What about Indians?
Indians? Goddamn Indians.
You'd just as soon not see them
unless they're dead.
They're nothing but
thieves and beggars.
Not what you would call much
of a going concern, is it?
Go down there.
- Why? There's nothing down there.
- Because I said.
Go down there.
Son of a bitch!
There ain't nothing here.
There ain't nothing here,
Lieutenant.
Lieutenant!
Everybody's run off or got killed.
All right.
Let's unload the wagon.
And leave it all here?
I'm staying, too.
There ain't nothing here!
No. Not at the moment.
We don't know what happened.
Things being as they are,
we might as well turn around
and head back.
This is my post.
- "This is my post"?
- This is my post.
"This is my post".
Jesus H. Christ.
Are you crazy, boy? Lieutenant?
That son of a bitch.
- Jesus H. Christ!
- This is my post.
Put it down.
These are the post's provisions.
Get off the wagon
and help me unload.
We're just talking. Put it down.
I'll tell them where you are.
Good.
Good luck, Lieutenant.
Thank you.
Have found Fort Sedgewick deserted,
Am waiting for garrison's return
or word from headquarters,
The post is in poor condition,
I have assigned myself clean-up duty
beginning tomorrow,
Supplies are abundant, the country
is all I dreamed it would be,
There can be no place like this
on earth,
Bad horse.
Come on, Cisco, one more time.
Get up, Cisco.
Get up. There you go.
Only a white man would make a fire
for everyone to see,
Maybe there's more than one,
There might be three or four,
I know three or four who will not
be making the trip back home,
We have nothing to show for
this trail,
We have no rifles,
White men are sure to have rifles,
It's hard to say how many
might be down there,
We should forget this and go home,
Then go,
I would rather die
than argue about a single line
of smoke
in my country,
He will not quit
until we are all dead,
Oh, look at me.
Don't hurt my mules.
Stop. Stop it.
Please don't hurt my mules.
Men had been living in these caves,
Why?
Were they frightened?
Had there been some revolt?
I can make no sense
of the clues left here,
Perhaps my relief
will provide the answers,
It's been almost 30 days,
Still no sign of Captain
Cargill's command,
Communications can take place
only if I leave, and I don't want
to abandon my post,
I've decided to ration my goods
as if I were part of a post
rather than the whole affair,
There is a wolf who's intent
on the goings on here,
He's not inclined to be a nuisance,
And aside from Cisco,
he's been my only company,
He's come each afternoon
for two days,
He has milky white socks
on both feet,
If he comes calling tomorrow,
I will name him Two Socks,
You there!
Have made first contact
with an Indian,
One came and tried to steal
my horse,
When I appeared, he became
frightened and ran off,
I don't know how many there are,
but where there's one,
there's another,
I have decided
to bury excess ordnance
lest it fall into enemy hands,
My rides have been reduced
to short patrols,
always in sight of the fort,
I am still alone, however,
Unless troops arrives soon,
all may be lost,
It's been two days and nothing,
My presence must have been reported,
I have made all preparations
I can think of,
Cannot mount an adequate defense
but will try to make a big
impression when they come,
Waiting,
Postscript,
The man I encountered was
a magnificent-looking fellow,
I do not care for this talk
about a white man,
Whatever he is,
he is not Sioux,
and that makes him less,
When I hear that more whites
are coming, I want to laugh,
We took a hundred horses
from these people,
There was no honor in it,
They don't ride well, They don't
shoot well, They're dirty,
These soldiers could not even
make it through one winter here,
These people are said to flourish?
I think they will all be dead soon,
I think this fool is probably lost,
Wind In His Hair's words
are strong and I have heard them,
It's true the whites are a poor race
and hard to understand,
But make no mistake,
The whites are coming,
Even our enemies agree on this,
So when I see one man alone
without fear in our country,
I do not think he is lost,
I think he may have medicine,
I see someone who might speak for
all the white people
who are coming,
I think this is a person with
which treaties might be struck,
I have heard,
Kicking Bird is always
looking ahead,
and that is good,
But this man cannot cover
our lodges or feed our children,
He is nothing to us,
I will take some men,
We will shoot some arrows into this
white man, If he truly has medicine,
he will not be hurt,
If he has no medicine,
he will be dead,
No man can tell another
what to do,
But killing a white man
is a delicate matter,
If you kill one,
more are sure to come,
It's easy to become confused
by these questions,
It's hard to know what to do,
We should talk about this
some more,
That is all I have to say,
We'll be heroes,
They'll write songs about us!
What happened?
What is it?
I don't know, my arm doesn't work,
You shouldn't have fallen off,
Now we'll get in trouble,
It was your idea,
My idea was
to take the horse,
not fall down,
Otter hurt himself,
I'm the one who's hurt,
I will be when my father finds out,
His bow will be across my back,
Oh, God.
I am Wind In His Hair,
I am Wind
In His Hair,
Do you see
that I am not afraid of you?
Do you see?
I realize I have been wrong,
All this time I've been waiting,
Waiting for what?
For someone to find me?
For Indians to take
my horse? To see a buffalo?
Since my arrival,
I've been walking on eggs,
It's a bad habit,
I am sick of it,
Tomorrow I will ride out
to the Indians,
I do not know the wisdom of this,
I've become a target,
A target makes a bad impression,
I am through waiting,
What are you looking at?
Son of a bitch.
Wait.
You need help. You're hurt.
Let me help you.
You need help.
You need help. You're hurt.
Let me help you.
You're hurt.
Don't!
She's hurt.
You are not welcome here!
Go away from us!
No, she's hurt.
Go away!
You are not welcome here,
Stop!
The soldier did not come to fight,
He is going away,
and we will let him,
I am in agreement with Kicking Bird,
We will go down and talk
to the white man,
And find out why
he is here,
I have heard Ten Bears,
If this council decides to talk
to the white man,
then let it be so,
But in my mind it's not right
that a chief as great
as Ten Bears
goes to ask the business
of a puny, trespassing white man
with a smart horse and
a few white man's clothes,
I will not go,
You will go,
And you will go,
That is all I have to say,
Welcome.
Hi.
Come.
Please sit down.
Sit down.
Wait just a minute.
His mind is gone,
Tatanka, Buffalo.
Buffalo.
Buf...
- Buf...
- Buffalo. Tatanka,
The fierce one seems very tough,
I hope I never have to fight him,
From what I know, he seems to be
honest and direct,
I like the quiet one immensely,
He's patient and inquisitive,
He's eager to communicate,
I conclude that he is a man
of weight among his people,
Buffalo.
I made a greater impression
on their next visit,
I produced a coffee grinder,
which they'd never seen,
Is the coffee not good?
It's too strong, maybe.
Too strong.
Taste it.
Sugar.
You want some?
That's a lot.
It's good to have some company,
So much goes unsaid,
I feel these people,
particularly the quiet one,
want something from me,
Gave away coffee and
most of the sugar,
It wouldn't last anyway,
You could say a foundation for
good relations is being laid,
Stands With A Fist,
We will talk awhile,
Your wounds are healing well?
Yes they are,
Are you happy here,
with my family?
I am glad to be here,
I am missing my husband,
Perhaps you will marry again
when the time is right,
Perhaps,
We have word from many places
that the whites are coming,
They are coming into
everyone's country,
I think they will soon be in ours,
This white man who lives
at the old soldier fort,,,
I have visited him and believe
his heart
is a good one,
What do you say?
I am afraid of the white man
at the fort,
I am afraid he will tell others
that I am here,
I am afraid they will try
to take me away,
I've heard they take people away,
Every warrior in camp
would fight them if they tried,
I cannot make the white man
language,
He cannot speak Sioux,
It has been a long time
since I made this talk,
I want you to try,
I don't know how,
Yes you do,
- I can't,
- Yes you can,
I can't, It's dead in me,
I don't ask this for myself,
I ask this for all the people,
He knows things about the whites
which we do not,
Now, you must remember,
I can't,
Will she make
the white words?
She's won't try,
She's being difficult,
Well, she's the one who's crying,
Perhaps the difficulty is yours,
Christine!
Billy, get away from those puppies.
Get the kids in the house.
Go on, now.
Christine!
Christine! Where are you?
Who is it, Willie?
They look like Pawnee.
Our fathers are talking to them.
- What do they want?
- I don't know.
Go on. You heard us.
Get out of here.
Run, Christine!
I said run!
Christine!
Mommy! Mommy!
Come on, Two Socks. Bacon.
Two Socks, like Cisco,
has become a trusted friend,
He won't eat from my hand,
but his eyes and ears alert me
when something is wrong,
Tatanka,
No. I haven't seen any buffalo.
Sorry.
Are you hungry?
I have food.
I have a lot of food.
Nothing I've been told
about the Indians is true,
They are not beggars and thieves,
They are not bogeymen,
They are polite and have
a familiar humor I enjoy,
Real communication is slow,
and the quiet one is
as frustrated as I am,
Most of our progress is built on
the basis of failure, not success,
I thought to ask about the woman
I found on the prairie,
but it's far too complicated,
given our limitations,
One thing is clear, however,
There are no buffalo,
and it weighs on their minds,
Yesterday's visit was the best yet,
I've been invited to the village,
I am looking forward to going,
We were waiting for you,
Now tell him we are glad
that he is here,
Hello.
You...
here...
good.
Thank you. I feel good.
Ask him why he is at
the soldier fort,
The soldier fort...
Wait.
What are your names?
Our names?
What is his name?
He's right,
Introductions should come first,
He...
Kick...
Kick.
Kick, more.
More kick?
- More kicking?
- Kicking.
Kicking...
Bird.
Kicking Bird.
What is he?
Is he Chief?
A holy man.
Holy man.
Your name?
- I don't know.
- What's your name?
Get up?
Stand up?
Stands. Stands.
Stands. Your name is Stands?
Stands...
wiff...
- With.
- Stands With...
Fist?
Yes.
Stands With A Fist?
Stands With A Fist.
I am John
Dunbar.
John Dunbar.
Dunbear.
No, not Dunbear.
Dunbar.
Not Dunbear.
An exciting breakthrough
with the Indians,
A woman among them speaks English,
Clear progress was made,
I'm reluctant to answer
their questions,
My sense of duty or something
tells me not to say too much,
It was good to see
Fort Sedgewick again,
I look forward to visiting my
neighbors, but this is still home,
I watch for my relief
and hope my negotiations
will bear fruit,
Buffalo! Buffalo!
I've seen buffalo!
Buffalo!
Tatanka!
Riders were sent out
to pick up the trail,
By the time I'd got my things,
the entire tribe was on its way,
The efficiency and speed
of the people would impress
any military commander,
Overnight, I have gone from
a person of suspicion
to one of genuine standing,
I am greeted with open smiles
and looks of appreciation,
In short,
I have become a celebrity,
Loo-ten-tant.
Scouts picked up the trail
where I said it would be,
It was not hard to find,
A giant swath of torn-up ground
extending to the horizon,
The numbers it took to create this
impossible image was unimaginable,
Loo-ten-tant.
Who would do this?
The field was proof
that it was a people
without value or soul,
with no regard for Sioux rites,
The wagon tracks left little doubt,
My heart sank as I knew
it was white hunters,
Voices that had been joyous
were silent as the dead buffalo
were left to rot,
killed only for their tongues
and the price of their hides,
As they celebrated the coming hunt,
it was hard to know where to be,
I don't know if they understood,
but I couldn't sleep among them,
There had been no looks
and no blame,
Only the confusion of people
not able to predict the future,
Are you all right?
I can't.
No, I'm full.
I'm full. And I can't tell
the story any more.
You want to try it?
Here.
I can't.
This is too much.
Good trade.
This is a good trade.
No, I can't. I'm full.
I'm tired.
Tatanka,
Big tatanka,
That's my hat.
You're wearing my hat.
It's my hat.
I found it on the prairie,
It's mine,
My hat.
That hat belongs to the Lieutenant,
He left it on the prairie,
He didn't want it,
Well, you can see
he wants it now,
We all know that
it's a soldier's hat,
We all know
who wears it,
If you want to keep it,
that's all right,
But give something for it,
Good trade.
It seems every day ends
with a miracle here,
Whatever God may be,
I thank God for this day,
To stay longer
would've been useless,
We had all the meat
we could possibly carry,
We had hunted for 3 days,
losing 6 ponies,
And only 3 men injured,
I'd never known people
so eager to laugh,
so devoted to family,
so dedicated to each other, The word
that came to mind was "harmony",
Many times I've felt lonely,
But until this afternoon,
I'd never felt completely lonely,
Though only 2 days,
it seems like a week,
I am missing the company
of my new friends,
I can see all their faces,
but it is not enough,
Tomorrow I will make a visit,
They are my neighbors,
What can it hurt?
Go home!
Go!
Go home, Two Socks.
Bad wolf. Bad wolf.
It is autumn, and I am spending
more time with my friends,
They have given me my own lodge
and I feel comfortable,
We talk every day,
but Kicking Bird
is frustrated with me,
He wants to know how many more
white people are coming,
I tell him white people
will only pass through
this country,
But I am speaking in half-truths,
One day there will be too many,
But I cannot tell him that,
I am sure Stands with a Fist
knows I am holding back,
But she says nothing,
A war party is going against
the Pawnee, I have asked to go,
I sensed that I made a mistake
in doing so,
But I didn't take it back,
They are my friends, and the Pawnee
have been very hard on them,
I hope I have not overstepped
my bounds,
Come in, please.
Sit down.
Kicking Bird wants to know
why you want to make war
on the Pawnee.
They have done nothing to you.
They are Sioux enemies.
Only Sioux warriors to go.
Tell him I have been a warrior
longer than many
of the young men who will go
on the war party.
He says the Sioux way
of being a warrior
is not the white way.
You are not ready.
I know. But tell him
I cannot learn these ways in camp.
He also asks that you
watch over his family
while he is gone.
This thing he asks is
a great honor
for you.
I would be happy
to watch over his family.
He thanks Dances With Wolves
for coming.
Who is Dances With Wolves?
It is the name which
the people are calling you now.
Dances With Wolves.
That's right.
That day.
Dances With Wolves.
How do you say it?
Keep on with the white man talk,
if it pleases you,
I like to make the talk,
Oh, I cut this off today.
I shaved it off.
Go on.
Grass grows on the prairie.
Wrong.
You said,
"Fire lives on the prairie".
I did?
No laughing now.
How did you get your name?
I was not very old...
when I came to be with our people.
And I was made to work.
I worked every day very hard.
And there was one woman
who didn't like me much.
She used to call me bad names
and sometimes she...
beat me.
One day, she was calling me
these bad names...
with her face in my face.
And I hit her.
I was not very big,
but she fell down.
She fell hard and didn't move.
And I stood over her with my fist
and asked
if there was any other woman
who wanted to call me bad names.
No one bothered me after that day.
No, I wouldn't think so.
Show me.
Show me where you hit her.
Why are you not married?
- I'm sorry.
- I have to go.
I'm sorry.
- Can I help you?
- No.
Some of your words are wrong,
but you are learning fast,
So,,,
what can I tell you today?
I want to know about
Stands With A Fist,
Why is there no man with her?
She is in mourning,
I do not understand "mourning",
She cries for someone,
Cries for who?
It is not polite
to speak of the dead,
But you are new,
so I will tell you,
She cries for her husband,
He was killed not long ago,
That is how you came to find her
on the prairie
crying,
How long will she cry?
It is Kicking Bird's place to say
when she is finished,
He's the one that found her
when she was very little,
People are talking about you,
What are they saying?
They are proud of
the medicine you are making
with Dances With Wolves,
I have hurt him,
and I should go talk to him,
You can't, He is gone,
He left this morning,
I bet you were thinking,
"Now, why don't he write".
Hello, Two Socks.
Come on.
Come on, you can do this.
You can do this.
Come on.
It's easy.
This is easy, Two Socks.
I am in mourning.
No one can know.
We must be careful.
What?
I don't know.
The Pawnee are coming.
40 or 50 men.
Hunters found them to the north.
- They're heading for our camp.
- Stone Calf, wait,
I will follow you,
The Pawnee do not come for horses,
They come for blood,
Get your weapons
and come to my lodge,
I will go.
I will get them,
Stone Calf, wait,
I have guns,
I have many rifles,
- At the fort?
- Yes.
No, The ride is long
and we can spare no men,
Guns would make one warrior
like two,
Take one man and go quickly,
I will take Smiles A Lot,
Very well,
Shoot the gun!
It was hard to know how to feel,
I had never been
in a battle like this,
There was no
dark political objective,
It was not a fight for territory
or riches or to make men free,
It was fought to preserve
our winter food stores,
to protect the lives
of women and children right here,
Stone Calf was a great loss,
But no one could remember
such a great victory,
I began to look at it
in a new way,
I felt a pride
I had never felt before,
I'd never really known
who John Dunbar was,
Perhaps the name had no meaning,
But as I heard my Sioux name
being called
I knew for the first time
who I really was,
Where are you going?
There is gambling tonight,
Horseback's games are always good,
I'm tired,
Horseback already has
a good rifle of mine,
Good night,
How long will
Stands With A Fist mourn?
I don't know,
I hope it will not be long,
Has something happened?
What?
She has found love again,
With who?
Who do you think?
Tell me,
Dances With Wolves,
Are you certain of this?
When you see them together,
you will know,
What are people saying?
They like the match,
No one is angry?
It makes sense,
They are both white,
I suppose I will be the one
to say something,
She's your daughter now,
I know,
Relax, you can't see
everything coming,
Stop it,
Quit your playing,
Stands With A Fist,
You will mourn no more,
You look good,
You know, the man she mourned for,,,
He was my best friend,
I didn't know that,
He was a good man,
It has been hard for me
to like you,
I am not the thinker
Kicking Bird is,
I always feel anger first,
There were no answers
to my questions,
But now I think
he went away because
you were coming,
That is how I see it,
This is a good day for me,
And for me.
Stands With A Fist,
if you want this man,
take his hand in yours,
I'd never been married,
I don't know if all grooms
feel the same,
but as Kicking Bird described
what was expected
of a Sioux husband, my mind shut out
everything but her,
The tiny details of her costume,
The contours of her shape,
The light in her eyes,
The smallness of her feet,
I knew the love between us
would be served,
Have you heard what I have said?
Good, then
take her inside,
She is your wife,
Oh, good.
Thank you,
It's good to be out,
Yes, it must be,
We are trying for a baby,
No waiting?
No waiting,
I was just thinking that
of all the trails
in this life,
there is one that matters most,
It is the trail of a true
human being,
I think you are on this trail,
and it is good to see,
You ride your horse often,
I like that,
You always ask about
the white people,
You always want to know
how many more are coming,
There will be a lot, my friend,
More than can be counted,
How many?
Like the stars.
Like the stars,
It makes me afraid
for all the Sioux,
We should tell this to Ten Bears,
The men who wore this came
in the time of
my Grandfather's Grandfather,
Eventually,
we drove them out,
Then the Mexicans came,
They do not come here any more,
In my own time, the Texans,
They have been like all the others,
They take
without asking,
I don't know if we are ready
for these people,
But I think you are right,
I think they will keep coming,
When I think of that,
I look at this helmet,
Our country is all that we have,
and we will fight to keep it,
Tomorrow we will strike the village
and go to the winter camp,
You have everything
from the soldier fort?
Yes. There's nothing for me there.
That's good.
The journal.
Wait.
The book is like a trail
for people to follow.
It tells everything about
my life here. I must get it.
Enough.
We cannot wait for you.
I'll catch up.
Injuns!
Stay down. Stay.
Oh, God.
It's okay.
Something must have happened,
Dances With Wolves is not coming,
He must have trouble,
Algo ha pasado,
no es normal,
Pick two good men and send them
back to the soldier fort,
Spivey.
- Spivey.
- Yeah, Sergeant?
Tell the major he's waking up.
Move your worthless ass.
You got yourself
a hell of a shiner,
didn't you?
Does he speak English?
I don't know, sir.
You speak English?
You talk English?
Talk!
I speak English.
Who are you?
Lieutenant John J. Dunbar.
This is my post.
Why are you dressed like that?
I came out from Fort Hays
last April, but nobody was here.
You have proof of that?
My journal's in my quarters.
My orders are in the journal.
It'll tell you everything.
Spivey, you and Edwards
were the first here.
Did you find a journal?
We didn't find nothing, sir.
Where's Edwards?
He's outside.
He didn't find nothing either.
You turned Injun, didn't you?
Didn't you?
- He's a soldier.
- He's an officer.
Officer? Do you salute him
or shoot him?
Here, you, eyes front.
Eyes front!
Why are you out of uniform?
Why's the army out here?
The Lieutenant
is asking the questions.
We're charged with
apprehending the hostiles,
recovering stolen property,
retrieving white captives
taken in raids.
There are no hostiles.
We'll be the judge of that.
If you guide us to these camps,
your conduct will be reevaluated.
What conduct?
Your status as
a traitor might improve
if you cooperate
with the U.S. Army.
There's nothing for you
to do out here.
Are you willing to cooperate?
Speak up!
I am Dances With Wolves,
What's that?
I am Dances With Wolves!
I have nothing to say to you,
You are not worth talking to,
Form a detail and take this man
to the river.
Let him clean up his face.
Not you, Spivey.
Hey, Spivey.
You got paper?
- What's it to you?
- Well, give me some.
Can you read?
No, I can't read.
You can't read either.
Just give me some.
Give me some!
All right! Hold your horses.
Lap it up, Injun. Lap it up.
Son of a bitch. I'll kill you.
It's all right.
You're just gonna get hungrier.
But maybe that don't matter.
They're gonna ship you
back to Hays.
And once you get there,
they gonna hang you.
Forget about him. Get out of here.
Spivey, what is that?
Looks like he's following us.
Hell, I'm gonna shoot him.
You missed him.
Don't shoot.
- It's my shot.
- Wait, I saw him first.
That stupid bastard
ain't even moving.
Wait a minute, that's my shot.
Get him. He's standing there.
- He ain't hurt, is he?
- Shoot him!
He might've killed you.
I got him!
Dead shot, boys. Come on.
Son of a bitch. Get up!
Get up!
I'll kill you.
Stop bashing him or
I'll put shackles on you.
You men get back here!
God damnit.
Let's go.
I don't see nobody.
Dances With Wolves
is quiet these days,
Is his heart bad?
Killing the soldiers at the river
was a good thing,
I did not mind killing those men,
I was glad to do it,
But the soldiers
hate me now,
like they hate no other,
They think I am a traitor,
And they will hunt for me,
And they find me,
they find you,
I think it would be wise
to move the village now,
As soon as possible,
I will be leaving,
I must go and talk with those
who would listen,
Quiet,
You are hurting my ears,
You are the only white man
I have ever known,
I have thought about you a lot,
More than you know,
But I think you are wrong,
The man the soldiers are looking for
no longer exists,
Now there is only
a Sioux named
Dances With Wolves,
Let's smoke awhile,
With Ten Bears,
it was always more than a while,
Everything he did had a purpose,
He wanted me to stay,
But I would be an excuse,
all the army needed
to find this place,
I pushed him to move the camp,
But in the end, he only smiled
and talked of simple pleasures,
He reminded me that at his age,
a good fire is better than anything,
Ten Bears was an extraordinary man,
You have nothing to say?
What can I tell you?
Whatever's on your mind.
You've made the decision.
My place is with you.
I go where you go.
You're not afraid?
I told Ten Bears we'd leave
when the snow breaks.
Did you tell everyone?
Not everyone.
It's all right,
You...
finish your pipe?
The pipe...
How...
does it smoke?
I've never smoked it.
We come far,
you and me.
I will not forget you.
Dances With Wolves!
I am Wind In His Hair,
Do you see that I am your friend?
I am your friend!
Can you see that you will
always be my friend?