It's another hot and sunny
Southern California day.
The temperature in downtown
Los Angeles is 29°C...
And at night will drop to...
♪ I think about that day ♪
♪ I left him at the
Greyhound station ♪
♪ West of Santa Fe ♪
♪ We were 17 but he was
sweet and it was true ♪
♪ Still I did what I had to do ♪
♪ Cause I just knew ♪
♪ Summer: Sunday nights ♪
♪ We'd sink into our
seats right as ♪
♪ They dimmed out all the lights ♪
♪ A Technicolor world made
out of music and machine ♪
♪ It called me to
be on that screen ♪
♪ And live inside each scene ♪
♪ Without a nickel to my name
Hopped a bus, here I came ♪
♪ Could be brave or just insane ♪
♪ We'll have to see ♪
♪ Cause maybe in
that sleepy town ♪
♪ He'll sit one day,
the lights are down ♪
♪ He'll see my face and think
of he used to know me ♪
♪ Climb these hills, I'm
reaching for the heights ♪
♪ And chasing all the
lights that shine ♪
♪ And when they let you down ♪
♪ You'll get up off the ground ♪
♪ Cause morning rolls around
And it's another day of sun ♪
♪ I hear them every day ♪
♪ The rhythms in the canyons
that'll never fade away ♪
♪ The ballads in bar-rooms left
by those who came before ♪
♪ They say: "You got to
want it more" ♪
♪ So I bang on every door ♪
♪ And even when the answer's "no"
or when my money's running low ♪
♪ The dusty mic and neon glow ♪
♪ Are all I need ♪
♪ And someday as I sing my song ♪
♪ A small-town kid'll come along ♪
♪ That'll be the thing to
push him on and go go ♪
♪ Climb these hills, I'm
reaching for the heights ♪
♪ And chasing all the
lights that shine ♪
♪ And when they let you down ♪
♪ You'll get up off the ground ♪
♪ Cause morning rolls around
and it's another day of sun ♪
♪ And when they let you down ♪
♪ The morning rolls around ♪
♪ It's another day of sun ♪
♪ It's another day of sun
Sun, sun, sun, sun ♪
♪ It's another day of sun ♪
♪ Just one more day of sun ♪
♪ Another day has just begun ♪
♪ It's another day of sun ♪
We could not believe
what was happening.
I swear to God. She was wrecked.
She was completely
wrecked. I know.
I know, it was... it
was pure insanity.
"It was insanity?"
Lunacy. "It was pure lunacy."
What is his problem? I should go.
- Cappuccino, please.
- Right. Of course.
- On us.
- Oh no thank you. I insist.
AUDITION.
Shit.
Mia, where do you
think you're going?
Oh, it's five after.
- You better be early tomorrow.
- Okay.
Have a good night.
She was wrecked
It was pure lunacy. It was...
It was so crazy and I just...
Oh you would have died.
No, Turner is fine.
Turner is fine. I just...
Are you going to wait until
Denver to tell her, or?
What?
Okay.
No, I'm happy for you.
I am. I'm happy for you. I just...
I just thought...
I don't know what I thought
I guess it just...
I'm sorry.
- What Ruby?
- Jessica called.
- Tell her I call her back.
- In two minutes?
Less than two minutes.
- I'll go get your lunch.
- I'm almost done. Thank you.
Oh you know what? I
think we're good.
Thanks for coming in.
Holy shit. You want
to open a window?
It was trying to give
you an entrance.
Thank you.
Mia. How the audition go?
Same here. Was Jen
there? Or Rachel?
I do not know who
Jen and Rachel are.
They are the worst.
- I don't know if they were there.
- I bet that they were.
Why is there a convention
in the bathroom?
Oh right.
Two minutes people. Mia
you're coming, right?
I can't.
I'm working.
What?
Did she just say "working"?
- What?
- Sorry it didn't go well today.
And there's like four
things in my inbox that
you're perfect for and
I will submit you.
But right now, you're coming.
It will be fun.
It's not gonna be fun.
- It could be.
- It's not.
It's gonna be a bunch
of social climbers.
All packed into one of
those big glass houses.
This looks familiar.
- I was gonna give that back.
- How long have you had this?
- Come on Mia.
- A long time.
When else are you gonna get to
see a very Hollywood cliche...
crammed into the same room?
We'll make fun of it together.
"I'm disappointed in you, Lex."
There's nothing to make fun of.
This party is gonna be like...
humanity at its finest.
- ♪ You got the invitation ♪
- ♪ You got the right address ♪
♪ You need some medication? ♪
♪ The answer's always "yes" ♪
♪ A little chance encounter ♪
♪ Could be the one
you've waited for ♪
♪ Just squeeze a bit more ♪
- ♪ Tonight we're on a mission ♪
- ♪ Tonight's the casting call ♪
♪ If this is the real audition ♪
Oh, God, help us all.
♪ You make the right impression
Then everybody knows your name ♪
♪ We're in the fast lane ♪
♪ Someone in the crowd could
be the one you need to know ♪
♪ The one to finally lift
you off the ground ♪
♪ Someone in the crowd could
take you where you wanna go ♪
♪ If you're the someone
ready to be found ♪
♪ Someone ready to be found ♪
♪ Do what you need to do
until they discover you ♪
♪ And make you more than
who you're seeing now ♪
♪ So with the stars aligned ♪
♪ I think I'll stay behind ♪
♪ You've got to go and find ♪
♪ That someone in the crowd ♪
Hey girl.
♪ Is someone in the crowd the
only thing you really see? ♪
♪ Watching while the world
keeps spinning around? ♪
♪ Somewhere there's a place where
I find, who I'm gonna be ♪
♪ Somewhere... ♪
♪ That is just waiting
to be found ♪
♪ Someone in the crowd could
be the one you need to know ♪
♪ The someone who could
lift you off the ground ♪
♪ Someone in the crowd could
take you where you want to go ♪
♪ Someone in the crowd
could make you ♪
could take you ♪
♪ Flying off the ground ♪
♪ If you're someone
ready to be found ♪
No.
Oh come on. What?
Please stop sneaking into my home.
Do you think Mum and Dad
would call this a "home"?
What are you doing?
Please don't do that.
Please don't sit on that.
- Are you kidding?
- Please don't sit on that.
Don't sit on that.
- Hoagy Carmichael sat on that.
- Oh my god.
The Baked Potato
just threw it away.
I can't imagine why.
And now you're just sitting on it.
I got you a throw rug.
I don't need that.
What if I said Miles
Davis pissed on it?
It's almost insulting.
Is it true?
When are you going to
unpack these boxes?
When I unpack them in my own club.
Oh, Sebastian.
It's like a girl broke up with
you and you're stalking her.
You're not still going
by there, are you?
That's...
I can't believe they turned
it into a samba-tapas place.
- Oh my god, Sebastian.
- Samba. Tapas.
Pick one, you know. Do one right.
I have someone I want you to meet.
I don't want to meet anyone.
No... no, I don't
want to meet anyone.
Dad gave you this?
- Yes.
- You'll like her.
I don't think I'm gonna like her.
- Does she like jazz?
- Probably not.
Then what are we gonna talk about?
I don't know. It
doesn't matter, okay?
Because you're living
like a hermit.
You're driving without insurance.
- Doesn't matter?
- Yes. Doesn't matter.
- Okay.
- You need to get serious.
Well then I know a guy with a
face tattoo you should see.
- Okay, low blow.
- With a heart of gold.
- Get serious.
- Get serious? Laura...
I had a very serious
plan for my future.
I know.
It's not my fault
I got Shanghaied.
You didn't get Shanghaied.
You got ripped off.
What's the difference?
I don't know. It's not
as romantic as that.
Don't sit...
Everybody knew that guy was
shady, except for you.
Why do you say "romantic"
like it's a dirty word?
Unpaid bills are not
romantic. Call her.
I'm not going to call her.
The thing is... You're acting
like life's got me on the ropes.
I want to be on the ropes.
Okay? I'm just... I'm letting
life hit me until it gets tired.
And then I'm gonna hit back.
It's a classic "rope-a-dope".
Okay, Ali. I love you.
Unpack your boxes.
- I'm gonna change the locks.
- You can't afford it.
I am a phoenix rising
from the ashes.
Hey.
Hey Bill, thanks for
letting me back.
You're welcome.
I want you to know that
you're looking at a new man.
Good.
- A man that's happy to be here.
- Excellent.
Very easy to work with.
And you're gonna
play the set list?
Happy to.
Even though I don't think
anybody cares what I play.
But yeah.
Well, if by "anyone"
you mean anyone
other than me, that
would be correct.
I care, and I don't wanna
hear the free jazz.
Right. Okay.
Although I thought that in this
town worked on a sort of...
"one for you, one for
me" type system.
How about two for you, one for me?
How about all for you
and none for me?
- That's perfect. Yes.
- Great.
- Okay.
- Okay. Mutual decision.
Right. Made... made by me.
Right. And I signed
off on it so...
Whatever. Tell yourself
what you wanna know.
Hello. Welcome back.
There's a nice way
to say that, Karen.
Seb.
I do... I do... I hear
what you're saying. But
I don't think you're
saying what you mean.
Yeah, I don't think you hear
what I'm saying. You're fired.
Well I... That's what
you're saying but
that's not what you
mean. You mean is.
You're fired.
Play the set list.
No. What I'm saying is "too late".
It is a warning.
What... what planet are you from?
- Don't fire me. Don't fire me.
- You're done. I'm sorry, Seb.
It's Christmas.
Yeah, I see the decorations.
Good luck in the New Year.
I just heard you play,
and I wanted to...
I don't like the fissure
on the GT scan.
Did you test for achromatopsia?
D.O.A. on 23rd, perp laughing
his face off at the P.D.
Damn Miranda Rights.
This is my classroom.
You don't like it, the
door's to my left.
Lady why you be
tripping like that?
No, Jamal.
You be tripping.
Mia.
- Hi.
I want you to meet
my friend Carlo.
- Hi. Carlo.
- This is Mia.
- Nice. Mia?
- Yes, Mia.
- Hi. How are you?
- Carlo is a writer.
Yeah. They say I have
a knack for world
building. I got a lot
of heat right now.
It's from a lot of buzz, people
talking about me.
It's just exciting.
You work so hard and then
all of it validated...
I'm gonna go grab a drink.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
It's really nice to meet you.
Sorry.
Thank you. Any other requests?
The girl in the front.
- "I Ran".
- "I Ran". A fantastic suggestion.
All right, piano man, tickle
those ivories. Let's hit it.
One two three four.
That's right.
♪ I walk alone the avenue ♪
♪ I never thought I'd
meet a girl like you ♪
♪ Meet a girl like you... ♪
Me?
♪ With auburn hair
and tawny eyes ♪
♪ The kind of eyes that
hypnotise me through ♪
♪ That hypnotise me through ♪
♪ And I ran, I ran so far away ♪
♪ I couldn't get away ♪
All right. I remember you.
And I would admit I was a
little curt that night.
"Curt"?
Okay, I was an asshole.
I can admit that.
Okay.
But requesting "I
Ran" from a serious
musician is just... it's too far.
My Lord. Did you just say
"a serious musician"?
I don't think so.
Can I borrow what you're wearing?
Why?
Because I have an
audition next week.
I'm playing a serious firefighter.
So you're an actress.
I thought you look
familiar. Have I seen
you on anything?
A coffee shop on the Warner
Bros. Lot. That's classic.
- Oh, I see.
- Yeah.
You're a barista.
And I can see how
you could then look
down on me from all
the way up there.
Next set.
He doesn't... I don't...
He doesn't tell me what to do.
- He just told you what to...
- I know. I let him.
What is your name?
- Mia.
I guess I'll see
you in the movies.
- You know Joseph Campbell?
- Yeah.
I have this idea that
you were reimagining
"Goldilocks and the
Three Bears"...
from the perspective of the bears.
- You know it's thrilling.
- It could be a franchise.
Right.
So well we don't know if they were
cooped up up there. We don't know.
George Michael.
Hello.
Sorry. It's... I know that guy.
Did you get your keys?
- Yes.
- Can you grab mine?
Sorry what?
Will you be able to
grab my... my keys?
I can't hear you.
- Sorry, can you grab my keys?
- Oh.
- Please.
- Oh, there we go.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- What kind?
- It's a Prius.
- That doesn't help me.
- With a green ribbon.
All right.
Those look, comfortable.
They are.
Thank you for saving
the day back there.
Well, you didn't really
give me much of a choice.
It's pretty strange that we
keep running into each other.
It is strange.
- Maybe it means something.
- I doubt it.
- Yeah. I don't think so.
- Where's my car?
Put that thing to your chin.
- This?
- Yeah.
It makes your head
into an antenna.
I think it gives you cancer
but you find your car faster.
What?
I mean you don't get
to live as long
but you get where you're going...
- quicker so it all evens out.
- That sounds terrible.
Just a suggestion.
You're a real...
What's the word am I looking for?
Knight in shining armour.
- Weirdo. That was the word.
- Okay.
Not much to look at, huh?
I've seen better.
♪ The sun is nearly gone ♪
♪ The lights are turning on ♪
♪ A silver shine that
stretches to the sea ♪
♪ We stumbled on a view
That's tailor made for two ♪
♪ What a shame those
two are you and me ♪
♪ Some other girl and guy ♪
♪ Would love this swirling sky ♪
♪ But there's only you and I ♪
♪ And we've got no shot ♪
♪ This could never be ♪
♪ You're not the type for me ♪
Really?
♪ And there's not a
spark in sight ♪
♪ What a waste of a lovely night ♪
♪ You say there's nothing here? ♪
♪ Well, let's make
something clear ♪
♪ I think I'll be the
one to make that call ♪
But you'll call?
♪ And though you look so cute
in your polyester suit ♪
It's wool.
♪ You're right, I'd never
fall for you at all ♪
♪ And maybe this appeals
To someone not in heels ♪
♪ Or to any girl who feels there's
some chance for romance ♪
♪ But I'm frankly
feeling nothing ♪
♪ Is that so? ♪
♪ Or it could be
less than nothing ♪
♪ Good to know so you agree? ♪
♪ That's right ♪
♪ What a way to waste
of a lovely night ♪
Hi, Greg.
Hi. Oh, sorry I'm late.
Yeah. Very soon. Okay. Bye.
- It's just right there.
- Just right here.
Do you want a ride to your car?
No, I'm just right up here.
Good night.
Excuse me. This is
gluten free, right?
- No.
- What?
I'd like a refund.
Okay. Let me check it out.
Mia, you're closing Friday.
I can't close on Friday. I
have an audition, remember?
Do I look like I care?
We schedule it.
Oh and we need to have a
little talk tomorrow, okay?
- Fix your apron, please.
- Okay.
You again.
What are you doing here?
You know, just meetings
and studio heads.
How did you get on the lot?
I basically just run
past the guard gates.
I think I have 20 minutes
until they find me.
You have a break
coming up, do you?
I'm off in ten minutes.
Can I hide in the bathroom?
- Yes.
- Okay.
Sorry.
I actually do have
to check. I'm sorry.
That's the window
that Humphrey Bogart
and Ingrid Bergman looked
out of in Casablanca.
- Wow.
- Yeah.
I can't believe you work right
across the street from there.
- Yeah.
- That's amazing.
What was you're,
you're Bogart's name?
What's his name? Is it Greg?
Yeah, Greg.
Right. How long have you been...?
We've been seeing each
other for about a month.
That's great.
It's sweet. Anyway, I love being
around this stuff. You know?
I know what you mean. I get
coffee 5 miles out of the way...
just so I can be near a jazz club.
Really?
Yeah, the Van Beek.
Do you know it?
All the big swing
bands used to play
there. Count Basie, Chick Webb.
Anyway, it's a samba-tapas
place now, so...
What's a samba-tapas place?
You know, it's like a samba
place where they serve tapas.
Oh.
Yeah. So the joke's on... history?
I don't know. That's L.A.
They just... They worship
everything and they value nothing.
We're about to roll.
Stop please guys.
- You're rolling?
- Yeah.
They shoot movies on my street
all the time so no problem.
- Come this way.
- Right.
It's a lockdown.
- I love her.
- And here we go.
Hey, Mia. How did
you get into this?
- And... roll.
- Get into what?
- You know, movies, acting.
- Action.
- My aunt was an actress.
- Oh, okay.
She was in a travelling
theatre company.
I grew up in Boulder City, Nevada.
So across the street
from my house,
there was this little library.
That had an old movies section.
So she... she took me
and spent an entire
day watching all
these old movies...
like "Notorious", "Bringing
Up Baby," "Casablanca"...
and...
Cut it there. Cut.
Check the tapes.
- We can talk now.
- She sounds incredible.
She was incredible.
And I would put
on all these plays
in my bedroom...
and it would basically
just she and I
re-enacting the scenes
from the movies.
And then I wrote my
own plays. Yeah.
Wow.
I love it.
So anyway, I left college
after two years to come here.
And my last audition
was for a teen soap
pitched as Dangerous
Minds meets The OC.
So yeah, should've been a lawyer.
Because the world
needs more lawyers.
Doesn't need more actresses.
You're not just an actress.
What do you mean
"just an actress"?
You said it yourself. You were
a child prodigy playwright.
That is not what I said.
Well, you're too modest
to say it but it's true.
So you could just write
your own roles, you know.
Write something that's as
interesting as you are...
and you don't have to
audition for this pishi kaka.
Yeah.
Look at Louis Armstrong, you know.
He could have just
played the marching
band charts that he was given.
But he didn't do it.
What did he do?
He made history, didn't he?
Well, I'm gonna stop
auditioning and
I'm gonna make history instead.
Well, my work is done here.
I should probably tell
you something now.
To get it out the way.
I hate jazz.
You okay?
What do you mean you hate jazz?
It just means that when I
listen to it, I don't like it.
Yeah but it's just a blanket
statement that you
don't like jazz.
What are you doing right now?
Nothing.
You know, I just think
that when people say that,
you know, hate jazz.
They just... they don't
have context. They
don't know where it
comes from. You know?
Jazz was born in a little
flophouse in New Orleans...
and just because
people were crammed in
there, they spoke five
different languages.
They couldn't talk to each other.
The only way that they could
communicate was with jazz.
You know, what about Kenny G?
What?
What about Kenny G? I mean,
what about elevator music?
You know, jazz music that I know.
- What about it?
- From my life.
I just... I mean find it relaxing.
It's not relaxing. It's not.
It's not.
Sidney Bechet shot
somebody because
he told him he
played a wrong note.
That's hardly relaxing.
Where I grew up, there was
this station called KJAZZ 103.
And people would just
put on that station
when they had a cocktail party...
Right.
And everyone would just
kind of talk over it.
- I know.
- Yes. It was...
Okay, okay. So I think
that that's part of the
problem is that you can't
hear it, you know.
You have to see it, you have
to see what's at stake.
I mean, look at these fellas. Look
at the saxophonist right now.
He just hijacked the song.
He's on his own trail.
Everyone of these
guys are composing,
rearranging, they're writing...
and they're playing the
melody. They're just...
And now look, the trumpet
player. He's got his own idea.
It's so... it's conflict and it's
compromise, and it's just...
It's new every time. It's
brand new every night.
It's very, very exciting.
And it's dying.
It's dying, Mia. It's
dying on the vine.
And the world says, "Let
it die. It had its time".
Well, not on my watch.
What are you gonna do?
I'll have my own club.
- Really?
- Yes.
We're gonna play whatever we
want, whenever we want...
however we want, as
long as it's pure jazz.
Hi, this is Mia Dolan.
Yeah, I just missed a call.
- I got a callback.
- What?
Come on. For what?
For a TV show. The one I
was telling you about.
The Dangerous Minds meets The OC?
Yeah.
Congratulations.
That's incredible.
It's really exciting.
I feel like I said negative
stuff about if before.
What?
It's like "Rebel Without
a Cause" sort of.
"I got the bullets."
Yes.
- You've never seen it.
- I've never seen it.
Oh my. You know it's
playing in the Rialto.
- Really?
- Yes.
You should go. I mean,
I can take you.
- Okay.
- You know, for research.
- For research. Yeah.
- Yeah.
Okay.
Monday night, ten o'clock.
- Yeah. Great.
- Okay.
For research.
♪ City of stars are you
shining just for me? ♪
♪ City of stars there's so
much that I can't see ♪
♪ Who knows? ♪
♪ Is this the start of
something wonderful? ♪
♪ Or one more dream that
I cannot make true? ♪
- Stand there please.
- Okay. Nice to meet you.
- Hi.
- On your own time.
- Okay.
Two options:
You either follow my rules,
or follow my rules. Capisce?
Thank you.
- Thanks.
- I could do it a different way.
That's... that's fine. Thank
you very much. Thank you.
- That was fun. Thanks.
- Bye.
Hey Mia.
- What?
- Greg's here.
What do you mean...?
Hey babe. Got a space out front.
- Great.
- We should get going.
My brother landed really early.
Did you forget?
- Shit.
- You forgot.
That's tonight.
- That's okay. Yeah. You forgot.
- Yeah. Okay. All right.
So then I'll just get changed.
- Okay. Great.
Yeah, that's him. Hey, Josh. Yeah.
Just picking up Mia. We'll
be there in like...
But now we got this
surround sound set-up.
Oh, it's like being
in a movie theatre.
Well, better than being
in a theatre, really.
- I can't wait.
- You know theatres these days.
- Yeah.
- They're so dirty.
Yeah, I know. They smell bad.
And they're either
too hot or too cold.
I know, the quality
has gone far and off.
Oh, it's terrible and there's
always people talking.
- Many people.
- Oh it's...
I'm sorry. Just...
hold on a second.
- Hello?
- It's probably work.
Sorry. So you know, we love it.
- It's so nice.
- Well you have to come.
You should come by.
I have one more for
you man: Indonesia.
I don't know. I never
heard anyone say that.
I know, you know I can't
even keep track of
it but honestly, it was
just life changing.
- Really.
- Yeah.
Is it amazing?
- Yes.
- A five-star jungle-ECO resort.
- Well, you would not believe.
- Amazing.
We were thinking about
going to Nicaragua.
I think Nicaragua
is less developed.
- It's a bit underdeveloped.
- Right.
It's a little more.
I just... I don't know... I
don't know if it's safe there.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- I don't know if it's safe.
I'm sorry.
An immensity of our universe.
For many days, before
the end of our Earth,
people will look into the
night sky and notice a star,
increasingly bright and
increasingly near.
As this star approaches us...
Jim Stark.
- I'll go find a place. I'm sorry.
- As this star approaches us,
the weather will change.
The great polar fields
of the north and south
will rot and divide. And
the seas will turn warmer.
The last of us search the
heavens and stand amazed.
For the stars will
still be there...
moving through their...
I have an idea.
What is that? Is that a script?
- It's a play.
- A play?
You better give us all roles.
Actually, it's a one woman show.
So I can't.
Wow. Is that gonna
happen every time?
I think so.
Wait. It's one way.
Sebastian.
- Keith.
- Come here, man.
- How are you?
- Very good, man.
This is Mia. Mia, Keith.
- Hi Mia. Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
I used to play with this guy.
We went to school together.
- So how you been brother?
- Great.
Never been better. How about you?
I've been really good.
Been very busy.
- I got a new combo.
- Okay.
Cool.
We're looking for keys.
- Are you kidding me?
- No, I'm not kidding.
- No, I'm good.
- You sure? It pays.
I'm good.
Let's just grab a drink then.
It's been too long.
- Okay. Nice to meet you Mia.
- Nice to meet you.
The end.
It's...
Genius.
- Really?
- Yes.
It feels really nostalgic to me.
- That's the point.
- Is it too nostalgic?
- That's...
- Are people gonna like it?
Fuck them.
- You always say that.
- Well, I truly believe that.
- I made you something.
- For what?
For your club.
Why does it say "Seb's"?
Because I think you
should call it "Seb's".
What?
Because no one's gonna come
to "Chicken on a Stick".
Is that a music note?
Is it an apostrophe?
Yes.
That's pretty cool. It's got to
be "Chicken on a Stick".
Because Charlie Parker
got his nickname...
I know because he loves chicken.
That's why they call him "Bird".
So I'm gonna have chicken, beer,
jazz. "Chicken on a Stick"
I know. I think you
should drop the chicken,
and just have drinks
and jazz, and...
- also there could be...
- I'm not dropping the chicken.
You could maybe do
it somewhere else.
Find a new spot?
It's got to be the Van Beek.
It doesn't have to
be the Van Beek.
I can't let them samba
all over its history.
I can't do it.
You can let them
but you refuse to.
Your play's incredible.
You know? The whole world
from your bedroom.
What else do they want?
Who's doing that?
- I'm doing that.
- You're doing that.
Who was that guy
in The Lighthouse?
The guy that offered you the gig?
Keith.
Yeah. Why was it so
weird between you two?
It's just always weird with him.
- Really?
- Yeah.
But he seemed kinda nice because
he did offer you a job.
Are you gonna call him?
- No. No.
- All right.
So...
- Here's what we know.
- Yeah.
It's definitely
"Chicken on a Stick"
and your play's
gonna be a triumph.
It's a one woman show.
So it's just me.
No, I mean I'm acting in it.
No, Mum, I'm not getting
paid. I'm paying to do it.
He's great. He's gonna
open his own jazz
club. Yeah, it's
gonna be incredible.
No. He's... he's
nobody yet. He needs
He's saving up, I think.
No but he doesn't
have a steady gig.
But he's... he's
figuring it out. It's
just been a little
too Gilly lately.
Mum, he's gonna find a way to open
it and you're gonna love it. Okay?
How's Dad?
Sebastian. Come on in, man.
- Thanks for coming.
- Thanks for having me.
I wasn't sure I'd see you today.
- So here's the deal.
- Okay.
We got distribution with
Universal. We got our own imprint.
We're about to go on the road.
We can pay you a
thousand bucks a week...
plus a cut of the ticket revenue
and merchandising. Sound good?
- Sebastian?
- Yup.
All right.
- Let's play.
- Okay.
(scatting)
I know. It's different.
But you say you want to save jazz.
How are you gonna save jazz
if no one's listening?
Jazz is dying because
of people like you.
You play into 90 year
old at The Lighthouse.
Where are the kids? Where
are the young people?
You're so obsessed with Kenny
Clarke and Thelonious Monk.
These guys were revolutionaries.
How are you going to
be a revolutionary,
if you're such a traditionalist?
You holding on to the past,
but jazz is about the future.
I know. The other guy, he
wasn't as good as you.
But you're a pain in the ass, man.
♪ City of stars
Are you shining just for me? ♪
There's so much that I can't see ♪
♪ Who knows? ♪
♪ I felt it from the first
embrace I shared with you ♪
♪ That now our dreams
they've finally come true ♪
♪ City of stars ♪
♪ Just one thing everybody wants ♪
♪ There in the bars ♪
♪ And through the smokescreen
Of the crowded restaurants ♪
♪ It's love ♪
♪ Yes, all we're looking for
is love from someone else ♪
♪ A rush ♪
♪ A glance ♪
♪ A touch ♪
♪ A dance ♪
♪ A look in somebody's eyes ♪
♪ To light up the skies ♪
♪ To open the world
and send it reeling ♪
♪ A voice that says, "I'll be
here and you'll be alright" ♪
♪ I don't care if I know
just where I will go ♪
♪ Because all that I need's
this crazy feeling ♪
♪ The ratatat on my heart ♪
♪ I think I want it to stay ♪
♪ City of stars
Are you shining just for me? ♪
♪ City of stars ♪
♪ You never shined so brightly ♪
♪ I don't know why I
keep moving my body ♪
♪ I don't know if this is
wrong or if it's right ♪
♪ I don't know if there's a beat,
or something's taking over me ♪
♪ And I just know I'll
feel so good tonight ♪
♪ I don't know what your
name is but I like it ♪
♪ I've been thinking about
some things, I wanna try ♪
♪ I don't know what you came to
do, but I wanna do it with you ♪
♪ And I just know I'll
feel so good tonight ♪
♪ Oh, if we keep on dancing
Take our rhythm to new heights ♪
♪ Feel the heat of passion, baby
Light up the night ♪
♪ We could start a fire ♪
♪ Come on, let it burn baby ♪
♪ Let the tables turn baby ♪
♪ We could start a fire ♪
♪ I just know I feel so good ♪
♪ Don't you know I feel so good
I just know I feel so good ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
♪ I don't care if this
turns into a riot ♪
♪ Lets get reckless, tear this
place down to the floor ♪
♪ Turn the music way up loud ♪
♪ Can't nobody stop us now ♪
♪ I just know I feel
so good tonight ♪
♪ We could start a fire ♪
♪ Come on, let it burn baby ♪
♪ Let the tables turn baby ♪
♪ We could start a fire ♪
♪ I just know I feel so good ♪
♪ Don't you know I feel so good ♪
♪ Don't you know,
don't you know? ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
Hey, it's me.
I'm not sure where you are
right now. I think Boston.
Maybe Dallas, I don't know.
I haven't heard from you
in a little while...
And I miss you.
All right bye.
I thought...
Surprise.
I got to leave first thing in the
morning, but I just...
I had to see you.
It's so nice to be home.
I'm so glad you're home.
How's the play going?
I'm nervous.
You are? Why?
Because... what if people show up?
Pishi kaka.
You're nervous about
what they think?
I'm nervous to do it.
I'm nervous to get up on that
stage and perform for people.
I mean, I don't need
to say that to you.
It's gonna be incredible.
You don't get it
but I'm terrified.
They should be lucky to
see it. I can't wait.
I can.
When do you leave? In the morning?
Yeah. 6:45. Boise.
- Boise?
- Boise.
To Boise.
You should come.
To Boise?
Yeah. You can knock it
off your bucket list.
Oh. That would be really
exciting. I wish I could.
What are you doing after the tour?
Why can't you?
- Come to Boise?
- Yeah.
Because I have to rehearse.
Yeah but can't you
rehearse anywhere?
Anywhere you are?
I mean... I guess.
Well, all my stuff is here
and it's in two weeks. So I don't
think really think
that would be...
Okay.
- The best idea right now, but...
- Right.
I wish I could.
We're just gonna have
to try and see each
other, you know, so
that we see each other.
I know but when are you done?
What do you mean? I mean...
When you're finish
with the whole tour?
After we finish, we're gonna go to
recording and then
we'll go back on tour.
You know, we tour so we
can make the records
so we can go back
to tour the record.
So it's like the long haul?
What do you mean the "long haul"?
I mean the long haul
that you're gonna
stay in this band for a long time.
On tour.
I mean, what did you
think I was going to do?
I don't...
I hadn't really
thought it through.
I didn't know that the band...
Would be important. You didn't
think we would be successful.
No, that's not really what I
mean. I just mean that you...
I mean... You'll be on tour
for what? Months now? Years?
Yeah I don't mean... this is it...
I mean, this is... it
could feasibly be...
yeah for... I could be
on tour with this...
For a couple of years at
least, just this record.
Do you like the music
you're playing?
I don't...
I don't know... what...
what it matters.
Well, it matters because...
if you're going to give
up your dream. I think
it matters that you like
what you're playing
on the road for years.
Do you like the music that I play?
Yeah.
I do.
I just didn't think that you did.
Yeah well...
You know, you said
Keith is the worst
And now you're gonna
be on tour with
him for years, so I just didn't...
I don't know what... What
are you doing right now?
- Know if you were happy.
- Why are you doing this?
I don't... What do you mean
"why are you doing this"?
I thought you wanted me to do this
and it just sounds like now
you don't want me to do it.
What do you mean I
wanted you to do this?
This is what you wanted for me.
To be in this band?
To be in a band to
have a steady job.
You know, to... to be... you know.
Of course, I wanted you
to have a steady job...
so that you can take
care of yourself and
your life and you could
start your club.
Yes so I'm doing that so
I don't understand...
I mean why aren't we celebrating?
Why aren't you starting your club?
You said yourself no one
wants to go to that club.
No one wants to go to a club
called "Chicken on a Stick".
So change the name.
Well, no one likes
jazz. Not even you.
I do like jazz now because of you.
And this is what I thought
you wanted me to do.
What am I supposed to do? Go
back to playing Jingle Bells?
I'm not saying that. I'm
saying why don't you take...
what you've made and
start the club...
that people will wanna go to it...
because you're
passionate about it...
and people love what other
people are passionate about.
You remind people of
what they've forgotten.
Not in my experience.
Well, whatever alright. It's...
it's time to grow up, you know.
I have a steady job,
this is what I'm doing.
And now all of a sudden if
you had these problems,
I wish you would've
said them earlier...
before I signed on the
goddamn dotted line.
I'm pointing out that you had a
dream that you followed, that...
you were sticking...
This is the dream.
- This is not your dream.
- Guys like me...
work their whole lives to be in
something that's successful,
that people like. You know?
I mean, I'm finally in
something that people enjoy.
Since when do you care
about being liked?
Just because I don't enjoy
it, it doesn't matter.
Why do you care so much
you about being liked?
You are an actress. What
are you talking about?
Maybe you just liked me
when I was on my ass...
because it made you feel
better about yourself
- Are you kidding?
- No.
I don't know...
Okay fellas. I'll...
see you tomorrow.
- Sebastian?
- Yeah?
You're good for tonight, right?
- What are you talking about?
- At 7, the photo shoot.
For Mojo. You good?
I thought that was next Thursday.
No, it's tonight.
Is that okay?
- Tonya, give me the other camera.
- What's wrong with that?
"What's wrong with that"?
Oh I don't know...
It does not bloody work.
That's what's wrong with it.
Alright trumpet, that's lovely.
Lovely. Beautiful. Beautiful.
Okay, keyboard. Okay,
look up. That's
good. That's good. That's lovely.
Wonderful. Okay, cut the music.
That is lovely. That's lovely.
Okay, now look. Now bite
your lip like this...
like you're concentrating
on something, I
don't know, like a
piece of your music.
- Bite my what?
- Your lip. Bite your lip.
That's good. That's
great. Beautiful.
Beautiful.
Okay. Now, just move your
glasses down on your nose.
A little bit further. Just a
little bit touch further.
Keep your head down, but look
up at me. Look sort of moody.
Yeah. That is beautiful.
That is great.
Okay, turn on the
keyboard on live.
You want to hear the keyboard?
No. You don't have to
bite your lip now.
Well, you should play something.
Play something, you
know. Anything.
You're pianist, aren't
you? Play something.
That's great. That's beautiful.
That's lovely. Oh, that's good.
Now, don't stop. Keep playing.
Come on, just keep
playing. That was great.
Shoot myself in the head.
She's not even good. And
the window thing...
- What was that?
- Yes.
What did she do with the window?
Oh my God. Don't
quit your day job.
Oh well...
Mia.
Mia. I'm so sorry.
Just tell me how it
went? How was it?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I missed your play.
I'm sorry I didn't come.
You're sorry. You're sorry.
You're sorry.
- You're sorry.
- Let me make it up to you.
Let me make it up to you. Okay?
- I don't blame you if...
- It's over.
- What is?
What?
All of this.
I'm done embarrassing
myself. I'm done. I'm done.
- Nobody showed up.
- So what?
I can't pay back the
theatre. This is so...
I'm gonna go home for a while.
- I'll come see you tomorrow.
- No, I'm going "home" home.
- This is home.
- No, it's not any more.
Yep?
Hi. I'm trying to
reach a Mia Dolan.
Wrong number.
Yeah, she said if she's not on her
cell, I'm told I
might find her here.
Not any more.
Okay well, if you
do talk to her...
I won't.
Could you tell her
Jane and Amy Brandt
casting is trying to reach her.
Casting?
What the hell is that?
Stop that fucking noise.
Why did you come here?
Because I have good news.
What?
Amy Brandt, the casting director.
Yeah?
She was at your play
and she loved it.
And she loved it so
much that she wants you
to come in tomorrow and
audition for this...
huge movie that she's got.
I'm not going to that.
What?
That one's gonna be... No.
That one's gonna be...
I'm sorry?
That will kill me.
- What?
- What? Stop.
- No.
- You have to be quiet.
- If you want me to be quiet.
You're gonna wake
up the neighbours.
You have to make sense.
If you want me to be quiet, you're
gonna have make
some goddamn sense.
They're gonna call, they're
gonna call the police.
Because... because...
I've been to a million
of auditions and
the same thing happens every time.
Where I get interrupted because
someone wants to get a sandwich.
Or I'm crying and
they start laughing.
Or there's people
sitting in the waiting
room and they're and they're...
like me but prettier
and better at the...
because maybe I'm not good enough.
- Yes, you are.
- No.
- Maybe I'm not.
- You are.
Maybe I'm one of those people
who always wanted to do it...
but it's like a pipe
dream for me, you know?
You said it: You change your
dreams and then you grow up.
Maybe I'm one of those people
and I'm not supposed to.
And I can go back
to school and find
something else that
I'm supposed to do.
Because I left to do that...
and it's been six years and I
don't wanna do it any more.
Why?
Why what?
Why don't you wanna
do it any more?
Because I think it hurts
a little bit too much.
You're a baby.
I'm not a baby. I'm
trying to grow up.
You are. You're
crying like a baby.
Oh my God.
And you have an audition
tomorrow at 5:30.
I'll be out front at 8:00 am.
You'll be out front
or not. I don't know.
How did you find me here?
The house in front of the library.
- I got coffee.
- Okay, great.
Mia?
Hi, Mia. I'm Amy
and this is Frank.
- Hi, how are you?
- Pleasure to meet you.
- I'm glad we found you.
- Me too.
The film shoots in Paris and
we don't have a script.
It's gonna be a
process. We're gonna
build the character
around the actress.
It's a three-month rehearsal
and a four-month shoot.
Okay.
And we thought you could
just tell us a story.
- About?
- Just tell us anything.
Anything?
Yes. Tell us a story.
You're a storyteller.
Whenever you're ready.
My aunt used to live in Paris.
I remember, she used to come
home and she would tell us...
These stories about
being abroad and...
I remember she told us that she
jumped into the river once...
Barefoot.
She smiled...
♪ Leapt ♪
♪ Without looking ♪
♪ And tumbled into... ♪
♪ The Seine ♪
♪ The water was freezing ♪
♪ She spent a month sneezing ♪
♪ But said she would do it again ♪
♪ Here's to the ones who dream ♪
♪ Foolish as they may seem ♪
♪ Here's to the hearts that ache ♪
♪ Here's to the mess we make ♪
♪ She captured a feeling
Sky with no ceiling ♪
♪ The sunset inside a frame ♪
♪ She lived in her liquor
And died with a flicker ♪
♪ I'll always remember the flame ♪
♪ Here's to the ones who dream ♪
♪ Foolish as they may seem ♪
♪ Here's to the hearts that ache ♪
♪ Here's to the mess we make ♪
♪ She told me a bit
of madeness is key" ♪
♪ "To give us new
colours to see" ♪
♪ "Who knows where
it will lead us?" ♪
♪ "And that's why they need us" ♪
♪ So bring on the rebels ♪
♪ The ripples from pebbles ♪
♪ The painters, and
poets, and plays ♪
♪ And here's to the
fools who dream ♪
♪ Crazy as they may seem ♪
♪ Here's to the
hearts that break ♪
♪ Here's to the mess we make ♪
♪ I trace it all back to then ♪
♪ Her, and the snow,
and the Seine ♪
♪ Smiling trough it ♪
♪ She said she'd do it ♪
♪ Again ♪
When do you find out?
They said the next couple of days.
But I'm not expecting
to find anything out.
- You're gonna get it.
- I really might not.
- Yes, you are.
- I don't want to be disappointed.
I know.
I know. I know these things.
Where we are?
Griffith Park.
- Where are we?
- I know.
I don't know.
What do we do?
I don't think we
could do anything,
because when you get this...
- If I get this.
- When you get this...
You got to give it
everything you got.
Everything. It's your dream.
What are you gonna do?
I got to follow my
own plan. You know?
Stay here and get
my own thing going.
You'll be in Paris.
Good jazz there.
And you love jazz now.
Right?
Yes.
I guess we're just gonna
have to wait and see.
I'll always gonna love you.
I'll always gonna love you too.
Look at this view.
I've seen better.
- It's the worst.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
I've never been here
during the day.
Hi. Can I have two
iced coffees, please.
Right. Of course.
- On us.
- Oh, no thank you. I insist.
Sounds good. Harris
did a good job.
- It took him long enough.
- He always does. Signature time.
It's not doing too bad, Seb.
"Not too bad" is great.
- See you tonight.
Hi.
- How was your day?
- Good.
- How is she?
- She's great.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, come on.
Hi Myke.
I didn't think you were
gonna be home yet.
- Are you drawing?
- Yeah.
Can I help? You know
I love to draw.
Okay Chelsea, we're
gonna go. Are you good?
- We're good.
- You need anything?
Bye baby.
- Say "Bye bye, Mummy."
- Sleep well.
- Bye, Mummy.
- Have fun with Chelsea.
- Have fun. Bye, Mia.
- Bye. Thank you so much.
- Good night guys. Bye sweetie.
- Good night.
Oh boy.
What if we miss this? What
do you wanna tell Natalie?
Maybe we'll just see
her back in New York.
Okay.
- I do not miss this.
- It is bad.
Do you just wanna pull off
here and go to dinner?
- Sure yeah. Yeah.
- Yeah. Okay.
Do you wanna check it out?
Okay.
This place is pretty cool.
I love it.
- Cal Bennett on the sax.
- Yeah.
Javier Gonzalez on trumpet.
The lovely Nedra Wheeler on bass.
The one and only Clifton
"Fou Fou" Eddie on drums.
And a little too
good on the piano...
So good that he's gonna own
this place if I'm not careful,
Khirye Tyler, everybody.
Welcome to Seb's.
I just heard you play
and I wanted to...
You want to stay through another?
No, we should go.
Okay.
One, two... one, two, three, four.