♪ Say, it's only a paper moon ♪
♪ Sailing over a cardboard sea ♪
♪ But it wouldn't
be make-believe ♪
♪ If you believed in me ♪
♪ Yes, it's only a canvas sky ♪
♪ Hanging over a cotton tree ♪
♪ But it wouldn't
be make-believe ♪
♪ If you believed in me ♪
♪ Without your love ♪
♪ It's a honky-tonk parade ♪
♪ It's a melody played
in a penny arcade ♪
♪ It's a Barnum and Bailey world ♪
♪ Just as hollow as it can be ♪
♪ But it wouldn't
be make-believe ♪
♪ If you believed in me ♪
♪ Rock of ages, cleft for me ♪
♪ Let me hide myself in thee ♪
♪ Let the water and the blood ♪
♪ From thy wounded
side which flowed ♪
♪ Be of sin the double cure ♪
♪ Safe from wrath
and make me pure ♪
"Judge me, oh Lord,
"for I have lost
in mine integrity.
"I have trusted also in the Lord,
"therefore I shall not slide.
"Examine me, oh
Lord, and prove me.
"Try my reins and my heart,
"for Thy loving kindness
is before mine eyes
"and I have walked in Thy truth.
"I have not sat with evil persons.
"Neither will I go
in with dissemblers.
"I will wash mine hands
"in innocency.
"So will I compass
Thine altar, O Lord,
"that I may publish with
the voice of thanksgiving
"and tell of all Thy
wondrous works..."
Howdy.
Loggins' funeral.
Yes, madam.
- You ain't related, are ya?
- Related, madam?
We're looking for the child's kin.
Thought I saw some resemblance.
No kin, huh?
None we know of, except out
in Missouri some place.
- Missouri...
- Seems you got the child's jaw.
No, madam, just a friend of her
mama's, just passing through town.
If ever a child needed a friend.
"Will I bless the Lord.
"Amen."
Amen.
Amen, Essie Maye. I just
know your ass is still warm.
Would you like some water, Addie?
We'll get the child some water.
Bless you child, I just want to
pay my respects to your mama.
Well, I'm going to
have to be going.
It's a long way to St. Louis.
- St. Louis? You mean in Missouri?
- Yes, madam.
I sell the good book, madam.
Just moving through the country
with the Lord's good news.
Addie, child, don't you have your
Aunt Billie living in St. Joseph?
St. Joseph, Missouri.
It's her poor mother's sister.
- The child's only known relative.
- That so?
You're driving your
chariot to Missouri, sir.
You could deliver this
child to her kin folk.
Well, I wouldn't exactly
call it a chariot, Reverend.
I'll write the women
a letter tonight.
Hold it, hold it.
I have to think upon
this, you know...
I mean, I may have to make
a few stops along the way.
I never travelled
with no child before.
- But you're going that way.
- The child's got no place to go.
Well...
The eyes of the Lord... Expect
I have no choice, do I?
- Hallelujah.
- God works in mysterious ways.
Don't he now?
Come on, Addie. Better get
your things together.
This nice man's going to
take you to your aunt.
- How come you're taking me?
- Huh?
How come you're taking me?
Because I'm going that way, honey.
Although, I do want to make just
one stop before we leave town.
Got a little business
to take care of.
- You know my mama real good?
- Oh, pretty good.
You just stay out here
till I come for you.
Don't you say a word
unless I ask you to.
Mr Robertson?
- That's right.
- I'd like a minute of your time.
- Not buying today.
- Oh, not selling.
Just want you to meet somebody,
Mr Robertson. Only take a second.
So what?
- Tell him your name, honey.
- Addie.
- Addie what, honey?
- Addie Loggins.
You done real fine. I'll
be out in a minute.
Ain't she a sweet child?
No, she ain't a sweet child.
Well, maybe she don't seem sweet
right now. That's
because she's sad.
That is with her mama being dead,
what with your brother
getting drunk
and driving into
that tree like that.
What are you trying to
pull? Get out of here.
All right, I'm going, but let me
tell you where I'm going to go.
I don't care where
you're going to go.
I'm going to go see
Mr J.T. Faraday.
Now, you know who
Mr J.T. Faraday is?
He's one of the biggest
lawyers in Kansas.
And he don't favour
the man with the
money, he favours
the man without it.
And you know what's gonna
happen to your brother?
There's gonna be a lawsuit against
him. You know what happens then?
Everything's gonna be just tied
up in knots, just sitting there.
That's his banking money, his
house, everything he owns.
Including half this plant.
Now, don't think that poor child
ain't entitled, because she is.
I was thinking...
couple a thousand dollars
would be acceptable.
Couple of thou? I'll give you 200.
$200?
$200.
It's a deal.
There you are.
That'll be, $67.54.
You sure these tyres are new?
$67.54.
Now, we'll have you
to St. Jo in no time.
What time's the next
train to St. Joseph?
St. Joseph? Let's see here.
That'll be the 4:14.
Change trains in Kansas City, and
that'll put you into
St. Jo at 9:52am.
I want one child's price ticket.
That will be $11.45.
I want you to send this here
telegram to Mrs Billie Roy Griggs,
Cosmo Road, St. Joseph.
Train arriving 9:52am,
and bringing love,
affection and $20 cash.
Oh, make that $25 cash.
And sign it just Addie Loggins.
Ten words, that will
be 85 cents more.
That will be 12 and 30.
12 and 30, huh?
You better say in
that message there,
love, affection and $20 cash.
Love, affection and $20 cash.
Now, here's your ticket, and
here's $20 for your Aunt Billie.
Well, we got till 4:15.
I don't suppose you can wait
here by yourself, can you?
You hungry?
You want a Nehi and
a Coney Island?
- Ain't you gonna eat it?
- I ain't hungry.
Do you worry about
going on the train?
You'll like the train.
Don't worry about it.
Before you know it,
you'll be asleep in your
aunt's house, all your
troubles will be over.
- So eat your Coney Island.
- She don't even know me.
- She's going to know you now.
- She ain't gonna want me.
What are you making trouble for?
She ain't even seen you, yet.
She never even cared for my mama.
Nobody didn't care for your mama.
- And she was her sister.
- Your mama was a fine woman.
Everybody said she weren't.
Well everybody don't
know your mama, do they?
How good you know my mama?
Good enough to know
you can be real proud
of the happiness she
give to people.
Now, eat your Coney Island.
You meet my mama in a bar room?
Where would you get a
question like that?
I hear Miss Ollie
talking, the neighbour
lady. Says one of you's my pa.
Well, don't the world
have a wild imagination?
Eat your Coney Island.
You my pa?
Of course I ain't your pa.
I'll get you some relish.
A Coney Island ain't no
good without relish.
Look, I know how you feel. I lost
my ma, too. I even lost my pa.
I don't even know
where my sister is.
I wish I could tell you I'm your
pa, but it just ain't like that.
You met her in a bar room.
Just because a man
meets a woman in
a bar room don't
mean he's your pa.
Eat your Coney Island.
Well, then, if you ain't
my pa, I want my $200.
What's that?
I want my $200.
I heard you through the
door talking to that man.
It's my money you
got, and I want it.
Now, you... you just
hold on a second.
I want my money. You took my $200.
- Will you quiet down, you hear?
- I want my $200.
Hold on, now, just hold on.
Let me explain something to you.
It ain't as if you was my
pa. That'd be different.
Well, I ain't your pa, so just
get that out of your head.
I don't care what those
neighbour ladies said.
- I look like that.
- You don't look nothing like me.
You don't look any more like me
than you do that Coney Island.
Eat that damn thing, you hear?
- We got the same jaw.
- Lots of people got the same jaw.
- It's possible.
- No, no, it ain't possible.
- Then I want my $200.
- All right.
All right, maybe we
got the same jaw,
but same jaw don't
mean same blood.
I know a woman looks
like a bullfrog,
but that don't mean
she's its mother.
- You met my mum in a bar room.
- For God's sakes, child.
You think everybody gets met
in a bar room gets a baby?
It's possible.
Anything is possible, but
possible don't make it true.
Then I want my money.
Will you quiet down?
You know what the trouble is with
you? You got no appreciation.
All right.
Maybe I did get a
little money from
that man, and you're
entitled to that,
but I'm entitled to my share for
getting it for you, ain't I?
And where do you think
you'd be without me?
You think them folks would spend a
penny to send you east? No, sir.
But who got you a
ticket to St. Jo? Who
got you a Nehi and a Coney Island?
And threw in $20 extra,
not to mention 85 cents
for that telegram.
You wouldn't have had
any of that without me.
Now, I didn't have to take
you, but I took you, didn't I?
All right, I think
that's fair enough.
We're both a little better off.
You get to St. Jo, I get
myself a little better car.
Fair is fair.
Now, drink your Nehi, and
eat your Coney Island.
I want my $200.
I don't have your $200 no
more, and you know it.
If you don't give me
my $200, I'm going
to tell a policeman
how you got it,
and he'll make you give it
to me, because it's mine.
But I don't have it.
Then get it.
How we doing, Angel Pie?
We going to have a little dessert
when we finish up our hot dog?
I don't know.
What do you say, Daddy?
Why don't we get Precious a little
dessert if she eats her dog?
Her name ain't Precious.
I want my money back
on this here ticket,
and I want you to send
this here telegram.
Trip delayed, but I'm
coming real soon.
You just lie down in
the seat and be quiet.
Folks don't take to children
when they're doing business.
- Yes?
- Good afternoon, madam.
Is Mr Rudolf Morgan
at home, please?
Mr Morgan?
Yes, madam. My name
is Pray, Moses Pray,
Kansas Bible Company. He'll know.
Oh, I'm sorry. Mr
Morgan has passed on.
Oh, madam, I'm... I just...
I don't know what to say.
What was it you were
seeing him about?
Well, he ordered this
here bible from...
- Bible?
- Rudolph ordered a bible?
Yeah, he ordered this
here deluxe edition
with the lady's
name in the corner.
Lady's name?
Oh, I expect some special
gift for a family friend.
But under the circumstances,
I'll just give you back Mr
Morgan's dollar deposit,
and there won't be no
further obligation.
Madam, I just don't
know how to put into
words the sense of
sorrow that I feel.
What, what... what
name is in the corner?
I don't really know
what name Mr...
Morgan had put in
the corner, madam.
Let's see, now.
It's here somewhere. I've got it.
Here it is.
- Pearl...
- Pearl.
I'm Pearl.
Well, he must have got this
here good book for you, madam.
Yes. Yes, he bought it for me.
Of course, now, you're
not obliged to take it.
Of course I'll take it.
There's just one
thing. You see, I...
I told him that I could
sell him a cheaper bible,
but no, naturally he
wanted the best, the
best, of course, being
the deluxe edition
with the lady's name printed in
child-in-the-manger gold letters.
Oh, he would.
Bringing a balance due
of... $8.00? $8.00.
$8.00?
Well, that's, $8.00 minus
the dollar deposit,
making it $7.00.
I'll go get my purse.
Well, you're not obliged
to take it, now.
Of course I'm obliged.
He ordered the deluxe.
But cold or no cold, it's good
to be back in old Manhattan.
Well, tell me, Jack, you've been
in town now since Thursday.
What have you been
doing with yourself?
Oh, I've had a lot of fun, Don.
I saw some shows, went to
a couple of nightclubs,
and last night, I
was invited over to
Fred Allen's apartment for dinner.
Oh, Fred Allen?
Yeah, he and I are
pretty good friends now.
Well, I'm glad to hear it. Has
Fred got a nice apartment?
Oh, how could I tell, Don,
with all that laundry
hanging in the living room?
Ain't you gonna go to sleep?
Don't you want to hear Jack Benny?
No.
I don't want to sound catty...
You're too young to
smoke. You're going
to set this whole place on fire.
I now owe you $103.72.
Seventy-four.
♪ I always knew ♪
♪ Someday I'd accompany you ♪
♪ Along Flirtation Walk ♪
♪ A dream foretold ♪
♪ A story that you would unfold ♪
♪ That lives forever
and never grows old ♪
♪ I always felt ♪
♪ That your little
heart would melt ♪
♪ Along Flirtation Walk ♪
Frank D. Roosevelt said we're
all feeling a lot better.
He did, did he?
Made me feel good
when he said that.
Better than I've
felt in a long time.
Bet old Frank sure
does wish he was 21.
You don't like me, do you?
No, I don't like you.
Yes?
Afternoon, madam. I was wondering
if Mr Bates might be at home.
Mr Bates is dead. He
died over a week ago.
Oh, you mean he
passed over, madam?
Why, I was just talking to him
not less than a month ago.
- What was it you wanted?
- Well...
My name is Pray,
Kansas Bible Company.
I'm just here to deliver this
bible that Mr Bates ordered.
Bible?
Who is it? What's the trouble?
Something about Benjamin
buying a bible.
Bible? What kind of bible?
He said he talked to Benjamin,
less than a month ago.
Well, I'm not exactly
sure of the dates, madam.
Well, I don't see how.
Benjamin didn't go
nowhere near that shop
for more than a month
before he died.
Well, I may be a little
mixed up on the dates.
What company you say you're from?
The Kansas Bible
Company, out of Wichita.
Kansas Bible Company?
I ain't never heard of
no Kansas Bible Company.
Daddy...
Can't we go now? I want to get
to church and pray for Mama.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Sure we can, honey.
Daddy was just fixing to leave.
This here is my little girl.
It's just the two of us now.
- My Mama's gone to the Lord.
- Oh, so has poor Mr Bates, honey.
I'll just, give you back
his dollar deposit,
and you let us know if
there's anything we can do.
Hold on, there. Wait
one damn minute.
He actually done
ordered a bible, huh?
He sure did. Here
it is, right here
in gold for somebody
named "Marie".
That's her. She's Marie.
Oh, she sure did
mean a lot to him.
He especially had me get
the deluxe edition.
- How much to keep this here book?
- Oh, well, that one is the...
It's the $12 one, Daddy.
- $12?
Yeah, well, honey, we have to have
a little goodness in our hearts,
I mean, considering
the circumstances.
Never mind the circumstances.
And if it'll make that
woman happy, I'll take it.
You owe me $85.74.
I mean, we're going to
Washington on the QT.
Molly, she says we
can't go on the QT,
we've got to take
the Pennsylvania.
Hey, I'd better get going.
Hey, Molly, where's my
suitcase? Do you know?
I'm sure I don't know, McGee.
You had it last night.
Oh, I know where it is. It's
right here in the hall...
He's going to open the closet.
Now he's going to say how he's got
to straighten the closet out.
Got to straighten out that
closet one of these days.
How'd you like to do a
little business with me?
You mean instead
of paying me back?
Now, don't get nervous.
I'll pay you back.
I'm just saying, while
we're heading east,
how'd you like to do a little
business together, that's all?
Well, you're looking
at me like I'm
out to cheat you or something.
I am offering you a business
proposition. Take it or leave it.
And turn off that
radio. You're like
to drive us all deaf
with that radio.
In an average way, of course.
Ok, I want you to
remember one thing:
I decide on the price.
Maybe you don't know
French, but there's
something in this world
called "finesse".
$12. I never sold
no bible for $12.
That man was a law officer. You
could've had me put me in jail.
We got it, didn't we?
I don't care if we got it. Don't
you go making the decisions.
I make the decisions.
All you got to
do is look like a
pretty little girl.
You ain't got something like a
ribbon in that cigar box, do you?
I got my mum's kimono in my
suitcase, Chinamen with umbrellas.
That ain't quite
what I had in mind.
You look real nice in that ribbon.
First off, I didn't know
was she a boy or a girl?
I'm a girl.
Well, it makes all the difference.
Ain't she got a sweet
little face, somehow.
Well, seeing how I
just got paid today,
we'll take a ribbon
in each colour.
How much that going
to set me back?
Well, that'll be 15 cents.
Bought my grandchildren ribbons
just like this last holiday time.
Grandchildren? I don't believe it.
You break a five?
Well, you can believe
it, all right.
I'm just as old as I look.
Well, now, here you be.
That's one, two,
three, four, five.
This old wallet of mine is
about to bust its sides.
I'll give you five ones back,
you give me that $5 bill.
How many grandchildren
you got altogether?
Well, I got two little
granddaughters,
a nine-year-old, a ten-year-old,
two grandsons near 16,
and I got a grandson 35 years old.
Come on, you're pulling my leg.
Why don't you just
give me a $10 bill?
Here's the $5, and
five ones, there.
That way I won't be so quick
to see it break apart.
- Six children, huh? My, my, my...
- I've got a daughter, 51.
Oh, now, I don't mean to
be handing you no line,
but that's just pretty hard to
believe you got a
51-year-old child.
You can believe it, all right.
Well, I'm afraid I'd have to see
it to believe it. Much obliged.
- See you again.
- You all come back.
That just don't seem
quite right... somehow.
Yes?
I'm looking for Mr Stanley, madam.
Mr Stanley's dead.
Oh, well, I'm looking for Mr
Warren M. Stanley, madam.
Warren's passed on, sir.
Oh, that's hard to believe.
I was just talking to Warren
not more than two weeks back.
He ordered this
here bible from me.
Warren spent money on a bible?
Yes, madam, with the name
Elvira in the corner.
Why would Warren spend
money on a bible?
He took fast to the idea, madam.
Only thing is, he left
a balance due of,
well, let's see, not counting
the dollar deposit...
Daddy, this one's
already paid for.
Mr Stanley paid for the whole
thing, don't you remember?
Afternoon, madam. Mr Huff at home?
Mr Huff passed away,
young man, a week ago.
Oh, gee, I'm sorry.
I was just talking
to Mr Huff not more
than a month ago.
What was it you wanted?
Oh, well, my name is Pray,
Kansas Bible Company.
Mr Huff ordered this bible as a
gift for someone named Edna.
Oh, that's my name.
You don't have to take
it if you don't want to.
I'll just give you back Amos's
dollar deposit and then...
Of course I want to keep it.
He bought me a bible.
Yes, madam. Now, I told Amos I
could sell him a cheaper one,
but no, naturally,
he wanted the best,
the best, of course,
being the deluxe edition
with the name printed in
child-in-the-manger gold letters,
- bringing up a balance due of...
- of $24.
$24. I'll get my purse.
What's your name, honey?
- Addie.
- Addie. What a sweet little name.
Addie Pray, madam.
Well, Addie Pray, I'm
going to give you $24,
and an extra $5 for
just coming to my door.
- Praise the Lord.
♪ Keep your sunny side up, up ♪
♪ Hide the side that gets blue ♪
- Moze, let's give him some money.
- No.
Just a little bit. We got $305.16.
Whole another business
giving it away.
It's bad enough you
give away bibles.
But they're poorly.
The whole country's poorly,
I told you before.
But Frank D. Roosevelt says we
got to look out for one another.
I don't care about
Frank D. Roosevelt.
- But he says it.
- That so?
Why don't you ask Frank
D. Roosevelt what
he thinks about taking
care of himself?
You think he don't eat
off silver trays?
He could eat off
table tops like the
rest of us, but he
don't. You know why?
Because that would
make him look common.
And besides, Frank
D. Roosevelt ain't
running this thing,
I'm running it.
So don't you make
up no rules about
what we're going to give away.
It's my money too, you
know. $200 belong to me,
- and don't you forget that.
- You want it?
Well, just put my
share in my pocket,
and I'll take you
to a train station.
How do you like that?
Get the map. Find out where
the nearest depot is.
Nothing but trouble, anyway.
First you charge too much,
then you want to give it away.
- Where are we now?
- We just left Plainville.
$12 for a bible,
then it's up to $24.
If I stay with you, I'll spend
the rest of my life in jail.
There's a depot in Lincoln.
You can take me to Lincoln.
You bet I will.
- Where's Lincoln?
- Clear over there.
Oh, boy, you think I'm going
to take you clear over there
just to get you to some depot?
Then keep going east. We'll
hit one in Sylvan Grove.
- Where's Sylvan Grove?
- Right here.
Well, that'll take us
down through Lucas.
We got to go through something
to get to Sylvan Grove.
I'm not complaining.
I'm just saying
that'll take you through Lucas.
You got to go through Paradox and
Waldo and Lorraine and Lucas
if you want to get
to Sylvan Grove.
Those are pretty
good towns in there.
We could do some
business in there.
Well, it won't matter much. We're
near out of bibles anyway.
What do you mean, we're
out of bibles? Why
didn't you tell me
we're out of bibles?
You look in the box
too, don't you?
Well, you've got an
excuse for everything.
Because you blame
me for everything.
If we were running out of bibles,
you should have told me.
We're running out of bibles.
Well, then we got to get new ones.
Then let's get new ones.
We can pick some up in Great Bend.
Great Bend's the other way.
Well, we gotta have
bibles, don't we?
Let's see, now, we
can veer down to
Lucas, and we'll
veer over to Wilson.
Veer off to Lorraine and Bushton.
And we could veer
off to Hoisington.
We'll just have to keep
on veering, that's all.
I'm getting hungry.
You getting hungry?
Huh.
♪ Just one more chance ♪
♪ To prove it's you
alone I care for ♪
♪ Each night I say a
little prayer for ♪
You sweet thing.
Don't you tell me that. Ooh.
Sometimes I just don't know,
with all the old doodly-doo.
Doodly-doo, doodly-doo.
Ok, now, you go on back, now.
I'll see you another time.
- Don't send me back.
- Oh, you got to go on back.
I'll see you another
time, I promise.
I want to go in your place.
No, no.
You trying to keep
secrets from me?
You got diamonds and
rubies in there?
Go on, go on.
Oh, Fido... Night-night, old Fido.
- Woof-woof.
Woof-woof.
♪ Still I'm holding on awhile ♪
♪ You'll give me
just one more word ♪
There it is.
- Much obliged.
- Thank you, sir.
All right, boy, you're next.
I ain't a boy.
- Aw, don't let it bother you.
- It ain't funny.
No reason to get that sore.
He called me a boy, didn't he?
He just got mixed up, that's all.
He did not. He looked
me straight in the eye.
Yeah, well, I'm looking
you straight in
the eye, and I think
you're beautiful.
- Oh, you're just saying that.
- Would I make that up?
You're as beautiful
as your mama, and she
put all the flowers in
the world to shame.
You know, they wouldn't
even let her come
to Holland for fear
she'd droop the tulips,
and you got all the good
looks she ever had.
Then how come that
man called me a boy?
I don't know, maybe it's...
Maybe it's because of what
you got on, or something.
What's wrong with what I got on?
Oh, nothing wrong with it, just...
don't exactly make
you look feminine.
Maybe it wouldn't be a bad idea
we get you fixed up a little bit,
get you a new dress, a fancy
new hat, or something.
Come to think of it, it wouldn't
exactly hurt business, either.
You really think I'm
as pretty as my mama?
Of course I do.
How much money we got in the box?
$405.16.
Give me a $20.
- What for?
- Give me a $20.
- Come on.
- Where are we going?
We're going to get us
some fancy new outfits
with this money you got
from your Aunt Helen.
- I don't have no Aunt Helen.
- Oh, sure you do, honey.
Come on, let me explain it to you.
Yes, sir?
I'd like an Ipana toothpaste
and a pack of Sen-Sen.
- Twenty and five.
- Twenty-five.
- Yes, sir.
- Here you go.
75 makes one,
four makes five, and 15 makes 20.
Thank you very much.
I don't need a bag.
- Thank you very much.
- Thank you. Bye now.
Hello. How much is this?
That'll be 35 cents.
65 cents makes a dollar.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Yes?
May I have a bottle of
purple toilet water, please?
That'll be 25 cents.
There you go.
Lady, you made a mistake.
Huh? I give you $4.75.
But I gave you a $20 bill.
You give me a $5.
No, madam, it was a $20 bill.
You give me a $5, and
I give you $4.75.
It was a $20 bill.
Got no $20s in with no $5s.
What's all the turmoil?
What's going on here?
This little girl give me a $5
bill, and I give her change.
I gave her a $20
bill, I know I did.
It was a birthday present from
my Aunt Helen in Wichita,
and she wrote "Happy Birthday,
Addie" on the end of it.
You just go look and see.
That's it right there.
That's my $20 bill I got from
my Aunt Helen in Wichita.
- Give the child her $20 bill.
- I'm giving it.
Give the child her $20
bill, Miss Brownwell.
Yes, sir.
- And give her a piece of candy.
- Yes, sir.
And pay attention to
things, Miss Brownwell.
Yes, sir.
Come on in, get your cotton candy.
Sweetheart, Cotton Candy.
Five cents.
Do you have change for this five?
There you are, little girl.
Cotton candy, get
your cotton candy.
Mister, this purse is sure full.
If you give me the five back,
I'll give you five ones.
Cotton candy, get your
cotton candy right here.
Mister, if you got
a ten dollar bill
I'll give you the five back
with the five ones you have.
Would you give me a
ten dollar bill?
There, now don't bother me
any more, you understand?
Cotton candy.
Step up and get your cotton candy.
Come and get it.
Get your tickets. Only
one fourth of a dollar.
The show goes on in five minutes.
Six unusual little ladies
unveiling the secrets of passion.
Found only a few years back
in the actual Egyptian
tomb of Queen Nefereti.
And featuring the luscious
Miss Trixie Delight.
- I had my photo took, Moze.
- You did, huh? Ain't that fine.
Moze, can you come have
your photo took with me?
- Can't right now, sweetheart.
- Only take a minute.
Not now, you hear me?
But it's almost down here tonight.
- It wouldn't be here after...
- I can't help that.
Now excuse me, you understand?
How many times you
going to see it?
As many times as I like,
that's how many times.
You seen it half a dozen times.
And I might see it
a half dozen more.
Now why don't you go
play bingo or something?
I don't want to play bingo.
Well, then why don't you go write
another love note
to St. Roosevelt?
Maybe I will.
And stop standing
around here checking
on me. You don't have to worry.
I ain't about to leave
some poor little
child stranded in the
middle of nowhere.
I got scruples, too, you know. You
know what that is, "scruples?"
No, I don't know what it is,
but if you got them, I sure bet
they belong to somebody else.
And his name ain't
Frank, it's Franklin.
Hey there, my little turtle-dee.
I wondered where you got to.
Where's your pa?
- Is my picture ready?
- Sure, it's...
Excuse me, folks, come right back.
Sit back in the moon there,
I'll be right with you.
Let's see.
Here it is, here.
Hey, now, I thought you were gonna
sit in the moon with your pa.
He ain't my pa.
Hi, folks. Get ready.
Smile. Hold it.
Hold it.
Beautiful.
I don't want you smoking
in the car tomorrow.
What?
I didn't say nothing. I'm
just listening to you.
Well, there are going to be a
couple extra people
riding with us,
and this particular person
don't like cigarette smoke.
- What extra person?
- What?
I said "what extra person?"
A lady and her maid. I'm
giving them a ride to Topeka.
I didn't know we was
going to Topeka.
Well, that's because you
don't know everything.
What's the lady's name?
Miss Delight. Miss Trixie Delight.
She's a real lady. She
comes from a good family.
I'm just giving her
a ride, that's all.
Well, that's what
you're always talking
about, ain't it? Helping
other people out.
Now don't you drop
nothing, Imogene.
You take care of those
breakables, understand?
Yes, Miss Trixie.
Morning. Car is right over here.
You better ride in the
back-seat a while.
And then I danced in Tuscaloosa.
And the mayor was
there, and he just
said the nicest things about me.
The newspaper ran a
whole big photo on me.
I got a scrap book telling stories
on me from towns all over.
Tell him about the time that man
tried to crack your head open
with the bottle, Miss Trixie.
Why, Imogene, you silly old
thing. You know that's not true.
That old country boy
wasn't going to
hit me over the head
with no bottle.
He was just horsing around.
Ask me real nice, maybe I'll
tell you about that sometime.
Well, tell him about the time you
almost got thrown in
jail, Miss Trixie.
I just don't understand it, Daddy,
but this little baby has to
go winky-tinky all the time.
Well, don't you worry
none. We'll just
plan on stopping here for dinner.
But we just stopped for her
to winky-tink at lunch.
That's right, and now we're
stopping for dinner.
- Come on.
- I ain't hungry.
- Want one?
- Ok.
- How old are you?
- I don't know, 15. Why?
Just asking, that's all.
- Where are you from?
- Nowhere.
Well, you got to
be from somewhere.
Down by Troy, I guess.
How long have you worked for her?
Ain't kept count.
A year, maybe. How old you be?
Nine.
She really do all that dancing?
Well, if you want to
call it "dancing".
All she do is wag her hips and
shake her old behind a little.
How come she'd leave
that job back there?
Because the boss man tried to
make her put out for his friends.
And she don't believe in
putting out for free.
She put out much?
Just like a gum machine.
You drop something in and
she'll put something out.
How much she charge?
Most she can get.
But she always asks for $5.00.
She ain't putting out
for your pa, though.
Says she's going to
wait and get all
she can before she
put out for him.
He tell her he was my pa?
Well, not exactly.
I heard him mumbling
something like
he didn't want to talk about it.
- Ain't he?
- I'm with him, ain't I?
And how do you come
to be with her?
Because she promised to
give me $4.00 every week.
She ain't gave me nothing.
Except a nickel or
dime, sometimes.
- Why don't you quit?
- Quit?
How am I going to quit?
And what if I do quit?
Ain't got no money
to get home to Mum.
And what if I do get home?
They got hard times as it is.
My mama say, "You go
work for a white lady,
"she'll take good care of you."
- You want to know what I think?
- Yeah.
You know the little white speck
on top of chicken doo-doo?
Yeah.
Well, that's the kind of white
I think Miss Trixie is.
She's just like that little white
speck on top of old chicken shit.
Oh, I just love it, love it,
love it. All this white.
It is absolutely the
proper thing for
my particular kind of appearance.
You know, it wouldn't be bad for
you to have a new dress, too.
The right kind of dress makes
all the difference in the face.
Especially since you got the
right kind of bone structure.
Oh...
Oh, my, oh, my.
Daddy, but wouldn't you
look handsome sitting
behind the wheel of
a thing like that?
Course, you know, everything
is in the bone structure.
You know, a person
can tell his whole
life on what his
bone structure is.
I tried pushing her out a
window once in Little Rock.
Oh...
Oh, I think there's
bugs all over the...
I just hope there's no
snakes around here.
You know, I think
we ought to go now.
Thank you so much.
Now hurry... oh.
Come on, hurry up. Get those
things in there, now.
Don't break anything, either.
Let's go.
Hurry up, doctor, this baby's
got to go winky-tinky.
Don't worry.
Hey.
Come on, we're ready.
- Come on, now.
- I ain't ready.
Well, you don't
look real busy with
nothing, so you just come on down.
I ain't coming.
- Now you listen here, child.
- No, I won't listen here.
What the heck's up with you, then?
I want to sit in front.
And how come we ain't
working no more?
Because we're on
vacation, that's why.
And Miss Delight and
me are sitting in
front because we
are two grown-ups,
and that's where grown-ups
do the sitting.
And little children
do not tell grown-ups
what to do with their
lives, you understand that?
Well, she ain't my
grown-up, and I ain't
planning no more to
sit in the back.
Not for no cow.
Will you keep your voice down?
And Miss Delight ain't no
cow. She's a proper woman.
She has a high school diploma,
and right now she's gotta
go to the bathroom,
so you just get on
down to the car.
She always has to
go to the bathroom.
She must have a bladder
the size of a peanut.
Well, I ain't getting back in that
car. Not till she gets out of it.
Hey, what's up, kiddo? Daddy
says you're wearing a sad face.
Ain't good to have a sad face.
Hey, how would you
like a colouring
book? Would you like that?
You like Mickey the Mouse?
Oh, son of a bitch.
Ooh... oh.
Now come on down to the car
and let's all be friends.
You see me smile? Come on, let's
see you smile like Aunt Trixie.
Now, come on.
Come on down to the car
with mademoiselle.
Kiddo, I understand how you feel.
Well, you don't have to worry.
One of these days, you're going to
be just as pretty as mademoiselle,
maybe prettier.
You already got bone structure.
When I was your age, I didn't
have no bone structure.
Took me years to get
bone structure.
And don't think bone
structure's not important.
Nobody started to call me
mademoiselle till I was 17
and getting a little
bone structure.
When I was your age, I was
skinnier than a pole.
I never thought I'd
have nothing up here.
You're going to have
them up there, too.
Look, I'll tell you what. Want me
to show you how to use cosmetics?
Look, I'll let you put
on my earrings. You
can see how pretty
you're going to be.
And I'll show you how
to make up your eyes.
And your lips.
And I'll see to it you get
a little bra or something.
But right now you're gonna
pick your little ass up,
you're gonna drop
it in the back-seat
and you're gonna cut out the crap,
you understand?
You're going to
ruin it, ain't you?
Look, I don't want
to wipe you out,
and I don't want you
wiping me out, you know?
So, I'm going to
level with you, ok?
Now, you see, with me, it's
just a matter of time.
I don't know why,
but somehow I just
don't manage to hold on real long.
So, if you wait it out a little,
it'll be over, you know?
I mean, even if I want a fella,
somehow or other I manage
to get it screwed up.
Maybe I'll get a new pair of
shoes, nice dress, a few laughs.
Times are hard.
Now, if you fool around
on the hill up here,
then you don't get nothing,
I don't get nothing,
he don't get nothing.
So how about it, honey?
Just for a little while,
let old Trixie sit up
front with her big tits.
Hey, come on.
We're coming, baby doll.
And if you don't find me
some old gas station soon,
this little old snowflake's
going to wet her pantaloons.
Oh, my, I almost fell down.
Yoo-hoo. Look what we got.
Ain't she the sweetest
little thing,
and don't he look like a
prince on that wheel?
Now, come on, Imogene. Now,
get everything in here.
We got more room than the
whole state of Kansas.
And listen to the horn.
Blow the horn, Daddy.
Oh, go ahead.
Do it again.
Sticks his tongue into the water,
and there's an alligator
in the river...
Very funny.
This girl's sitting
on the trolley,
and she reaches in her bag,
and she takes out this magazine,
and she starts to read it.
Well, she ain't read more
than a couple of pages.
And real slow and careful now,
she takes her stockings down
and takes off her shoes.
Now, she turns the stockings wrong
side out, and she
puts them back on.
She puts her shoes back on.
Well, all the passengers
are watching.
They wonder what's going on.
This old guy, he
leans over to her,
and he asks her, he
says, "What's...?
"I saw you indulge in a strange
procedure, madam.
What were you doing?"
And she said, "Well, I was reading
this here magazine, you know?
"And I found it to be
such hot stuff that I...
"Well, I felt compelled to
turn the hose on myself."
Oh, turn the hose on.
When you said that, I...
They wouldn't have a room with
a canopy bed, would they?
You wouldn't have a room with
a canopy bed, would you?
No. But I got one
with a fireplace.
Oh, I'd like that one, Daddy.
It ain't no canopy bed,
but it sure do open up a whole
new can of peas, don't it?
Can of peas.
- Ain't that cute?
- Huh? How's that?
Come on, Imogene. Now, help
the boy with these things.
Give them 234, 235, and 236.
They're working on the
elevator right now,
and it's the first flight
up, if you don't mind.
- It's all right. Thank you.
- Thank you.
"Can of peas". Did you hear that?
Yeah, what was that all about?
Well, you know,
Canopy... can of pea...
They rhyme, you know?
- Oh, I see. Can of peas, canopy.
- Yeah.
I get it now.
I knew you'd get it if
I explained it to you.
♪ Picture Henry Ford
without a car ♪
♪ Picture heaven's
firmament without a star ♪
♪ Picture Grigsby Chrysler
without a fiddle ♪
♪ Picture poor Philadelphia
without a Biddle ♪
♪ Picture Central Park
without a sailor ♪
♪ Picture Mr Lord
minus his detailer ♪
♪ Mix 'em all together,
and what have you got? ♪
♪ Just a picture of
me without you ♪
Now there's a rip in the
seam of that dress, Imogene.
You get it sewed
up good, you hear?
- And wash these hose.
- Yes, Miss Trixie.
- Got my bath ready?
Hope the water's not too hot.
You've been making that water
awful hot lately, Imogene.
I knows you like it
hot, Miss Trixie.
Well, not that hot.
Now, you go on, finish
up all these things
and come back in an
hour and dry me off.
Yes, Miss Trixie.
What you doing up there?
I got us an idea. Come on.
What kind of idea?
Come on in here,
and I'll tell you.
Go on.
Imogene, what do you suppose
Miss Trixie would do
if somebody offered
her $25 to put out?
Oh-wee, you crazy.
For that much money, that woman
would drop her pants down
- in the middle of the road.
- That's what I figured.
What you got in mind?
You want to get away from
Miss Trixie, don't you?
Well, if you help
me, I'll give you
enough money to get
home to your mama.
- How much money?
- $30.
- When do we start?
- Tomorrow morning.
Miss Trixie,
you know that man down at the
desk who checked us in yesterday?
Yeah, I know him. What about him?
Well, he tell me, he'd pay $25
just to have a good time with you.
What?
Well, that little two-bit
bum nerve of that guy.
$25. I bet that little John
don't make that much in a week.
Where would he get 25 bucks?
I don't know. All I know
is what he told me.
25 bucks, huh?
Sure have to see the
money to believe it.
Here you go. You come back
and see us again real soon.
I'll have a Juicy
Fruit gum, please.
Here you go, my little beauty.
Want I should chew it for you?
Say, you know that red-headed lady
that comes down here named
Miss Trixie Delight?
Well, she thinks you're real cute.
Oh, yeah? Says you and who else?
No, honest. She says you're
better looking than Dick Powell.
She did? Well, the lady's
got good taste, don't she?
Well, just thought
you'd like to know.
Hey, just a minute.
Give these here to
the lady, and tell
her they're with
Floyd's compliments.
Oh. She'll like that.
Maybe you should write her a note.
- Yeah. What kind of a note?
- Oh, I don't know.
I thought men always wrote ladies
notes when they
send them presents.
Maybe you should ask
her for a date.
That will sure tickle her.
Yeah. Maybe I ought to.
Say, she's not married up or
anything like that, is she?
Of course not. She don't even
have a regular boyfriend.
That man who come in here
yesterday with her is my daddy.
He's her manager. She's a dancer.
A dancer?
You know, I figured she
was something like that.
Whereabouts she dance?
Oh, lots of big
places. She's a star.
Well, how about that.
Why don't you print it?
She like men who prints.
Print it, huh?
"Some sweets for
the sweet. Ha, ha.
"Some girls say I'm a pretty
smooth dancer myself.
"How about trying
me out sometime?"
You sure this is going to work?
I don't know, but we're sure
going to give it a try.
Throw this in the
drawer, will you?
And keep your fingers crossed.
- Who is it?
- It's me, Addie.
Oh. What do you want?
I got a message from Moze.
He asked me to tell you he had to
run over to Hainesville today.
He won't be back until suppertime.
I think he had to get
something fixed on his car.
- He'll be gone all day.
- Oh.
Well... ok.
Ok.
- Howdy.
- What you having?
- Waffles.
I already ate. I had waffles, too.
They sure are good, ain't they?
They ain't bad for waffles.
Mr Moze, Miss Trixie
don't feel so good.
She say she's going
to stay in bed today.
She say she'll see you
around suppertime.
She sick? Sick in bed?
I better go up there.
Oh, she ain't real sick. Ain't
nothing to worry about.
She's just having her lady's time.
Oh.
Well, you tell her I'll
see her this evening.
Well, just wanted to
say good morning.
I think I'll go upstairs
and polish my shoes.
- Somebody at the door, Imogene.
- Yes, Miss Trixie.
It's something for
you, Miss Trixie.
- Oh, what is it?
- It was outside the door.
What is that?
Imogene, let all that go now.
You can run along. I'll
call you when I need you.
Yes, Miss Trixie.
Well, hello, cupid.
Miss Trixie wants to see you. She
says it's real
important. Room 235.
Oh, she does, does she? When?
- Right now.
- Well, I can't get off right now.
But she says it's real important.
Well, you tell her
I'll come up later
tonight... when the moon is full.
But you can't come tonight.
She won't even be
here after tonight.
Matter of fact, she won't
even be here after today.
She won't, huh? Well...
You won't be sorry.
I guess I could go up
for a few minutes.
What's that room number again?
Room 235. She's waiting for ya.
Ok. You tell her I'm on
my way up, sweetheart.
He's coming. He's coming.
- Who is it?
- Sheik of Araby.
Well, then, don't you look pretty?
Well, come on in, honey.
Come on.
You don't give a girl much time.
Oh, I manage to get around.
Say, you're not one
of these fellows
goes around babbling,
are you, honey?
What do you mean?
Well, you know, now most
of the time I don't mind,
but it's important to me right
now not to get talked about.
Hey, now do I look like
that kind of fellow?
Say... oh, say you are a
wild one, aren't you?
Hold it, hold it. Now, wait a
minute, you're going to tear it.
Now, now, just let me slip it off.
Hey, there.
Well, now, ain't you a show dog?
Ooh... ooh.
I'm going.
The key... Give me the key.
Mr Moze's going to
kill that man. He's
going to kill them
both, I just knows it.
- Wait for me here.
- Ok.
- Moze.
- What's the trouble?
Better go up to Trixie's
room right away.
Why? What? She sick?
No, she's not sick. Just
do what I tell you.
And take the elevator.
Don't knock. Use the key.
Your daddy going to kill
that man, I reckon.
I expect he cut him up pretty bad.
Moze wouldn't do a
thing like that.
Well, down home, when a
man come in from work,
and hear a man inside house
in bed with his wife,
he just walk around
to the woodpile
and get his double-blade
axe, and go
inside, chop 'em both
up to little pieces.
Folks say he cut 'em up
just like kindling wood.
Get your things,
Addie. We're leaving.
- Now?
- Right this minute.
I swan, I don't know why that
girl did such a thing to me.
I'd have done almost
anything for that girl.
Just ain't fair.
I reckon she's been...
carrying on a long time.
- From the start.
- You mean, there were other men?
Lots of 'em.
Well, dadblammit, why
didn't you tell me?
I just knew you
wouldn't believe me.
I want you to promise
me just one thing.
What, Moze?
When you grow up, don't
you be the kind of woman
who goes around deceiving men.
- Promise me that.
- I promise, Moze.
♪ Oh, my love, let's take a walk ♪
♪ Just a little ways away ♪
♪ While we walk
along, we'll talk ♪
♪ Talk about our wedding day ♪
♪ Only say that you'll be mine ♪
♪ And in our home,
we'll happy be ♪
♪ Down beside where
the waters flow ♪
♪ Down on the banks ♪
Moze?
Moze, pay attention.
- What's the trouble?
- I seen something peculiar.
- What's that?
- That man in there.
- What man?
- Standing by the door.
What's peculiar about him?
He's got a roll of money could
choke us both to death.
Well, I'm not up to
anything right now.
But he's got a black
book for making
notes in, and all that money,
and he keeps going outside and
then coming back in again.
- Bootlegger.
- Bootlegger?
No question about it.
You think we might do
some business with him?
Maybe drop a wad or something?
We ain't done nothing in two
months, ever since Trixie.
And we only have $212 left.
Better ways of doing
business with bootleggers.
What ways?
Oh, heaps of ways.
Look, he's going out again.
Follow him.
- Should I, Moze?
- I told you, didn't I?
Follow him. Find
out where he goes.
♪ Thinking, "Lord, what
a deed I have done." ♪
♪ Killed the girl I
loved, you see ♪
♪ Because she would not marry me ♪
♪ Only say that you'll be mine ♪
♪ And in our home,
we'll happy be ♪
♪ Down beside where
the waters flow ♪
♪ Down on the banks of the Ohio ♪
Thank you.
♪ Big brown eyes and curly hair ♪
What'd you find out?
He's got a lot of bottles he keeps
in some kind of bin out back.
How big's the bin?
About as big as our
car trunk, maybe.
What you plan to do?
Find out where he keeps his goods.
Well, there was a little shack out
there, too, but he
didn't go in it.
Well, honey... how
about a little walk
before Daddy puts you in the bed?
Oh, goody.
Our friend's name is Jess Hardin.
He's a bootlegger, all right.
Wholesales pretty near
everybody in the county.
His brother's some sort
of a big shot, too,
but the girl couldn't
tell me about him.
Some Romeo walked up, and I had
to beat it. Now, where is it?
- Right over there.
- Ok, come on.
Ok, now, you watch the hotel.
You see anybody coming, you cough
real low. I'm going inside.
- It may be locked.
- Shucks, honey.
Folks in the country never lock
anything. Don't you know that?
♪ Come sit by my side,
little darling ♪
♪ Come lay your cool
hand on my brow ♪
♪ Promise me that you will never ♪
♪ Be nobody's darling but mine ♪
Your name Hardin?
That's right.
Conrad's the name.
Jack said I ought to look you up.
Jack who?
Oh, just Jack's good
enough, I reckon.
Don't know no Jack.
Well, maybe you ought
to get acquainted.
He's running the biggest
wholesale business in the state.
- You selling?
- That's right.
Ain't interested in no shiney.
I ain't selling no shiney, I
only deal in bonded goods.
- What kind?
- All kinds.
I can let you have a pretty good
deal on some Three Feathers.
How much?
Well, it depends. You take 20
cases, I'll let 'em
go for $25 per.
- That's too much.
- Ain't too much.
You can't get it that cheap
where they sell it legal.
Ain't legal here.
That's all the more reason
you're getting a bargain.
Give you just $20.
Can't do it. Price is
set down in Wichita.
How long before delivery?
Oh... how's early in the morning?
You got it in the county?
That's right.
♪ My mother is dead
and in heaven ♪
Where do I pick it up?
♪ My daddy ♪
- That'll do it.
- Did you leave some?
Plenty. He'll never miss it.
Moze?
Moze, we better get.
- Here.
- It's all filled up, I told you.
Them's for me.
Get going.
Hurry.
Get up there.
Now hold on.
And make sure nothing spills off.
Well, you'd better go slow.
And hurry.
Easy.
Well, I got to turn
corners, don't I?
Moze, ain't he going
to miss his whisky?
Oh, maybe in about a week,
but by the time he's figured
it out, we'll be in Missouri
and he can't do nothing
once we're in Missouri.
Come on.
Where is it?
Scoot over.
- How much you get?
- $625.
$625, and he bought
his own whisky.
That's $625 plus the
$212 we already got.
And if we drop some wallets
and do some 20s, we'll...
- What's that?
- Where?
Behind us.
I don't see nothing.
- There's something back there.
- Nothing but pitch black.
I thought I seen
something flicker.
Nothing there.
- You put the money in the box?
- Huh.
I'll be glad to get out of
this town, I'll tell you that.
There it is again.
Dadblammit.
Something flickered, sure as hell.
Nothing behind us, Moze.
- Oh.
- I told ya.
- Who could it be?
- Christ.
- Don't stop, keep going.
- I can't keep going.
The damn car's in front of me.
Everything's going
to be all right.
You just let me do the talking.
You playing games with us, Mister?
Oh, I didn't know
who was back there.
It's a risky thing to do. Might
get your tyres shot off.
Where you heading?
Me and my little girl
are going to Saint Jo.
- Oh. Live there?
- Nearby.
What's your business?
Livestock, mostly... mules
and horses. Some cattle.
That's funny. I heard
you was a bootlegger.
Oh, no, sir, not me, friend.
Must be some mistake.
Maybe... Maybe not.
The way I hear it...
you just had a transaction
by the old barn.
Where'd you hear a
thing like that?
Oh, a... friend of the family.
No, I'm sorry, I...
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I'm talking about bootlegging.
I'm talking about $625.
Now, just where might that be?
I don't have no $625. I don't
know what you're talking about.
I don't even know where
the old barn is.
Well...
I reckon we'll just
have to explain
a little more
thoroughly, won't we?
Come on, Beau, you take a
ride with these nice people.
- Love to.
- We're all going back to town.
Damn.
Just when you think
you got it made...
just ain't made, is it?
You pretty good at
this little thing?
Not too good.
Not too good, huh?
Old bootlegger's sitting there
with his own little game,
and he ain't even
good at his own game.
Yes, sir, that is some good joke.
I found these on the front seat.
Wasn't any money in the car. Went
all through it, inside and out.
Livestock business, huh?
That whisky's for a friend.
Hold out your hands.
Huh?
I said, hold out your
hands. You heard me.
I didn't say put 'em down, did I?
Mighty clean hands for livestock.
Them hands don't look
like they do nothing much
except play a little
casino every now and then.
I told you, that whisky's for a
friend. I didn't see no harm...
Didn't see no harm?
Hear that, Beau? Big bootlegger
claims he don't know the law.
Well, Mr Bootlegger, I
don't need no couple
of bottles to make a
case against you.
Law says all I need is
just one little old drop.
And... law says you use a vehicle
to transport alcoholic beverages,
and said vehicle is confiscated to
be sold at public auctions, so...
you can just kiss that pretty
little old car of yours goodbye.
Hey, hold on. That seems
pretty rough just because...
Don't lower your hands. I didn't
tell you to lower your hands.
I tell you to lower your hands,
then you lower your hands.
You don't do nothing till I
tell you to. Understand?
Answer me. You understand?
Yes, sir.
Ah, I already done that.
Ain't nothing in
his clothes except
him. He ain't worth five cents.
No, she ain't got
nothing on her, either.
You don't know what kind of
real bad trouble you're in.
You better start thinking on it.
I've got a case against you for
possession and
transporting whisky,
and I reckon if I try, I can
think of a few other things.
Better face it, you're going to be
up in these parts
for quite a while,
working on the county roads.
Maybe you're lucky, you
get out in six months.
Six more months, influencing a
child, maybe get six
years for that.
Maybe we could work something out.
What's there to work out?
While I rustle one up,
'you all listen to
this little goodie
'from a couple of years ago...'
Ah, I sure don't like to send a
man to a road gang. Never have.
Always felt sorry for
them poor devils.
But I can't overlook the fact
that you've been paid $625,
and you ain't telling
me where it is.
Now, I know you're
a bootlegger, so
what's there for me to work out?
All right. Let's cut this
ring-around-the-rosy.
Where's that... money?
You think I'm fooling around?
I ain't fooling around.
Maybe you'll come around in time.
Get a little thirsty and
get a little hungry.
Time sure does have a way with
criminals, don't it, Beau?
Sure do.
Well, it's getting on to 5:00.
Somebody ought to be
stirring over at the café.
I think I'll step
over there a while.
See if that friend of
the family's there.
I'll be on back before long.
I got all day, you know? I got
all the time in the world.
♪ Trouble's just a bubble ♪
♪ And the clouds
will soon roll by ♪
♪ So let's have another
cup of coffee ♪
♪ And let's have
another piece of pie ♪
♪ Let a smile be your umbrella ♪
♪ For it's just an April shower ♪
♪ Even John D. Rockefeller ♪
Sir, may I get my things, please?
♪ Mr Herbert Hoover ♪
Ok.
♪ So let's have another
cup of coffee ♪
♪ And let's have
another piece of pie ♪
Daddy...
I need to go to the shithouse.
Well, there's a place
down the hall.
Daddy, I'm scared.
I want you to come
stand by the door.
All right if I go with her?
Down there.
- Run.
- You crazy?
Hey.
Where are we running? Oh, my God.
Stop them people. Hey,
there's bootleggers.
Jesus Christ, this
is the craziest...
- Hurry.
- I'm hurrying.
- Stop.
- Oh, Jesus.
- I'm going to hit him.
- Make him jump. Don't slow down.
I could have killed him. They're
going to have me up for murder.
- They're shooting at us.
- But they're missing. Keep going.
- We ain't gonna make it.
- Yes, we will.
Not in this car, we
ain't. Every lawman in
Kansas is going to be
looking for this car.
We got to get across
the river to Missouri.
Where's the bridge?
- Oh, Jesus.
- What's the matter?
- Damn bridge is the other way.
- What?
Hang on.
Ah, this ain't no good. We're
gonna make it too easy for 'em.
We got to get off
this road. Hang on.
Holy smoke.
Blow your horn.
Won't do no good. He
can't pull off the road.
Ain't we got all the luck, selling
whisky to a sheriff's brother?
Hang onto your hat.
- What?
- Hold on, I said.
Oh, God.
- You all right?
- Huh.
Ok, we threw a hobble on 'em for a
while, but we got to
get off this road,
or we're going to end
up in a town for sure.
And take that money out of there.
You like to give me heart failure.
We made it, didn't we?
Anybody home?
Howdy.
Need to get rid of my car here.
I need to get rid of my car.
Sheriff wants to
take away my little
girl, put her in an orphanage.
You know anybody who
might want to swap?
How about that truck over there?
Well, we'll just let him
chew on it a while.
Well, the rear tyres
look new, anyway.
- The radio looks ok.
- Think this thing runs?
It better. We got to have
some way of travelling.
Where we going to go?
Out of Kansas, across
the river to Saint Jo.
That's where.
Here he comes.
Look at 'em all.
All I'm looking for is a swap
and three days' head start
before you take it
out on the highway.
It's all legal. Got the papers
right here to prove it.
Just have to fill out that form
on the back, and you own it.
Ain't gonna swap.
Well, it's brand-new.
That car ain't no good.
What's the matter with it?
Can't haul nothing in it.
Oh, well, if that's all
that's bothering you,
you can sell the car and get two
trucks to do your hauling in.
I ain't gonna swap.
Wrassle you for it.
- Are you crazy?
- If I win, we swap.
You win, you can keep the
car and the truck both.
- Moze...
- Quiet down.
- What kind of wrassling?
- You name it.
- Catch as can?
- Shoes or barefoot?
Makes no never mind to me.
Barefoot.
You're gonna get killed just
to give something away.
I ain't got no choice.
Get that city boy.
Get the city boy.
Let's go.
Make him say "calf rope," Leroy.
Come on, Leroy. Get him, Leroy.
Get him.
That ain't fair. You stop that.
You make him fight fair.
Look out for that rake, Leroy.
Watch out, Leroy.
- Let's go in the car. Come on.
- Yee-haw.
Woo-hoo. Yoo-hoo. Woo-hoo.
- Are you pushing?
- Of course I'm pushing.
Ok, it'll go now. Put
your foot on the brake.
- The brake. The brake.
- It don't work.
The brake, goddamn it. The brake.
Don't you even know where
the damn brake is?
It don't work.
Oh...
Well, it figures.
Well, we're in Missouri anyway.
What'll we do now, drop some 20s?
- How much money we got?
- $837 and some change.
42 cents, I think.
Well, we're just outside
of St. Jo, ain't we?
- So what?
- So...
It's a big town, ain't it?
We can do better than 20s.
'You all know that one.
"'Let's have another
cup of coffee,
let's have another piece of pie."
'Well, it's 10:30, and it's
Sunday morning in St. Jo,
'and you all get
to church now, ok?
'Here's the news:
'In Omaha, President Roosevelt
told the nation last night...'
- Moze?
- Yeah?
What if that old man
don't believe ya?
He'll believe me, all right.
He's in the market for making
a killing, just like we are.
Maybe he don't even
have a silver mine.
I had him checked out real
thorough. Where's the money?
And he's just what people
say he is, rich and greedy.
'The independent candidate
for Senate this year...'
- Pull up your socks.
- Moze...
If we get a silver
mine, we could get
a house and everything,
couldn't we?
Everything, just... everything.
♪ Just around the corner,
there's a rainbow in the sky ♪
♪ So let's have another
cup of coffee ♪
Ok, you got it straight?
Corner of East Warring and
Burlington, 11 o'clock.
Just show there with tears
in your eyes. That's all.
Moze, don't forget the money.
Of course I won't
forget the money.
I'll see you in 30 minutes.
Moze, could we get a piano, too?
A piano? We'll have
a whole factory.
♪ Just around the corner ♪
♪ There's a rainbow in the sky ♪
I guess you just didn't
make a good enough swap.
My brother's real sore at ya.
Seems you sold him some
of his own whisky.
You can't arrest me
now. We're in Missouri.
And your damn brother's
a bootlegger.
You got an awful
big mouth, Mister.
Maybe I can't arrest
you in Missouri,
and maybe I don't want to.
But I sure can make
sure that you ain't
gonna feel real good
while you're here.
Let's go.
Addie...
Moze.
Moze...
I sw...
I swallowed my gold tooth.
- Aw, Moze.
- They took it all.
- Oh, Moze, you're all beat up.
- Ain't nothing left.
Don't worry none.
I've been keeping
ten dollars for emergencies.
What the hell we do
with ten dollars?
We could buy some bibles,
do a little widow business.
Must be lots of good
towns around here.
Do some 20s, drop some wallets...
before you know it, we'll
be real good again.
I'll bet in no time we could have
a whole new car and everything.
You're going to take me to
Aunt Billie's now, ain't ya?
- Aw, Moze...
- Don't start crying.
I won't.
That's where we set
out for, ain't it?
Looks nice.
Yeah, it looks real fine.
- That must be your uncle Daniel.
- He looks nice, too, don't he?
Yup. Real nice.
Maybe if Frank D. Roosevelt comes,
he'll tell him to take me
to the station to see him.
Maybe you write, old Frankie'll
have a place to
write you back now.
Yeah, he might, at that.
Course he will. Ain't no
question but he will.
All this talk's just wasting time.
Here's your... here,
your skates, your radio.
- Where you gonna go?
- Don't worry about me.
I got plans. New ideas
coming in every day.
Get going.
You know, if I knew for
sure you wasn't my pa...
It's for sure I ain't your pa.
Although sometimes
I used to figure
Mr Connors could have been my pa,
the way he touched
my shoulder, get me
things from the candy
counter for free.
And Mr Pritchard, he smiled
at me once real nice.
Except they don't have
my jaw or nothing.
So long.
Ain't you coming to
the door with me?
There it is, right there. How much
closer am I supposed to bring you?
They'll wonder how I got here.
Tell 'em a family
friend brung you,
and you had a little
trouble on the
way with your car
and with finances.
Now, get going.
Yes?
I'm Addie.
Addie?
Addie.
I've been worried sick about you.
Addie... come on in, child.
I been writing letters,
and your Uncle
Daniel's been trying
to call those people down there
to see where you've been.
You're just the spitting image of
your mother, pretty as a picture.
I don't know why I go
on like this. What
you need is some
ice-cold lemonade.
Now you just sit right there,
and I'll be right back.
Everybody's going to be
so happy to see you.
We're going to get
those clothes off you.
You're going to get into
a nice, fresh, bath...
and then you're going to sleep
in your own little bed,
alongside your cousin, Edna.
I just near give up on you, child.
I bet you're starving
to death. I'm
going to cut you a
big piece of pie.
We got those telegrams, and
then we never did hear from ya.
I told you, I don't want you
riding with me no more.
You still owe me $200.
Moze, look.
Come on.
Hurry up.
♪ Keep your sunny side up ♪
♪ Keep it up high, the
side that gets blue ♪
♪ If you have nine sons in a row ♪
♪ Start a baseball team,
they make money, you know ♪
♪ Keep your funny side
up, don't let up ♪
♪ Let your laughter come
through, doodley-doo ♪
♪ Stand up on your legs ♪
♪ Be like two fried eggs ♪
♪ Keep your sunny side up ♪