SHINE ON YOU CRAZY DIAMOND
Remember when you were young?
You shone like the sun.
Shine on, you crazy diamond
Now there's a look in your eyes
Like black holes in the sky
Shine on, you crazy diamond
You were caught in the crossfire
Of childhood and stardom,
Blown on the steel breeze
Come on you target
for faraway laughter;
Come on you stranger, you legend,
You martyr, and shine
You reached for the secret too soon
You cried for the moon
Shine on, you crazy diamond
Threatened by shadows at night
And exposed in the light
Shine on, you crazy diamond
Well, you wore out your welcome
With random precision
Rode on the steel breeze
Come on you raver, you seer of visions,
Come on you painter, you piper,
You prisioner, and shine
Nobody knows where you are,
How near or how far
Shine on, you crazy diamond
Pile on many more layers
And I'll be joining you there
Shine on, you crazy diamond
And we'll bask in the shadow
Of yesterday's triumph
And sail on the steel breeze
Come on you boy child,you winner and loser,
Come on you miner for?truth and delusion,
And shine
LEARNING TO FLY
Into the distance a ribbon of black
Stretched to the point of no turning back
A flight of fancy on a windswept field
Standing alone my senses real
A fatal attraction is holding me fast
How can I escape this irresistible grasp?
Can't keep my eyes from the circling skies
Tongue tied and twisted Just an earth bound misfit I
Ice is forming on the tips of my wings
Unheeded warnings I thought I thought of everything
No navigator to find my way home
Unladened, empty and turned to stone
A soul in tension that's learning to fly
Condition grounded but determined to try
Can't keep my eyes from the circling skies
Tongue tied and twisted just an earth bound misfit, I
Above the planet on a wing and a prayer,
My grubby halo, a vapour trail in the empty air.
Across the clouds I see my shadow fly
Out of the corner of my watering eye
A dream unthreatened by the morning light
Could blow this soul right through the roof of the night
There's no sensation to compare with this
Suspended animation, A state of bliss
Can't keep my mind from the circling skies
Tongue-tied and twisted just an earth-bound misfit, I
HIGH HOPES
Beyond the horizon of the place we lived when we were young
In a world of magnets and miracles
our thoughts strayed constantly and without boundary
The ringing of the division bell had began
Along the long road and on down the causeway
Do they still meet there by the cut?
There was a ragged band that followed in our footsteps
Running before time took our dreams away
Leaving the myriad small creatures trying to tie us to the ground
To a life consumed by slow decay
The grass was greener
The light was brighter
With friends surrounded
The nights of wonder
Looking beyond the embers of bridges glowing behind us
To a glimpse of how green it was on the other side
Steps taken forwards but sleepwalking back again
Dragged by the force of some inner tide
At a higher altitude with flag unfurled
We reached the dizzy heights of that dreamed of world
Encumbered forever by desire and ambition
There's a hunger still unsatisfied
Our weary eyes still stray to the horizon
Though down this road we've been so many times
The grass was greener
The light was brighter
The taste was sweeter
The nights of wonder
With friends surrounded
The dawn mist glowing
The water flowing
The endless river
Forever and ever
TAKE IT BACK
Her love rains down on me
easy as the breeze
I listen to her breathing
it sounds like the waves on the sea
I was thinking all about her,
burning with rage and desire
We were spinning into darkness,
and the earth was on fire
She could take it back,
she might take it back some day
So I spy on her, I  lied to her,
I make promises I cannot keep
Then I hear her laughter rising,
rising from the deep
And I make her prove her love for me,
I take all that I can take
And I push her to the limit
to see if she will break
She might take it back,
she could take it back some day
Now I had seen the warnings,
screaming from all sides
It's easy to ignore them
God knows I've tried
All of this temptation,
you know it turned my faith to lies
Until I couldn't see the danger
or hear the rising tide
She Can take it back,
she Will take it back some day
She can take it back,
she will take it back some day
She will take it back,
She will take it back some day
COMING BACK TO LIFE
Where were you
when I was burned and broken
While the days slipped by
from my window watching
And Where were you?
when I was hurt and I was helpless
Because the things you say
and the things you do surround me
While you were hanging yourself
on someone else's words
dying to believe in what you heard
I was staring straight
into the shining sun
Lost in thought and lost in time
While the seeds of life and the seeds of change were planted
Outside the rain fell dark and slow
While I pondered on this dangerous but irresistible past-time
I took a heavenly ride through our silence
I knew the moment had arrived
For killing the past and coming back to life
I took a heavenly ride trough our silence
I knew the waiting had begun
And headed straight... into the shining sun
SORROW
The sweet smell of a great sorrow lies over the land
Plumes of smoke rise and merge into the leaden sky.
A man lies and dreams of green fields and rivers,
But awakes to a morning with no reason for waking
He's haunted by the memory of a lost paradise
In his youth or a dream,he can't be precise
He's chained forever to a world that's departed
It's not enough, it's not enough
His blood has frozen and curdled with fright
His knees have trembled and given way in the night
His hand has weakened at the moment of truth
His step has faltered
One world,
One soul
Time pass,
The river rolls
And he talks to the river of lost love and dedication
And silent replies that swirl invitation
Flow dark and troubled to an oily sea
A grim intimation of what is to be
There's an unceasing wind that blows through this night
And there's dust in my eyes, that blinds my sight
And silence that speaks so much louder that words,
Of promises broken.
KEEP TALKING
For millions of years mankind lived just like the animals
Then something happenend
which unleashed the power of our imagination
We learned to talk
There's a silence surrounding me
I can't seem to think straight
I'll sit in the corner
No one will bother me
I think I should speak now  (Why won't you talk to me?)
I can't seem to speak now (You never talk to me)
My words won't come out right (What are you thinking?)
I feel like I'm drowning  (What are you feeling?)
I'm feeling weak now (Why won't you talk to me?)
But I can't show my weakness (You never talk to me)
I sometimes wonder (What are you thinking?)
Where do we go from here (What are you feeling?)
It doesn't have to be like this
All we need to do is make sure we keep talking
(Why won't you talk to me?) I feel like I'm drowning
(You never talk to me) You know I can't breathe now
(What are you thinking?) We're going nowhere
(What are you feeling?) We're going nowhere
Why won't you talk to me?
You never talk to me
What are you thinking?
Where do we go from here?
It doesn't have to be like this
All we need to do
is make sure we keep talking
ANOTHER BRICK IN THE WALL PART 2
We don't need no education
We dont need no thought control
No dark sarcasm in the classroom
Teachers leave them kids alone
Hey! Teachers! Leave them kids alone!
All in all it's just another brick in the wall.
All in all you're just another brick in the wall.
We don't need no education
We dont need no thought control
No dark sarcasm in the classroom
Teachers leave them kids alone
Hey! Teacher! Leave them kids alone!
All in all it's just another brick in the wall.
All in all you're just another brick in the wall.
ONE OF THESE DAYS
One of these days
I'm going to cut you into little pieces.
SPEAK TO ME
"I've been mad for fucking years, absolutely years, I've been over the edge for yonks, been working me buns off for bands, for ages..."
"I've always been mad, I know I've been mad, like the most of us have...very hard to explain why you're mad, even if you're not mad..."
BREATHE
Breathe, breathe in the air.
Don't be afraid to care.
Leave but don't leave me.
Look around and choose your own ground.
Long you live and high you fly
And smiles you'll give and tears you'll cry
And all you touch and all you see
Is all your life will ever be.
Run, rabbit run.
Dig that hole,forget the sun,
And when at last the work is done.
Don't sit down it's time to dig another one.
For long you live and high you fly
But only if you ride the tide
And balanced on the biggest wave
You race towards an early grave.
TIME
Ticking away the moments that make up a dull day
You fritter and waste the hours in an offhand way.
Kicking around on a piece of ground in your home town
Waiting for someone or something to show you the way.
Tired of lying in the sunshine staying home to watch the rain.
You are young and life is long and there is time to kill today.
And then one day you find
Ten years have got behind you.
No one told you when to run,
You missed the starting gun.
And you run and you run to catch up with the sun but it's sinking
And racing around to come up behind you again.
The sun is the same in a relative way but you're older,
Shorter of breath and one day closer to death.
Every year is getting shorter never seem to find the time.
Plans that either come to naught
or half a page of scribbled lines
Hanging on in quiet desperation is the English way
The time has gone, the song is over,
Thought I'd something more to say...
Home, home again
I like to be here when I can
When I come home cold and tired
It's good to warm my bones beside the fire.
Far away across the field The tolling of the iron bell
Calls the faithful to their knees
To hear the softly spoken magic spells...
THE GREAT GIG IN THE SKY
"And I am not frightened of dying,
any time will do, I don't mind.
Why should I be frightened of dying
There's no reason for it, you've gotta go sometime."
MONEY
Money, get away.
Get a good job with more pay and you're okay.
Money, it's a gas.
Grab that cash with both hands and make a stash.
New car, caviar, four star daydream,
Think I'll buy me a football team.
Money, get back.
I'm all right Jack keep your hands off of my stack.
Money, it's a hit.
Don't give me that do goody good bullshit.
I'm in the high-fidelity first class travelling set
And I think I need a Lear jet.
Money, it's a crime.
Share it fairly but don't take a slice of my pie.
Money, so they say
Is the root of all evil today.
But if you ask for a raise it's no surprise that
they're giving none away.
US AND THEM
Us,
and them
And after all we're only ordinary men.
Me,
and you.
God only knows it's not what
we would choose to do.
Forward he cried from the rear
and the front rank died.
And the general sat and the lines on the map
moved from side to side.
Black
and blue
And who knows which is which
and who is who.
Up
and down.
And in the end it's only
round and round... and round
Haven't you heard it's a battle of words
The poster bearer cried.
Listen son, said the man with the gun
There's room for you inside.
Down
and out
It can't be helped
but there's a lot of it about.
With,
without.
And who'll deny
it's what the fighting's all about
Out of the way, it's a busy day
I've got things on my mind.
For want of the price of a tea and a slice
The old man died.
BRAIN DAMAGE
The lunatic is on the grass.
Remembering games and daisy chains and laughs.
Got to keep the loonies on the path.
The lunatic is in the hall.
The lunatics are in my hall.
The paper holds their folded faces to the floor
And every day the paper boy brings more.
And if the dam breaks open many years too soon
And if there is no room upon the hill
And if your head explodes with dark forebodings too
I'll see you on the dark side of the moon.
The lunatic is in my head.
The lunatic is in my head
You raise the blade, you make the change
You re-arrange me 'till I'm sane.
You lock the door
And throw away the key
There's someone in my head but it's not me.
And if the cloud bursts,thunder in your ear
You shout and no one seems to hear.
And if the band you're in starts playing different tunes
I'll see you on the dark side of the moon.
ECLIPSE
All that you touch
All that you see
All that you taste
And all that you feel.
All that you love
All that you hate
All you distrust.
And all that you save.
All that you give
All that you deal
All that you buy,
beg, borrow or steal.
All you create
And all you destroy
All that you do
All that you say.
All that you eat
And everyone you meet
All that you slight
And everyone you fight.
All that is now
All that is gone
All that's to come
and everything under the sun is in tune
but the sun is eclipsed by the moon.
WISH YOU WERE HERE
So, so you think you can tell
Heaven from Hell
Blue skies from pain
Can you tell a green field
From a cold steel rail
A smile from a veil
Do you think you can tell
And did they get you to trade
Your heroes for ghosts
Hot ashes for trees
Hot air for a cool breeze
Cold comfort for change
Did you exchange
A walk on part in the war
For a lead role in a cage
How I wish
How I wish you were here
We're just two lost souls
Swimming in a fish bowl
Year after year
Running over the same old ground
What have we found
The same old fears
Wish you were here
COMFORTABLY NUMB
Hello,
Is there anybody in there
Just nod if you can hear me
Is there anyone at home
Come on now
I hear you're feeling down
I can ease your pain
And get you on your feet again
Relax
I'll need some information first
Just the basic facts
Can you show me where it hurts
There is no pain, you are receding
A distant ship smoke on the horizon
You are only coming through in waves
Your lips move but I can't hear what you're saying
When I was a child I had a fever
My hands felt just like two balloons
Now I've got that feeling once again
I can't explain, you would not understand
This is not how I am
I have become comfortably numb
OK.
Just a little pin prick
There'll be no more
But you may feel a little sick
Can you stand up
I do belive it's working, good
That'll keep you going, through the show
Come on it's time to go.
There is no pain you are receding
A distant ship smoke on the horizon
You are only coming through in waves
Your lips move, but I can't hear what you're saying
When I was a child
I caught a fleeting glimpse
Out of the corner of my eye
I turned to look but it was gone
I cannot put my finger on it now
The child is grown
The dream is gone
And I... have become
Comfortably numb.
RUN LIKE HELL
You better make your face up,
In your favorite disguise,
With your button-down lips,
And your roller blind eyes.
With your empty smile,
And your hungry heart,
Feel the bile rising,
From your guilty past.
With your nerves in tatters,
As the cockleshell shatters,
And the hammers batter,
Down your door,
You better run.
You better run all day,
And run all night.
And keep your dirty feelings deep inside.
And if you're taking your girlfriend out tonight,
You better park the car well out of sight.
Cause if they catch you in the back seat,
Trying to pick her locks,
They're gonna send you back to Mother,
In a cardboard box.
You better run!