Encoded By #ALLSAFE #GUGI _/
♪ Yo ho
Yo ho
♪ A pirate's life for me
♪ We extort, we pilfer
We filch, we sack
- ♪ Drink...
- Quiet, missy!
Cursed pirates sail these waters.
You don't want to bring
them down on us, do ya?
Mr. Gibbs, that will do.
She was singing about pirates!
Bad luck to be singing about pirates
with us mired in this unnatural fog,
mark my words.
Consider them marked.
- On your way.
- Aye, lieutenant.
It's bad luck to have
a woman on board too.
Even a miniature one.
I think it'd be rather exciting
to meet a pirate.
Think again, Miss Swann.
Vile and dissolute creatures,
the lot of 'em.
I intend to see to it that any man
who sails under a pirate flag
or wears a pirate brand
gets what he deserves.
A short drop and a sudden stop.
Lieutenant Norrington,
I appreciate your fervor,
but I'm concerned about the effect
this subject will have upon my daughter.
My apologies, Governor Swann.
Actually, I find it all fascinating.
Yes. That's what concerns me.
Look! A boy!
There's a boy in the water!
Man overboard!
Man the ropes!
Fetch a hook!
Haul him aboard!
He's still breathing.
Mary, Mother of God!
What happened here?
Most likely the powder magazine.
Merchant vessels run heavily armed.
Lot of good it did them.
Everyone's thinking it,
I'm just saying it.
Pirates!
There's no proof of that!
It was probably an accident.
Rouse the captain.
- Aye, sir.
- Heave to and take in sail.
- Launch the boats.
- Heave to!
Elizabeth, I want you
to accompany the boy.
He'll be in your charge.
Take care of him.
It's OK.
My name's Elizabeth Swann.
Will Turner.
I'm watching over you, Will.
You're a pirate!
Has he said anything?
His name's William Turner.
That's all I found out.
Take him below.
Elizabeth!
Are you all right?
Are you decent?
Yes.
Yes?
Still in bed at this hour?
It's a beautiful day.
I have a gift for you.
- Oh, it's beautiful!
- Isn't it?
May I inquire as to the occasion?
Does a father need an occasion
to dote upon his daughter?
Go on.
Actually, I...
I had hoped you might wear it
for the ceremony today.
Ceremony?
Captain Norrington's promotion ceremony.
I knew it!
Commodore Norrington,
as he's about to become.
A fine gentleman, don't you think?
He fancies you, you know.
Elizabeth?
How's it coming?
It's difficult to say.
I'm told it's
the latest fashion in London.
Well, women in London
must've learned not to breathe!
My Lord, you have a visitor.
Ah, Mr. Turner.
Good to see you again.
Good day, sir.
I have your order.
Well...
The blade is folded steel.
That's gold filigree
laid into the handle.
If I may?
Perfectly balanced.
The tang is nearly
the full width of the blade.
Impressive. Very impressive.
Very nice.
Commodore Norrington's going
to be very pleased with this.
Do pass my compliments
onto your master.
I shall.
A craftsman is always pleased
to hear his work is appreciated.
Elizabeth!
You look absolutely stunning.
Will.
It's so good to see you.
I had a dream about you last night.
About me?
Is it entirely proper for you...?
About the day we met.
Do you remember?
How could I forget, Miss Swann?
How many times must I ask you
to call me Elizabeth?
At least once more, Miss Swann.
As always.
Now, you see?
At least the boy
has a sense of propriety.
We really must be going.
Come on.
Good day, Mr. Turner.
Come along!
Good day...
...Elizabeth.
Hold up there, you!
It's a shilling to tie up
your boat to the dock.
And I shall need to know your name.
What do you say to three shillings,
and we forget the name?
Welcome to Port Royal, Mr. Smith.
Two paces... march!
Right about... face!
Present... arms!
This dock is off-limits to civilians.
I'm terribly sorry, I didn't know.
If I see one,
I shall inform you immediately.
Apparently, there's some high-toned
and fancy to-do up at the fort, eh?
How could it be two upstanding
gentlemen, such as yourselves,
did not merit an invitation?
Someone has to make sure this dock
stays off-limits to civilians.
It's a fine goal, to be sure.
But it seems to me, a...
A ship like that...
...makes this one here
a bit superfluous, really.
Oh, the Dauntless is the power
in these waters, true enough,
but there's no ship that can match
the Interceptor for speed.
I've heard of one.
It's supposed to be very fast,
nigh uncatchable.
The Black Pearl.
There's no real ship
that can match the Interceptor.
The Black Pearl is a real ship.
No. No, it's not.
Yes, it is. I've seen it!
You've seen it?
- Yes.
- You haven't seen it!
- Yes, I have!
- You've seen a ship
with black sails,
that's crewed by the damned,
and captained by a man so evil
that hell itself spat him back out?
No.
But I have seen a ship
with black sails.
Oh... And no ship that's
not crewed by the damned,
and captained by a man so evil
that hell spat him back out
could possibly have black sails,
therefore couldn't possibly
be any other ship
than the Black Pearl,
is that what you're saying?
No.
Like I said,
there's no real ship
that can match the Interceptor...
Hey!
You!
Get away from there!
You don't have permission
to be aboard there!
Sorry. It's such a pretty boat.
Ship!
What's your name?
Smith!
Or Smithy, if you like.
What's your purpose in Port Royal,
Mr. Smith?
Yeah, and no lies!
All right then.
I confess.
It is my intention to commandeer
one of these ships, pick up a crew
in Tortuga to rape, pillage, and pilfer
my weasely black guts out.
I said, no lies!
I think he's telling the truth.
If he were telling the truth,
he wouldn't have told us.
Unless he knew you wouldn't believe
the truth, even if he told it to you.
May I have a moment?
You look lovely, Elizabeth.
Yes.
I apologize if I seem forward,
but I must speak my mind.
This promotion throws into sharp relief
that which I have not yet achieved.
A marriage to a fine woman.
You have become a fine woman, Elizabeth.
I can't breathe.
Yes, I...
I'm a bit nervous myself.
And then they made me their chief.
Elizabeth?
Elizabeth!
The rocks!
Sir, it's a miracle she missed them!
- Will you be saving her, then?
- I can't swim!
Pearl of the King's Navy, you are!
Do not lose these!
What was that?
Make way!
I got her!
She's not breathing!
Move!
I never would've thought of that.
Clearly you've never been to Singapore.
Where did you get that?
On your feet.
Elizabeth!
- Are you all right?
- Yes, I'm fine.
- Shoot him!
- Father! Commodore...
...do you intend to kill my rescuer?
I believe thanks are in order.
Had a brush with the East India
Trading Company, did we?
Pirate?
Hang him.
Keep your guns on him, men.
Gillette, fetch some irons.
Well, well.
Jack Sparrow, isn't it?
Captain Jack Sparrow,
if you please, sir.
Well, I don't see your ship...
...captain.
I'm in the market, as it were.
He said he'd come to commandeer one.
I told you he was telling the truth.
These are his, sir.
No additional shots nor powder.
A compass that doesn't point north.
And I half expected it
to be made of wood.
You are, without doubt,
the worst pirate I've heard of.
But you have heard of me.
Commodore, I really must protest!
Carefully, lieutenant.
Pirate or not, this man saved my life!
One good deed is not enough to redeem
a man of a lifetime of wickedness!
But it seems enough to condemn him.