BATTLE OF UHUD....
There is Hamza can you see him?
He is your fortune
Ubada! Those horse-men on the flank out there
they are replaced
they are under Khalid.
Khalid...
I often thought of that yound man
Hamza!
Yes!
Prophet asks if you have noticed those horse-men
Yes I have. I don't like them
he's sending our 50 archers to watch them
no matter what happens,
the archers must hold off those horse-men
Zaid, tell the Prophet that we are ready
What do you think Hamza?
Besides their numbers, I'd say its a fair fight
we see them and they see us
what faces me has never frightened me
All praise be Hubar!
When Muhammed gives the word, we'll go to them
Hamza!
Weapons ready
we march now!
attack
they've killed Hamza!
tackle them
Fight! Fight!
This is a moment of victory
Running away from us. Let's get the loot
Stand where you are told to stand
come back to your positions
all of you, come back!
Its a road
Their centry is gone
We've lost the battle, Khalid
Not yet
hold on
Where is the prophet?
Muhammad is dead
I saw him fall
No No! He's alive! Find him!
back. back to the mountains
halt
I thought we were beaten!
Now, victory is yours, Khalid!
We have no victory until
we've finished Muhammad
he's up in those rocks
We've finished our business. we've avenged Badr
But we can end Islam and him forever!
Some of his fenatics are still with him!
They have the advantage of the mountains
The risk is too high
Muhammad, listen
A day for a day! the day of Uhub for the day of Badr
Our dead have answered to your dead
Our dead are in Paradise,
your dead are in hell fire
Hamza! Hamza! do you hear me Hamza?
ok You know that I am with you, I, Hind!
do you remember anything Hamza?
How you killed my father and my brother?
now you too are dead!
now, my heart is light
do you hear Hamza? Light!
But I haven't finished with you!
Death is too small
Wahshi, Cut him open, cut him!
They lost a battle and what do they do?
They came home and dig the ground harder
They are mad
I agree with you!
They defy reason,
they are even happy they lost
god send the defeat they say
to trial in their faith
Oh yes! they are fighting with the sky!
They'll get what they want!
They want Mecca!
They'll get Mecca
when we see the stars at noon....
immm... don't underestimate him, I learned that on my cost
my friend, Mecca is more than their home
It's where God spoke to man
Mecca is like a home-sickness to the soul
This year they are going as pilgrims
What?
Unarmed!
Unarmed?
Abu Sufian will slaughter them in the dessert
If you believe in God as they do,
it might be possible not to get slaughtered
But I agree with you, they probably will be
Be still, do not let them provoke you.
That is what they want. stand firm
Peace be upon you!
Prophet says: All who love God
must renew their Oaths to him
under the tree....
They've sent someone else!
Its Salool.
That means we might come to an agreement
Muhammad, you have been given conditions of truce
between yourself and Mecca
Have you agreed to them yet?
What is this?
In the name of God, the most gracious
Who is this new God they call gracious?
I do not know him. strike him out
And I cannot agree with this...
"Muhammad, the messenger of God?"
If I have thought you were the messenger of God
I would not have fought you
Make it "Muhammad, the son of Abdullah
agrees with Suheil, the son of Amr"
That is the more fact
well, so I understand
good, that is better
Now, it is agreed
that you do not continue your pilgrimage,
you must turn around and go home
Mecca is home
However, you may continue your
pilgrimage next year
and for 3 days only
in and out.
we also agree to the truce
for 10 years...
During that time you will not attack any
tribe or ambush any caravan
or any individual associated with us and vice versa
If you injure any one of us, the truce ends
and vice versa. Is that clear?
10 years... 10 years of peace....
We need that time
We will use that time
These letters, from Muhammad, the messenger of God
to rulers of the world
Call the world to Islam.
to Heraclius, emperor of Byzantium
Kisra, Emperor of Persia,
Mephocus, patriarch of Alexandria
God is great
There are no different races in Islam and
Arab is not superior to foreign
not a  white man superior to a black.
All return equally to god
Unless you desire for your neighbour,
what you desire for yourself.
You don't have faith
A man goes to bed with his belly full,
while his neighbor is hungry.
He isn't a Muslim
The Ink of a scholar is holier than
the blood of a martyr
A man reading is handsome in the side of god
So, learn to read and when you have learned
teach
The people of the book,
Jews with their Bible, the Christians with their testament
must be respected by you for their books likewise came from god
you must all think of Muhammad as more than a man
He was collecting firewood one day.
Let me do it, I said
Why? He said,
You're the prophet of god,
you can't go round scratching for firewood
But he looked at me mumbling
God does not like the man
who considers himself above
other men, he said.
So, I laid back and watched him
Suddenly he stopped.
he stood to his full height and came to me
Yes!
I am the Prophet of god, he said,
but even I do not know what will become of me
Arm. have you come to take me again?
No
I've come to ask you to take me
I witness that there is only one god
and that Muhammad is His messenger
May god forgive me the times I have fought against you
lslam does the way with all that went before it
I'm sorry, I came here wearing...
Here are my jewels,
what they are worth
I give to the poor
And may I offer you my ?
Yes
But you were the bitterest sword against Islam
Now by the will of god,
I will be the raised sword of god
Ah, its all easy to god
Just as he might gain in losing
be may lose in winning
2 years agon we thought we were beaten
when we had to sign that truce
Look at us now! charging from victory to victory in the hearts of men
What's that?
Abu Sufian is coming
Why am I insulted like this?
Abu Sufian
I expect some courtesy
we are not at war
we have a truce
I've come to speak to Muhammad
Where is he?
he is in the mosque
Muhammad we did not break the truce
I have come to re-affirm the truce
I speak for Mecca
Muhammad, why do you turn from me?
Don't go
Muhammad, don't go
Biduns broke the truce, not us.
The night was dark
I am here to testify that the night was dark
Baara! This is your city
Hudaifa, you are my kin
and descendant
why must you be hard?
I am Mecca, I am the leader of Mecca
Why am I insulted like this?
Because you keep no promise
and respect no pledge
I've heard what I thought
I'd never hear
Abu Sufian asking for pity
To be out-fought, out-fought
who we knew to be a one time shepherd
you saw that shepherd's religion grow from a speck (dust)
speck was in my eye
I could see nothing
Tell Mecca that the gods are dead.
It is useless to resist god
Travel fast or every man here
will curse behind you
Its you who have broken the truce
For tonight will be 10,000 men from every tribe
Now we can fight them. you are back
we will close the streets, and defend from the houses
Its no use
There are thousands of them and they are joined by more
You coward!
Hind, go home!
You coward! Are you the leader of Mecca?
Look at yourself!
You are broke, they swallowed you and sput you out
When my father and brother die, my husband ran away?
You go home! You!
We can not resist! Mecca is taken
No, no!
We are to camp here for the night
We can see Mecca even through the mountains!
So many fires, I can not count them
It is very beautiful
When we drove them out of Mecca, I did not know
that he carried Mecca with him
we can smell the bread they are baking
Yes
It means they don't intend to plonder,
though I do hope at least thats what it means
They don't want blood on our walls and doorsteps
I can bargain with that
Take me to him!
So you are giving us your city
you offer me no bread
I understand
You may decide to kill me
Say what you have come to say
I saw your fires, the men around them
and I know what power you put into them
We can no longer resist Muhammad
Now if you agree
you dare to come here and ask for conditions
Isn't it yet time enough for you to recognize who Muhammad is?
Muhammad, there is still doubt in my heart
If I were to cut off your head, it would remove all your doubts
Khalid,
there is no composion in religion
A man may take many years
or only need minutes
its god who decides the time!
So respect his doubts
You're a black slave, you have the best school
I am only what God has given me
Yes
The Gods that I worshipped,
have never been in use
It would have helped me
I require no composion.
There is one God,
and you are the messenger of god.
Now, let me go.
get inside
No doors may be broken down,
nothing plondered, nothing seized
no one abused, all behind closed doors are safe
All in hAbu Sufian's house are safe
All by the side of Kabbalah are safe
At least, he kept his word,
they haven't forced any door
He's stolen hearts, not walls.
Its a permanent victory
I dread going out
we must... we must in the end
were we so wrong?
The way we lived, yes. that was wrong
we were trapped in our own faults
our gods were less than us
Now there he is, making his entrance to the Kabbaah
In the name of god, most gracious, most merciful
God gave this house to Abraham to be a sacred place,
worship no other God but Him
and cleanse his house
so it was
Muhammad took no revenge and allowed all.
He declared Mecca a holy place
Noone may shed blood
or cut down a tree,
or kill a living thing in Mecca
Soon,
all Arabia was converted not only to the new worship
but to the new laws, manners,
attitudes contained in Islam
The Prophet had lived to see his work done,
and now he began to feel the nearness of death
One great act of his Prophet would remain
the setting of its seal
He called the people to him
and he spoke for the last time
His message was to surrender to god
and humanity to man
''Oh, mankind! Listen well!
I may not be with you much longer
the weak among you
feed them and watch what you eat
Dress them as you are dressed,
you will meet your god
and he will call you
to count your actions
Let those who are present warn those who are absent
You are all are descendant from Adam
and the best among you
is he who most regards god
Think deeply about what I say.
Let all your feuds be abolished
you must know that every Muslim
is the brother of every other Muslim
and all Muslims are brothers of one-another
Between Muslims, there are no races and no tribes
Not must you take anything from your brother
except what is given freely
Do not oppress and do not be oppressed
O my people!
I'm but a man,
It may be that the angel of death will visit me soon
and death will overtake me
But I have left you a book,
revealed by god,
The Qur'an, which is light and guidance
Now he repeated to the people
the final repetition of the Qur'an,
the sea of determination
not Muhammad's words, but god's word
''This day I have perfected your religion for you
and completed my favour to you
and I have chosen for you Islam as your religion''
ON June the 8th  632
in his 63rd year
Muhammad died
Many of his followers
could not believe the fact
How can such a man die?
But Abu Bakr, the Prophet's friend
stood up in the mosque:
"If anyone worships Muhammad,
Let him know that Muhammad is dead
but who worships god
Let him know that god is alive and can not die''
They buried Muhammad beside his mosque in Medina
But the religion he preached
found its place in the heart of man
It endured. It multiplied.
Still to Mecca, they come, the mankind
The people of Islam dressed in their pilgrim white
all equal before god,
all united in this place of crowd.
Each individual soul joined in a community of worship...
"ONE GOD"