She isn't coming yet, Toto.
Did she hurt you?
She tried to, didn't she?
Come on, we'll go tell Uncle Henry
and Auntie Em. Come on, Toto.
Aunt Em. Aunt Em.
Aunt Em, just listen to what
Miss Gulch did to Toto...
Dorothy please, we're
trying to count.
- But Aunt Em, she hit him...
- Don't bother us now, honey.
This old incubator's
gone bad and we're
likely to lose a
lot of our chicks.
That poor little thing.
But Aunt Em, Miss Gulch hit Toto
right over the back with a rake
just because she says
he gets in her garden
and chases her nasty
old cat every day.
70. Dorothy, please.
But he doesn't do it every day.
Just once or twice a week.
And he can't catch
her old cat anyway.
And now she says she's
gonna get the Sheriff...
Dorothy, Dorothy, we're busy.
All right.
- How's she coming?
- Take it easy.
You got my finger.
Well why don't you get
your finger outta the way.
- There you are.
- Right on my finger.
Lucky thing it wasn't your head.
Zeke, what am I gonna
do about Miss Gulch?
Just because Toto
chases her 'ol cat...
Listen honey, I got
them hogs to get in.
Now look it Dorothy, you ain't
using your head about Miss
Gulch. You'd think you didn't
have any brains at all.
- I have so got brains.
- Well, why don't you use them?
When you come home, don't you
go by Miss Gulch's place.
Then Toto won't get
in her garden, and
you won't get in no trouble, see?
Hunk, you just won't
listen, that's all.
Well, your head ain't
made of straw, you know.
Say, get in there before I
make a dime bank outta ya.
Listen kid,
are you gonna let that old Gulch
heifer try and buffalo ya?
She ain't nothing to be afraid of.
Have a little courage, that's all.
I'm not afraid of her.
Then the next time she squawks,
walk up to her and
spit in her eye.
That's what I'd do.
Zeke.
Help. Help me, Zeke.
Get me outta here.
Help.
- Are you all right, Dorothy?
- Yes, I'm all right.
I fell in, and Zeke...
Why Zeke, you're just
as scared as I am.
What a matter, gonna let a little
'ol pig make a coward out of ya?
Look at you Zeke,
you're just as white...
Here, what's all
this jabber-walking
when there's work to be done?
I know of 3 shiftless
farm hands that'll
be out of a job before
they know it...
Well, Dorothy was walking along...
I saw you tinkering with
that contraption Hickory.
Now, you and Hunk get
back to that waggon.
All right Mrs Gale,
but someday they're gonna erect a
statue to me in this town, and...
Well, don't start
posing for it now.
Here. Here. Can't work on an empty
stomach. Have some crullers.
- Gosh, Mrs Gale.
- Just fried.
You see, Dorothy
toppled into the...
It's no place for Dorothy
around a pigsty.
Now, you go feed those hogs before
they worry themselves
into anaemia.
- Yes.
- Auntie Em,
really, you know what Miss Gulch
said she was gonna do to Toto?
She said she was gonna.
Now, Dorothy dear,
stop imagining things.
You always get yourself
into a fret over
nothing. Now you just
help us out today
and find yourself a place where
you won't get into any trouble.
Some place where there
isn't any trouble.
Do you suppose there
is such a place, Toto?
There must be.
It's not a place you can get
to by a boat or a train.
It's far, far away.
Behind the moon,
beyond the rain...
♪ Somewhere over the rainbow ♪
♪ Way up high ♪
♪ There's a land that I heard of ♪
♪ Once in a lullaby ♪
♪ Somewhere over the rainbow ♪
♪ Skies are blue ♪
♪ And the dreams that
you dare to dream ♪
♪ Really do come true ♪
♪ Someday I'll wish upon a star ♪
♪ And wake up where the
clouds Are far behind me ♪
♪ Where troubles melt
like lemon drops ♪
♪ Away above the chimney tops ♪
♪ That's where you'll ♪
♪ Find me ♪
♪ Somewhere over the rainbow ♪
♪ Bluebirds fly ♪
♪ Birds fly over the rainbow ♪
♪ Why then ♪
♪ Oh, why can't I? ♪
♪ If happy little bluebirds fly ♪
♪ Beyond the rainbow ♪
♪ Why, oh, why ♪
♪ Can't I? ♪
- Mr Gale.
- Howdy, Miss Gulch.
I want to see you and your
wife right away about Dorothy.
Dorothy? Well what
has Dorothy done?
What's she done?
I'm all but lame from
the bite on my leg.
- You mean, she bit you?
- No, her dog.
She bit her dog?
No.
That dog's a menace to the
community. I'm taking
him to the Sheriff and
make sure he's destroyed.
Destroyed. Toto?
You can't. You mustn't.
Auntie Em. Uncle Henry. You
won't let her, will ya?
Of course we won't.
Will we Em?
Please, Aunt Em.
Toto didn't mean to. He didn't
know he was doing anything wrong.
I'm the one that ought to
be punished. I let him go
in her garden. You can send
me to bed without supper.
If you don't hand over
that dog, I'll bring
a damned suit that'll
take your whole farm.
There's a law that protects them
folks against dogs that bite.
How would it be if she keeps him
tied up? He's really gentle.
With gentle people, that is.
That's for the Sheriff to decide.
Here's his order
allowing me to take him.
Unless you wanna go
against the law.
Yes.
We can't go against the law. I'm
afraid poor Toto has to go.
- Now you're seeing reason.
- No.
Here's what I'm taking him in,
so he can't attack me again.
No, No. I won't let you take him.
You go away. I'll bite you myself.
Dorothy.
You wicked old witch. Uncle Henry,
Auntie Em, don't
let 'em take Toto.
- Don't let her take him, please.
- I've got an order.
- Let me have him.
- Please stop her.
Put him in the basket, Henry.
- The idea.
- Don't, Uncle Henry.
Toto.
Almira Gulch, just because
you own half the county
doesn't mean you have the
power to run the rest of us.
For 23 years I've been dying to
tell you what I thought of you.
And now...
well, being a Christian
woman, I can't say it.
Toto, darling.
I got you back. You came back.
I'm so glad.
They'll be coming back
for you in a minute.
We've got to get away.
We've got to run away.
Well, well, well. House guests?
And who might you be?
No, no, no now, don't tell me.
Let's see. You're...
you're travelling in disguise.
No, that's not right. You're...
you're going on a visit.
No, I'm wrong. Let's
see what we...
You're... you're running away.
How did you guess?
Professor Marvel never
guesses, he knows.
Now, why are you running away?
No, no now, don't tell me.
They... they don't understand you
at home. They don't
appreciate you.
You want to see other lands. Big
cities, big mountains, big oceans.
Why, it's just like you could
read what was inside of me.
Toto, that's not polite.
We haven't been asked yet.
He's perfectly welcome.
As one dog to another.
Now let's see, where were we?
Please Professor, why
can't we go with you
and see all the crowned
heads of Europe?
Do you know any? You
mean the thing, yes.
Well... I never do
anything without
consulting my crystal first.
Let's go inside here. We'll...
just come along, I'll show you.
That's right. Here. Sit
right down here. That's it.
This... this is the same genuine,
magic, authentic crystal
used by the Priests
of Isis and Osiris
in the days of the
Pharaohs of Egypt
in which Cleopatra
first saw the approach
of Julius Caesar and Marc Anthony.
And so on, and so on. Now...
you... you'd better close your
eyes, my child, for a moment
in order to be better in
tune with the infinite.
We can't do these things without
reaching out into the infinite.
Yes, that's all right
now, you can open them.
We'll gaze into the crystal.
What's this I see? A house
with a picket fence
and a barn with a weathervane
of a running horse.
- That's our farm.
- Yes.
Yes. There's a... there's a woman.
She's... she's wearing a polka-dot
dress. Her face is careworn.
That's Aunt Em.
Yes. Her name is Emily.
That's right. What's she doing?
Well, I can't quite see.
Why, she's crying.
Someone has hurt her.
Someone has just about
broken her heart.
Me?
Well, it's... it's someone
she loves very much.
Someone she's been very kind to.
Someone she's taken
care of in sickness.
I had the measles once, and she
stayed right by me every minute.
What's she doing now?
Yes, she's... what's this?
Why, she's... she's putting
her hand on her heart.
She's... she's dropping
down on the bed.
Well, that's all. The
crystal's gone dark.
You don't suppose she could
really be sick, do you?
I've gotta go home right away.
But what's this? I thought you
were going along with me.
No, no. I have to get
to her right away.
Come on, Toto. Come on.
Goodbye, Professor Marvel.
And thanks a lot.
Better get under cover, Sylvester.
There's a storm's blowing up.
A whopper, to speak in the
vernacular of the peasantry.
Poor little kid. I hope
she gets home all right.
Get them horses loose.
Where's Hickory? Hickory?
Doggone it.
It's a twister. It's a twister.
Dorothy.
Everybody in the storm cellar.
Henry, I can't find Dorothy.
She's out in the storm.
We can't look for her now.
Come on, get in the
cellar. Hurry up.
Auntie Em.
Auntie Em?
Auntie Em. Uncle Henry.
Auntie Em.
We must be up inside the cyclone.
Miss Gulch.
Toto...
I have a feeling we're
not in Kansas any more.
We must be over the rainbow.
Now I know we're not in Kansas.
Are you a good witch
or a bad witch?
Who, me?
Why, I'm not a witch at all.
I'm Dorothy Gale, from Kansas.
Well, is that the witch?
Who, Toto? Toto's my dog.
I'm a little muddled.
The Munchkins
called me because a new witch
has just dropped a house on
the Wicked Witch of the East.
And there's the house,
and here you are
and that's all that's left of
the Wicked Witch of the East.
And so, what the
Munchkins want to know
is, are you a good
witch or a bad witch?
But I've already told you,
I'm not a witch at all.
Witches are old and ugly.
What was that?
The Munchkins. They're
laughing because I am a witch.
I'm Glinda, the
Witch of the North.
You are?
I beg your pardon.
But I've never heard of a
beautiful witch before.
Only bad witches are ugly.
The Munchkins are happy
because you freed them
from the Wicked Witch of the East.
But if you please,
what are Munchkins?
The little people who live in
this land. It's Munchkinland
and you are their national
heroine, my dear.
It's all right. You may all
come out and thank her.
♪ Come out, come out
wherever you are ♪
♪ And meet the young lady
who fell from a star ♪
♪ She fell from the sky
she fell very far ♪
♪ And Kansas, she says is
the name of the star ♪
♪ Kansas, she says ♪
♪ Is the name of the star ♪
♪ She brings you good news ♪
♪ Or haven't you heard? ♪
♪ When she fell out of Kansas ♪
♪ A miracle occurred ♪
♪ It really was no miracle
what happened was just this ♪
♪ The wind began to switch
the house to pitch ♪
♪ And suddenly the hinges
started to unhitch ♪
♪ Just then the witch
to satisfy an itch ♪
♪ Went flying on her broomstick
thumbing for a hitch ♪
♪ And oh, what happened
then was rich ♪
♪ The house began to pitch ♪
♪ The kitchen took a slitch ♪
♪ It landed on the Wicked Witch
in the middle of a ditch ♪
♪ Which was not a healthy
situation for the Wicked Witch ♪
♪ The house began to pitch
the kitchen took a slitch ♪
♪ It landed on the Wicked Witch
in the middle of a ditch ♪
♪ Which was not a healthy
situation for the Wicked Witch ♪
♪ Who began to twitch and was
reduced to just a stitch ♪
♪ Of what was once
the Wicked Witch ♪
We thank you very sweetly.
For doing it so neatly.
You've killed her so completely.
That we thank you very sweetly.
Let the joyous news be spread. The
Wicked Old Witch at last is dead.
♪ Ding-Dong, the Witch is dead ♪
♪ Which old Witch?
The Wicked Witch ♪
♪ Ding-Dong, the
Wicked Witch is dead ♪
♪ Wake up, you sleepyhead rub
your eyes, get out of bed ♪
♪ Wake up, the Wicked
Witch is dead ♪
♪ She's gone where the goblins
go, below, below, below ♪
♪ Yo-ho, let's open up and
sing and ring the bells out ♪
♪ Ding-Dong, the merry-o
sing it high, sing it low ♪
♪ Let them know the
Wicked Witch is dead ♪
♪ As Mayor of the Munchkin City ♪
♪ In the county of
the Land of Oz ♪
♪ I welcome you most regally ♪
♪ But we've got to
verify it legally ♪
♪ To see ♪ - ♪ To see? ♪
♪ If she ♪ - ♪ If she? ♪
♪ Is morally, ethically ♪
- ♪ Spiritually, physically ♪
- ♪ Positively, absolutely ♪
♪ Undeniably and reliably dead ♪
♪ As coroner I must aver ♪
♪ I thoroughly examined her ♪
♪ And she's not only merely dead ♪
♪ She's really most
sincerely dead ♪
Then this is a Day of Independence
for all the Munchkins
and their descendants.
If any.
Yes, let the joyous
news be spread.
The Wicked Old Witch
at last is dead.
♪ Ding-Dong, the Witch is dead ♪
♪ Which old Witch?
The Wicked Witch ♪
♪ Ding-Dong, the
Wicked Witch is dead ♪
♪ Wake up, you sleepyhead rub
your eyes, get out of bed ♪
♪ Wake up, the Wicked
Witch is dead ♪
♪ She's gone where the goblins
go, below, below, below ♪
♪ Yo-ho, let's open up and
sing and ring the bells out ♪
♪ Ding-Dong, the merry-o
sing it high, sing it low ♪
♪ Let them know the
Wicked Witch is dead ♪
♪ We represent the
Lullaby League ♪
♪ The Lullaby League,
the Lullaby League ♪
♪ And in the name of
♪ We wish to welcome
you to Munchkinland ♪
♪ We represent the
Lollipop Guild ♪
♪ The Lollipop Guild,
the Lollipop Guild ♪
♪ And in the name of
♪ We wish to welcome
you to Munchkinland ♪
♪ We welcome you to Munchkinland ♪
♪ Tra-la-la-la-la-la
Tra-la-la, tra-la-la ♪
♪ Tra-la-la-la-la la-la ♪
♪ From now on you'll be history
- ♪ You'll be his ♪
- ♪ You'll be history ♪
♪ And we will glorify your name ♪
- ♪ You will be a bust ♪
- ♪ Be a bust ♪
- ♪ In the hall of fame ♪
♪ Tra-la-la-la-la-la
Tra-la-la, tra-la-la ♪
♪ Tra-la-la-la-la la-la ♪
♪ Tra-la-la-la-la-la
Tra-la-la, tra-la-la ♪
♪ Tra-la-la-la-la la-la ♪
♪ Tra-la-la-la-la-la
Tra-la-la, tra-la-la ♪
♪ Tra-la-la-la-la la ♪
I thought you said she was dead.
That was her sister, the
Wicked Witch of the East.
This is the Wicked
Witch of the West,
and she's worse than
the other one was.
Who killed my sister? Who
killed the Witch of the East?
Was it you?
No. No, it was an accident. I
didn't mean to kill anybody.
Well, my little pretty, I
can cause accidents too.
Aren't you forgetting
the ruby slippers?
The slippers, yes.
The slippers.
They're gone.
The ruby slippers. What
have you done with them?
Give them back to me or I'll...
It's too late. There they
are, and there they'll stay.
Give me back my slippers. I'm the
only one that knows
how to use them.
They're of no use to you. Give
them back to me. Give them back.
Keep tight inside of them. Their
magic must be very powerful
or she wouldn't
want them so badly.
Stay out of this, Glinda,
or I'll fix you as well.
Rubbish. You have no power here.
Begone, before somebody
drops a house on you too.
Very well. I'll bide my time.
And as for you, my
fine lady, it's true I
can't attend to you here
and now as I'd like.
But just try to
stay out of my way.
Just try.
I'll get you, my pretty
and your little dog too.
It's all right. You can
get up. She's gone.
It's all right. You
can all get up.
What a smell of sulphur.
I'm afraid you've made an
enemy of the Wicked Witch.
The sooner you get out
of Oz altogether,
the safer you'll sleep, my dear.
Oh, I'd give anything to
get out of Oz altogether.
But which is the way back to
Kansas? I can't go the way I came.
No, that's true. The only
person who might know
would be the great and wonderful
Wizard of Oz himself.
The Wizard of Oz? Is he
good or is he wicked?
Very good, but very mysterious.
He lives in the Emerald City,
a long journey from here.
Did you bring your
broomstick with you?
- No, I'm afraid I didn't.
- Well then, you'll have to walk.
The Munchkins will see you safely
to the border of Munchkinland.
And remember, never let those ruby
slippers off your
feet for a moment
or you will be at the mercy of
the Wicked Witch of the West.
But how do I start
for Emerald City?
It's always best to
start at the beginning.
And all you do is follow
the Yellow Brick Road.
But what happens if I...
Just follow the Yellow Brick Road.
Goodbye.
My.
People come and go
so quickly here.
♪ Follow the Yellow Brick Road ♪
♪ Follow, follow, follow, follow,
follow the Yellow Brick Road ♪
♪ Follow the Yellow Brick ♪
♪ Follow the Yellow Brick Road ♪
♪ You're off to see the Wizard,
the wonderful Wizard of Oz ♪
♪ You'll find he is a whiz of a
wiz if ever a wiz there was ♪
♪ If ever, oh ever a wiz there was
the Wizard of Oz is one because ♪
♪ Because, because,
because, because, because ♪
♪ Because of the wonderful
things he does ♪
♪ You're off to see the Wizard,
the wonderful Wizard of Oz ♪
Follow the Yellow Brick Road?
Follow the Yellow...?
Now which way do we go?
Pardon me. That way
is a very nice way.
Who said that?
Don't be silly, Toto.
- Scarecrows don't talk.
- It's pleasant down that way too.
That's funny. Wasn't he
pointing the other way?
Of course, people do go both ways.
Why, you did say
something, didn't you?
Are you doing that on purpose,
or can't you make up your mind?
That's the trouble. I
can't make up my mind.
I haven't got a brain.
Only straw.
How can you talk if you
haven't got a brain?
I don't know.
But some people
without brains do an
awful lot of talking, don't they?
Yes, I guess you're right.
Well, we haven't really
met properly, have we?
Why, no.
- How do you do?
- Very well, thank you.
- I'm not feeling at all well.
You see, it's very
tedious being stuck up
here all day long with
a pole up your back.
Oh dear, that must be terribly
uncomfortable. Can't you get down?
Down? No, you see,
I'm... well I'm...
Well, here, let me help you.
Oh, that's very kind
of you. Very kind.
Oh dear, I don't quite
see, how I can...
Of course, I'm not bright
about doing things,
but if you'll just
bend the nail down in
the back, maybe I'll
slip off and come...
Yes.
- There goes some of me again.
- Does it hurt you?
No, I just keep picking it up
and putting it back in again.
My. It's good to be free.
Did I scare ya?
No, no, I just thought
you hurt yourself.
- But I didn't scare ya?
- No, of course not.
I didn't think so.
Boo. Scat. Boo.
You see? I can't
even scare a crow.
They come from miles
around just to
eat in my field and
laugh in my face.
I'm a failure, because
I haven't got a brain.
Well, what would you do with
a brain if you had one?
Do? Why, if I had a
brain, I could...
♪ I could while away the hours
conferring with the flowers ♪
♪ Consulting with the rain ♪
♪ And my head I'd be
scratching while ♪
♪ My thoughts were busy hatching ♪
♪ If I only had a brain ♪
♪ I'd unravel every riddle
for any individual ♪
♪ In trouble or in pain ♪
♪ With the thoughts
you'd be thinking ♪
♪ You could be another Lincoln ♪
♪ If you only had a brain ♪
♪ Oh, I could tell you why ♪
♪ The ocean's near the shore ♪
♪ I could think of things
I never thunk before ♪
♪ And then I'd sit and
think some more ♪
♪ I would not be just a nothing
my head all full of stuffing ♪
♪ My heart all full of pain ♪
♪ I would dance and be merry
life would be a ding-a-Derry ♪
♪ If I only had a brain ♪
Wonderful.
Why, if our scarecrow back
in Kansas could do that
the crows would be
scared to pieces.
They would?
- Where's Kansas?
- That's where I live.
I wanna get back
there so badly, I'm
going all the way to Emerald City
to get the Wizard
of Oz to help me.
You're going to see a wizard?
Do you think if I went with you,
this wizard would give me brains?
I couldn't say.
But even if he didn't, you'd be
no worse off than you are now.
- Yes, that's true.
- But maybe you better not.
I've got a witch mad at me, and
you might get into trouble.
Witch? I'm not afraid of a witch.
I'm not afraid of anything.
- Except a lighted match.
- I don't blame you for that.
But I'd face a whole
box full of them
for the chance of
getting some brains.
Look, I won't be any trouble,
because I don't eat a thing.
And I won't try to manage
things, because I can't think.
Won't you take me with you?
Why, of course I will.
Hooray. We're off to see a wizard.
You're not starting out very well.
I'll try. Really, I will.
- To Oz?
- To Oz.
♪ We're off to see the Wizard ♪
♪ The wonderful Wizard of Oz ♪
♪ We hear he is a whiz of a
wiz if ever a wiz there was ♪
♪ If ever, oh ever a wiz there was
the Wizard of Oz is one because ♪
♪ Because, because,
because, because, because ♪
♪ Because of the wonderful
things he does ♪
♪ We're off to see the Wizard,
the wonderful Wizard of Oz ♪
Apples.
Look.
What do you think you're doing?
We've been walking a long
ways and I was hungry and...
Did you say something?
- She was hungry.
Well... how would
like to have someone
come along and pick
something off you?
Dear. I keep forgetting
I'm not in Kansas.
Come along, Dorothy.
You don't want any
of those apples.
Are you hinting my apples
aren't what they ought to be?
No. It's just that she doesn't
like little green worms.
You.
I'll show you how to get apples.
Hooray. I guess that
did it. Help yourself.
Why, it's a man.
A man made out of tin.
Yes.
Look.
Did you say something?
He said "oil can."
- Oil can what?
- Oil can?
Here it is.
Where do you want
to be oiled first?
He said his mouth.
The other side.
My goodness. I can talk again.
Oil my arms, please.
Oil my elbows.
Here.
- Did that hurt?
- No, it feels wonderful.
I've held that axe up for ages.
Goodness. How did you
ever get like this?
Well, about a year ago
I was chopping that tree
when suddenly it began to rain.
And right in the middle of
a chop, I rusted solid.
And I've been that way ever since.
Well, you're perfect now.
My neck. My neck.
Perfect?
Bang on my chest if you
think I'm perfect.
Go ahead, bang on it.
Beautiful. What an echo.
It's empty.
The tinsmith forgot
to give me a heart.
- No heart?
No heart.
All hollow.
♪ When a man's an empty kettle ♪
♪ He should be on his mettle ♪
♪ And yet I'm torn apart ♪
♪ Just because I'm presuming
that I could be kind of human ♪
♪ If I only had a heart ♪
♪ I'd be tender, I'd be gentle
and awful sentimental ♪
♪ Regarding love and art ♪
♪ I'd be friends
with the sparrows ♪
♪ And the boy who
shoots the arrows ♪
♪ If I only had a heart ♪
♪ Picture me a balcony ♪
♪ Above, a voice sings low ♪
♪ Wherefore art thou, Romeo? ♪
♪ I hear a beat ♪
♪ How sweet ♪
♪ Just to register emotion
jealousy, devotion ♪
♪ And really feel the part ♪
♪ I could stay young and chipper
and I'd lock it with a zipper ♪
♪ If I only had a heart ♪
Are you all right?
I'm afraid I'm a little rusty yet.
Dear.
That was wonderful.
You know, we were just wondering
why you couldn't come with us
to the Emerald City to ask the
Wizard of Oz for a heart.
Oh, suppose the Wizard wouldn't
give me one when we got there.
But he will.
He must.
We've come such a
long way already.
You call that long?
Why, you've just begun.
Helping the little lady along,
are you, my fine gentlemen?
Well, stay away from her
or I'll stuff a mattress with you.
And you.
I'll use you for a beehive.
Here, scarecrow. Wanna play ball?
Fire. I'm burning. I'm burning.
I'm not afraid of her.
I'll see you get
safely to the Wizard
now, whether I get a brain or not.
Stuff a mattress with me.
I'll see you reach the Wizard,
whether I get a heart or not.
Beehive. Blah.
Let her try and make
a beehive out of me.
You're the best friends
anybody ever had.
And it's funny, but I feel as
if I've known you all the time.
- But I couldn't have, could I?
- I don't see how.
You weren't around
when I was stuffed
and sewn together, were you?
And I was standing over there
rusting for the longest time.
Still, I wish I could remember.
But I guess it doesn't
matter anyway.
We know each other now, don't we?
- That's right.
- We do.
- To Oz?
- To Oz.
♪ We're off to see the Wizard ♪
♪ The wonderful Wizard of Oz ♪
♪ We hear he is a whiz of a
wiz if ever a wiz there was
♪ If ever, oh ever a wiz there was
the Wizard of Oz is one because ♪
♪ Because, because,
because, because, because ♪
♪ Because of the wonderful
things he does ♪
♪ We're off to see the Wizard,
the wonderful Wizard of Oz ♪
I don't like this forest.
It's dark and creepy.
Of course, I don't
know, but I think
it'll get darker before
it gets lighter.
Do...
Do you suppose we'll
meet any wild animals?
We might.
Animals that eat straw?
Some, but mostly lions
and tigers and bears.
- Lions.
- And tigers?
And bears.
♪ Lions and tigers
and bears, oh, my ♪
Put 'em up. Put 'em up.
Which one of you first?
I'll fight you both
together, if you want.
I'll fight you with one
paw tied behind my back.
I'll fight you
standing on one foot.
I'll fight you with
my eyes closed.
Pulling an axe on me?
Sneaking up on me? Why...
Here, here. Go away
and let us alone.
Scared, huh?
Afraid, huh?
How long can you stay
fresh in that can?
Come on, get up and fight,
you shivering junk yard.
Put your hands up, you
lopsided bag of hay.
Now, that's getting
personal, Lion.
Yes, get up and
teach him a lesson.
What's wrong with
you teaching him?
Well, I hardly know him.
Well, I'll get you anyway, peewee.
Shame on you.
What did you do that
for? I didn't bite him.
No, but you tried to.
It's bad enough picking
on a straw man, but when
you go around picking
on poor little dogs...
Well, you didn't have to
go and hit me, did ya?
Is my nose bleeding?
Well, of course not.
My goodness, what a
fuss you're making.
Well, naturally,
when you go around
picking on things
weaker than you are...
Why, you're nothing but
a great big coward.
You're right, I am a coward.
I haven't any courage at all.
I even scare myself.
Look at the circles under my eyes.
I haven't slept in weeks.
Why don't you try counting sheep?
That doesn't do any good.
I'm afraid of 'em.
That's too bad.
Don't you think the Wizard
could help him too?
I don't see why not.
Why don't you come along with us.
We're on our way to see the
Wizard now. To get him a heart.
And him a brain.
I'm sure he could give
you some courage.
Wouldn't you feel
degraded to be seen
in the company of a cowardly lion?
I would.
No, of course not.
Gee, that's awfully nice of you.
My life has been
simply unbearable.
Well, it's all right now.
The Wizard will fix everything.
It's been in me so long.
I just gotta tell you how I feel.
Well, come on.
♪ Yeah, it's sad,
believe me, Missy ♪
♪ When you're born to be a sissy ♪
♪ Without the vim and verve ♪
♪ But I could show my prowess,
be a lion, not a mouse ♪
♪ If I only had the nerve ♪
♪ I'm afraid there's no denying
I'm just a dandy lion ♪
♪ A fate I don't deserve ♪
- ♪ I'd be brave as a blizzard
- I'd be gentle as a lizard ♪
♪ I'd be clever as a gizzard ♪
♪ If the Wizard is a
wizard who will serve ♪
♪ Then I'm sure to get a brain ♪
♪ A heart - A home ♪
♪ The nerve ♪
♪ We're off to see the Wizard,
the wonderful Wizard of Oz ♪
♪ We hear he is a whiz of a
wiz if ever a wiz there was ♪
♪ If ever, oh ever a wiz there was
The Wizard of Oz is one because ♪
♪ Because, because, because
because, because ♪
♪ Because of the wonderful
things he does ♪
♪ We're off to see the Wizard,
the wonderful Wizard of Oz ♪
So you won't take warning?
All the worse for you.
I'll take care of you
now, instead of later.
When I gain those ruby slippers
my power will be the
greatest in Oz.
And now, my beauties
something with poison
in it, I think.
With poison in it.
But attractive to the eye
and soothing to the smell.
Poppies.
Poppies will put them to sleep.
Sleep...
Now they'll sleep.
There's Emerald City.
We're almost there.
At last. At last.
It's beautiful, isn't it?
Just like I knew it would be.
He really must be a wonderful
Wizard to live in
a city like that.
Come on, what are we waiting for?
- Nothing. Let's hurry.
- Yes, let's run.
- Come on. Come on.
- Hurry. Hurry.
Look.
Come on. Come on.
Look at the scenery.
It's wonderful.
Emerald City.
What's happening?
What is it?
I can't run any more.
I'm so sleepy.
Here, give us your hand
and we'll pull you along.
No, please. I have to
rest for just a minute.
Toto. Where's Toto?
You can't rest now.
We're nearly there.
Don't cry. You'll
rust yourself again.
Come to think of it, 40
winks wouldn't be bad.
- Don't you start it too.
- No.
We ought to try and carry Dorothy.
I don't think I could,
but we could try.
- Let's.
- Yes.
Now look at him. This is terrible.
Here, Tin Man, help me.
This is terrible. I can't
budge her an inch.
This is a spell, this is.
It's the Wicked
Witch. What'll we do?
Help. Help.
It's no use screaming
at a time like this.
Nobody will hear you. Help. Help.
Help.
It's snowing.
No, it isn't.
Yes, it is.
Maybe that'll help.
But it couldn't help.
It does help. Dorothy,
you're waking up.
Unusual weather we're
having, ain't it?
Look. He's rusted again.
- Give me the oilcan, quick.
- Here.
- He is rusted.
- Quick.
Curses. Curses.
Somebody always helps that girl.
But shoes or no shoes, I'm still
great enough to conquer her.
And woe to those who
try to stop me.
Come on, let's get outta here.
Look. Emerald City is closer
and prettier than ever.
♪ You're out of the woods ♪
♪ You're out of the dark,
you're out of the night ♪
♪ Step into the sun,
step into the light ♪
♪ Keep straight ahead for
the most glorious place ♪
♪ On the face of the
earth or the sky ♪
♪ Hold on to your breath,
hold on to your heart ♪
♪ Hold on to your hope ♪
♪ March up to the gate
and bid it open ♪
To the Emerald City,
as fast as lightning.
♪ You're out of the woods ♪
♪ You're out of the dark,
you're out of the night ♪
♪ Step into the sun,
step into the light ♪
♪ March up to the
gate and bid it ♪
♪ Open ♪
Who rang that bell?
- We did.
- Can't you read?
- Read what?
- The notice.
- What notice?
- It's on the door.
As plain as the nose on my face.
"Bell out of order. Please knock."
Well. That's more like it.
Now, state your business.
We wanna see the Wizard.
The Wizard?
But nobody can see the great Oz.
Nobody's ever seen the great
Oz. Even I've never seen him.
Well then, how do you
know there is one?
Because he's...
You're wasting my time.
Please. Please, sir. I've
got to see the Wizard.
The Good Witch of
the North sent me.
Prove it.
She's wearing the ruby
slippers that she gave her.
So she is. Well, bust my buttons.
Why didn't you say that
in the first place?
That's a horse of a
different colour.
Come on in.
Cabby. Cabby.
Just what you're looking for. Take
you any place in
the city, we does.
Would you take us
to see the Wizard?
The Wizard? The Wizard? I can't...
Yes, of course. But first I'll
take you to a little place
where you can tidy up a bit, what?
Thank you so much.
We've been gone such a long
time, and we feel so mess...
What kind of a horse is that? I've
never seen a horse
like that before.
No, and never will again, I fancy.
There's only one of
him, and he's it.
He's the horse of a different
colour you've heard tell about.
♪ Ha-ha-ha, ho-ho-ho ♪
♪ And a couple of tra-la-Las ♪
♪ That's how we laugh the day away
in the merry old land of Oz ♪
♪ Bzz, bzz, bzz,
chirp, chirp, chirp ♪
♪ And a couple of la-di-das ♪
♪ That's how the
crickets crick all day ♪
♪ In the merry old land of Oz ♪
♪ We get up at 12 and
start to work at 1 ♪
♪ Take an hour for lunch
and then at 2 we're done ♪
♪ Jolly good fun ♪
♪ Ha-ha-ha, ho-ho-ho ♪
♪ And a couple of tra-la-Las ♪
♪ That's how we laugh the day away
in the merry old land of Oz ♪
♪ Ha-ha-ha, ho-ho-ho ♪
♪ Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha ♪
♪ That's how we laugh
the day away, with a ♪
♪ Ho-ho-ho, ha-ha-ha ♪
♪ In the merry old land of Oz ♪
♪ Pat, pat here, pat, pat there ♪
♪ And a couple of
brand-new straws ♪
♪ That's how we keep you young and
fair in the merry old land of Oz ♪
♪ Rub, rub, here,
rub, rub, there ♪
♪ Whether you're tin or bronze ♪
♪ That's how we keep you in repair
in the merry old land of Oz ♪
♪ We can make a dimpled
smile out of a frown ♪
♪ Can you even dye my
eyes to match my gown? ♪
♪ Jolly old town ♪
♪ Clip, clip, here,
clip, clip, there ♪
♪ We give the roughest claws ♪
♪ That certain air of savoir-faire
in the merry old land of Oz ♪
♪ That's how we laugh the day away
♪ That's how we laugh the
day away, with a ha-ha-ha ♪
♪ In the merry old land of Oz ♪
Who's her? Who's her?
It's the witch. She's
followed us here.
"Surrender, Dorothy."
Dorothy? Who's Dorothy?
- The Wizard will explain it.
- To the Wizard.
Dear. Whatever shall we do?
We better hurry if we're
gonna see the Wizard.
Here. Here, here.
Everything is all right.
Stop that now, just...
It's all right.
Everything is all right.
The great and powerful Oz has
got matters well in hand.
I hope.
So you can all go home. And
there's nothing to worry about.
Get outta here. Now
go on. Go on home.
Go home.
If you please sir,
we wanna see the
Wizard right away, all 4 of us.
Orders are, nobody can see the
great Oz. Not nobody. Not no how.
But... but please,
it's very important.
I got a permanent just
for the occasion.
Not nobody. Not no how.
But she's Dorothy.
The Witch's Dorothy?
Well, that makes a difference.
Just wait here. I'll
announce you at once.
Did you hear that? He'll
announce us at once.
I've as good as got my brain.
I can fairly hear
my heart beating.
I'll be home in time for supper.
In another hour, I'll
be King of the Forest.
Long live the King.
♪ If I were King of the Forest ♪
♪ Not Queen ♪
♪ Not Duke ♪
♪ Not Prince ♪
♪ My regal robes of the forest ♪
♪ Would be satin ♪
♪ Not cotton ♪
♪ Not chintz ♪
♪ I'd command each thing,
be it fish or fowl ♪
♪ With a woof ♪
♪ And a woof ♪
♪ And a royal growl ♪
♪ As I'd click my heel, all
the trees would kneel ♪
♪ And the mountains bow
and the bulls kowtow ♪
♪ And the sparrow
would take wing ♪
♪ If I ♪
♪ If I were King ♪
♪ Each rabbit would
show respect to me ♪
♪ The chipmunks genuflect to me ♪
♪ Though my tail would lash ♪
♪ I would show compash ♪
♪ For every underling ♪
♪ If I ♪
♪ If I were King ♪
♪ Just King ♪
♪ Monarch of all I survey ♪
♪ Monarch ♪
♪ Of all I survey ♪
Your Majesty, if
you were King, you
wouldn't be afraid of anything?
Not nobody. Not no how.
- Not even a rhinoceros?
- Imposserous.
How about a hippopotamus?
Why... I'd trash him
from top to "bottom-us."
Supposing you met an elephant?
I'd wrap him up in "cello-phant".
What if it were a brontosaurus?
I'd show him who's
King of the Forest.
- How?
Courage.
What makes a King out
of a slave? Courage.
What makes the flag on the
mast to wave? Courage.
What makes the elephant
charge his tusk
in the misty mist
or the dusky dusk?
What makes the muskrat
guard his musk? Courage.
What makes the sphinx the
7th Wonder? Courage.
What makes the dawn come
up like thunder? Courage.
What makes the Hottentot so hot?
What puts the "ape" in apricot?
What have they got
that I ain't got?
- Courage.
- You can say that again.
The Wizard says go away.
Go away?
Looks like we came a
long way for nothing.
And I was so happy.
I thought I was on my way home.
Don't cry Dorothy, we're
gonna get you to the Wizard.
We certainly are.
Auntie Em was so good to me
and I never appreciated it.
Running away and
hurting her feelings.
Professor Marvel
said she was sick.
She may be dying
and it's all my fault.
I'll never forgive myself.
Never, never, never.
Please don't cry any more.
I'll get you into
the Wizard somehow.
Come on. I had an
Aunt Em myself once.
Wait a minute, fellas.
I was just thinking,
I really don't
wanna see the Wizard this much.
I'd better wait for you outside.
- What's the matter?
- He's just scared again.
Don't you know the Wizard's
gonna give you some courage?
I'd be too scared
to ask him for it.
Well then, we'll ask him for you.
I'd sooner wait outside.
Why? Why?
Because I'm still scared.
- What happened?
- Somebody pulled my tail.
You did it yourself.
Here.
Come on.
Come forward.
Tell me when it's over.
Look at that. Look at that.
I wanna go home.
I am Oz
the great and powerful.
Who are you?
If you please,
I am Dorothy,
the small and meek.
We've come to ask you...
Silence.
Jiminy crickets.
The great and powerful Oz
knows why you have come.
Step forward
Tin Man.
You dare to come to me
for a heart, do you?
You clinking, clanking, clattering
collection of caliginous junk.
Yes, sir.
Yes, Your Honour.
You see
a while back, we were walking down
the Yellow Brick Road, and...
Quiet.
And you, Scarecrow,
have the effrontery
to ask for a brain,
you billowing bale
of bovine fodder.
Yes, Your Honour. I
mean, Your Excellency.
I mean, Your Wizardry.
Enough.
And you, Lion.
Well?
You ought to be
ashamed of yourself
frightening him like that
when he came to you for help.
Silence, whippersnapper.
The beneficent Oz
has every intention
of granting your requests.
What's that? What'd he
say? Huh? What'd he say?
But first, you must
prove yourselves worthy
by performing a very small task.
Bring me the broomstick
of the Witch of the West.
But if we do that, we'll
have to kill her to get it.
Bring me her broomstick
and I'll grant your requests.
Now go.
But what if she kills us first?
I said go.
"I'd turn back if I were you."
I believe there's
spooks around here.
That's ridiculous.
Spooks. That's silly.
Don't you believe in spooks?
No. Why, only...
Are you all right?
I do believe in spooks.
I do, I do, I do, I do.
I do believe in spooks. I
do, I do, I do, I do, I do.
You'll believe in more than that
before I'm finished with you.
Take your army to
the haunted forest
and bring me that
girl and her dog.
Do what you like with the others,
but I want her alive and unharmed.
They'll give you no trouble,
I promise you that.
I've sent a little insect on ahead
to take the fight out of them.
Take special care of those ruby
slippers. I want
those most of all.
Now, fly. Fly.
Bring me that girl
and her slippers.
Fly. Fly. Fly.
Help. Help.
Go away now.
Toto. Toto. Help.
Help. Help. Help.
What's happened to you?
They tore my legs off and
they threw them over there.
Then they took my chest out
and they threw it over there.
Well, that's you all over.
They sure knocked the stuffings
outta ya, didn't they.
Don't stand there gawking, put me
together. We've got
to find Dorothy.
Now, let's see...
What a nice little dog.
And you, my dear, what
an unexpected pleasure.
It's so kind of you to
visit me in my loneliness.
What are you gonna do with
my dog? Give him back to me.
All in good time,
my little pretty.
- All in good time.
- Please give me back my dog.
Certainly, certainly
when you give me those slippers.
But the Good Witch told me not to.
Very well.
Throw that basket in the
river and drown him.
No, here. You can have your old
slippers, but give me back Toto.
That's a good little girl.
I knew you'd see reason.
I'm sorry. I didn't do it.
Can I still have my dog?
No. Fool that I am, I
should have remembered
those slippers will never come off
as long as you're alive.
But that's not what's worrying
me, it's how to do it.
These things must
be done delicately
or you hurt the spell.
- Run, Toto, run.
- Catch him, you fool.
Run, Toto, run.
He got away. He got away.
Which is more than you will.
Drat, you and your dog.
You've been more
trouble to me than
you're worth, one way or another.
But it'll soon be over now.
Do you see that?
That's how much longer
you've got to be alive.
And it isn't long, my
pretty. It isn't long.
I can't wait forever
to get those shoes.
I'm frightened.
I'm frightened, Auntie
Em. I'm frightened.
Dorothy. Dorothy.
Where are you? It's
me. It's Auntie Em.
We're trying to find
you. Where are you?
I'm here in Oz, Auntie Em.
I'm locked up in
the Witch's castle
and I'm trying to get
home to you, Auntie Em.
Oh, Auntie Em, don't go away.
I'm frightened. Come
back. Come back.
"Auntie Em, Auntie Em. Come back."
I'll give you Auntie
Em, my pretty.
Look. There's Toto.
Where'd he come from?
Why, don't you see? He's
come to take us to Dorothy.
Come on, fellas.
I hope my strength holds out.
I hope your tail holds out.
What's that? What's that?
That's the castle of
the Wicked Witch.
- Dorothy's in that awful place?
- I hate to think of her in there.
- We've got to get her out.
- Don't cry now.
We haven't got the
oil can, and you've
been squeaking enough as it is.
Who's them? Who's them?
I've got a plan how
to get in there.
Fine, he's got a plan.
And you're gonna lead us.
- Me?
- Yes, you.
- I gotta get her outta there?
- That's right.
All right, I'll go in
there for Dorothy.
Wicked Witch or no Wicked Witch
guards or no guards,
I'll tear 'em apart.
I may not come out alive,
but I'm going in there.
There's only one thing I
want you fellas to do.
What's that?
Talk me out of it.
- No, you don't.
- Oh, no.
- Now, wait a minute.
- Up.
Come on, I've got another idea.
Do you think it would be
polite, dropping in like this?
Where do we go now?
There.
Wait. We better make sure.
Dorothy, are you in there?
- It's us.
- Yes.
It's me. She's locked me in.
We gotta get her
out. Open the door.
Hurry. Please hurry.
The hourglass is almost empty.
Stand back.
Toto. Toto. Lion.
I knew you'd come.
I knew you would.
Hurry, we've got no time to lose.
Going so soon? I
wouldn't hear of it.
Why, my little party's
just beginning.
Trapped. Trapped
like mice... rats.
That's right. Don't
hurt them right away.
We'll let them think
about it a little first.
Seize them. Seize them.
Stop them, you fools.
There they go. Now we've got them.
Half of you go this way,
half of you go that way.
Hurry. Hurry.
Where do we go now?
This way. Come on.
Back. Back.
Well.
Ring-around the Rosie, a
pocket full of spears.
Thought you'd be pretty
foxy, didn't you?
Well, the last to go will see
the first 3 go before her.
And her mangy little dog too.
How about a little
fire, Scarecrow?
Help. I'm burning. I'm
burning. It's burning. Help.
Don't throw that water.
You cursed brat. Look
what you've done.
I'm melting. Melting.
Oh, what a world. What a world.
Who would've thought a
good little girl like you
could destroy my
beautiful wickedness?
Look out. Look out.
I'm going.
She's dead. You've killed her.
I didn't mean to kill
her. Really, I didn't.
It's just that he was on fire.
Hail to Dorothy. The
Wicked Witch is dead.
Hail. Hail to Dorothy. The
The broom.
- May we have it?
- Please, and take it with you.
Thank you so much.
Now we can go back
to the Wizard and
tell him the Wicked Witch is dead.
The Wicked Witch is dead.
Can I believe my eyes?
Why have you come back?
Please, sir. We've
done what you told us.
We've brought you the broomstick
of the Wicked Witch of the West.
We melted her.
You liquidated her?
- Very resourceful.
- Yes, sir.
So we'd like you to keep your
promise to us, if you please, sir.
Not so fast. Not so fast.
I'll have to give the
matter a little thought.
Go away and come back tomorrow.
Tomorrow? But I wanna go home now.
You've had plenty of time already.
Do not arouse the wrath of
the great and powerful Oz.
I said come back tomorrow.
If you were really great and
powerful, you'd
keep your promises.
Do you presume to
criticise the great Oz?
You ungrateful creatures.
Think yourselves lucky that I'm
giving you audience tomorrow
instead of 20 years from now.
The great Oz has spoken.
Pay no attention to that
man behind the curtain.
The great and... Oz has spoken.
Who are you?
I am the great and
powerful Wizard of Oz.
You are? I don't believe you.
I'm afraid it's true. There's
no other Wizard except me.
You humbug.
Yes, that's exactly
so. I'm a humbug.
You're a very bad man.
No, my dear. I'm a very good man.
I'm just a very bad wizard.
What about the heart
you promised Tin Man?
And the courage you
promised Cowardly Lion?
- And Scarecrow's brain?
Why, anybody can have a brain.
That's a very mediocre commodity.
Every pusillanimous creature
that crawls on the earth
or slinks through slimy
seas has a brain.
Back where I come from,
we have universities,
seats of great learning, where
men go to become great thinkers.
And when they come out,
they think deep thoughts,
and with no more
brains than you have.
But they have one thing you
haven't got, a diploma.
Therefore, by virtue of the
authority vested in me,
by the Universitatus
Committeeatum E Pluribus Unum
I hereby confer upon you
- the honorary degree of Th.D.
- Th.D?
That's Doctor of Thinkology.
The sum of the square roots of any
2 sides of an isosceles triangle
is equal to the square root
of the remaining side.
Joy. Rapture.
I've got a brain.
- How can I ever thank you enough?
- Well, you can't.
As for you, my fine friend, you're
a victim of disorganised thinking.
You are under the
unfortunate delusion that
simply because you
run away from danger
you have no courage. You're
confusing courage with wisdom.
Back where I come from, we have
men who are called "heroes."
Once a year, they take their
fortitude out of mothballs
and parade it down the
main street of the city.
And they have no more
courage than you have.
But they have one thing that
you haven't got, a medal.
Therefore,
for meritorious conduct,
extraordinary valour,
conspicuous bravery
against wicked witches,
I award you the Triple Cross.
You are now a member of
the Legion of Courage.
Shucks folks, I'm speechless.
As for you, my galvanised
friend, you want a heart.
You don't know how lucky
you are not to have one.
Hearts will never
be practical until
they can be made unbreakable.
But I still want one.
Back where I come
from, there are men
who do nothing all
day but good deeds.
They are called philo... philo...
goodeedoers. And their hearts
are no bigger than yours.
But they have one thing you
haven't got, a testimonial.
Therefore, in consideration
of your kindness
I take pleasure at this
time in presenting you
with a small token of our
esteem and affection.
And remember, my
sentimental friend,
that a heart is not judged
by how much you love
but by how much you
are loved by others.
It ticks.
Listen. Look, it ticks.
Read what my medal
says... "Courage."
Ain't it the truth.
They're all wonderful.
Hey, what about Dorothy?
Yes, how about Dorothy?
- Yeah, Dorothy next.
- Yeah, Dorothy...
I don't think there's anything
in that black bag for me.
Well, you force me into
a cataclysmic decision.
The only way to get
Dorothy to Kansas
is for me to take
her there myself.
Will you? Could you?
But are you a clever enough
wizard to manage it?
Child, you cut me to the quick.
I'm an old Kansas man myself,
born and bred in the heart
of the western wilderness,
premier balloonist par
excellence to the
Miracle Wonderland
Carnival Company.
Until one day, while performing
spectacular feats of
stratospheric skill
never before attempted
by civilised man
an unfortunate phenomena
occurred. The
balloon failed to
return to the fair.
- It did?
- Weren't you frightened?
Frightened? You are
talking to a man
who has laughed in
the face of death,
sneered at doom and chuckled at
catastrophe. I was petrified.
Then, suddenly the wind changed
and the balloon floated down into
the heart of this noble city
where I was instantly acclaimed
Oz, the First Wizard Deluxe.
Times being what they
were, I accepted the job
retaining my balloon against
the advent of a quick getaway.
And in that balloon,
my dear Dorothy
you and I will return to the
land of E Pluribus Unum.
My friends. I mean, my friends.
This is positively the finest
exhibition ever to be shown,
be that as it may.
I, your Wizard per ardua ad alta,
am about to embark
upon a hazardous
and technically
unexplainable journey
into the outer stratosphere.
To confer, converse
and otherwise hobnob
with my brother wizards.
And I hereby decree
that until what time,
if any, that I return,
the Scarecrow, by virtue of
his highly superior brains
shall rule in my stead,
assisted by the Tin Man, by
virtue of his magnificent heart
and the Lion, by
virtue of his courage.
Obey them as you
would me. Thank you.
Toto. Come back. Toto.
Don't go without me.
I'll be right back.
Stop that dog.
This is a highly
irregular procedure.
This is absolutely unprecedented.
- Ruined my exit.
- Come back. Come back.
Don't go without me.
Please come back.
I can't come back. I
don't know how it works.
Goodbye, folks.
Goodbye.
Now I'll never get home.
Stay with us then, Dorothy.
We all love you.
We don't want you to go.
That's very kind of you
but this could never
be like Kansas.
Auntie Em must have
stopped wondering
what happened to me by now.
Scarecrow, what am I gonna do?
Look.
Here's someone who can help you.
Will you help me? Can you help me?
You don't need to be
helped any longer.
You've always had the power
to go back to Kansas.
I have?
Then why didn't you
tell her before?
Because she wouldn't have believed
me. She had to learn
it for herself.
What have you learned, Dorothy?
Well,
I think that it...
that it wasn't enough just to want
to see Uncle Henry and Auntie Em.
And it's that, if
I ever go looking
for my heart's desire again,
I won't look any further
than my own back yard
because if it isn't there
I never really lost
it to begin with.
Is that right?
That's all it is.
But that's so easy. I should've
thought of it for you.
I should've felt it in my heart.
No, she had to find
it out for herself.
Now those magic slippers will
take you home in 2 seconds.
- Toto too?
- Toto too.
- Now?
- Whenever you wish.
Dear, that's too
wonderful to be true.
It's...
it's gonna be so
hard to say goodbye.
I love you all too.
Goodbye, Tin Man.
Don't cry.
You'll rust so dreadfully.
Here, here's your oilcan.
- Goodbye.
- Now I know I've got a heart
because it's breaking.
Goodbye, Lion. You know,
I know it isn't right
but I'm gonna miss the way
you used to holler for help
before you found your courage.
I would never have found it
if it hadn't been for you.
I think I'll miss you most of all.
- Are you ready now?
- Yes.
Say goodbye, Toto.
- Yes, I'm ready now.
- Then close your eyes
and tap your heels
together 3 times
and think to yourself:
"There's no place like home."
There's no place like home.
- Wake up, honey.
- There's no place like home.
There's no place like home.
There's no...
Dorothy. Dorothy dear,
it's Aunt Em, darling.
Auntie Em, it's you.
- Yes, darling.
- Hello there. Anybody home?
I just dropped by
because I heard the
little girl got
caught in the big...
Well, she seems all right now.
She got quite a bump on the head.
We kinds thought there for a
minute, she was gonna leave us.
But I did leave you, Uncle
Henry, that's just the trouble.
And I tried to get back
for days and days.
There, there, lie quiet now.
- You just had a bad dream.
- Sure.
Remember me,
your old pal, Hunk?
And me, Hickory?
You couldn't forget
my face, could ya?
No, but it wasn't a
dream, it was a place.
And you and you and you
and you were there.
But you couldn't have
been, could you?
We dream lots of silly
things when we...
No, Aunt Em, this was a
real, truly live place.
And I remember that some
of it wasn't very nice
but most of it was beautiful.
But just the same,
all I kept saying
to everybody was, "I
want to go home."
And they sent me home.
Doesn't anybody believe me?
Of course we believe you, Dorothy.
But anyway, Toto, we're home.
Home. And this is my room
and you're all here.
And I'm not going to leave
here ever, ever again
because I love you all.
And... Auntie Em,
there's no place like home.