I never knew
the old Vienna before the war
with its Strauss music,
its glamour and easy charm.
Constantinople suited me better.
I really got to know it in
the classic period of the black market.
We'd run anything if people wanted it
enough and had the money to pay.
Of course, a situation like that
does tempt amateurs.
But, well, they, you know, they can't stay
the course like a professional.
Now the city, it's divided
into four zones, you know,
each occupied by a power, the American,
the British, the Russian and the French.
But the centre of the city,
that's international,
policed by an international patrol,
one member of each of the four powers.
Wonderful. What a hope they had,
all strangers to the place,
and none of them
could speak the same language,
except a sort of smattering of German.
Good fellows, on the whole.
Did their best, you know.
Vienna doesn't really look any worse
than a lot of other European cities.
Bombed about a bit.
Oh, I was gonna tell you. Wait.
I was gonna tell you about Holly Martins,
an American, came all the way
here to visit a friend of his.
The name was Lime. Harry Lime.
Now, Martins was broke,
and Lime had offered him
some sort, I don't know,
some sort of a job.
Anyway, there he was, poor chap,
happy as a lark and without a cent.
- Passport, please.
- Oh.
- What's the purpose of your visit here?
- Friend of mine offered me a job here.
- Where are you staying?
- With him. 15 Stiftgasse.
- His name?
- Lime. Harry Lime.
- Okay.
- Thought he'd be here to meet me.
- Speak English?
- English?
Uh...
Little. Little.
Uh, 10 minutes too late.
- Already gone.
- Who?
Um, his friends and the, uh... no.
- Uh, coffin.
- Coffin?
Mr Lime's. An accident.
Knocked over by a car,
here in front of the house.
Have seen it myself.
Killed at once, immediately.
Already in hell,
or in heaven.
Sorry for the gravediggers.
Hard work. It is frost.
Can you tell me, uh... who's the...
A fellow called Lime.
Like a lift to town?
I've got a car here.
Thanks.
- My name's Calloway.
- Martins.
- You a friend of Lime?
- Yeah.
- Been here long?
- No.
You've had a bit of a shock, haven't you?
You could do with a drink.
Could you buy me one?
I haven't got any Austrian...
- Of course.
- Thanks.
Schmolka.
I guess nobody knew Harry like he did.
- Like I did.
- How long ago?
Back in school.
I was never so lonesome
in my life till he showed up.
- When did you see him last?
- September '39.
- When the business started?
- Mmm-hmm.
- See much of him before that?
- Once in a while.
- Best friend I ever had.
- That sounds like a cheap novelette.
I write cheap novelettes.
I'm afraid I've never heard of you.
What's your name again?
- Holly Martins.
- No, sorry.
You ever hear of The Lone Rider
of Santa Fe?
Can't say that I have.
- Death at Double-X Ranch?
- Uh... "Ranch."
- Nope.
- Hmm.
He must've known I was broke.
He even sent me an aeroplane ticket.
- It's a shame.
- What?
Him dying like that.
Best thing that ever happened to him.
What are you trying to say?
He was about the worst racketeer
that ever made a dirty living in this city.
- Policeman, huh?
- Come on, have another drink.
No, I never did like policemen.
I have to call them sheriffs.
- Ever seen one?
- Pin it on a dead man.
Some petty racket
with gasoline or something.
Just like a cop.
You're a real cop, I suppose.
- It wasn't petrol.
- So it wasn't petrol.
So it was tyres or saccharin or...
Why don't you catch
a few murderers for a change?
Well, you could say that murder
was part of his racket.
It's all right, Paine. He's only
a scribbler with too much drink in him.
Take Mr Holly Martins home.
Holly Martins, sir?
The, uh... the writer?
The author of Death at Double-X Ranch?
- Listen, Callaghan...
- Calloway. I'm English, not Irish.
You're not going to close your
files at a dead man's expense.
So you're going to find me the real criminal?
Sounds like one of your stories.
When I'm finished with you,
you'll leave Vienna, you'll look so silly.
Here's some army money. It should see
you through tonight at Sacher's Hotel,
if you don't drink too much in the bar.
We'll keep a seat for you
on tomorrow's plane.
Please be careful, sir. Up we come.
- Written anything lately?
- Take him to Sacher's.
Don't hit him again if he behaves.
And you go carefully there.
It's a military hotel.
I'm so glad to have met you, sir.
I've read quite a few of your books.
I like a good western.
That's what I like about them, sir.
You can pick them up
and put them down anytime.
- Oh, Mr Hardtmuth.
- Yes, sir?
Major Calloway said this gentleman's
gotta have a room for the night.
- He'll be off tomorrow.
- Passport, please.
Can't very well introduce you
to everybody.
Would you mind filling this in?
- Mr Crabbin.
- What is it, Sergeant?
- Mr Holly Martins, sir.
- Who?
- The author. Thought you might be interested.
- Never heard of him.
He's very good, sir.
I've read quite a few of his books.
Have you, Sergeant? Author? Martins?
Thank you, Sergeant.
Mr Martins? My name's Crabbin.
I represent the CRS of GHQ.
- You do?
- Yes. Cultural Re-education Section.
Uh, propaganda. Very important
in a place like this.
We do a little show each week.
Last week we had Hamlet.
- The week before we had, um, something.
- The striptease, sir.
Yes, the Hindu dancers.
Thank you, Sergeant.
This is the first opportunity we've had
of making an American author welcome.
- Welcome?
- Now, I'll tell you what, Mr Martins.
On Wednesday night, at our institute,
we're having a little lecture
on a contemporary novel.
- Thought perhaps you'd like to speak.
- They wouldn't know me.
Oh, nonsense. Your novels are very
popular here. Aren't they, Sergeant?
- Very popular, sir.
- Very popular. Are you staying long?
How long can one stay here
on this stage money?
Listen, Mr Martins,
if you'd agree to be our guest,
we'd be delighted to have you.
- Would you?
- As long as you care to stay.
But he's due to leave tomorrow, sir.
Excuse me. Have you got a toothache?
- Number 8, Mr Martins.
- Come upstairs a moment.
- I know a very good dentist.
- I don't need a dentist.
Somebody hit me, that's all.
Goodness. We must report that to the police.
Were they trying to rob you?
Oh, just a soldier. I was trying
to punch his major in the eye.
- No. A major? Were you really?
- Heard of Harry Lime?
Well, I've heard of him, of course,
but I didn't exactly know him.
I was going to stay with him,
but he died Thursday.
Goodness, that's awkward.
That what you say to people after death?
"Goodness, that's awkward"?
Mr Martins. Excuse me. Telephone.
- Who is it?
- Baron Kurtz.
Must be some mistake. Yes?
I was a friend of Harry Lime.
I'd very much like to meet you, Baron.
Come around.
Austrians aren't allowed in your hotel.
- Couldn't we meet at the Mozart Cafe?
- Where?
- Just around the corner.
- How will I know you?
I'll carry a copy of one of your books.
Harry gave it to me.
Be there in a moment. Wait a minute.
If I do this lecture business,
you'll put me up here a while?
- Certainly.
- It's a deal.
You ever read a book of mine called
The Lone Rider of Santa Fe?
No, not that one, sir.
It's a story about a man
who hunted down a sheriff
who was victimizing his best friend.
- Seems exciting.
- It is.
I'm gunning just the same way
for your Major Callaghan.
Sounds anti-British, sir.
- Baron Kurtz?
- Mr Martins?
Delighted to meet you.
Come, let's sit down here.
- What would you like? Tea? Coffee?
- Coffee.
It's wonderful how you keep the tension.
- Tension?
- Suspense.
You really liked it?
At the end of every chapter
you are left guessing
what he'll be up to next.
So, you were a friend of Harry's?
I think his best. Except you, of course.
The police have a crazy notion that
he was mixed up in some sort of a racket.
Everyone in Vienna is. We all sell
cigarettes and that kind of thing.
I tell you, I've done things that would
have seemed unthinkable before the war.
Once when I was hard up,
I sold some tyres on the black market.
I wonder what my father would have said.
I'm afraid the police meant
more than that.
They get rather absurd ideas sometimes.
He's somewhere now
he won't mind about that.
Even so, I'm not going
to leave it at this.
Will you help me?
I wish I could.
But, you know, I am an Austrian.
I have to be careful with the police.
I'm afraid I can't help you.
Except with advice, of course.
Advice.
We came out of his place like this,
and were walking this way.
A friend of his called to him
from over there.
Harry went across,
and from up there came the truck.
It was just about here.
Here?
Yes.
His friend and I picked him up.
Carried him across over here.
It was a terrible thing. Terrible.
We laid him down just about here.
And this is where he died.
Even at the end,
his thoughts were of you.
What did he say?
I can't remember the exact words, Holly.
I may call you Holly, mayn't I?
He always called you that to us.
He was anxious I should
look after you when you arrived,
to see that you got safely home,
tickets, you know, and all that.
But you said he died instantaneously.
Well, he died before
the ambulance could reach us.
Well, there was only you and this, uh...
this friend of his. Uh, who was he?
A Romanian. Mr Popescu.
I'd like to talk to him.
He has left Vienna.
- Uh, excuse me.
- Yes?
- Did you know Mr Lime well?
- Mr Lime? Yes.
- You remember me. Upstairs.
- Yes, I remember you.
Who used to visit Mr Lime?
Visit? Eh...
- What did he say?
- He says he doesn't know everybody.
Excuse me.
Who was at the funeral besides you?
Only his doctor, Dr Winkel.
Wasn't there a girl there?
Some girl of the Josefstadt Theatre.
You know what Harry was.
You oughtn't to speak to her.
It would only cause her pain.
Not necessarily.
She'd probably want to help.
What's the good of another post-mortem?
Suppose you dig up something,
well, discreditable to Harry?
- Would you give me your address?
- I live in the Russian sector.
But you'll find me at
the Casanova Club every night.
One has to work the best way one can,
you know.
- What's the name of this girl?
- I don't know.
I don't think I ever heard it.
You did mention the theatre.
Josefstadt.
But I still think it won't do
Harry any good.
You'd do better to think of yourself.
I'll be all right.
Of course. I'm so glad I've met you.
A master of suspense!
Such a good cover, I think.
- Number 8, please.
- Major Calloway's compliments, sir.
- Here's the ticket for the plane tomorrow.
- You tell the major I won't need it.
Oh, porter, order me a ticket tonight
for the Josefstadt Theatre.
- Ah, Mr Martins.
- Good evening, Mr Crabbin.
He said I was to drive you
to the airfield,
or take you to the bus, sir.
Whichever you prefer.
Didn't you hear Mr Crabbin offer me
the hospitality of the HQ BMT?
I was a friend of Harry Lime.
Afterwards.
Uh, Miss Schmidt?
Oh, come in.
- Thank you.
- Sit down.
Thank you. I enjoyed the play very much.
Excuse me.
You were... You were awfully good.
Do you understand German?
No. Excuse me.
I could follow it fine.
- Oh, yes.
- Perhaps Harry told you about me.
My name is Holly Martins.
- No, he never told me about his friends.
- Oh.
- Would you like some tea?
- Thank you.
Someone threw me this packet last week.
Sometimes the British do instead
of flowers, you know, on the first night.
That was a bouquet, too, from an American.
Would you rather have whisky?
Oh, tea's fine.
Good. I wanted to sell it.
- Oh, there is some tea left.
- Had you known him some time?
- Yes.
- I wanted to talk to you. No, thank you.
I wanted to talk to you about him.
There's nothing really to talk about,
is there? Nothing.
Well, I saw you at the funeral.
I'm so sorry. I didn't notice much.
You were in love with him, weren't you?
I don't know.
How can you know
a thing like that afterwards?
I don't know anything any more,
except I want to be dead, too.
Some more tea?
No. No tea.
Would you like a cigarette?
Oh, American. Thank you. I like them.
I was talking to another friend
of Harry's, a Baron Kurtz.
- Do you know him?
- No.
- He's got a little dog.
- Oh, yes, yes.
Don't understand what Harry saw
in a fellow like that.
That was the man who brought me
some money when Harry died.
He said Harry had been
anxious at the last moment.
Hmm. He said he remembered me, too.
Seems to show he wasn't in much pain.
Dr Winkel told me that.
Dr Winkel? Who's he?
A doctor Harry used to go to.
He was passing just after it happened.
- His own doctor?
- Yes.
Well, were you at the inquest?
Yes. They said it wasn't
the driver's fault.
Harry had often said what
a careful driver he was.
- He was Harry's driver?
- Mmm-hmm.
Well, uh... I don't get it.
All of them there!
Uh, Kurtz, this Romanian, uh... Popescu,
his own driver knocking him over,
his own doctor just passing by.
No strangers there at all.
I know.
I've wondered about it 100 times,
if it really was an accident.
What difference does it make?
He's dead, isn't he?
- But if it wasn't an...
- Fräulein Schmidt.
I must hurry.
They don't like us to use the lights.
- The porter saw it happen.
- Then why worry?
Look, do you know that porter?
Yes.
- What's he saying?
- He says it happened right down there.
Happened, yes.
Happened right down there.
- You saw it?
- Well, not saw, heard.
Heard. I heard the brakes.
And I got to the window and saw them
carry the body to the other side,
uh... of the Josef, the Josef...
Emperor Josef statue.
Why didn't they bring him in the house?
- Could he have been conscious?
- Conscious?
Uh, was he still alive?
Ah, alive! He couldn't have been alive,
not with his head in the way it was.
I was told that he did not die at once.
No, I mean that...
No, you...
- He was quite dead.
- He was... Oh, yeah. He was quite dead.
He was quite dead.
But this sounds crazy.
If he was killed at once,
how could he have talked about me
and this lady here after he was dead?
Why didn't you say
all this at the inquest?
Uh, it's better not to be
mixed up in things like this.
Things like what?
I was not the only one
who did not give evidence.
Who else?
Three men helped to carry
your friend to the statue.
- Kurtz?
- Yes.
- The Romanian?
- And?
- There was a third man.
He didn't give evidence.
- You don't mean the doctor?
- No, no, no.
He came later, after they carried him
to the Josef statue.
What did this man look like?
I didn't see his face.
He didn't look up. He was, uh...
quite, uh... gewöhnlich, ordinary.
He... He might have been
just anybody.
Just anybody.
Hello? Hello.
Hello.
Hello?
Who was that?
I don't know. They didn't answer.
But I was told
there were only two men there.
You've got to tell your story
to the police.
The police? Why police?
It's nonsense! It is all nonsense!
It was an accident.
You don't know it was an accident.
You only saw a dead man
with three men carrying him.
I should have listened to my wife.
She said you were up to no good. Gossip.
Suppose I take your evidence
to the police?
Now, hold on.
I have no evidence.
I saw nothing, I said nothing.
- It's not my business.
- Well, make it your business.
Hold on.
I have always liked you,
but you must not bring this gentleman again.
You must go at once, please. Please!
Please!
You shouldn't get mixed up in this.
Well, if I do find out something,
can I look you up again?
Why don't you leave this town? Go home.
What is it?
What's she talking about?
The police. They are searching my room.
- What the devil?
- Getting around, Martins?
Oh, pinning things on girls now.
Miss Schmidt, I should like
to see your papers, please.
Don't you give him anything.
Thank you.
You were born
in Graz of Austrian parents?
Yes.
Paine.
Hmm.
It's very good, sir, isn't it, eh?
How much did you pay for this?
I'm afraid I shall have to keep
this for a while, Miss Schmidt.
How do you expect her to live
in this city without her papers?
Write her out a receipt, Paine.
- And give her a receipt for those letters, too.
- This way, miss.
I suppose it wouldn't interest you
to know that Harry Lime was murdered.
You're too busy. You haven't even
bothered to get the complete evidence.
- Must you take those?
- They'll be returned, miss.
They are private letters.
That's all right, miss. Don't worry.
We're used to it. Like doctors.
There was a third man there. I suppose
that doesn't sound peculiar to you.
I'm not interested in whether
a racketeer like Lime
was killed by his friends
or by an accident.
The only important thing
is that he's dead.
- I'm sorry.
- Tactful, too, aren't we, Callaghan?
- Calloway.
- Must you take those letters?
- Yes, I'm afraid so.
- They're Harry's.
- That's the reason.
- You won't learn anything from them.
They're only love letters.
There are not many of them.
They'll be returned to you, Miss Schmidt,
as soon as they've been examined.
There's nothing in them.
Harry never did anything.
Only a small thing once,
out of kindness.
And what was that?
You've got it in your hand.
Major Calloway.
- Finished?
- Yes. Okay.
You will have to come
with us, Miss Schmidt.
You're not locking her up.
Go home, Martins,
like a sensible chap.
You don't know what you're mixing in.
Get the next plane.
As soon as I get to the bottom of this,
I'll get the next plane.
Death's at the bottom of everything, Martins.
Leave death to the professionals.
Mind if I use that line
in my next western?
You can't chuck me out.
My papers are in order.
Here we are, miss.
Your receipt for the letters.
I don't want it.
Well, I've got it
when you want it, miss.
Anything really wrong with your papers?
They're forged.
Oh.
Why?
The Russians would claim me.
I come from Czechoslovakia.
What's she saying?
Only complaining about the way
they behave in her house.
Give her some cigarettes.
- Uh, cigarettes, hmm?
- Danke.
Miss Schmidt, ready?
Now, look,
I'll, uh... straighten out
all this nonsense about Harry.
You'll be all right.
Sometimes he said I laughed too much.
Oh, what's the name of that doctor?
Harry's doctor?
- Dr Winkel.
- What do you want to see a doctor for? Hmm?
- A bruised lip.
- Good.
Laboratory,
we're coming right down.
You wait here, Miss Schmidt.
Is Dr Winkel in?
- Dr Winkel. I'm sorry. I don't speak German.
- Nein.
Please, won't you say that
I'm a friend of Harry Lime?
Thank you.
- Dr Winkel?
- "Winkel."
Uh, Dr Winkel.
Quite a collection of, uh... collection.
Yes.
Come, come, come...
Is that your dog?
Yes. Would you mind, Mr, uh...
- Martins.
- Martins, coming to the point, please?
- Thank you.
- I have guests waiting.
- We were both friends of Harry Lime.
- I was his medical adviser.
I want to find out all I can.
- Find out?
- Hear the details.
I can tell you very little.
He was run over by a car.
He was dead when I arrived.
Who was with him?
Two friends of his.
You sure? Two?
Quite sure.
Could he have been at all conscious?
I understand he was, yes,
for a short time,
while they carried him across the road.
- In great pain?
- Mmm, not necessarily.
Could he have been capable
of making plans,
for me and others just...
Just during those few moments?
I understand he left some
instructions before he died.
I cannot give an opinion.
I was not there.
My opinion is, uh...
limited to the causes of death.
Have you any reason to be dissatisfied?
Was it possible that his death
might have been
not accidental?
Could he have been...
Pushed, Dr Winkel?
"Winkel."
I cannot give an opinion.
The injuries to the head and skull
would have been the same.
Major, may I see you
for a moment, please?
Certainly, Brodsky. What is it?
This forgery is very clever,
and we are interested in this case.
- Have you arrested the girl?
- No, not yet.
Please, keep this passport to yourself
until I make some inquiries. Will you, Major?
- Yes, of course.
- Thank you.
Right, sit down, Miss Schmidt.
We'll send your letters
and things back to you.
- And my passport?
- We'll need that for a while longer.
What did he mean?
You know as much as I do.
Miss Schmidt,
you were intimate
with Lime, weren't you?
We loved each other. Do you mean that?
- Do you know this man?
- I've never seen him.
- Joseph Harbin.
- No.
- He works in a military hospital.
It's stupid to lie to me, Miss Schmidt.
I'm in a position to help you.
I'm not lying.
You're wrong about Harry.
You're wrong about everything.
In one of his letters,
he asked you to telephone
a good friend of his called Joseph.
He gave you the number
of the Casanova Club.
That's where a lot of friends
of Lime used to go.
It wasn't important.
What was the message?
Something about meeting Harry
at his home.
Harbin disappeared
the day you telephoned.
We've got to find him.
You can help us.
What can I tell you, but
you've got everything upside down.
Okay.
That American friend of yours
is still waiting for you.
He won't do you much good.
I thank you, Miss Schmidt.
We'll send for you when we want you.
Hello, Mr Martins. I've been trying
to get you at your hotel.
I've arranged that lecture for tomorrow.
- Well, what about?
- On the modern novel.
- You remember what we arranged.
- Oh.
Now, they want you to talk
on the crisis of faith.
- What's that?
- Oh, I thought you'd know. You're a writer.
But of course you do.
Good night, young man.
Oh, I've forgotten my hat.
- I'll let you know the time later.
- Mmm.
- Drink?
- Whisky.
Two whiskies.
How much?
Oh, they don't take army money here.
How much did he say?
- Harry?
- Yes.
He moved his head,
but the rest is good, isn't it?
- Good evening, Miss Schmidt.
- Good evening.
You've found out my little secret.
A man must live.
How goes the investigation?
- Have you proved the policemen are wrong?
- Not yet.
But you will. Our friend Dr Winkel
said you had called.
- Wasn't he helpful?
- Well, he was, uh... limited.
- But Mr Popescu is here tonight.
- The Romanian?
- Yes, the man who helped carry him.
- I thought he'd left Vienna.
He's back now.
Well, I'd like to meet
all of Harry's friends.
I'll bring him to you.
Haven't you done enough for tonight?
The porter said three men carried
the body, and two of them are here.
Who are you looking for now?
Ssh, ssh. Don't. Don't. Please don't.
Silly-looking bunch.
- Mr Popescu, Mr Martins.
- How do you do?
- Any friend of Harry is a friend of mine.
- I'll leave you together.
- Good evening, Miss Schmidt.
- You remember me?
- Of course.
- I helped Harry fix her papers, Mr Martins.
- Oh, you did?
Not the sort of thing
I should confess to a stranger,
but you have to break
the rules sometimes.
Humanity is a duty.
Cigarette, Miss Schmidt?
Keep the pack.
I understand you were with Harry...
Two double whiskies.
It was a terrible thing.
I was just crossing the road
to go to Harry.
He and the Baron were on the sidewalk.
Maybe if I hadn't started to cross the road,
it wouldn't have happened.
I can't help blaming myself
and wishing things had been different.
Anyway, he saw me and stepped
off the sidewalk to meet me.
And the truck...
It was terrible, Mr Martins. Terrible.
I've never seen a man killed before.
I think there was something funny
about the whole thing.
- Funny?
- Something wrong.
Of course there was.
Some ice for Mr Martins.
You think so, too, hmm?
It was so terribly stupid
for a man like Harry
to be killed in an ordinary
street accident.
- That's all you meant?
- What else?
Who was the third man?
I oughtn't to drink it.
It makes me acid.
What man would you be
referring to, Mr Martins?
I was told that a third man
helped you and Kurtz carry the body.
Oh, I don't know how you got that idea.
You'll find all about it
in the police report.
There was just the two of us.
Me and the Baron.
Who could have told you
a story like that?
The porter at Harry's place.
He was cleaning the window at the time.
And saw the accident?
No, no, he didn't see the accident,
but he saw three men carrying the body.
Why wasn't he at the police inquiry?
He didn't want to get involved.
You'll never teach these Austrians
to be good citizens.
It was his duty to give the evidence.
Even so, he remembers wrong.
What else did he tell you?
That Harry was dead
before you got him to that statue.
He probably knows a lot more than that.
- Somebody's lying.
- Hmm, not necessarily.
The police say he was
mixed up in some, uh... racket?
Oh, that's quite impossible.
He had a great sense of duty.
Your friend Kurtz
seems to think it was possible.
I understand how an Anglo-Saxon feels.
The Baron hasn't travelled, you know?
He seems to have been around a bit.
Do you know a man called, uh... Harbin?
- No.
- Joseph Harbin.
Joseph Harbin? No. No.
That's a nice girl, that,
but she ought to go careful in Vienna.
Everybody ought to go careful
in a city like this.
He will meet us at the bridge. Good.
Hello! Is it so very important for you?
- Yes, it is.
- I am not a bad man.
I'd like to tell you something.
Tell me, how did the car...
Ssh, ssh.
Come tonight. My wife goes out.
- All right, I'll come back, but...
- Shh! Tonight.
Does that mean come in?
Oh, yes, yes. Come in.
The porter's going to talk
to us tonight.
Need we go through it all again?
I can manage by myself. You busy?
Just another part I've got to learn.
Can I hear you?
- In German?
- I can try.
Is it comedy or tragedy?
Comedy. I don't play tragedy.
- Do I, uh... read...
- Well, you read this.
Oh. Well, uh...
- What's that?
- Uh, Heurigen, I guess.
H-E-Z-T...
Oh, let me see.
No, no, that's not the cue.
It means she has to sit down.
Well, uh... Frau Hausman...
No, no.
It's no good.
Bad day?
It's always bad about this time.
He used to look in around 6:00.
I've been frightened.
I've been alone without friends and money.
But I've never known anything like this.
- Please talk. Tell me about him.
- Tell you what?
Oh, anything. Just talk.
Where did you see him last?
When? What did you do?
Oh, we didn't make much sense.
We drank too much.
- Once he tried to steal my girl.
- Where is she?
Oh, that was nine years ago.
Tell me more.
Well, it's very difficult.
You knew Harry.
We didn't do anything very amusing.
He just made everything
seem like such, uh... fun.
Was he clever when he was a boy?
I suppose so. He could fix anything.
- What sort of things?
- Oh, little things.
How to put your temperature up
before exam. The best crib.
Uh, how to avoid this and that.
He fixed my papers for me.
He heard the Russians
were repatriating people like me
who came from Czechoslovakia.
He knew the right person
straightaway for forging stamps.
Yeah.
When he was 14,
he taught me the three-card trick.
That's growing up fast.
He never grew up.
The world grew up
around him, that's all.
And buried him.
Anna.
You'll fall in love again.
Don't you see I don't want to?
I don't ever want to.
Come on out and have a drink.
Why did you say that?
Seemed like a good idea.
It was just what he used to say.
Well, uh... I didn't learn that
from him.
If we have to see the porter,
we'd better go.
What's the hurry? Can't we talk quietly
for a couple of minutes?
I thought you wanted...
A moment ago, you said
you didn't want to see the porter.
We're both in it, Harry.
- Holly.
- I'm so sorry.
It's all right.
You might get my name right.
You know, you ought to
find yourself a girl.
His English is so very bad,
we'll let him talk German.
If you'll just be good enough to...
Look.
- That's Harry's place, isn't it?
- Yes.
- Let's go away.
- What's the matter?
Let's not get into any more trouble.
Wait here.
What's the matter?
Uh, what is, uh...
I... I don't understand.
Um, porter, uh... dead.
Kaputt.
The porter is...
- Porter?
- He's murdered.
I, uh... don't understand.
- What is it?
- The porter's been murdered.
They think you did it.
Papa!
Their money's no good.
Sneak out the other way
and go back to your theatre.
I'd better not see you again.
- What are you going to do?
- I wish I knew.
Be sensible. Tell Major Calloway.
- Get me Major Callaghan on the phone.
- Oh, Mr Martins.
It's very urgent.
Just get him on the telephone.
Uh, do you know his number?
- No, I don't know his number.
- I'll look it up for you.
Is there a car here I can use?
Of course. There's one waiting for you.
Never mind about the number.
Take me to the headquarters...
Hold on! Hold on! I haven't even
told you where to take me yet!
Driver! Driver!
Slow down!
Have you got orders to kill me?
Ah, Mr Martins!
What a relief to see you.
I was beginning to think
something had happened to you.
Come along, Mr Martins.
Everything's ready for you.
I was frantic in case you hadn't
got my message at the hotel.
The porters out here are so unreliable,
if you know what I mean.
We're all set for a wonderful meeting.
You'll find the audience
most appreciative.
Oh, let me take your coat. I've got it.
There'll be refreshments afterwards.
Come along, Mr M. Follow me.
Well, here we are, ladies and gentlemen.
All's well that ends well.
Would you look after those for me?
Thank you.
Would you like to sit there, Mr Martins?
That's right.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I have much pleasure in introducing
Mr Holly Martins from the other side.
Well...
Bring the car and anyone
else who'd like to come.
Don't be long. Hmm.
Yeah, well, I...
I suppose that is what I meant to say.
Of course, of course, of course.
Do you believe, Mr Martins,
in the stream of consciousness?
Stream of consciousness? Well, uh...
Well, uh...
What author
has chiefly influenced you?
- Grey.
- Grey? What Grey?
- Zane Grey.
- That's Mr Martins' little joke, of course.
We all know perfectly well
Zane Grey wrote what we call "westerns."
Cowboys and bandits.
Mr James Joyce.
Now, where would you put him?
Oh, uh... would you mind
repeating that question?
I said, where would you put
Mr James Joyce?
In what category?
Can I ask, is Mr Martins
engaged on a new book?
Yes. It's called The Third Man.
- A novel, Mr Martins?
- It's a murder story.
I've just started it.
It's based on fact.
Why, it's Mr Popescu!
Oh, very great pleasure
to see you here, Mr Popescu.
As you know, ladies and gentlemen,
Mr Popescu is a very great supporter
of one of our medical charities.
Are you a slow writer, Mr Martins?
Not when I get interested.
I'd say you were doing something
pretty dangerous this time.
- Yeah?
- Mixing fact and fiction.
- Should I make it all fact?
- Why, no, Mr Martins.
I'd say stick to fiction.
Straight fiction.
I'm too far along
with the book, Mr Popescu.
Haven't you ever
scrapped a book, Mr Martins?
Never.
Pity.
Ladies and gentlemen, if there are
no more questions for Mr Martins,
I think I can call the meeting
officially closed.
Who's there? Who is it?
Who is it?
It's all right. It's all right.
I told you to go away, Martins.
This isn't Santa Fe, I'm not a sheriff
and you aren't a cowboy.
You've been blundering around with
the worst bunch of racketeers in Vienna,
your precious Harry's friends,
and now you're wanted for murder.
- Put down drunk and disorderly, too.
- I have.
- What's the matter with your hand?
- Parrot bit me.
Oh, stop behaving like a fool, Martins.
I'm only a little fool. I'm an amateur at it.
You're a professional.
You've been shaking
your cap and bells all over town.
Paine, get me the Harry Lime file,
and get Mr Martins a large whisky.
I don't need your drinks, Calloway.
You will. I don't want
another murder in this case
and you were born to be murdered,
so you're going to hear the facts.
You haven't told me a single one yet.
- Have you ever heard of penicillin?
- Well?
In Vienna, there hasn't been
enough penicillin to go around.
So a nice trade started here.
Stealing penicillin
from the military hospitals,
diluting it to make it go further
and selling it to patients.
- Do you see what that means?
- Are you too busy
chasing a few tubes of penicillin
to investigate a murder?
These were murders.
Men with gangrened legs,
women in childbirth,
and there were children, too.
They used some of this
diluted penicillin against meningitis.
The lucky children died.
The unlucky ones went off their heads.
You can see them now in the mental ward.
That was the racket
Harry Lime organised.
Calloway, you haven't shown me
one shred of evidence.
We're just coming to that.
Paine, magic lantern show.
Very good, sir.
You know,
Paine's one of your devoted readers.
He's promised to lend me one of your books.
Which one is it, Paine?
The Lone Rider of Santa Fe, sir.
That's right. The Lone Rider
of Santa Fe.
I'd like to visit Texas one day, sir.
Come on. Show me
what you've got to show.
- All right, Paine?
- Yes, sir.
Paine, Paine, Paine.
I got them muddled.
It's the new lot
that's just come in for Mr Crabbin.
See this man here? A fellow called Harbin,
a medical orderly at the general hospital.
He worked for Lime and helped
to steal the stuff from the laboratories.
We forced him to give information to us
which led us as far as Kurtz and Lime.
But we didn't arrest them,
as our evidence wasn't complete
and it might have spoiled
our chances of getting the others.
- Next, Paine.
- I'd like a word with this orderly Harbin.
- So would I.
- Well, bring him in.
I can't. He disappeared a week ago.
This is more like a mortuary
than police headquarters.
We have better witnesses. Look here.
How could he have done it?
£70 a tube.
Go back to the hotel,
and do keep out of trouble.
I'll try and fix things with the Austrian
police. You'll be all right in the hotel
but I can't be responsible
for you on the streets.
I'm not asking you to.
I'm sorry, Martins.
I'm sorry, too.
You still got
that aeroplane ticket on you?
We'll send one across
to your hotel in the morning.
Thank you. Excuse me.
Get me Austrian police headquarters.
Can I have that woman's passport?
You know, the Anna Schmidt one.
Oh...
We're not going to pick her up for that,
are we?
What can we do?
We have our instructions.
Me.
It's me.
Hello.
What is it?
What's happened to you?
Just came to see you.
Come in. I thought you
were going to keep away.
Are the police after you?
I don't know.
- You're drunk, aren't you?
- A bit. I'm sorry.
But I did want to say goodbye
before I pushed off.
- I'm going back home.
- Why?
It's what you've always wanted.
All of you.
Kitty? Here, kitty.
Kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty.
Don't you want to play, kitty?
Aw, sleepy? Sleepy, kitty?
Not very sociable, is he?
No, he only liked Harry.
What made you decide so suddenly?
Uh, I brought you these, uh.
They got a little wet.
- What happened to your hand?
- A parrot...
- Let it go.
- Have you seen Calloway?
Imagine a parrot nipping a man.
- Have you?
- It's...
Oh, I...
I've been saying goodbye
all over, you know.
He told you, didn't he?
Told me?
About Harry.
Do you know?
I've seen Major Calloway today.
He's better dead.
I knew he was mixed up,
but not like that.
I knew him for 20 years.
At least, I thought I knew him.
Suppose he was laughing
at fools like us all the time?
- He liked to laugh.
- £70 a tube.
He wanted me to write
for his great medical charity.
I'll put these flowers in the water.
Perhaps I could have raised
the price to £80 for him.
Oh, please. For heaven's sake,
stop making him in your image.
Harry was real.
He wasn't just your friend and my lover.
- He was Harry.
- Well, don't preach wisdom to me.
You talk about him
as if he had occasional bad manners.
No. I don't know. I'm just a
hack writer who
drinks too much and
falls in love with girls.
You.
- Me?
- Don't be such a fool. Of course.
If you'd rung me up and asked me
were you fair or dark
or had a moustache,
I wouldn't have known.
Oh, I am leaving Vienna.
I don't care whether Harry was murdered
by Kurtz or Popescu or the third man.
Whoever killed him,
there was some sort of...
Justice.
Maybe I would've killed him myself.
A person doesn't change
because you find out more.
Look. I've got a splitting headache,
and you stand there
and just talk and talk and talk.
I... I hate it.
That's the first time
I ever saw you laugh.
Do it again.
There isn't enough for two laughs.
I'd make comic faces and
stand on my head and grin at you
between my legs
and tell all sorts of jokes...
I wouldn't stand a chance, would I?
Hmm.
Well...
You did tell me
I ought to find myself a girl.
What kind of a spy do you think you are,
satchel foot?
What are you tailing me for?
Cat got your tongue?
Come on out.
Come out, come out, whoever you are.
Step out in the light,
and let's have a look at ya.
Who's your boss?
Harry.
Harry!
I followed his shadow until suddenly...
Well?
This is where he vanished.
- I see.
- I suppose you don't believe me.
- No.
- Look. I tell you...
- You don't think I'm blind, do you?
- Yes.
Where were you when you saw him first?
Fifty yards right down there.
Which side of the road?
I was on that side.
His shadow was on that side.
And there are no turnings
on either side.
What about the doorways?
- I tell you, I heard him running ahead of me!
- Yes, yes, yes.
And then he vanished out there, I suppose,
with a puff of smoke and like a clap of...
It wasn't the German gin.
Well, what's this? Where are we?
It's the main sewer.
Runs right into the blue Danube.
Smells sweet, doesn't it?
We should have dug deeper than a grave.
You knew him, Major?
Hmm. Yes.
Yes. Joseph Harbin.
Medical orderly at the general hospital.
- He used to work for Harry Lime.
- Joseph Harbin?
Yes.
He's the man I told you was missing.
Next time we'll have
a fool proof coffin.
Where are you taking me?
International police headquarters,
just to check up.
I'm sorry, miss. It's orders.
We can't go against the protocol.
I don't even know what protocol means.
Neither do I, miss.
Mademoiselle, your lipstick.
Thank you.
Anna, what's happened to you?
- All right, all right. Keep out of this.
- Listen, I've got to talk to you.
- I've just seen a dead man walking.
- All right, chum. Get back.
- I saw him buried.
- Have you?
And now I've seen him alive.
Just a minute. Bring her in here.
You stay out here.
Come in, Miss Schmidt.
Now then, Miss Schmidt,
I'm not interested in your forged papers.
That's purely a Russian case.
When did you last see Lime?
Two weeks ago.
I want the truth, Miss Schmidt.
We know he's alive.
It is true, then.
Joseph Harbin's body
was found in the coffin.
What did you say? I'm sorry.
I said another man
was buried in his place.
Where's Harry?
That's what we want to find out.
I'm sorry. I don't seem able
to understand anything you say. I...
He is alive.
Now this minute, he is doing something.
Miss Schmidt, we know he's somewhere
across the canal in the Russian sector.
You may as well help us.
In a few minutes, Colonel Brodsky will
be questioning you about your papers.
- Tell me where Lime is.
- I don't know.
If you help me,
I am prepared to help you.
Martins always said you were a fool.
Vienna is a closed city, Miss Schmidt.
He can't get away. Right.
Poor Harry.
I wish he was dead.
He would be safe from all of you then.
Why, that's you! Come up.
Winkel, look who is here.
I want to speak to you, Kurtz.
- Of course. Come up.
- I'll wait here.
- I don't understand.
- I want to talk to Harry.
- Are you mad?
- All right. I'm mad.
I've seen a ghost.
You tell Harry I want to see him.
Be reasonable. Come up and talk.
No, thank you. I like the open.
Tell him I'll wait by that wheel there.
Or do ghosts only rise
by night, Dr Winkel?
You got an opinion on that?
Hello, old man. How are you?
Hello, Harry.
Well, well, they seem to be giving you
quite some busy time.
- Well, listen.
- Hmm, yes?
- I want to talk to you.
- Talk to me?
Well, of course. Come on.
Kids used to ride this thing
a lot in the old days.
But they haven't the money now,
poor devils.
Listen, Harry. I didn't believe that...
It's good to see you, Holly.
I was at your funeral.
That was pretty smart, wasn't it?
Oh, the same old indigestion, Holly.
These are the only things
that help, these tablets.
These are the last. Can't get 'em
anywhere in Europe any more.
- Do you know what's happened to your girl?
- Hmm?
- She's been arrested.
- Tough. Very tough. But don't worry, old man.
- They won't hurt her.
- They're handing her over to the Russians.
What can I do, old man?
I'm dead, aren't I?
- You can help somehow.
- Holly...
Exactly who did you tell about me, hmm?
- I told the police.
- Unwise, Holly.
- And Anna.
- Unwise.
Did the, uh... police believe you?
You don't care anything at all
about Anna, do you?
I've got quite a lot on my mind.
- You wouldn't do anything.
- What do you want me to do?
- Be reasonable.
- Get somebody else to…
- Do you expect me to give myself up?
- Why not?
It's a far, far better thing that
I do, with the old limelight, the
fall of the curtain. No.
Holly, you and I aren't heroes.
The world doesn't make any heroes...
- You've got plenty of contacts.
- ...outside of your stories.
I've got to be so careful.
I'm only safe in the Russian zone. I'm only
safe here as long as they can use me.
- As long as they can use you?
- I wish I could get rid of this thing.
So that's how they found out about Anna.
You told them, didn't you?
Don't try to be a policeman, old man.
- What do you expect me to be? Part of your...
- Part?
You can have any part you want
as long as you don't interfere.
I've never cut you out of anything.
Yes, I remember when they raided the
gambling joint, you knew a safe way out.
- Sure!
- Yeah, safe for you. Not safe for me.
Old man, you never should have
gone to the police, you know.
You ought to leave this thing alone.
Have you ever seen any of your victims?
You know, I never feel comfortable
on these sort of things.
Victims? Don't be melodramatic.
Tell me.
Would you really feel any pity
if one of those dots stopped moving forever?
If I offered you £20,000
for every dot that stopped,
would you really, old man,
tell me to keep my money?
Or would you calculate how many
dots you could afford to spare?
Free of income tax, old man.
Free of income tax.
The only way you can
save money nowadays.
A lot of good your money
will do you in jail.
That jail's in another zone.
There's no proof against me...
Besides you.
I should be pretty easy to get rid of.
Pretty easy.
I wouldn't be too sure.
I carry a gun.
I don't think they'd look for a bullet wound
after you hit that ground.
They dug up your coffin.
And found Harbin?
Mmm-hmm.
Pity.
Holly.
What fools we are
talking to each other this way
as though I'd do anything to you
or you to me.
You're just a little mixed up
about things in general.
Nobody thinks in terms of human beings.
Governments don't. Why should we?
They talk about the people
and the proletariat.
I talk about the suckers and the mugs.
It's the same thing.
They have their five-year plans,
and so have I.
You used to believe in God.
Oh, I still do believe in God, old man.
I believe in God and mercy and all that.
But, the dead are happier dead.
They don't miss much here, poor devils.
What do you believe in?
Well, if you ever get Anna out of this mess,
be kind to her. You'll find she's worth it.
I wish I had asked you to bring me
some of those tablets from home.
Holly, I would like
to cut you in, old man.
There's nobody left
in Vienna I can really trust,
and we have always done
everything together.
When you make up your mind,
send me a message.
I'll meet you any place, any time.
And when we do meet, old man,
it is you I want to see, not the police.
Remember that, won't you?
And don't be so gloomy.
After all, it's not that awful.
Remember what the fellow said.
In Italy, for 30 years under the Borgias
they had warfare, terror, murder
and bloodshed,
but they produced Michelangelo,
Leonardo da Vinci and the Renaissance.
In Switzerland, they had brotherly love.
They had 500 years of democracy and peace,
and what did that produce? The cuckoo clock.
So long, Holly.
But, look here, Martins.
You can always arrange to meet him at
at some little cafe
here in the international zone.
- It wouldn't work.
- We'll never get him in the Russian zone.
Calloway, you expect too much.
Oh, I know he deserves to hang,
you proved your stuff. But
20 years is a long time.
Don't ask me to tie the rope.
Okay, forget it.
- Busy, Major?
- What is it, Brodsky?
We have identified the girl.
Here is her report.
I've questioned her.
We've got nothing against her.
We shall apply for her
at the Four Power meeting tomorrow.
She has no right to be here.
I've asked your people
to help with Lime.
That's a different case.
It is being looked into.
So long, Major.
In the last war, a general would
hang his opponent's picture on the wall.
He got to know him that way.
I'm beginning to know Lime.
I think this would have worked,
with your help.
What price would you pay?
Name it.
Here we are. You'll be
all right here, miss.
I don't understand Major Calloway.
I expect he's got
a soft spot for you, miss.
Why has he done all this?
Don't you worry, miss.
You're well out of things.
There we are, miss.
- Thank you, you have been so kind.
- Well, I'll be saying good night.
- Good night, miss.
- Goodbye.
Are you going, too?
Oh...
What are you doing here?
I wanted to see you off.
See me off? From here?
Oh, I watched you out on the train.
Uh, no harm in that, is there?
How did you know I would be here?
I heard something about it
at police headquarters.
Have you been seeing
Major Calloway again?
Of course not. I don't live
in his pocket.
Harry, what is it?
For heaven's sake,
stop calling me Harry.
I'm sorry.
Hey, come on.
What is on your mind?
Why did you hide here?
Hide? Can't a fellow
have a drink?
- Here, it will be cold on that train.
- I shall be all right.
You send me a wire
as soon as you are.
What is going to happen?
Where is Harry?
- He's safe in the Russian zone.
- How do you know?
- Oh, I saw him today.
- How is he?
He can look after himself,
don't worry.
- Did he say anything about me? Tell me.
- Oh, the usual things.
There's something wrong.
Did you tell Calloway about meeting Harry?
- Of course I didn't tell Calloway.
- Why should he help me like that?
- The Russians will only make trouble for him.
- Oh, that's his headache.
- His?
- Oh, well.
Why are you lying?
We're getting you
out of here, aren't we?
I'm not going.
You...
Anna, don't you recognise a good turn
when you see one?
You have seen Calloway.
What are you two doing?
Well, they
they asked me to help take him,
and I'm helping.
Poor Harry.
Poor Harry?
Poor Harry
wouldn't even lift
a finger to help you.
Oh, you've got your precious honesty
and don't want anything else.
You still want him.
I don't want him any more.
I don't want to see him, hear him,
but he is still part of me. That's a fact.
I couldn't do a thing to harm him.
Oh, Anna, why do we always
have to quarrel?
If you want to sell your services,
I'm not willing to be the price.
I loved him. You loved him.
What good have we done him?
Love.
Look at yourself.
They have a name for faces like that.
- Oh, Calloway.
- Oh, there you are.
- Come in here, there isn't much time.
- I want to get a plane out of here tonight.
- So she talked you out of it.
- She gave me these.
A girl of spirit.
She's right.
It is none of my business.
It won't make any
difference in the long run.
I'll get him.
Well, I won't have helped.
That'll be a fine boast to make.
Well, I always wanted you
to catch that plane, didn't I?
You all did.
I'd better see if there's anyone still
at the terminus. You may need a priority.
Do you mind if I drop off
somewhere on the way?
I've got an appointment,
it won't take five minutes.
- Of course.
- Why don't you come in, too?
You're a writer. It might interest you.
This is the biggest children's hospital
in Vienna.
All the kids in here are the result
of Lime's penicillin racket.
It had meningitis.
They gave it some of Lime's penicillin.
Terribly pity, isn't it?
Paine lent me one of your books,
Oklahoma Kid, I think it was.
I read a bit of it. Looks as if
it's going to be pretty good.
What made you take up
this sort of thing?
Been doing it for long?
All right, Calloway. You win.
I never knew there were
snake charmers in Texas.
- I said, you win.
- Win what?
I'll be your dumb decoy duck.
Psst!
Paine.
Look, sir.
How much longer
are you going to sit here?
Shall I go over there, sir?
No, no. Leave them for a while.
Nein, danke. Nein.
Balloons?
Go on, hop it, scarper!
Come on.
All right, all right. Only one.
Go on, scarper.
You should have gone.
- How did you know I was here anyway?
- From Kurtz.
They have just been arrested.
But Harry won't come, he's not a fool.
Yes, Paine. Slip over there.
See what she is up to.
Right, sir.
Don't tell me
you're doing all this for nothing.
What is your price this time?
No price, Anna.
Honest, sensible, sober,
harmless Holly Martins.
Holly, what a silly name.
You must feel very proud
to be a police informer.
Harry, get away! The police are outside.
- Quick!
- Anna.
Shoot him!
In the back!
All right.
Martins, get back!
Harry!
- Is that you?
- You're through, Harry.
Come out! You haven't
got a chance this way.
- What do you want?
- You might as well give up.
Mr Martins, sir, get back!
Get back!
Keep back, sir, come back!
Hey, come back, sir!
Martins! Martins!
Be careful, Martins!
Don't take any chances!
If you see him, shoot!
What time is it?
2:30.
I'll have to step on it,
if you're going to catch that plane.
Calloway, can't you
do something about Anna?
I'll do what I can,
if she'll let me.
- Wait a minute. Let me out.
- Well, there's not much time.
One can't just leave. Please.
Be sensible, Martins.
I haven't got a sensible name, Calloway.
Sync by Lez
using Subtitle Edit