♪ Seize upon that
moment long ago ♪
♪ One breath away and
there you will be ♪
♪ So young and carefree ♪
♪ Again you will see ♪
♪ That place in time ♪
♪ So gold ♪
♪ Still away into
that way back when ♪
♪ You thought that all
would last for ever ♪
♪ But like the weather ♪
♪ Nothing can ever
and be in time ♪
♪ Stay gold ♪
♪ But can it be when we can see ♪
♪ So vividly a memory ♪
♪ And "yes" you say ♪
♪ So must the day too fade away ♪
♪ And leave a ray of sun ♪
♪ So gold ♪
♪ Life is but a
twinkling of an eye ♪
♪ Yet filled with
sorrow and compassion ♪
♪ Though not imagined all
things that happen ♪
♪ Will age too old ♪
♪ Though gold ♪
♪ Gold, though gold ♪
♪ When I stepped out ♪
♪ Into the bright sunlight ♪
♪ From the darkness
of the movie house ♪
♪ I had only two
things on my mind ♪
♪ Paul Newman and a ride home ♪
"This is Ames, mister."
Hey, look. Greaser.
Wash all that grease out
of your hair, Greaser.
Take a shower.
♪ Don't you cramp my style
I'm a real wild child ♪
♪ Come on, baby, shake
all night long ♪
♪ I'm gonna keep on moving, baby ♪
♪ Don't you cramp my style
I'm a real wild child ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Well, I'm gonna pick
you up in my 88 ♪
♪ Get ready, sugar,
but don't be late ♪
♪ We're gonna move
it all night long ♪
♪ Until a whole lot of
shaking gonna be done ♪
♪ I'm a wild one Oh,
yeah, I'm a wild one ♪
♪ I'm gonna keep on shaking I'm
gonna keep on moving, baby ♪
♪ Don't you cramp my style
I'm a real wild child ♪
Hey, Greaser. Yeah. We're gonna
give him a haircut. Get him, guys.
Get him down.
♪ Don't you cramp my style
I'm a real wild child ♪
Stick it. Stick it
in. Go on. Do it.
Maybe over here. Or
maybe how about there?
Shut him up.
- Let's get out of here.
- Come on. Let's go.
- Hey.
- Get off.
Them over there.
Son of a bitch.
We'll get you later, Greaser.
Greaser. Greaser.
♪ Watch out ♪
They didn't hurt you
too bad, did they?
- No.
- Hey, Pony.
- Did they pull a blade on you?
- Yeah.
Hey, they ain't gonna hurt
you no more. Come on.
Walking by yourself.
You don't ever think.
All's I did was walk
home from the movies.
Movies and books.
You know, I wish that you could
concentrate on something else
just once in a while.
Why don't you concentrate on
girls and cars? It works for me.
Look, if you had
to go by yourself,
you should have carried a blade.
Oh, yeah, that would
have been a great excuse
for the Socs to cut his
neck a little more there.
If I want my kid
brother to tell me
what to do with my
other kid brother,
I'll ask you, all
right, kid brother.
Geez, Soda. Why's he always
got to be like that?
He's just got more
worries than he used to.
- How's it, kid?
- I'm fine.
What are you doing out
of the cooler, Dal?
Yeah? And what are
you doing walking
by your lonesome on
the street, huh?
It's none of your business, Marty.
It is my business.
Look at my nose.
It's huge.
Smartass. He is a smartass kid.
- Hey, Dally. How you doing?
- I'm doing all right, man.
Thought you were in for
about 90 days, Dal.
Yeah, I got out early, man.
Good behaviour, you know.
Hey, Johnny, man.
How you doing, bro?
Things would go a lot better,
if the Socs stayed on the
southside of town, man.
Don't worry. We're gonna have it
out with them sooner or later.
We sure as hell are. They keep
coming over to our side of town.
Damn right.
Those the same guys that got you?
No. They were other guys.
Now that I'm out, I'm
gonna make it my business
to get the guy who did
that to your face.
What about me becoming your
personal body guard, huh, Ponyboy?
I don't think it's
too hot of an idea.
How about you and
Sylvia coming over
to game with us tomorrow night?
- I wanna go.
- Oh, we're taking Evie and Sandy.
- Which means no kids allowed.
- Big deal.
Nah, nah, nah. I'm gonna
go hunt some action.
If little kids are allowed.
We'll go with you, won't we, Pony?
I don't know, Dal. I can't get
in no trouble with the cops.
Darry says the court will
split us up for sure if I do.
Who's looking for
police trouble, man?
I wanna see a movie like the
good old days, right, Johnny?
All right. Six o'clock.
I was planning on putting down
a couple of six packs of Bud,
but if I don't get too
drunk, I'll join you all.
Check this out, buddy.
You guys wanna give
me a push-start?
Not really, but we will.
All right. Let's go.
See you guys later.
I see you got your
Christopher back, Dal.
Little broad was two-timing me
again when I was in jail, man.
It's cool. I'll see
you guys later.
- All right.
- See you later, Dal.
Hey, Ponyboy, you got homework.
You going home, Johnny Cade?
I don't know.
- See you around.
- All right.
Turn off these lights
and get to bed.
I got work in the morning.
We leave them alone.
I don't know.
Who can figure it?
- Are you cold, Pony?
- A little.
Hey, listen, kiddo.
Darry yells at you like that.
He don't mean nothing.
It's just that he got hit with
a lot of responsibilities
after Mum and Dad died
he ain't used to.
He loves you a lot.
Sure.
Soda?
How come you dropped
out of school?
Cos I'm dumb.
The only things I was passing
was automechanics and gym.
- You're not dumb.
- Yeah, I am.
Hey, you shut up, and I'll
tell you something, though.
You got to promise me that
you're not gonna tell Darry.
All right.
I think I'm gonna marry Sandy.
I'll probably wait till
you're out of school, though,
so I can help Darry with
the bills and stuff.
Soda?
Soda, are you in love with Sandy?
What's it like?
What's the time?
It's real nice.
♪ At just about midnight ♪
♪ She makes me feel so good ♪
♪ She makes me feel all right ♪
Hey, what's going
on, Dal? What's up?
- We're early.
- What do you wanna do?
Nothing legal, man. Let's get out.
♪ G-L-O-R-l-A, Gloria ♪
♪ I'm gonna shout loud
it all night Gloria ♪
♪ I'm gonna shout it
every day Gloria ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
How you doing, Joe?
♪ Gloria ♪
♪ G-L-O-R-l-A, Gloria ♪
♪ I'm gonna shout
it loud all night ♪
♪ Gloria ♪
♪ I'm gonna shout it every day ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
Hey, Soda, here come the hobos.
Hey, Sodapop, I ain't got no cash.
Anyone want to buy a
windscreen wiper?
- Come on, Dally.
- Give them the money.
So, what's the movie about?
Dallas. Huh?
I don't know, Johnny. One
of those beach movies.
You know, they put out
a whole bunch of them.
♪ At just about midnight ♪
♪ She makes me feel so good ♪
Hey, did I say you guys could
play on my grass, huh?
- No.
- Well, what are you doing here?
Give me those cards, will you?
♪ When she comes to my house ♪
You guys ever played 52 pick-up?
What?
Hey, don't get, don't get wise.
I don't like little kids. I
don't like them. I just...
♪ G-L-O-R-l-A, Gloria ♪
Get out of here, or I'll kill you.
♪ I'm gonna shout loud
it all night Gloria ♪
Go.
Get out of here, you little brats.
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
The sky's getting dark. Let's go.
Let's go, man.
Do you think Fanny
might have been right?
Why are you always worried?
Any reason she should be?
No reason at all.
For you either
Hey, Stella. Come here
- What do you think you're doing?
- Cherry, just relax.
I mean, just try. You're
supposed to be my girlfriend.
Don't ever pull anything
like that again.
Are you serious? Don't
do this to me, Cherry.
I'm not going back there.
I don't understand. I mean...
They wanna make
things complicated.
- Hey, Wayne, bring me a Coke.
- I don't have enough money.
Baby, you wanna see
what's hanging?
I'm gonna hang you, Two-Bit.
Are you sure you wanna do this?
I came here to see a movie,
and I'm gonna see a movie.
I'm freezing, man.
Why didn't you bring
a coat, stupid?
I forgot.
Some cute redhead, huh?
Are you a real redhead, huh?
Come on, Dal.
Are you real?
How can I find out if this is
your, your, your real red hair?
If this is the same red hair
that you have on your, your...
These eyebrows here. Is it?
Cut it out, Dal.
Get your feet off my
chair, and shut your trap.
- Who's gonna make me, huh?
- I'm gonna get a Coke.
- Who? Your boyfriend?
- Leave her alone, Dal.
That's the Greaser who just got
out of some jail or something.
Yeah, sure. Whatever
you say, honey.
Leave us alone, or
I'll call the cops.
Oh, my, my. You got
me scared to death.
What am I, what am I
gonna do now, Pony, huh?
This girl痴 making me shake.
Why don't you leave us alone?
Be nice and leave us alone.
I'm never nice.
Can I interest you in
a Coca-Cola or a 7UP?
Get lost, hood.
Hey, I'm sorry. I didn't...
I didn't know...
I didn't know you had this problem
with... yelling in my face.
Ok. All right. I'll go. I
know when I'm not wanted.
God. Your filthy Greaser.
Are you gonna start
on us now, too?
No.
You don't look the type,
anyway. What's your name?
Ponyboy Curtis.
That's an original name.
Yeah, my dad, he was
an original person.
I got a brother named Sodapop. It
says so on his birth certificate.
My name's Sherry, but my friends
call me Cherry cos of my hair.
I know. We go to the same
school. You're a cheerleader.
Yeah.
You don't look old enough
to be going to high school.
What's a nice boy like you doing
hanging around with that trash?
Dally's my buddy.
I'm a Greaser, too.
- We're all friends.
- I'm sorry. I didn't know.
Your brother, Sodapop, he works at
the gasoline station,
right? At DX.
Yeah, that's him.
Yeah, Soda's the cute one.
I should have known
you were brothers.
Hey, how come we don't see your
brother at school any more?
Has he been working full time
since your parents died?
- He's a dropout.
- Oh, that's too bad.
Here. I thought this
might cool you off.
Maybe that will cool
you off, Greaser.
When you learn to talk and act
decent, I might cool off, too.
Fiery, huh? Just the
way I like them.
- Get off me.
- Come on.
Look, leave her alone, Dal.
What did you say?
Come on. You heard
me. Leave her alone.
What did you say, you little
shit? What did you say?
- Come on.
- You wise ass.
Hey, wise guy, cool it, will you?
Sit down, punk.
Now you blew it.
Thank you. He had
me scared to death.
You sure didn't show it.
Nobody talks to Dal like that.
From what I saw, you do.
Why don't you all come sit here
with us so you can protect us?
- What do you think, man? Come on.
- Might as well.
How old are you all?
- 14.
- 16.
I thought you were both 14.
How come you all ain't scared
of us like you was of Dally?
Oh, you two are too
sweet-looking to scare anyone.
Besides, I know about
Dallas Winston.
You two don't look mean.
Yeah, right. We're
young and innocent.
No. You're just not dirty.
Come on, Dal's ok. I mean,
he's tough and all.
But he's a cool old guy,
if you get to know him.
He'd leave you alone if
he knew who you were.
Well, I'm glad he doesn't know us.
I kind of admire him.
Oi, Greaser. You're dead.
What's he doing? Get
out of my hair.
Hey, what have you done?
Here, kid, have a beer.
It'll settle your nerves.
Well, now, who we got here?
Your great-grandmothers, huh?
What are you two young ladies
hanging out with these Greasers?
Dal was bothering them.
- He was, huh?
- Yeah.
Where is old Dal now anyway?
Yeah, where is old Dally?
He left, Tim.
Hey, I know he slashed my tyres.
Look, Tim, he left.
He's not here. Really.
- You guys seen Dally?
- No, no.
Yeah, well, I'll be
looking for him.
- Dally got a blade?
- I don't think so.
Good deal. Tim will fight
fair as long as he don't.
You guys don't believe in
playing rough, do you?
- Well, a fair fight ain't rough.
- Yeah, boy. Real simple.
Yeah. If he gets
killed or something,
you just bury him. No sweat.
You dig, ok, baby.
You want a chew?
Come on, Two-Bit.
Help yourself. Put
hair on your chest.
Ponyboy, come with me and
get some Cokes and popcorn.
Sure.
- You all want some?
- I do.
Yeah, me, too. Get Johnny
some, too. I'm buying.
Here you go.
Your friend, the one with
the sideburns, is he ok?
Yeah, he ain't dangerous,
if that's what you mean.
- Hey, what are you doing?
- Hey, man.
He sure scared Johnny.
Johnny's a nervous wreck anyway.
He got beat up a few
months ago by some Soc.
Is that how he got his scar?
Yeah, the guy was
wearing a few rings.
- Not all of us are like that.
- Sure.
That's like saying all you
Greasers are like Dallas Winston.
- Leave him, will you?
- What you gonna do about it?
Let's take it outside.
That's what I'll do.
All right, you two. Why don't
you both take it outside?
Well, he's jumped a few people.
Anyway, you think the
Socs have it made.
The rich kids. The southside Soc.
Well, I'll tell you
something, Ponyboy,
and it might come as a surprise,
but things are rough all over.
Come on. Let's get out of here.
Or Two-Bit will think
we eloped to Mexico.
So, you're from the
southside, huh?
Yes.
- It must be a nice neighbourhood.
- It is. I like it.
Do you?
Yeah, I'm from
the other side of town.
Tell me about your oldest brother.
You never seem to talk about him.
What's to tell?
He's big and roofs houses.
No, really. I mean,
what's he like?
I feel like I know Soda for as
much as you talk about him.
Tell me about Darry. Is he
wild and reckless like Soda?
Or dreamy like you?
He ain't like Soda, and
he sure ain't like me.
He can't stand me.
I bet he wishes he
could stick me in
some boys' home.
Soda won't let him.
- What are you talking about?
- Come on. You all get along fine.
No, we don't. You
shut your trap, cos
you ain't wanted at home either.
You shut your mouth, kid.
I'm sorry. I got a little mad.
Don't worry about it.
We couldn't get along without you.
Marcia.
- Look who's coming.
- What are we gonna do?
- Just act normal. Just keep calm.
- Who are these clowns?
Cherry, what's going on?
What are you doing?
Just because we got
a little drunk...
You call reeling and passing
out on the streets "a little"?
Bob, I've told you before,
I'm never going out with
you when you're drinking.
That's no reason to go walking
the streets with these bums.
- Who are you calling bums, pal?
- You.
Randy.
We got two more in the back seat.
- Pity the back seat.
- If you're looking for a fight...
I am looking for a fight.
Let's go. Come on. Right not.
Come on.
All right. We'll go with
you. Just wait a minute.
We ain't scared of these bastards.
I hate fights. I hate them.
Come here, Ponyboy.
I'm sorry.
Look, I couldn't use this.
I could never cut no one.
Cherry. Come on.
We'd better go with them.
If I see you in school and I don't
say hi, don't take
it personal, ok?
Yeah, I know.
Really. You're a nice
boy and everything.
It's ok.
I hope I never see
Dallas Winston again.
If I do, I'll probably
fall in love with him.
- Come on, baby.
- Don't touch me.
♪ Blue moon ♪
♪ You saw me standing alone ♪
♪ Without a dream in my heart ♪
- Just watch it, greaseball.
- Says who?
♪ Without a love of my own ♪
Boy, those are two of the
best-looking girls I've ever seen.
Yeah.
- What was that?
- Marcia's number.
Probably a phoney one, too.
I must have been out of
my mind to ask for it.
Girl like that would never
go out with me, anyway.
Where are you all going?
- Home.
- Whoa.
Here. I got me a new hat.
You're crazy.
I don't why I handed
you that busted
bottle. You never
would have used it.
I might have. Where you headed?
I don't know. Maybe I'll go
play snooker or get drunk.
- I'll see you later.
- Ok.
I hate when my folks are
fighting. Let's go to the lot.
♪ Blue moon ♪
♪ You saw me standing alone ♪
It was because we're
Greasers, Pone.
Might have hurt her reputation
or something, that's all.
Don't worry about it.
Yeah, I guess so.
Man, that was a tough car, huh?
Mustangs, they're tough.
Big-time Socs, all right.
It's always the same.
♪ Blue moon ♪
♪ You saw me standing alone ♪
I can't take much more
of this, Ponyboy.
I'll kill myself or
something. I don't know.
Don't talk like that, Johnny.
Come on. You can't kill yourself.
I've got to do something.
Oh, God. It seems...
It seems like there's
got to be some
place without Greasers and Socs.
There must be some place...
with just plain ordinary people.
People.
It's like that out in the country.
Away from all the big towns.
Out in the country.
♪ If today was not
an endless highway ♪
♪ If tonight was not
an endless trail ♪
Ponyboy.
Pony, wake up.
Come on.
God. What time is it?
I don't know. I
went to sleep, too.
You better get home, all right?
I'm gonna stay all night out
here. Who'll care anyway?
All right. If you get cold,
come on to my house.
Yeah, all right.
What is Darry gonna say?
Yeah, it's Darry.
Yeah. Bye.
Where the hell have you been?
Do you know what time it is?
It's two o'clock in
the morning, kiddo.
- Where have you been?
- I feel asleep in the lot.
- You what?
- I was talking to Johnny.
And I fell asleep in the
lot. I didn't mean to.
And I can't even call the cops
because you two would be
thrown in boys' home so fast,
it would make your head spin.
Come on, Pony. Let's
go to bed now.
Look, I said I didn't mean to.
"I didn't mean to." "I forgot."
That's all I ever hear from you.
Come on, Darry...
Tired of you sticking up for him.
Don't you yell at him.
Ponyboy. I didn't mean to.
Come on, Johnny.
Move out of the way.
Take it easy, Pony. It will be all
right. You just have
to cool it, man.
Got a cigarette, Johnny?
I'm scared to death.
Well, don't be, man.
You're scaring me.
- What happened?
- Darry hit me.
I swear we used to get along
fine until Mum and Dad died.
Now he can't stand me.
I think I like it better when
the old man's hitting me.
At least he knows I'm there.
Let's walk to the park and back.
Maybe I'll cool off
enough to go home.
Yeah, all right. Ain't you
about to freeze to death?
You're ain't a' woofing.
Pony.
Pony, got a light?
Found this butt, man.
Yeah, here you go, Johnny.
Look what's coming.
This is our territory.
I bet they're looking for us.
- Wanna split?
- Stay cool.
Well, well, well. What
do you guys know?
They're drunk.
It's that guy with the rings, man.
Aren't these the Greasers who
tried to pick up our women?
You guys are out of your
territory. You better watch it.
No, pal. You better watch it.
You guys know what Greasers are?
White trash with long greasy hair.
- You know what a Soc is?
- What?
White trash with
Mustangs and madras.
Get them.
Johnny.
Stay down, pal.
Chuck him.
Grab his arms. Right down.
Did somebody get a drink
for this Greaser, huh?
Come on. Have a drink, pal.
I killed him.
I killed that boy.
Johnny, I think I'm gonna be sick.
Go ahead, man. I ain't... I
ain't gonna look at you.
Ain't gonna look at you.
Pony, are you all right?
You really did kill
them, huh, Johnny?
Yeah.
I had to.
They, they were drowning you,
and they might have killed you.
They were gonna beat me up.
- What happened to the other guys?
- Huh?
They... they all ran.
They all ran off.
When I stabbed him, they all ran.
What do you boys want?
Dally. We got to see Dally.
He's busy.
Just tell him it's Ponyboy
and Johnny, man. He'll come.
Come on.
What do you guys want?
- Johnny killed the Socs.
- What?
All right. Good for you. Let's go.
We figured you could get us
out, if anyone could, Dal.
I'm sorry I got you away
from this party and all,
but I just don't know
what to do, man.
I was just trying
to get some sleep.
I got into a fight
with Shepard tonight.
Let's see what we can do
about this mess. Get in.
- Ponyboy, are you wet?
- Yeah, I'm ok.
Hey, hey. Pony, come on, man.
You'll die of pneumonia before
the cops ever get to you.
Come on.
Hey, stupid, take the
sweatshirt off, will you, man?
You'll freeze to death.
Man, I wish I had a weed now.
Here. Don't point the
thing at me, will you?
It's loaded. Come on.
Here you go. That's 50 bucks.
Look, I'm not gonna
tell your brother
and get my head kicked in, man.
Then don't tell him.
Here. It's Buck's. It's big on
you, but it's dry. Come here.
Get the 3.15 train to
Windrixville. It's a freight.
There's an abandoned church
on top of Jay Mountain.
There's a pump in the back, so you
don't have to worry about water.
Get a week's supply of food,
as soon as you get there,
before the story gets out.
And then don't so
much as stick your
noses out the door. Am I clear?
Yeah.
I'll be up there as soon as
I think everything's cool.
Hey, relax, buddy. Come
on, man. It'll work out.
All right.
Man, I thought New York
was the only place
I'd end up in a murder wrap.
Jesus Christ.
Ok, you take care, kid. Good luck.
♪ Train arrive ♪
♪ 16 coaches long ♪
- Let's check the other car.
- Yeah.
♪ Train arrive ♪
♪ 16 coaches long ♪
♪ Well, that long black train ♪
♪ Got my baby and gone ♪
♪ Train, train ♪
♪ Coming round the bend ♪
♪ Well, it took my baby ♪
♪ But it never will again ♪
♪ Train, train ♪
♪ Coming down, down the line ♪
Wait up, man. Wait up.
- Well?
- Well, what?
Well, go and ask them.
Ask them where we are.
The story won't be
in the paper yet.
Why don't you go ask them?
My ankles hurt, and I
don't wanna walk on them.
What am I gonna say?
Just act like a farm boy taking
a walk. They'll never know.
Do I look like a farm boy to you?
Just ask them...
Ask them where... Jay Mountain
is. Don't worry about it.
They're gonna know who I am
as soon as they look at me.
They're not gonna know. Come on.
Excuse me. Can you tell me
the way to Jay Mountain?
- Huh?
- How could I get to Jay Mountain?
Follow this road up to
that hill. That's it.
- Thank you.
- Taking a walk?
Yeah. We're
playing Army. I was
supposed to report
to headquarters.
Boys will be boys.
Check it out, man.
The church.
♪ Well, there's a leak
in this old building ♪
♪ Yeah, there's a leak
♪ Well, there's a leak
in this old building ♪
♪ We're gonna move
to a better home ♪
♪ We got no pane in
this old window ♪
♪ We're gonna move
to a better home ♪
♪ Well, there's a hole in the
roof where the rain pours in ♪
♪ A hole in the floor where
it drops right out again ♪
♪ Well, there's a leak
in this old building ♪
♪ We're gonna move to a better ♪
♪ Move to a better ♪
♪ Home ♪
- What was that?
- Just an owl.
Johnny?
Yeah?
You all right?
Man, this floor sure is hard.
♪ I can't see my
reflection in the water ♪
School day. Rise and shine.
♪ I can't speak the sounds
that show no pain ♪
Come on, kiddo. Wake up. Wake up.
♪ I can't hear the
echo of my footsteps ♪
It's time to get up.
Johnny?
Hey, Johnny. Fancy...
Fancy meeting you here.
You're acting more like
Two-Bit every day, huh?
Who's acting? What did you get?
Let's go inside, man. Dally
told us to stay inside.
Right, I got a loaf of bread,
and a week's supply
of baloney here.
Peanut butter.
"Gone with The Wind"?
How did you know I always
wanted "Gone with The Wind"
I remember you saying
something about it once.
Me and you went to see
that movie, remember?
I thought maybe you could read
it out loud. Help kill time.
Thanks a lot, Johnny.
- Cigarettes.
- A deck of cards.
Peroxide?
You ain't thinking...
We're gonna cut our hair, Ponyboy.
You're gonna bleach yours.
We can't fit descriptions
in the newspaper.
No, sir. You ain't
gonna touch my hair.
You have to anyway,
if we got caught.
The first thing the judge does
is make you get a haircut.
- I don't see why.
- I don't either.
It's just the way they're
trying to break us.
I'm gonna cut mine off, too,
and wash all the grease out.
No, you ain't touching my hair.
Ponyboy, it's gonna
grow back, man.
It's not that it won't.
Go ahead.
Sorry, man.
♪ Gotta confess ♪
♪ My hair is a mess ♪
Damn knife.
- Don't pull so hard.
- Quit gabbing.
Sorry, man.
- Can I see now?
- No. You got to bleach it first.
Well, then bleach
it. Quit cutting.
Hey, Pony, this'll do it.
Here.
Jesus. This really
makes me look tough.
All right, go ahead.
Get your jollies.
- My pleasure.
- Yeah, I know it is.
♪ Lend me your comb,
it's time to go home ♪
Nice.
♪ Gotta confess ♪
♪ My hair is a mess ♪
- Hurts, don't it?
- Yeah, yeah.
Come on, man. I didn't
cut that much off you.
It was your bright idea, smarty.
I'm still tired.
Look, I'm sorry I cut
your hair off, Ponyboy.
Well, it ain't that.
It's just...
I don't know. I'm all mixed up.
Yeah, I know.
Things have been
happening so fast, huh?
Man, you know that one-horse
store this morning?
Two-Bit, he could have walked
out with half of that thing.
Old Two-Bit, huh?
Remember how he was
wisecracking last night?
Just last night we
was walking Cherry
and Marcia home from the movies.
Just last night we was laying up
in the lot looking at the stars.
Stop it, man. Will you
shut up about last night?
- Johnny.
- I killed a kid last night.
He couldn't have
been more than 17,
maybe 18 years old,
and I killed him.
How would you like to
live with that, huh?
I didn't mean to.
They was drowning you, and
I didn't know what to do.
There sure is a lot of
blood inside of people.
What are we gonna do?
Oh, man. It's all my fault,
bringing a 13-year-old kid along.
You ought to go home, Ponyboy.
You can't get into any trouble.
You didn't go kill him.
No. I'm 14 and I've
been 14 for a month.
And I'm in this just
as much as you are.
I'll stop crying in a
minute. I can't help it.
I didn't mean it
like that, Ponyboy.
Hey, don't cry.
Don't cry, man.
It'll be all right.
It'll be fine.
Let's just... Let's go
by the fire, all right?
- Johnny, are you awake?
- Yeah.
There's a monster outside.
What?
We're gonna be ok, Ponyboy.
♪ Yes, I'm gonna walk on
that milky white way ♪
"Lying in the pit of the sun,
"shoulder to shoulder,
head to feet,
"were hundreds of
wounded men lying
"in the tracks, the sidewalks,
"stretched out in endless
rows, under the car shed.
"Some lay stiff and still, but
many withered in the hot sun.
"Everywhere swarms of flies
hovered over the men
"crawling and buzzing
in their faces."
Man, that's gross.
"Everywhere was blood,
dirty bandages, groans,
"screamed curses of pain.
"But for four years,
she had seen others
"who had refused to
recognise defeat.
"Men who rode gaily
into sure disaster,
"because they were gallant."
Pretty cool, huh?
Gallant.
The cool old guys
remind me of Dally.
Dally? Shoot, he ain't got
no more manners than I do.
Soda's more like
them southern boys.
Yeah, the manners bit.
Charm, too, I guess, but...
- Dallas...
- Dallas so really scares me.
Come on. Read on.
Watch your smoke, Johnny.
One morning, I woke
up earlier than usual
The church was
colder than ever
Golly. That was sure pretty, huh?
Yeah.
It's like the mist is
what's pretty, you know.
All gold and silver.
Too bad it can't stay
like that all the time.
"Nothing Gold Can Stay".
Huh?
"Nature's first green is gold
"Her hardest hue to hold
"Her early leaf's a flower
"But only so an hour
"Then leaf subsides to leaf
"So Eden sank to grief
"So dawn goes down today
"Nothing gold can stay."
Where did you learn that?
That's what I meant.
Robert Frost wrote it.
I remembered it, cos I never
quite knew what he meant by it.
You know, I never noticed
colours, clouds and stuff
until you kept reminding
me about them.
It's kind of like they
were never there before.
Yeah.
I don't think I could ever tell
Steve or Two-Bit or even Darry
about the clouds and sunset.
Just you and Sodapop.
Maybe Cherry Valance.
I guess we're different, huh?
Shoot, kid. Maybe they are.
Maybe you're right.
Hey, blondie.
- Hey, Dal.
- Wake up.
How you been?
Hey, Johnny, rise and shine, man.
- How's Soda doing?
- Hey, Dallas. How are you?
- Is he upset?
- Are the fuzz after us?
Wait. One thing at a time. Are you
guys hungry? I'm starving, man.
You're starving? Try
baloney for four days.
- You got a cancer stick, Johnny?
- Yeah.
I got a special delivery
for... a Ponyboy Curtis.
- For you, man.
- Who's this from?
The president of the
United States of America.
- Yeah, right.
- I'm serious, man.
From your brother, Sodapop.
How did he know I was here?
I told him where you were,
but he didn't believe me.
He really wanted me to
give that to you, man.
I guess you got into
some trouble, huh?
Darry's awfully sorry he hit
you. You know he didn't mean it
Dallas got hauled
into the station,
and scared us something awful
And I wish you'd come back
and turn yourselves in
We miss you
Say hi to Johnny for
us. Sodapop Curtis
Dal, what's going on with the
cops? Did you hear anything?
How come you got hauled in?
Those boys down at the
station know me by now.
While I was there, they beat it
out of me that you guys were...
Get this one. That you guys
were headed for Texas, man.
They think you guys are in Texas.
Texas, man. God.
Look at this guy with his hair,
man. I can't believe that.
Blondie, man.
I know I look lousy,
but don't rub it in.
You guys wanna get
something to eat?
Hey, you better believe it.
Let's get out of here.
Where did you get this car? Huh?
- It's Buck's.
- Dal, don't.
- Watch it.
- I got it.
- What are you doing?
- Don't, Dal. Watch it.
I hope you guys are in the
mood for barbecue, man.
- Jerk.
- Trying to kill us?
Can we have three barbecue
sandwiches, three Cokes and a...?
You guys really are hungry, huh?
That kid you killed had
plenty of friends.
It's all over town,
Soc against Grease.
Look, I started carrying a heater.
Dal, you kill people with heaters.
Don't worry. It ain't loaded.
Hey, mister, do you have 15 cents?
Nah, I don't have any money, man.
Are you sure?
Could you go away?
We're busy here.
- Do you have a dime?
- Could you go away?
- Go away. Get out of here.
That was a close call.
Tim Shepard's gang and our outfit
are gonna have it
out with the Socs
in a vacant lot tomorrow night.
Hey, I didn't tell
you we got a spy.
A spy? Who?
Remember that good-looking
broad I tried to pick up
the night you wasted that kid?
What's her name? Cherry
something... The redhead?
- Cherry Valance.
- Cherry, the Soc. Yeah.
Yeah, we were hanging out
down at a vacant lot,
and she pulls up in a
little old Stinger, right?
I thought that took
a lot of nerve.
Yeah.
She said that she'd testify
that the Socs were drunk,
and they were the ones
looking for the fight.
And you guys just fought back
strictly on self-defence.
So, it's cool.
Man, that little broad
sure does hate me.
I offered to take her for a Coke,
and she told me to go to hell.
I don't know.
Yeah.
So you think she might
like me a little bit?
Huh? I think she's kinda cute.
- No?
- Right.
What do they do for kicks
around here? Play checkers?
This place is out of it.
I've never been to
the country before.
We're gonna turn ourselves in.
What? What?
I got a good chance of
being let off easy.
It was self-defence.
You just said.
Pony and Cherry could testify.
We won't say you helped us.
I'll give you back that gun. You
won't get into any trouble, Dal.
Are you sure this
is what you want?
Yeah.
It ain't fair for
Darry and Soda to
worry about Ponyboy all the time.
I guess my folks aren't worrying.
Hey, man, the boys are worried.
Two-Bit wanted to go to
Texas to hunt for you.
Dallas, I asked if my
parents asked about me.
No, they didn't. So what?
Do you think my old
man gives a hang
if I'm dead in a car wreck or
drunk or in jail or something?
He doesn't care. But that
doesn't bother me none.
Come on. You're not
going anywhere.
I get you this hideout. I get
you a hangout, man, a hideout.
And look at this. You wanna
split. This is just terrific.
Johnny, you don't know what a few
months in jail can do to you.
You get mean in jail.
I just don't want to see it happen
to you like it happened to me.
- What's going on?
- I wonder how that started?
Jesus Christ.
Pony, where are you going?
Get over here, man.
Gerry, some children are missing.
No, they're not, Theresa.
I'm sure of it. Some have
been gone for half an hour.
Get a hold of yourself.
Come back. Come back. Don't
go in there. You'll get hurt.
Come here, man. Get over here.
You're gonna get him?
Pony.
Go back before you get hurt.
Whoa.
What was that?
- Is that guy coming?
- No.
- How come? Too scared?
- No. He's too fat.
Come on, man. In here.
Hey, Dal. Take this
kid, man. Take him.
Are you ok?
Pony, give them to Dallas.
Get them and get out.
- Johnny.
- Come on, Johnny. Move.
Johnny. Come on. Are you crazy?
- You're burning.
- Come on, Johnny.
- No.
- Johnny.
Jesus Christ. Stupid kid.
I'm coming, Johnny.
- Johnny, Dallas...
- They're all right.
They're behind us. They're
in another ambulance.
Anyway, you guys are the bravest
kids I've seen in a long time.
What, are you guys professional
heroes or something?
We're Greasers.
- Are... are you kidding me?
- No, I ain't kidding you.
Take me to town. You'll
find out pretty fast.
You know, you shouldn't
be smoking, son.
Why not?
Cos you're a young man, that's
why. It's a bad habit to get into.
You're smoking.
I'm older than you. I've been
smoking for a long time, too.
Pull another stunt like that
again, I'm gonna kill you.
Ponyboy.
Oh, look at your tough hair.
Pony.
Darry, I'm sorry.
I thought we lost you,
like we did Mum and Dad.
You sure look fine.
Let's go, little
brother. We're home.
Whoa.
Getting pretty big to be carried.
Hi, Tim.
Hi, kid.
Can I get you some
breakfast or something?
No.
Thanks for letting
me use your couch.
Sure. Any time.
Anybody home?
Yeah, in here. Don't
slam the door.
Ponyboy, hey.
What you doing? Look what you did.
Whoa.
You made me ruin my
eggs, drop my spoon.
Look at the blond-headed monkey.
I wouldn't have believed it, if
I hadn't seen it in the paper.
Tell me, Ponyboy, what's
it like being a hero, huh?
A what?
A hero, man. You know,
like a, like a big-shotie.
Beer for breakfast, Two-Bit?
What I like is the
"turn hero" bit.
They're charging Johnny
with manslaughter?
What do they mean,
"if he recovers"?
Them kids, they'd have burned to
death, if it hadn't been for you.
Dallas will be mad when he hears
they didn't mention
his police record.
It's all about us.
Darry, me and Soda.
Not a thing about putting me
and Soda in a boys' home?
No way.
No, they ain't putting
me in a boys' home.
Oh, hell, Ponyboy, they
don't do that to heroes.
Where is Soda and
Super-Dope, anyhow?
- Whoa. Morning.
- Shut the door.
The what?
All brawn and no brains.
Darry, have you seen my DX shirt?
You got to wear pants, too, buddy.
I think there's a law about that.
How about my jeans?
I ironed them. They're
in my closet.
- Darry...
- Hurry up. You're gonna be late.
Darry, did you... did you hear
about that juvenile court thing?
Yeah, the cops told me last night.
Hey, after we stomp
the Socs real good,
me and Steve are
gonna throw a party
and everyone's gonna get ripped.
- Where you gonna get the dough?
- I'll think of something.
Hey, Two-Bit, Mickey's on TV.
Pony? Pony?
You know, I hate to leave
you here by yourself.
Maybe I ought to take the day off.
I'll be ok. I've stayed by
myself plenty of times.
Besides, we can't afford it.
Yeah, but I really ought to stay.
Don't worry. I'll baby-sit him.
Hey, why don't you get a job? Ever
think of getting a job, Two-Bit?
Hey, Soda, come on. We
got to get to work.
I got to quit smoking, or I
won't make track next year.
Hey, you all, do up the dishes.
- I'm gonna cut off your hair.
- Lay off.
- Yeah, Two-Bit, lay off.
- He ain't looking so good.
Lazy bum.
Pony...
You smoke more than a pack today,
and I'll skin you. You understand?
Yeah.
If you carry more than one bundle
of roofing at a time today,
me and Soda here will
skin you, understand?
- Hey, say hi to Johnny.
- All right.
- See you later, Pony.
- Ok.
We got to clean up the house.
The cops and reporters
are gonna come by.
And besides it's
time for the people
from the state to check on us.
Shoot, this house ain't messy.
You ought to see my house.
I have, and if you had the
sense of a billy goat,
you'd clean your house up,
instead of bumming around ours.
Shoot, kid. If I ever did that,
my mum would die of shock.
♪ You know what it takes,
you got it, baby ♪
I would drive, but the
brakes went out on my car.
Almost killed me and
Kathy the other night.
You ought to meet her
brother. Now, there's a hood.
Boy, he's so greasy, he
glides when he walks.
He goes to the barber shop for
an oil change, not a haircut.
♪ About my troubles,
troubles, troubles ♪
♪ When it rains, it really pours ♪
- Stay close.
- What do they want?
- I don't know.
- How many guys were in the car?
There were five. Come on.
Let's hurry up inside.
Let's see what they want.
Why do you want to
see what they want?
Just stay here.
No jabs before the rumble. You
know the rules, ape face.
We know. I wanna talk to you.
Go ahead. I'll keep my eye on him.
Come on.
Speaking of the rumble, pal...
I read about you in
the paper. How come?
I don't know. I felt like
playing the superhero.
- I wouldn't have.
- You wouldn't have what?
I would have let those
kids burn to death.
You might not have. You might
have done the same thing.
I don't know.
I just don't know anything
any more, I guess.
I never would have
believed a Greaser
could pull something like that.
A Greaser didn't have
nothing to do with it.
Check out their pants.
Do you wanna talk inside?
Are you boys waiting for a flood?
I hear they stamp your
face into gorilla cookies.
- You're funny.
- Oh, yeah?
I couldn't tell this
to anyone else.
My friends, they'd think
I was off my rocker.
That friend of yours, the one
that got burned, he might die.
Yeah.
And tonight, people will get hurt
at the rumble. Maybe
killed, right?
You can't win. You
know that, don't you?
It doesn't matter if you whip us,
you'll still be where you
were before, at the bottom.
We'll still be the lucky ones
at the top with all the breaks.
It doesn't matter.
The Greasers will
still be Greasers,
and the Socs will still be Socs.
It doesn't matter.
Anyway, thanks, Greaser.
Hey, I didn't mean that.
I meant, thanks, kid.
It's been nice talking to you,
Randy. My name's Ponyboy.
You're real funny, Two-Bit.
Come on, Let's go.
- Now get the hell out of here.
- See you at the rumble.
We're gonna kick some ass tonight.
So what did Mr Super
Soc have to say?
He ain't a Soc.
Just a guy that wanted
to talk, that's all.
- Take care.
- See you later. Take it easy.
Take it easy.
Well, I wanna see this doctor.
Nurse, Nurse, it's all
right. You can go in, boys.
He's been asking for
you. It can't hurt.
The doctor said you can
go in. There's the room.
- Hey, Johnny.
- Hey, you all.
How are they treating you, kid?
Look, got your picture in the
paper here for... being a hero.
Look at that.
Yeah, that's tough enough, huh?
Guess you can look at it later.
Do you want anything?
A book, man.
Can you all get me another one?
I think he wants a copy
of "Gone with The Wind",
so I can read it to him.
Would you mind going
downstairs and getting one?
They got a gift shop
downstairs. I'll go get it.
So...
I guess Dal's gonna be ok.
Me and Darry, we're getting
along real good now.
Johnny, are you ok?
Oh, yeah. It just hurts sometimes.
Usually, it don't, cos
I can't feel anything
below the middle of my back.
Pretty bad off, ain't I, Ponyboy?
No. You're gonna
be all right, kid.
You got to be.
Couldn't get along without you.
- I won't be able to walk again.
- Huh?
Not even on crutches. Doc
says I busted my back.
You're gonna be fine.
I know you are.
You wanna know something, Ponyboy?
I used to talk about killing
myself all the time.
Man, I don't wanna die now.
It ain't long enough. 16 years
ain't gonna be long enough.
Hell, I wouldn't
have minded so much,
if there wasn't so much
stuff I ain't done yet.
So many, so many damn things
I ain't seen or nothing.
That time we were up
in Windrixville...
Was the only time I've ever been
away from our neighbourhood.
Knock it off.
If you get too juiced up, the doc
won't let us see you no more.
Johnny, your mother's
here to see you.
I don't wanna see her.
It's your mother. She's
here to see you.
I said I don't wanna see her.
She probably just wants to tell
me how much trouble I'm causing.
Why don't you tell her
to leave me al...
- What's the matter?
- You can't see him now.
- Pony, is he ok?
- I don't know.
He's all right.
Make sure he gets this, all right?
Ok.
I've got a right to
see him. He's my son.
He'd rather see
these no-good punks
than his own mother. You scum.
No wonder he hates your guts.
You don't even care about
him, you damn drunk.
You go straight to hell.
You go right to hell.
- You just...
- Come on.
- What's happened to your gown?
- I threw it away.
Get out. Just get out. You
make my stomach sick.
- How are you doing?
- How are you doing, man?
Swiped you a gift, man.
It's good to see you guys, man.
This place gives me the creeps.
I want out.
Tim Shepard dropped by.
Saw my picture in the paper
and couldn't believe
it didn't have "wanted dead or
alive" written underneath it.
He started rubbing it in
about the rumble, man.
I hate missing it.
You got a cigarette, Pone?
Thanks.
How is he? How's
Johnny doing, man?
Look, Dal, I don't know
about stuff like this,
but... but he didn't
look too good.
He passed out cold before we left.
You still got that knife on you?
- What?
- The knife.
Give me it, will you?
Thank you.
You know, we got to win
that fight tonight.
We got to get even
with those Socs.
Let's do it for Johnny, man.
We'll do it for Johnny.
Are you ok, Pony?
Well, you feel kinda hot.
I'm ok.
Be a pal and don't tell
Darry, ok, Two-Bit?
I'll take a bunch of
aspirins when I get home.
All right.
Darry will kill me if he finds out
you're sick, and you fight anyway.
Keep your trap shut, he
won't find nothing out.
You know the only thing that keeps
Darry from being a Soc is us?
Yeah, I know.
Come on, man.
Tonight... I don't
like it one bit.
Something awful is gonna happen.
We're gonna stomp ass
on those Socs tonight.
- Everything's gonna be all right.
- Yeah.
- Tough little kids, huh?
- Yeah. Future Greasers.
Yeah.
Ponyboy.
Hey, Two-Bit.
What's up with the big times?
No weapons.
They play your way.
It's a fair deal.
Are you sure about that?
Well, Randy told me.
He knows for sure.
Good deal. Thanks, Cherry.
Ponyboy, wait a minute.
Come here. I wanna talk to you.
How's Johnny doing?
Not so good. Would you
come up and see him?
- No, I couldn't.
- Why not?
I couldn't.
He killed Bob.
Maybe Bob asked for it.
I know he did.
But you didn't know his other
side. He could be real sweet.
He wasn't just any boy.
Bob had something that
made him different.
Made people follow
him. Maybe better
than the crowd. You
know what I mean?
That's ok. I don't want
you to go see him.
We don't need your damn charity.
Ponyboy.
I wasn't trying to
give you charity.
I only wanted to help.
I liked you from the start.
The way we talked.
Wouldn't you try to help me
if you thought you could?
Can you see the sunset from
the southside very good?
Yeah, real good.
You can see it from
the northside, too.
Thanks, Ponyboy. You dig ok.
See you around.
Soda, when did you start shaving?
When I was 15.
- When did, when did Darry?
- When he was 13.
Why? Figuring on growing
a beard for the rumble?
Oh, you're funny.
Maybe I'll send you into
the Reader's Digest.
They pay a lot of money
for funny things.
- Let's go, then.
- Forget it.
- Come on. Come on, Soda.
- You like fights, huh, Soda?
- Yeah, I like fights, man.
- You like fights, huh?
- How come?
- It's a contest.
It's like a drag race,
or a dance or something.
We're gonna beat them
Socs' heads in, ain't we?
When I get into a fight, I
wanna stomp. I like it, too.
Why do you like fights, Darry?
He likes to show off his muscles.
Hey, I'm gonna show them off on
you, if you get any mouthier.
Hey, Pony...
I don't know if you ought
to be in this rumble.
How come? I've always come
through before, ain't I?
Yeah, but, you know, you was
in shape before, and...
You know, you ain't
looking so good.
You're tensed up all the time.
Let him fight, man. Everyone's
tensed up before a rumble.
It's skin against skin. He
ain't gonna get hurt, is he?
Come on. I'll grab
hold of little one.
We will need every man we can
get, but... I don't know.
If it was with knives or
chains, it'd be different.
I'll be ok.
All right, but you be careful, ok?
I will be.
How come you never worry
about him so much?
Man, that's one kid brother
I ain't got to worry about.
This kid can use
his head. At least
for one thing, to grow hair on.
Get out.
All right. Yeah. Go, go, go.
Come on, come on, come
on. What do you think?
Come on. Come on.
You and Ponyboy, if the fuzz
show, beat it out of there.
We'll get jailed, but you two
will get the boys' home.
Know what I'm saying?
Ain't nobody gonna call the
fuzz in this neighbourhood.
Hey.
All the same, you two beat it
out of there. Do you hear me?
Yeah, bro.
How are you doing, Tim?
Pretty good.
You and the quiet kid were the
ones who killed the Soc, right?
- Yeah.
- Good going, kid.
Curly always said you
were a good kid.
Curly's in the reformatory
for the next six months.
The odds are as even as we can
get. You stay close to me, kid.
Hello, Darrel. Long time no see.
Hello, Paul.
What's up?
They used to buddy around
together, play football.
I'll take you.
You know, a rumble ain't
a rumble without me.
Ponyboy.
What are you guys doing?
Let's get out of here.
Ponyboy, are you ok?
Are you ok? Come on.
Yeah.
Wait. Act sick. I'll pretend
like I'm taking you
to the hospital.
You've got to have a good
reason for driving like that.
The kid fell off his motorcycle.
I'm taking him to the hospital.
- How bad is he?
- I don't know, man.
Do I look like a doctor?
He looks pretty bad to me.
- Follow me.
- All right.
Sucker.
Man.
I was crazy. You know that, kid?
I was crazy about wanting Johnny
to stay out of trouble, man.
If he was smart like me, he
wouldn't have been in this mess.
wouldn't have ran in that church.
You better wise up, Pony, man.
You just better wise up, man.
You get tough like me,
and you don't get hurt.
Watch out for yourself, and
nothing can touch you, man.
Hey.
Hey, Johnny.
We beat the Socs, man.
We chased them right out
of our neighbourhood.
- Go on.
- It's useless.
- Huh?
- Fighting ain't no good.
You know, they're still writing
editorials about
you in the papers,
about you being a hero.
We're all proud of you, buddy.
It's gonna be all right.
Ponyboy...
S...
Stay gold, Ponyboy.
Stay gold.
Johnny, come on.
So, this is what you get, huh?
This is what you get
for helping people?
You punk.
Come on, Johnny. Don't die.
Come on.
Come on, Johnny.
Don't die on me now.
Please.
Bastards.
Hey, you, you're not allowed here.
I'm allowed anywhere I want.
You're out of your mind.
Why do you bother helping
people? It doesn't do any good.
Well, it makes me look
kinda... kinda tough.
What do you think, Soda? Do you
think it makes me look tough?
I think it makes you
look different.
That guy had sharp teeth.
What do you mean by "different"?
You got a hole in your mouth.
Hey, where you been?
Hey, Pony, what? What's wrong?
Johnny's dead.
I told him about beating the Socs.
I don't know... He just died.
Told me to "stay gold."
Hey, Pony.
Dally's gone.
He couldn't take it.
He's gonna blow.
Do you wanna buy
one of those, son?
You tear those up, you have to
pay for them. Don't do that.
You know, you got to
pay for that magazine.
Oh, God. Don't shoot.
Give me the money.
I'm so sick of you punks.
Take it and get out of here.
- Yeah?
- Hello, Darrel?
No, it's Steve. Dally?
- Steve, I want to talk to Darry.
- Yeah, sure.
- Hello?
- All right, Darry, listen.
Yeah?
I robbed a store. The
cops are looking for me.
Can you meet me in the park?
Sure, Dal. Are you all right?
- Yeah. Johnny's dead.
- We know.
Johnny.
Meet me in the park, will you?
Hang on. We'll be right there.
That was Dally. The cops are
after him. We got to hide him.
- You're never gonna get me alive.
- Drop it.
- It's not loaded. Don't.
- Stop.
It's not loaded.
No. No.
He's just a kid.
- No.
- Pony?
You stupid idiot.
You stupid freak.
Johnny and Dallas both...
- Soda?
- Yeah?
- Is somebody sick?
- Yeah, somebody's sick.
Quiet.
He tried to drown me.
I could have made it simpler.
For the fight not to have
happened in the first place.
Sure. Your name is Sherry?
But your nickname is Cherry?
Yes.
You know, to teach
them a lesson.
Yes, there was an argument
because my boyfriend showed up,
and... well, he was upset that
we were with the other boys.
They chased us and caught us.
It was Bob and I.
They threw me in the fountain
and tried to drown me.
- Just to go looking for them.
- Gonna beat up Johnny Cade.
You know, teach them a lesson.
I could have made it simpler
for the fight not to have
happened in the first place.
I could have made it simpler.
For the fight not to have
happened in the first place.
Defendant not guilty.
At this time, I will
place him in the
custody of his older
brother, Darrel.
This court is adjourned.
Hey, Ponyboy?
Oh, hi, Mr Simms.
I got to talk to you
about your grade.
Yeah, I know I'm doing lousy.
Frankly, you're flunking.
But, I'll tell you
what, taking into
consideration the circumstances,
you come up with a
good semester theme,
I'll pass you with a C.
Should it be some kind
of research paper?
Personal experience will do it.
Great. My first trip to the zoo.
With your brains and grades, man,
you could get a scholarship.
And we could put you through
college. Isn't that right, Soda?
You live in a vacuum, Pony, and
you're gonna have to cut it out.
There's no stop living,
cos you lose somebody.
I thought you knew that.
You don't like the way I'm running
things, you can get
out, all right?
You'd like me to just get out. But
it's not that easy, is it, Soda?
Goddamn, you guys.
Leave me out of it.
What's wrong with you?
Run on. I'll be right behind you.
Ok.
Goddamn it, Ponyboy.
You should have gone out for
football instead of track.
- Where you think you're going?
- I don't know, man.
Just, like, sometimes
I have to get out.
It's like I'm a middleman in a
tug-of-war between you guys.
I don't know. I can't take sides.
Ponyboy...
Darry could have put
you in a boys' home.
Worked his way through college.
I'm telling you true, Pony.
You don't wanna be
like me, anyway.
Cos I'm happy working
in a gas station.
You'd never be happy doing
something like that.
Darry...
You guys stop yelling
at him for every
little thing that he does, man.
He feels things
different than you.
It's bad enough having
to listen to you.
But when you start trying
to get me to take sides...
We're all we got left now.
If we don't have each other...
you end up like Dallas.
And I don't mean dead either.
I mean, how he was before.
So, please.
Don't fight any more.
Please.
Sure. Sure, little buddy. We
ain't gonna fight no more.
Ponyboy...
Pone.
Now, don't you start
bawling, too, Pony.
One bawling baby in
this family is enough.
I ain't crying.
Let's go home. I'm cold.
Ponyboy, I asked the nurse
to give you this book,
so you could finish it.
It was worth saving
those kids. Their
lives are worth more than mine.
They have more to live for.
Tell Dally I think it's worth it.
I'm gonna miss you guys.
I've been thinking about it, and
that poem, that guy that wrote it.
He meant you're gold when
you're a kid. Like green.
When you're a kid
everything's new.
Dawn.
Like the way you dig
sunsets, Pony. That's gold.
Keep it that way. It's
a good way to be.
I want you to ask
Dally to look at one.
I don't think he's
ever seen a sunset.
There's still lots of
good in the world.
Tell Dally. I don't
think he knows.
Your buddy, Johnny.
♪ When I stepped out into
the bright sunlight ♪
♪ From the darkness
of the movie house ♪
♪ I had only two
things on my mind ♪
♪ Paul Newman and a ride home ♪
♪ Seize upon that
moment long ago ♪
♪ One breath away and
there you will be ♪
♪ So young and carefree ♪
♪ Again you will see ♪
♪ That place in time ♪
♪ So gold ♪
♪ Still away into
that way back when ♪
♪ You thought that all
would last for ever ♪
♪ But like the weather ♪
♪ Nothing can ever
and be in time ♪
♪ Stay gold ♪
♪ But can it be when we can see ♪
♪ So vividly a memory ♪
♪ And "yes" you say ♪
♪ So must the day too fade away ♪
♪ And leave a ray of sun ♪
♪ So gold ♪
♪ Life is but a
twinkling of an eye ♪
♪ Yet filled with
sorrow and compassion ♪
♪ Though not imagined ♪
♪ All things that happen ♪
♪ Will age too old ♪
♪ Though gold ♪
♪ Gold, gold, though gold ♪