Let us in! Let us in!
Excuse me.
Get rid of them.
I don't want to see them.
Darling, don't be difficult.
Let's take our sweet,
lovely children on an outing!
Cor, I've not seen
anything like that, mate.
You can't do this. I know my rights.
I have the authority to close
you down, and I'm doing just that.
This exhibit degrades
everybody who sees it,
as well as the poor creature himself.
He is a freak.
How else will he live?
Freaks are one thing.
There's no objection to freaks.
But this is entirely different!
This is monstrous,
and should not be allowed!
These officers will see to it that you
are on your way as soon as possible.
Good day!
Move along, please.
This way, gentlemen.
Hold it there, sir. Come this way?
On the move again...
My treasure.
We'll be seeing a lot more of these
machine accidents, Mr. Hodges.
Yes, sir.
Abominable things, these machines,
but you can't reason with them.
What a mess.
Pull on the rope.
Irons, please.
Who is it?
- Excuse me, Mr. Treves, sir.
- Yes, what is it?
- I found it.
- Good. Did you see it?
- No.
- All right.
I'll see you in a moment. Thank you.
- Who's that?
- A friend of mine.
Oh, yes?
- What are you up to, Treves?
- Nothing.
Ah, come on, Freddie!
Nothing of any importance.
Do you know where Green Street is?
It's round the back, to the left,
then to the right, then straight through.
Thank you.
- Are you the proprietor?
- And who might you be, sir?
Just one of the curious.
I'd like to see it.
I don't think so.
No, sir, we're...
...closed.
Now, I'd pay handsomely
for a private showing.
- Are you the proprietor?
- Handsomely? Who sent you?
- I beg your pardon?
- Never mind.
I'm the...
...owner.
Life...
is full of surprises.
Consider the fate
of this creature's poor mother,
struck down,
in the fourth month
of her maternal condition
by an elephant.
A wild elephant.
Struck down...
on an uncharted African isle.
The result...
is plain to see.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the terrible...
Elephant...
Man!
- Stand up!
- Turn round!
- Turn around! Turn around!
Yes, um... you'll bring him to me
tomorrow morning at ten, Mr., er...?
Bytes. He'll be there.
Good.
Now here's my card,
and I'll send a cab. All right?
We have a deal.
We understand each other.
More than money has changed hands.
We understand each other
completely, my friend.
Yes. Well, thank you, Mr. Bytes.
Thank you. Tomorrow.
Thank you.
Cor, what a stink!
I'm looking for a Mr. Frederick Treves,
please, ma'am.
Very well, I'll send for him. Nurse!
Oh, Mr. Treves, sir, this, um...
- this, um...
- Yes.
- He says that, um...
- Thank you. Yes, I was expecting him.
Yes, are you the cab driver?
- Yes, sir.
- Anyone else with you?
- No, sir, just this gentleman.
- Thank you for your troubles.
- Not at all, sir. My pleasure.
- Thank you.
Will you come this way, please?
Mrs. Mothershead, I'll be in my room
and I'm not to be disturbed, all right?
Of course, sir.
Will you come with me, please?
You heard what the doctor said?
Go on!
Um...
My name is Frederick Treves,
and I am the surgeon here
at the London Hospital,
and, um...
I lecture in anatomy
at the, um... medical college.
So...
I'd like very much to examine you,
so that, um...
er...
I mean, would that be all right?
Please.
Er...
First, I...
I'd like to ask you a few questions.
Um... would that be all right?
Now, your owner tells me...
I mean the man who...
looks after you
tells me that, er...
you're English
and that your name is John Merrick.
John Merrick, is that right?
I tell you what, I think
I'll ask you a question, and, um...
you shake your head
like this for, er...
'no'.
Um...
Have you always been
the way you are now?
Are you in any pain?
Are your parents still alive?
Do you understand me?
Your father, your mother,
are they dead?
Freddie, what are you doing for...?
Oh, I'm dreadfully sorry.
I had no idea you had...
Freddie, Freddie, what the hell
have you got in there?
You'll know soon enough at the
meeting of the Society.
Until then, I beg of you,
not a word to anyone, please.
All right, if you insist.
But you must have quite a find in there.
- I don't know what I've got.
- "Nothing of any importance", eh?
Not a word, please, Fox.
Not a word.
All right.
Thank you.
It's all right.
I think I'll examine you now.
I'll leave the questions till later.
All right?
Will you take your hat off
for me, please?
Now, don't be frightened.
I simply want to look at you.
Take your hat off.
Don't be frightened.
Thank you.
- Good afternoon.
Mr. Thomas, Mr. Rogers.
Pull the curtains aside.
He is English.
He is 21 years of age,
and his name is John Merrick.
Gentlemen, in the course
of my profession I have come upon
many lamentable deformities
of the face due to injury or disease,
as well as mutilations and
contortions of the body
depending upon like causes.
But at no time have I
met with such a
perverted or degraded version
of a human being as this man.
Now, I wish to draw
your attention to the
insidious conditions
affecting this patient.
- Can you see over there?
- Yes, thank you.
Note, if you will,
the extreme enlargement of the skull,
the right upper limb,
which is totally useless,
the alarming curvature of the spine.
Would you turn round, please?
Turn round, please.
The looseness of the skin,
and the varying fibrous tumours
that cover 90% of the body.
And there is every indication that these
afflictions have been in existence,
and have progressed rapidly,
since birth.
The patient also suffers
from chronic bronchitis.
As an interesting side note,
in spite of the
aforementioned anomalies,
the patient's genitals
remain entirely intact and unaffected.
Thank you.
And his left arm is
perfectly normal, as you see.
So, then, gentlemen,
owing to this series of conditions,
the congenital exostosis of the skull,
extensive papillomatous growth,
large pendulous masses
in connection with the skin,
the great enlargement of
the right upper limb
involving all the bones,
the massive distortion of the head,
and the extensive area
covered by papillomatous growth,
the patient has been called
"the Elephant Man".
Thank you.
You never mentioned his mental state.
Oh, he's an imbecile,
probably from birth.
The man's a complete idiot.
Pray to God he's an idiot.
Where have you been?
Get out.
How can I eat with a noise like that?
Bytes, don't!
Where have you been?
What did you do?
- Our man's sick. Come right away.
- What is it?
Like this...
- What did you do with him?
- He's been like this all night.
He was fine when he left here.
Now look at him!
Yes, I intend to.
- What happened?
- He fell.
He... falls.
Looks like he's had
a very severe fall.
He's a...
clumsy soul.
Never looks where he's going.
But that's all right.
He has me to take care of him.
Why is he sitting up like this?
He needs rest!
Well, that's how he sleeps.
If he lies down, he'll kill himself.
His...
head's too big.
All right.
This man belongs in a hospital.
Can't you treat him here?
Listen, he's my livelihood.
We're...
business partners, he and I.
- He's the greatest freak in the world!
- Yes, now you listen.
You're not going to have
much of a livelihood if he dies.
Now stop wasting my time.
I'm going to fetch a cab.
I truly appreciate this, my friend.
Listen, um...
there are a lot of things
I could do for you.
You see, I move in the
proper circles for...
this type of thing.
In fact...
anything at all,
if you take my meaning.
- Everything will be taken care of.
- It's good to do business with you.
Here we go. Here we go.
Shhh...
- Can I have a bowl of oatmeal, please?
- Yes, sir.
Breakfasting with the
patients this morning, Mr. Treves?
Yes... no, I, it's for a patient.
There you are, sir.
- Thank you. Good morning.
- Morning.
Oh, Treves!
Just come here for a moment, will you?
Um...
What's that you've got there?
Good Heavens!
You haven't acquired a sudden taste
for this sort of stuff, have you?
- Yes, sir, it's quite nutritious.
- Possibly.
Not quite the diet for
a grown man. Nurse!
When you have a moment,
just take this up to the patient
in the isolation ward, will you?
Yes, sir.
Don't be frightened.
He won't hurt you.
Won't he, indeed?
Now, just a minute, Treves.
Something I want to say to you.
Come in.
A hospital's no place for secrecy,
you know, Mr. Treves.
Doctors spiriting hooded figures
about in the corridors
is apt to cause comment.
Why wasn't this patient
properly admitted?
Why is he in the isolation ward?
- He's not contagious, is he?
- Oh no, sir.
No, he's got chronic bronchitis
and he's been badly beaten.
Well, why isn't he in
the General Ward, then?
Well, sir, he's...
he's quite seriously deformed,
and, um...
I fear the other patients
would find him rather shocking.
Deformed, is that it?
Am I to assume, then, that
he is ultimately incurable?
- Yes, sir.
- But you must be aware, Mr. Treves,
that this hospital
doesn't accept incurables.
The rules are perfectly clear
on that point.
Yes sir, I'm well aware of that.
But this case is quite, quite exceptional.
Yes, I quite appreciate
your problem, Mr. Treves.
Why not contact the British Home
or the Royal Hospital for Incurables?
Perhaps they might
find a place for him.
Yes, I'll look into it.
Would you like to meet him?
Excuse me!
The Elephant Man.
Sorry.
I should have warned you.
Please forgive me.
- You all right?
- Yes, sir.
Please ask Mrs. Mothershead
to come up here,
and tell her to knock on the door,
and wait for me.
I'm sorry about that. I, er...
We'll bring you another breakfast.
I'm sure you must be very hungry.
And, er...
I think you'll be
quite comfortable here, for a while.
I'll see to it that you have
everything you need.
Cor blimey!
So...
this is the Elephant Man.
I ain't seen nothing like you before.
What the bleedin' hell
happened to yer?
Dumb, eh?
I like people that can keep quiet.
'ere, have a drink.
Go on!
No?
You should be more sociable, mate.
Get yourself disliked.
You and I...
are gonna be good friends.
And I've got a lot of friends
who'd like to meet you.
And they will, mate.
Believe me, they will.
I've brought your breakfast.
What are you doing down there?
Come on, up on the bed.
Come on!
- All he understands is a good smack.
- He's had his share of smacks.
I'm sure that's what
drives him under the bed.
You have to treat him
with kindness and patience.
Well, perhaps you've got time
for that sort of treatment, Mr. Treves,
but I haven't.
I've got a hospital to run.
Now, don't you waste your time
with him, sir.
It's like talking to a brick wall.
I don't mean to be harsh, but...
he doesn't belong here.
Well, honestly, sir...
honestly, what can you do for him?
Oh, and by the way,
Mr. Carr Gomm said, er...
he would like to see you
when you can spare a moment.
- Yes.
- Right.
Can't help you unless you help me.
I believe there's something
that you want to say to me.
Something back there.
Can't help you
unless you help me, you know?
I believe you want to say
something to me, don't you?
I've got to understand what you're feeling,
I've got to understand what you're thinking.
Do you understand me?
All right, just nod your head.
Can you understand me? Just...
just nod your head
if you understand me.
All right.
You do understand.
Now, I want to hear you talk.
We're going to show them
that you're not a wall.
Do you understand?
I want you to talk to me.
All right, now.
I want to hear you say it.
I've got to hear how you say things.
I'm not going to hurt you, but I've got
to understand how you say things.
I've got to hear them!
Very slowly, I want you to say "yes".
Say "yes".
Yes.
Yes!
Good. All right.
Now, just once more.
Say it again: "yes".
Yes...
Yes, I can understand that.
That's good!
That's very good.
All right, now,
I'm going to say some words to you,
and I want you to repeat them.
Do you understand?
Say "Hello, my name is..."
Hello.
My name is...
"John Merrick."
...on... errick.
No... "John"...
That's very good.
Say "John Merrick".
Merrick.
"Hello, my name is John Merrick".
Hello, my name...
is John Merrick.
You can speak!
How did you get up here?
- I want my man back.
- Just a moment. How did you get up...
Never mind that. I want my man.
He's still very sick.
Please, come downstairs with me,
and I'll explain the situation.
Don't!
Don't.
You've had plenty of time to...
cure him.
And now, he's leaving with me.
Do you understand me?
Now, Mr. Treves.
- We made a deal.
- You misunderstood.
This man has suffered a severe fall.
If you take my meaning.
- Now, he's my patient now.
- Pull the other one, why don't you?
Mr. Bytes, I'm sorry. But all you do
is profit from another man's misery.
- You think you're better than me?
- No, I don't.
You wanted the freak
to show to those doctor chums of yours,
to make a name for yourself.
You, my friend...
I gave you the freak...
on trust.
In the name of... science.
And now I want him back.
You do not own this man.
Now, stop it!
I want him back!
So you can beat him?
So you can starve him?
A dog in the streets
would fare better with you.
I shall go to the authorities.
Go to the authorities, then!
Go to them, by all means.
I'm sure they'll be very interested
to hear your story as well as ours.
Now...
I think we really do
understand one another.
Hmm?
All right.
A singularly unattractive character,
I must say!
Well, Treves, it seems to me I might
as well meet this patient of yours.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Um...
Well, shall we say
in a few days, then?
Shall we say two o'clock
tomorrow afternoon?
Um...
Yes... well, whatever's
most convenient for you, sir.
Two o'clock, then, tomorrow.
Thank you very much.
Two o'clock!
- Morning, Charles.
- Morning, Mr Treves.
- Early again, I see?
- Yes.
With these early habits of yours,
you'd have made a good milkman!
- I'll keep that in mind, Charles.
- Okay, sir.
"He restoreth my soul.
- He leadeth me into paths of...
- for his name's sake."
"Righteousness."
Righteousness.
"He leadeth me in the paths of
righteousness for his name's sake."
Good. That's very good.
Good. Now, when
your visitor comes today,
I want you to say it exactly the way
you've said it just now.
When I introduce him to you,
just say the words you've learned.
If you have trouble with any of
the words, I'll help you,
so there's nothing to worry about.
I'll introduce you to him and say:
"Please meet Mr. Carr Gomm."
And you will say:
Hello, my name is John Merrick.
I'm very pleased to meet you.
Good. Good.
I'll go and get Mr. Carr Gomm.
Now, it is only a physical problem.
He has trouble with certain sounds
because of the
constrictive deformity of the mouth.
- But he can talk...
- Well, talking's one thing, Treves,
but is he able to understand
what's said to him?
Yes. Oh, yes. Except...
Except he's so anxious
to make a good impression on you
that he might seem a little nervous.
Come in.
John?
May I introduce you to Mr. Carr Gomm?
Mr. Carr Gomm, this is John Merrick.
Hello... my name is John Merrick,
I'm very pleased to meet you.
- How are you feeling today?
- I feel much better.
Are you comfortable here?
Everybody's been very kind.
How is your bronchitis?
Mr. Merrick likes
the food here, don't you?
- Much better than what I'm used to.
- Oh yes?
Yes, and what was that?
Potatoes.
I understood that you'd been flogged?
I feel much better now.
That's splendid.
How do you find Mr. Treves?
As a teacher, I mean?
He's very kind.
How long did you and Mr. Treves
prepare for this interview?
Everybody's... very kind.
Yes, of course, I understand. Well,
it's been a pleasure meeting you,
Mr. Merrick.
Good day to you.
Very good, John.
It was very good.
I'll be back in a moment.
"The Lord is my shepherd,
I shall not want.
He maketh me lie down..."
Well, it was a brave attempt, Treves,
but the man was obviously
simply mouthing words taught by you.
Yes. Well I'm sorry
to have wasted your time.
"He restoreth my soul."
He simply doesn't belong here.
He'd be much better off somewhere else
where he can be constantly looked after.
I'm sorry, Treves, that things have
turned out this way. Good day to you.
"Yea,
though I walk through the valley of
the shadow of death, I fear no evil,
for Thou art with me, Thy rod and Thy staff..."
Mr. Carr Gomm!
Yes, what is it?
It's that!
I didn't teach him that part!
"Goodness and mercy
will follow me all the days of my life
and I shall dwell
in the house of the Lord forever."
How did you know the rest of it?
I didn't teach you the rest of it.
It's very strange.
Tell me, how did you know
the rest of it - the 23rd Psalm?
I used to read the Bible every day.
I know it very well,
and the Book of Common Prayer.
The 23rd Psalm's beautiful.
It's my favourite.
Treves, come and see me in my office
when you're through up here.
There's something important
I want to say to you.
Goodbye, Mr. Merrick.
I do hope we shall meet again.
Why didn't you tell me you can read?
I was frightened.
- Oh, I see.
- I was afraid to talk.
Please forgive me.
Can you imagine the kind of life
he must have had?
- Yes, I think I can.
- I don't believe so.
No-one could possibly imagine it.
I don't believe any of us can.
"Terrible though his appearance is,
so terrible indeed,
that women and nervous persons
fly in horror from the sight of him,
and that he is debarred from
seeking to earn his livelihood
in any ordinary way.
Yet he is superior in intelligence.
He can read and write,
is quiet, gentle, not to say
even refined in his mind."
I should very much like
to meet this gentleman.
- Have you seen this?
- No.
- Now listen to this!
- Hey up, hey up!
Hey up!
Now listen. This is a letter
to the London Times
from the governor of the 'ospital.
"There is now, in a little room
off one of our attic wards
a man named John Merrick,
so dreadful a sight, that he is unable
even to come out
by daylight to the garden.
He has been called the Elephant Man
on account of his terrible deformity.
His appearance is so terrible,
that women and nervous persons
fly in terror at the sight of him."
And how do you get tickets to see him?
- Your very own Sunny Jim!
- Well, let's go and see him, then!
All right, keep your shirt on.
The time must be right.
Right now, he's in the attic,
but tomorrow they're gonna
move him to Bedstead Square,
right into my lap.
Then, for the right price,
you will see something you'll
never ever see again in your life!
Well, don't look so glum, girls!
Enthusiastic volunteers should be
more cheerful, hmm?
Put your collar straight, girl!
And remember...
that under no circumstances whatsoever
are any mirrors to be
brought into this room.
- Yes, Mrs. Mothershead.
- Yes.
Right.
He's so ugly!
Yeah, well, ugly or not,
you're gonna help me.
Feeling better now, Mr. Merrick?
You look very nice in, er...
your new clothes.
- Thank you very much.
- Yeah, well, if there's nothing else,
- suppose we'll be leaving you now.
- No, there's nothing.
You ready for tea?
Please go in, John.
Make yourself comfortable.
Oh...
Anne, come along.
Meet our guest.
Mr. Merrick, I'd like you
to meet my wife, Anne.
Anne, this is John Merrick.
I'm very pleased to meet you,
Mr. Merrick.
I...
I'm very pleased...
What is it? What's the matter?
It's just that I...
I'm not used to being
treated so well by...
a beautiful woman.
Would you like a cup of tea,
Mr. Merrick?
That's a good idea.
Would you like to come and see
the rest of the house?
Come on, I'll show you.
How's your tea?
It's very good.
I'm enjoying my visit here very much.
It's so kind of you
to have me in your own home.
I'm sorry
that I made a spectacle of myself.
No, not at all.
I like the way that you've...
arranged the pictures
on the mantelpiece.
Oh, thank you.
Is that the way they do it
in most houses?
Yes, I'm sure they do, yes.
Who... who are they of?
Well, these are relatives
and these are our children.
Children? Oh, may I see?
Yes, of course.
Where are the children?
Well, um, they're...
out with friends at the moment.
Friends...
And here is Frederick's mother.
And these are my parents.
They have such...
noble faces.
Yes, I've always thought so myself.
Would you...
care to see my mother?
Your mother?
Yes, please.
Oh, but she's...
Mr. Merrick, she's beautiful!
Oh, she has...
She has the face of an angel.
I must...
...have been a
great disappointment to her.
No, Mr. Merrick, no. No...
No son as loving as you
could ever be a disappointment.
If only I could find her!
If she could see me...
with such lovely friends, here, now,
perhaps she could...
love me as I am.
I've tried so hard to be good.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
- I'm so sorry.
- Oh, please...
I'm so sorry.
Oh, please.
What's that you're doing?
What is it?
Oh, I see! It's St. Philip's!
Well that's very good!
You've got the windows
and arches just right.
I wish...
I could sleep...
like normal people.
Mr. Treves,
there's something that
I've been meaning to ask you
- for some time now.
- What's that?
Can you cure me?
No.
No, we, er...
we can care for you,
but we...
we can't cure you.
No.
I thought not.
Come in.
Ah, good morning.
Good morning.
There's someone here who'd
like to meet you, if that's all right.
May I introduce you to one of the
bright lights of the English stage?
Mrs. Kendal, Mr. John Merrick.
Good day, Mr. Merrick.
Good day!
I've brought you some things.
I hope you like them.
I hope you don't think it too forward?
Oh... oh, no.
- I knew you'd understand.
- I'll leave you together.
Here.
I want you to know I don't go about
giving my picture to just anyone.
No, I wouldn't think of it.
It's beautiful. You're so...
Well, I...
I'll... I shall put it in...
in a place of honour.
Here. Next to my mother.
- She's very pretty, your mother.
- Oh, yes.
Oh. I see you're constructing a...
church?
No. It's... it's a cathedral.
Do you see?
Only... I have to rely on my imagination,
for what I can't actually see, so...
Mr. Treves tells me
that you're in the theatre.
- Do you live there?
- Oh no, Mr. Merrick, I just work there.
It must be wonderful
just to work there.
- Is it beautiful?
- You've never been?
No, I'm afraid not.
Oh, Mr. Merrick, you must go!
The theatre's the most
beautiful place on earth.
Of course, I am a bit partial.
The theatre is...
romance.
Romance...
Oh, yes...
Which reminds me,
I've brought you something else.
Oh...
- Thank you.
- Have you read it?
No. Oh, but I certainly shall.
Oh! "Romeo and Juliet".
Yes, I've heard of this.
"If I profane with my unworthiest hand
this holy shrine,
the gentle fine is this:
Thy lips, two blushing pilgrims,
ready stand, to smooth that
rough touch...
with a tender kiss."
"Good Pilgrim,
you do wrong your hand too much,
which mannerly devotion shows in this.
For saints have hands
that pilgrims' hands do touch.
And palm to palm
is holy palmer's kiss."
"Oh, then, dear saint,
let lips do what hands do.
They pray, grant thou,
lest faith turn to despair."
"Saints do not move,
though grant for prayer's sake."
"Then move not,
while my prayer's effect I take.
Thus from my lips,
by thine, my sin is purged."
And then it says: they kiss.
"Then have my lips
the sin that they have took."
"Sin from my lips?
O trespass, sweetly urg'd.
Give me my sin again."
Oh, Mr. Merrick.
You're not an Elephant Man at all.
No?
No.
You're Romeo.
"Mrs. Kendal, always at the
forefront of fashion and form,
was seen leaving
"The London" the other afternoon.
No, dear readers, the most
facile actress of our day
has not been taken ill,
but rather said she was
visiting a friend.
And who was the lucky recipient
of this attention?
Quick enquiries proved it to be
none other than
Mr. John Merrick, the Elephant Man,
with whom our readers are
undoubtedly familiar.
After a chat of
three-quarters of an hour,
Mrs. Kendal was kind enough
to leave Mr. Merrick
with an autographed
portrait of herself."
I saw it in his room.
"Owing to a disfigurement
of the most extreme nature,
Mr. Merrick has never been
properly presented to London society.
But knowing that wherever
Mrs. Kendal goes,
others inevitably follow,
the question arises - will London
society present itself to him?"
This walking stick is so dashing!
And much more elegant
than my old one!
More tea?
You see, I don't go out
as often as I would like,
because naturally some people
do find my appearance disturbing.
If you have a chill,
I could close the window.
Er... oh no, I'm fine.
Please, er...
I mean, thank you.
Thank you.
You see,
people are frightened
by what they don't understand.
And it is hard to understand,
even for me, because my mother...
she was so very beautiful.
Mrs. Mothershead, I don't think
he should have any more visitors today.
And I have to lecture at the College,
so I'll be back this evening.
Excuse me, sir, but if you have time,
I would like a word with you.
I'm rather late. What is it?
- Well, sir, I don't quite...
- I don't quite understand
why it is you allow
that sort of people in there.
Why? Because he enjoys it,
and I think it's very good for him.
Yes, but, sir, you saw the
expression on their faces.
They didn't hide their disgust.
They don't care anything about John.
They only want to
impress their friends.
I think you're being rather
harsh on them, don't you?
I beg your pardon, sir.
You yourself hardly showed him
much love and kindness
when he first arrived, did you?
I bathed him, I fed him
and I cleaned up after him, didn't I?
And I see that my nurses do the same.
And if "loving kindness" can be called
care and practical concern
then I did show him loving kindness,
and I am not ashamed to admit it!
I didn't mean it exactly that way.
Now please believe me.
Of course I appreciate your concern.
I appreciate everything that
you've done for Mr. Merrick.
Thank you.
But I am the physician in charge
and I must do what I think is best for him.
- Please now, I'm also very late.
- If you ask my opinion,
he's only being stared at
all over again!
Thank you.
Night time!
Freddie.
What's the matter, Freddie?
- I've been thinking about Mr. Bytes.
- What on earth made you think of him?
Well, I'm beginning to believe that
Mr. Bytes and I are very much alike.
That's absurd.
It seems that I...
I've made Mr. Merrick into a
curiosity all over again, doesn't it?
Only this time in a hospital
rather than a carnival.
My name is constantly in the papers.
I'm always being praised to the skies.
Patients are now
expressly asking for my services.
Of course they do.
Because you are a very fine doctor.
John Merrick is happier
and more fulfilled now
than he's ever been in his entire life,
and it's completely due to you.
What was it all for?
Why did I do it?
Freddie, what are you trying to say?
Am I a good man,
or am I a bad man?
Steady on, Treves.
Steady on, my dear fellow.
Come and sit down, won't you?
Gentlemen,
I know we usually open these
proceedings by reading the minutes.
But on this occasion,
in the interests of urgency,
I think we should first conclude
the matter previously under discussion,
the case of Mr. John Merrick,
the Elephant Man.
One moment, Mr. Chairman!
As far as I'm concerned, this creature
has no business being here at all.
I for one am sick and tired
of this competitive freak-hunting
by these overly ambitious
young doctors
trying to make names for themselves.
To parade them about in front of
a pathological society
is one thing, Mr. Treves,
but to waste this committee's
valuable time
with requests for shelter for these...
abominations of nature
is quite another.
You must be more careful...
In the light of these facts,
our course is clear.
The question is not whether to
accept this creature as a patient,
the question is: when will those rooms
be vacated for use by better qualified,
- more deserving cases?
- Hear, hear.
I move that this Elephant Man
be removed from the premises
immediately.
We have a sacred duty
to cure the sick,
not care for circus animals!
- Mr. Broadneck...
- That is my last word on the subject.
Mr. Chairman, shall we vote?
I take it, Mr. Broadneck, that your mind
is quite unshakeable in this matter?
Mr. Chairman, do you not have ears?
I am unalterably opposed!
My mind is made up on this.
You shall not sway me.
May we now vote, Mr. Chairman,
at long last?
Yes, Broadneck.
I think the time has come.
Gentlemen, Her Royal Highness
Alexandra, Princess of Wales.
Good morning, gentlemen.
I hope I am not disturbing you.
On the contrary, ma'am,
your presence here
is always greatly appreciated.
We were just taking a vote
on Mr. Merrick.
Her Royal Highness has shown the
greatest interest in Mr. Merrick's fate.
Indeed I have, sir, as has the Queen.
I have a brief communication
from Her Majesty,
which she has requested
that I read to you.
"To the Governing Committee,
London Hospital.
I would very much like
to commend you
for the charitable face you have shown
Mr. John Merrick, the Elephant Man.
It is laudable that you have
provided one of England's
most unfortunate sons with a safe
and tranquil harbour, a home.
For this immeasurable kindness,
as well as the many other acts of mercy
on behalf of the poor,
of which Mr. Carr Gomm
has kept me informed,
I gratefully thank you.
Signed, Victoria."
I am sure I can count on you
gentlemen to do the Christian thing.
Thank you very much, ma'am.
I'm sure we shall all try.
Gentlemen, I wish to move
that Mr. John Merrick
be admitted to this hospital
on a permanent basis
provided the hospital
receives a yearly sum
equal to the cost of
the occupation of one bed.
All those in favour?
Thank you, gentlemen. The motion is carried.
Yes, come in!
Good afternoon.
Mr. Carr Gomm has something
he wants to say to you.
Mr. Merrick,
I have very great pleasure
in being able to welcome you
officially to the London Hospital.
This morning, the Governing Committee
unanimously voted that you should be
provided with these rooms
on a permanent basis.
This is your home now.
- I'm so very, very glad for you.
- Welcome home, lad!
This is...
my home?
Yes.
Please, will you thank
the Governing Committee for me?
I will do my utmost
to merit their kindness.
This... is my home?
Yes. And this is one other thing.
Your dressing case.
Oh... oh...
Oh... this is...
Oh, thank you!
Oh! Oh, thank you!
Oh, my friends, thank you!
Oh!
My friends!
Oh, my friends!
Oh, thank you!
Okay, mate.
And you, darling, behave yourself.
- Who's next?
- I... I say!
- What, you again?
- Well...
These young ladies have never seen it.
You're on, mate!
OK, that's it for this performance!
- Jim, can I go tonight?
- Sit down, Charlie!
There's always tomorrow, don't worry.
Room for one more?
At the right price.
There's room.
All right, all right,
keep the noise down!
We don't wanna frighten him, do we?
My name is John Merrick.
I'm very, very pleased to meet you.
I think you are...
very... beautiful!
Curtain time!
You look beautiful, darling!
I wouldn't change a thing!
You look like the bleedin'
Prince of Wales!
Here, my friends!
The Elephant Man!
I told you it was 'orrible!
Just horrible.
Perhaps the ladies
would like a closer look?
- Yeah, yeah!
- No, Jack, please!
Here's what you've been waiting for.
There!
Ooh!
He's quite a ladies' man, isn't he?
Come on.
Give the ladies' man a little kiss, eh?
Come on, give him a kiss!
Oh, Jack, leave off!
Here, here, that's enough romance!
Time for beddy-byes!
All right, keep the noise down!
Now keep it quiet.
Quiet! Hey! Now watch this!
Okay, that's enough!
Show's over!
See you back at the Peacock!
Get out of it!
Here, come on.
There you are. That's better, innit?
I've done well tonight.
Here, buy yourself a sweet.
My treasure!
John?
John!
Mr. Treves,
I know what happened last night.
Dear God!
Boy!
Where is he?
Where is Mr. Merrick?
Hmm? John?
Where is he?
Where's Mr. Merrick?
- I don't know what you mean, sir.
- Don't lie to me!
I know all about it.
You were seen.
You're involved with Bytes, aren't you?
You've taken him.
Where... is... he?
Now, wait a minute! I haven't
taken him anywhere. I dunno no Bytes.
We were just having a bit of fun.
We never hurt 'im.
You know, just having a laugh.
That's all.
You bastard, he's gone!
When I left him, he was
in bed, safe and sound!
You bastard!
You're not listening to me!
I told you, I dunno no Bytes!
I ain't done nothing wrong!
People pay money to see your monster,
Mr. Treves. I collect it.
You're the monster, you're the freak!
Now get out, you're finished!
Damn you!
You don't frighten me!
You and your bleedin' Elephant Man!
I'm glad what I done.
And you can do nothing about it!
Only Mothershead can sack me now!
Done!
There's something
I'd like to tell you, Treves.
You know, I felt
as deeply as you did about John.
Well now he's disappeared,
very likely to the continent.
There's no question of your
going after him.
You're desperately needed here
by your patients.
You did everything in your power.
Remember that, Treves.
Everything in your power.
Le terrible...
Homme lphant!
Get the stool!
Get up, you bastard!
Look at all these beautiful animals!
What a lot you have!
That sly bastard!
He's doing this to spite me!
You're doing this to spite me
and it's got to stop!
- Bytes, he's sick!
- Let him die!
But don't think
I'm going to bury that...
bag of flesh. No!
As a matter of fact...
- Bytes, stop!
- As a matter of fact!
Bytes, no, please!
No!
Bytes, please, just don't...
Don't make too much noise.
We've decided...
we're going to get you out of here.
All right?
Good on you, mate.
Good on you.
Luck, my friend!
Luck! And who needs it more than we?
Hey, mister!
Mister, why is your head so big?
Mister!
Why is your head so big, mister?
Why is your head so big? Tell me!
Why won't you answer me, mister?
Er, mister?
Why is your head so big, mister?
Mister!
Stop him, stop him!
No!
I am not an elephant!
I am not an animal!
I am a human being!
I...
am a man.
Out of the way, sir. Excuse me.
Mr. Treves, sir! They've found him!
I think they've found John!
- Keep still, girl!
- Sorry.
It was very nice of Mrs. Kendal
to give me this dress for tonight.
It's so beautiful!
Does Mrs. Kendal know
that John is dying?
Yes.
Yes, she knows.
How do I look?
Splendid!
You will not look out of place.
You look absolutely splendid.
- Splendid... shall we go?
- Yes.
Again, I can't tell you how sorry I am
for what happened.
You see, I had no idea. Really.
Please, you mustn't blame yourself.
Mr. Treves, don't worry about me.
My friend,
I am happy every hour of the day.
My life is full,
because I know that I am loved.
I have gained myself.
I could not say that,
were it not for you.
Well...
And I...
You've done so much for me as well.
Thank you.
So! Um...
I'll fetch Mrs. Mothershead and Nora,
and be back in a few minutes.
Very good, my friend.
My friend...
Mrs. Kendal!
Your Royal Highness,
ladies and gentlemen.
Tonight's performance
was very special to me,
because it was very special
to someone else.
A man who knows the theatre,
and who loves the theatre.
And yet this is the very first time
he's ever been here.
I wish to dedicate,
the whole company wishes
to dedicate with all their hearts,
tonight's performance,
to Mr. John Merrick,
my very dear friend.
Stand up for us.
- I can't.
- Go on, it's all right.
Just stand up.
They want to see you.
I really did believe that...
the ogre would never
get out of the dungeon.
Good.
So you really enjoyed yourself?
Oh, it was wonderful!
Then we must go again some evening.
Oh, yes. Oh, I hope so!
Yes, we will, we will.
Good, I'm pleased.
Well, um... I ought to go.
Must get some sleep.
Good night, and sleep well.
And you too, my friend.
So pleased you enjoyed yourself.
Good night.
It's...
finished!
Never, oh never. Nothing will die.
The stream flows, the wind blows,
the cloud fleets, the heart beats.
Nothing will die.