[DOOR OPENS]
[PANTING]
You'll be fine, Lucy.
This heat's wiping me out.
Well, wind the window
down, if you like.
Forget it.
It's even hotter outside.
At least there's not much traffic.
I'm not surprised.
Who would want to go out
on a day like this?
Aw, come on, don't be like that.
Have you still got your headache?
Yeah. It keeps coming and going
and won't get out.
Smoking's not gonna help it.
Cigarettes are
the only thing that eases it a bit.
[MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO]
♪ There is a war
between the rich and poor... ♪
Don't worry so much about me.
All I need is a good night's sleep.
That's all.
Could you pass me
one of those cigarettes, please?
♪ Between the ones
who say there is a war ♪
♪ And the ones
who say that there isn't ♪
♪ Why don't you come on
back to the war? ♪
♪ That's right, get in it ♪
♪ Why don't you come on
back to the war? ♪
♪ It's just beginning ♪
♪ Well, I live here
with a woman and a child ♪
♪ The situation
makes me kind of nervous ♪
♪ As I rise up, pull her arm ♪
♪ She says, ''I guess
you call this love'' ♪
♪ I call it service ♪
♪ Why don't you
come on back to the war? ♪
♪ Don't be a tourist ♪
♪ Why don't you
come on back to the war ♪
♪ Before it hurts us? ♪
♪ Why don't you
come on back to the war? ♪
♪ Let's all get nervous ♪
♪ You cannot stand
what I've become ♪
♪ You much prefer
the gentleman I was before ♪
♪ I was so easy to defeat,
I was so easy to control ♪
♪ I didn't even know
there was a war ♪
♪ Why don't you
come on back to the war? ♪
♪ Don't be embarrassed ♪
♪ Why don't you
come on back to the war? ♪
♪ You can still get married ♪
♪ There is a war
between the rich and poor ♪
♪ A war between
the man and the woman ♪
♪ There is a war between
the left and right ♪
♪ A war between
the black and white ♪
the odd and the even ♪
♪ Why don't you
come on back to the war... ♪
[DOG BARKING]
[RADIO STOPS]
Soak up the peace and quiet.
Pit stop.
Last hint of civilization
we'll see for a couple of days.
Let's see you stretching your legs.
Yeah, yeah, good idea.
You coming?
No, thanks.
I'm sick of following him.
You sure?
Yeah. Go ahead.
I'll be fine.
OK.
[BARKING]
So what is this place?
I don't know.
Never stopped here before.
- You all right?
- Yeah, yeah, fine.
- [TAPS ON CAR DOOR]
Are you coming?
- I'm shattered.
The less we get caught up,
the sooner we'll get there.
OK.
Glad to see you're all enthusiastic.
- Yours isn't coming either?
- Nope.
Well, a little bit better.
- How about a couple glasses of vino?
- [BARKING]
Oh, that's all
we fucking need. Lester!
Hey, come on, come on,
come on. Here.
[MURMURING]
[MURMURING STOPS]
[LAUGHTER]
[TURNS ON AND OFF
TAPE PLAYER]
What's wrong?
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[SILENCE]
Come on, I think
we should get going.
- It's getting late.
- Yeah.
Oh, no.
I'll... pay this time.
You were taking forever.
The old boy thinks
we should all go in my car.
He says this one might not make it
along the track.
I'm not leaving this here. No way.
I’d listen to him.
They have good instincts
about stuff like that.
The car will be fine.
Let's just go.
All right.
I hope it's still there
when I get back.
Who's gonna steal it out here?
- It's safe enough.
- It better be.
You ought to get yourself
one of these.
Take you anywhere you want.
Built like a tank, safe as houses.
You want kids?
Plenty of room for the kids.
We're almost there.
See the river? Down there.
- What do you think?
- I think it's great.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah, I try and work on it
every chance I can.
What about this location?
[BREATHS DEEPLY] Feel you can...
You can really breathe.
WOMAN: Why don't you open the door?
We can show them the inside.
OTHER WOMAN:
Good idea.
You're incapable of enjoying nature,
even for a minute, aren't you?
WOMAN: Thank you.
I think we're going to get sick of it.
Here, take it. Won't bite.
Look at this beauty.
I got this last year.
Feel how smooth that is.
If you two aren't going to help...
you can at least
get out of the way.
So, what do you think
of the sitting room?
You converted this?
Yeah. Yeah,
it used to be the stables.
You still think this is a crazy idea?
I'm telling you,
we should come and live here.
We could start a company again
like we did in London.
Oh, are you going to
start talking about work again?
You've been going on
about that all week.
Well, if it's bothering him...
then he should say something,
shouldn't he?
I'm not bothered. I'm...
Did I miss something?
I was about to finally
convince your husband...
that you should move here.
Oh. Thank you,
but I think I prefer civilization.
Oh, you, too?
I support the motion.
You don't want
to end up like the family...
in the little house
on the prairie, do you?
Oh, no. God forbid.
Give me that.
Oh, don't say my darling
Michael Landon has got angry.
[GLASS BREAKS]
[CRICKETS CHIRPING,
OWL HOOTS]
[DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES]
It's freezing in here.
Come on, get in here quick.
I feel awful.
- Completely exhausted.
- Yeah, too many kilometers.
Too much Paul.
- And she's so nice.
- Don't be like that.
You know he's invested
a lot in this place.
Oh, that's better.
- It feels so good laying down.
- [DISTANT SOUNDS OF LOVEMAKING]
Sounds like they've made it up.
Just as well.
I couldn't take
another supper like that one.
- Shall we turn off the light?
- Yeah.
Things will be a bit better
when we get some time on our own.
We've been traveling by car
for a week.
I don't know
if I can take any more driving.
Do you really not feel like it?
No, it's not that
I don't feel like it, but...
Look, I can't think right now.
Let's talk about it tomorrow, OK?
Yeah.
- [WOMAN LAUGHING]
- Listen to that.
[MAN MOANS]
- Don't. They'll hear us.
- So tomorrow I can't tell?
[BOTH LAUGH]
Oh, I am tired.
I still have an awful headache.
What's wrong?
I don't know.
I feel uncomfortable.
Shh, Norman, I said no!
A change of air
will do us both good.
Do you think that things are different
because we're here?
Do you feel different?
Because I don't.
- What do you feel?
- You know how I feel.
No, I don't.
I don't know anything.
Why did you walk in like that?
What?
In the bar.
Why did you walk in like that?
What do you mean?
You knew that
if you walked in like that...
everyone would look
at you and I’d see.
You did it to fuck with me.
Are you serious?
[DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES]
- What time is it?
- 6:30. Go back to sleep.
What are you doing up
at this time, Norman?
I'm going hunting with Paul.
- Hunting? You?
- [KNOCK ON DOOR]
PAUL: Norman, it'll be getting
dark again soon. Come on.
I'm coming.
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
PAUL: How you getting on
with that shotgun?
Heavy.
Ah, it's good to feel the weight.
Lets you know it's there.
You use it when you need it.
You sound like a proper hunter.
I am