Yeah!
What?
Already?
That's too far ahead of schedule.
Jesus!
Yeah, I'll be right there.
Yeah, I'm coming right now.
Laura!
What?
We got to get to the base.
Something happened.
Everything okay?
Something serious?
Just meet me in the car in
5 minutes. I'll get Tina.
Okay.
Dad what's going on?
Hi, baby.
5 minutes, meet me in the car?
Did you see what's happening outside?
What should we do?
Just stay calm, I need you to pack an
overnight bag. We're going to the base.
- How long are we to be gone?
- Not long.
- So I don't pack that much
- I don't know, baby.
Just get what you can and maybe
we come back for the rest.
But I got to get to the
base as soon as possible.
I want you there
with me, okay?
Okay.
Come on, Laura.
Let's go!
What's Kelvin’s ETA?
Somebody give me an answer ASAP!
I've got a force launch going in the space
loaded with nukes, way ahead of schedule
why is he not in here?
His locator shows him
nearly 60 miles of-site
- Get an escort and get it to him now
- Yes, sir.
Sir, that blast came out of nowhere.
Another one like that might take
our launch systems off-line.
Recommendations?
Well, the faster it gets up there,
the sooner it comes down and gets reloaded.
- Commence countdown.
- Copy that. Countdown commenced.
5, 4, 3, 2, 1...
Go!
Rockets firing...
And we now lift off...
The rocket is up, sir
Now, get him in here.
Ryan, can you slow down?
I guess I shouldn't even bother asking
why we're going to the base.
I just can't, Laura.
If you found out why, then...
I wouldn't be doing my job.
Thanks, baby
That's very reassuring.
You are unbelievable!
Unbelievable!
Is that one of yours?
Go! Go!
Oh my God!
Are you kidding me right now?
Who was that? Why would people be after us?
I'm not sure.
Not sure 'cause you don't know
or you're not sure,
because it's another
stupid government cover-up.
I'm not sure because
I really don't know
and I really don't want to find out
with the two of you in the car.
Everybody hold on.
I think they shot the tires.
What?
- Oh my God!
- We gonna have to make a run for it.
Run.
Come on!
Go!
Go back.
It's a dead end,
it's a dead end.
Now everybody get out.
Go, go!
come on!
Go! Go!
Hurry.
Dr Kelvin!
What are you doing with nuclear weapons?
Dr Kelvin?
What is he talking about?
What?
In the last year...
you have made 7 trips...
to the International Space Station,
armed with bombs.
Why?
Okay.
You gotta run, okay?
- We're all in danger, the whole world!
- Yes, by your actions.
Mr Kelvin?
Professor Kelvin?
- There is one more!
- Henreaux?
Henreaux?
What took you so long?
We got here as quick as we could, sir.
Don't worry, Mrs. Kelvin.
I have agents taking care of you and your
daughter before this project is finished.
I'll make all the arrangements myself.
Get them to the base.
They'll be safe there
Yes, sir.
I can't believe we were in danger
and you didn't tell us.
I didn't know.
Honestly.
Nobody outside the project
was supposed to know anything.
Well baby, obviously somebody found out.
I just...
How long..?
Tell me when it's gonna be over
and when we're gonna be safe?
A month.
One month.
One way or another
it'll all be over, I promise.
Okay.
Mam'!
I am Agent Green
This is my partner agent Dunne.
- We have a car waiting.
- Okay.
Mam’!
Sir!
Catch ya!
My wife, my daughter, myself...
whatever these guys found out from my side,
would have killed us afterwards.
You know, it's one thing for
me to put my life on the line.
Whoever inside the project leaked the
information out, we'll plug the leak.
Well please do it before it gets more out
of hand, before it gets out to the public.
before it causes worldwide panic.
Professor Kelvin!
Capt. James Moto, Air Force office of
Special Investigations.
Hi.
I've been assigned to go through your
computer systems,
emails, IM's, blog posts, you know
anything containing information ways.
You know enough about the project,
to know what you're looking for?
Well, yeah, I know that the
small burst of radiation
that have been hitting planet Earth,
the past couple of years,
is supposed to be prelude to a full
blast supernova that's coming in over us.
Not supposed to be about it.
Based on analysis we've been
getting the Spitzer Space Telescope,
there's gonna be enough gamma radiation
for a planet-killing catastrophe.
I need to go check on the space platform.
The climate will go haywire.
Everything controlled by
electricity will be fried.
Communications, water and you name it...
The earth will turn into
a radioactive wasteland.
That's how long we have
until the blast hits us.
And there is nothing that can
be done to stop it.
That's what this project is all about.
Another hand to help us
with our calculations?
Capt. Moto, Professor Huan Ye of China.
The People's Republic of China.
Professor Dzerzhinsky of Russia.
The People's Republic of Vodka.
Ye and I have been going over the
calculations, for nuclear missile launches.
and I think that we will have to alter
each launch by a few milliseconds,
in order for pattern to sustain cloud.
We have to re-program the US missile
launch codes in order to
match the timing of ours.
Or you could just let us do it.
I'm sure my government would be about
as happy about that as yours would.
Message me the new codes.
What a shame.
With so much at stake, you'd think we could
make decisions that
would benefit our own mutual interest.
Perhaps it's in all our mutual
interest that we study all the data,
and make our decision based on that.
- Touché!
- I don't care.
I just hope that when
we launch those nukes
that the cloud shield will protect the Earth
as much as possible.
Magnetosphere is earth's natural barrier
against radiation.
But our data show that the
incoming radiation would be too strong
for the magnetosphere to handle, so...
we're gonna help mother nature out.
There are two schools of thought
on where to explode the nukes.
Inside the magnetosphere
and outside the magnetosphere.
Honestly, unless we can't
get more nukes up there,
neither of these plans are gonna cut it.
Let me ask you a question.
You trust these guys?
I have to.
we're all gonna be up on that space platform
together controlling the missile launches.
I wish we could launch them from down here,
But...
without the earth's
gravitational pull we can...
pinpoint the launches right
where we want them and...
and detonate them more quickly.
What happens if one the bursts
fries the platform's electronics?
Well...
We've had them retro-fitted
with radiation shield,
like we did on the space shuttle, so...
let’s hope that doesn't happen.
Where is it?
Mrs. Kelvin?
Tina, are you sure you haven't seen it,
I thought you had it last.
I can't remember.
Mrs. Kelvin?
It gotta be here somewhere.
- Ms. Kelvin?
- What?
I'm not leaving here without
her mom's necklace, okay?
Mrs. Kelvin?
What?
We did you the courtesy
of coming back here.
We are on a tight timetable and
we need to escort you to base.
Now.
10 more minutes.
and we're leaving.
Your father told me he hid it in some
stupid hiding place that only he knows.
You know, you really need
to cut him some slack.
He has some pretty big
things on his mind.
You're right.
Will you help me look?
And there you go my man, Gin.
Oh, come on.
You know you'll need male
equipments to be an astronaut.
Funny, funny, funny.
Okay, they're loading the nuclear
warhead on the shuttle now.
This is it.
The last one.
Let us do our part
to save the world again.
Let me see.
For the nuclear cloud shield
to be strong enough to last this,
the entire supernova burst,
we should have more
warheads that we thought.
You're right.
I wish that we had more.
But, given the time constraint
that we have and
the fact that we only have 3 shuttles
to carry everything to the platform, I...
Yes.
I just wish we had
one more load of
of nuclear warheads.
Up there.
Because, at this point,
every shuttle, especially this last one,
will make a difference, as to whether
our little nuclear shield will...
protect the whole earth, or not.
Look, I know,
but we're just gonna do the best with
what we've got and hope that it works.
A massive earthquake has triggered
an infamous volcano
in Italy, back into activity.
Now, two thousand years later, Mount
Vesuvius has reared its head once again,
burying hundreds of square
kilometers in ash and pumice.
Guess what I found?
Thanks.
What's wrong, sweetie?
Are you kidding me?
We almost got murdered this morning
and now we are supposed to
get in the car and go right back into it?
I know, I just...
I don't know what else to do...
Why can't he just stay here with us?
Why can't he just be here?
Sweetheart, it's just
like you said, it's just...
He's got a lot on his plate right now.
She'd know what to do.
Yeah.
I know she would.
- When is it gonna stop?
- Let's just hold on.
Let's go!
Come on, get the two. Let's get out of here.
Come on.
From here on out,
stronger energy bursts are
going to hit earth and
and worse it will beget.
The shuttle.
Please tell me the platform
is intact.
I'm sorry, Dr. Kelvin, but I'm not
sure we're gonna be able to launch it.
There could be problems
launch structure now.
We don't have any other choice,
Those warheads have to
get up on the platform
or parts of the earth are gonna go
unprotected and destroyed by radiation.
Okay, I'll have the structure
gone over again, but...
I know, I know,
everyone is aware of the risk.
Please do it.
I'll find out when the
after-shocks are gonna hit, so
we can schedule the
next launch.
Alright, good, thanks. I...
I gotta take
care of something else now.
Ryan?
Thank God.
Yeah, we are okay.
The house was destroyed in the
earthquake.
No, no, we're okay.
Yeah, we are on our way there now.
Agents are right in front of us.
They are keeping an eye on us.
Good, good, just...
do what they tell you and
everything will be alright.
Okay, I will.
I love you too.
Brace yourself.
Look out!
The tremors feel like they...
Is it over?
I think so.
Laura.
Ryan!
What happened...? Laura?
I can hardly hear you.
Oh my God!
- Professor Kelvin?
- I'm sorry, what?
The next after-shock won't hit for hours.
I spoke with NASA,
and they Okayed the launch structure so
they're gonna go ahead as scheduled.
Good.
Let’s pray nothing else happens
between now and then.
Sir!
What is it?
We're picking up a major
surge in energy particles
about to reach the earth's atmosphere.
That's almost four hours
ahead of our calculations.
We have to get a hold of
launch control and see if
there's any way we could
stop them from launching.
If the shipments of warheads
doesn't make it up there...
we won't have enough to protect
us against the full supernova burst.
It's not much we can do about it now.
The launch is a GO in... 3,
2, 1...
Mission Control?
Mission Control, can you read me?
Mission Control, please respond!
That flight had to happen.
We needed those warheads.
We have to re-compute
the missile launch pattern.
Now that we don't have as many
as we need.
Let's get an uplink.
I'll run a full diagnostic to see if
there's any damage on the platform.
That is if the energy
burst will let us through.
I will re-check energy burst,
to try to figure out...
why we were so far off in calculating speed.
Dr. Kelvin.
What?
Based on our newest data...
that we are getting now, our...
our calculations on
when the supernova will arrive
are off by more than 24 hours.
Jesus!
But that could change,
it could get shorter, if the...
stronger blast that comes right before the
supernova is moving faster than we think.
And I think we should take another look
at where we are going to do the explosions,
inside or outside magnetosphere.
You know my feelings on this and
the reason I believe we need
to create the shield outside it.
Yes, but I just did a
new computer simulation of
the nuclear explosions with fewer warheads,
and molecules will stay more
tightly bound together
if the explosions occur
inside the magnetosphere.
Not outside, it won't
be as effective.
And if we explode the warheads
inside the magnetosphere,
we run the chance of destroying
the earth's atmosphere.
changing the climate and destroying
this planet as we know it.
Oh please.
I think we need to concentrate
on the immediate threat.
The supernova.
We can't just trade off one form of
the earth being destroyed for another.
That's only if we accept your theory.
You do not know what will
happen anymore than I do.
Got a second?
I've been running through all
the internet traffic
in and out here for the
past couple of days,
I found that someone sent out a message
to a blind email account.
Professor Ryan Kelvin is
the one in charge of
putting nuclear weapons into
space for the U.S. government.
It's no wonder that the Iranians came after
me. Any idea who signed in to this computer?
You did.
Or someone using
your name and password.
Look, somebody’s being smart.
Is there any way that I, when I...
my username signs in to use a program
that we attach a voice ID and a password?
Sure, no problem.
- Take care of yourself.
- Oh,
One oth... I mean if you can...
I've been trying to get a hold of my wife
all day and it's just nothing but static.
I can use a signal booster and
see if that will do the trick.
Thanks... 'cause I'm just...
with the earthquake I...
Don't worry about it,
I'm on it right now
Okay?
It's stuck.
The links are probably down.
Just an after-shock.
Hello!
Got it.
Laura?
Thank God, I've been trying
get through to you.
The agents were killed
in the earthquake.
Where are you?
You're still on your way, right?
We're trying to get
to the air base but
the bridge is blocked so
we can't get through.
You okay?
Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm worried, I've been
trying to get a hold of you.
Maybe you shouldn't try to meet me here.
I don't know what to do.
We can't keep driving.
No, what I was thinking is,
maybe you'd meet me at Patterson.
There is an underground secure
facility there, it's where all the...
shuttle launch computers are,
where all the NASA higher-ups are going
because we had it special radiation treated.
Meet me at the fall out okay?
So,
We heard on the news about,
the supernova, that's true?
Yes.
Me not talking to you the last few years...
I couldn't.
There's something else I want to talk to
you about, but not on the phone, okay?
Meet me at the fallout shelter.
Okay, hum.
Tell them to expect us, okay?
Baby, I love you.
I love you too.
When they get to the gates
they're gonna use his name.
What I want you to do is assign them a
secure living quarter until he gets there.
You're a good man.
I got it setup now, so any time your
password logs onto a computer,
somebody's gonna need to
register a voice command
before the computer does anything.
One less thing to worry about.
Laura, look out!
Who taught you how to drive?
The heat is really climbing.
I can't believe that
storm caught up to us.
Get in, let's get outta here.
It keeps getting closer.
I know.
I've never seen clouds
move so fast.
Look out!
Laura!
Okay, don't touch anything. Any Metal
will be electrified.
It's okay.
I think we'll be alright.
The cab's like a Faraday cage,
Thank God the windows are rolled up.
The electricity will find a
way to the ground in a second.
You are your father’s daughter aren't you?
The Faraday's cage isn't enclosed anymore.
It means...
That electricity can get us now.
Alright, uh...
Maybe we can get a ride.
Get out.
Now.
We have to get away from the car,
it will attract the lightning.
Alright, go there!
Go!
Stay away from trees!
They attract lightning the most!
Remind me to thank your father...
Oh God!
Even if the lightning doesn't get us,
one of those feelers still could.
We're gonna be okay.
Oh God, Laura!
Come on!
Great, the launch computers on
the platforms are not responding.
We can't get through to them?
I can communicate with other systems,
onboard, just not those.
It's a good thing we have
back-ups that is functioning, right?
Don't we?
I'll go over it to make
sure that it is,
but it has to gonna come onboard
with us on the shuttle.
Wait, it needs to be
programmed with the latest data.
And you have to run
that test-fire simulation
to make sure of its launch capabilities.
The speed of the energy burst,
is increasingly hitting us,
means that the launch computer
will have to reconfigure
time, space and location
of missile launches,
and destination, second by second.
We are almost just guessing how
fast the supernova is really moving,
until it is right about to hit us.
Moto?
I'm gonna be down at A-13,
Do me a favor, will you?
Keep trying to get a hold of my wife.
Kelvin Ryan, project head.
Are all the electric power turned
on to the platform mark-up?
Yes, sir.
I heard that you had
a problem.
It kind of makes me wonder if God
wants us interfering with his plans!
Right now I wonder how the grapevine
around here knows about mine.
Okay.
Come on, baby, I don't
need any more problems now.
Let's check the control panel.
Great. At least the
emergency system works.
Kelvin!
Kelvin.
Fuck.
Kelvin, it's me, Henreaux!
Come on, sit down!
You okay?
You got any idea
who attacked you?
No, just...
what they were after, just...
someone dressed in black, and kicked
my ass in a real professional way.
How long was I out?
20 minutes, maybe.
If someone wanted to sabotage this project
they could have destroyed
this with the replacing panel.
Or they just wanted
to get rid of you.
It's gotta be someone
inside this project.
But after what?
There's been no unauthorized access,
but I'm cross-checking the
password and log-in now.
Where's Motto?
He's dead.
He came looking for you with a message but
he ran into your man in black instead.
Jesus!
Dead?
It is desperate.
Do whatever you can.
Yes.
Goodbye.
Where is Ye?
Did the simulation work?
You both been here the
whole time since I left?
I was gone a few minutes to
pick up some sandwiches, but...
Why? Didn't Moto find you?
You saw Moto?
He was here.
He was looking for you. He said...
your wife called and that
she needed your help.
Desperately.
Time is growing... shorter.
It looks like the lightning stopped.
For right now.
How are we gonna get to the base?
Howdy.
You all get lost?
All 'em fire is burning
because of the heat and lightning.
Hey, do you happen to have a phone
we can use?
Sure do.
If it's still working.
This heat.
The two of you must be pretty desperate
to get somewhere to be out in this on foot.
We had a car.
But the storm...
We're trying to get to my dad
before he takes off on the space shuttle.
He's working on that big project?
Ryan?
Laura?
Where are you?
Why haven't you gotten to Patterson yet?
What?
Listen, we're...
we're okay, for right now, but
I don't know if we're gonna
make it to Patterson.
I'm coming to get you guys.
No.
Baby, You can't leave
project now.
Look, I have to see you.
Baby, I want to see you too.
More than anything, but...
Listen, I know that you have
to do what you're doing.
Okay? You have a job to do, and...
there's too much at stake for
you should leave now.
I can't leave you out
there unprotected, Laura.
Somehow we'll...
we'll be fine.
Really.
You know that cave that we
went exploring out during our vacation?
We'll go in there,
there'll be protection.
We'll be fine.
Honey...
I haven't told you my part.
It's up on the space platform
launching the missiles.
If any part of the supernova burst
makes it trough the platform, it won't...
Look honey, if I haven't
told you enough lately or...
if you ever doubted...
I know, baby.
I know.
I just want you to know,
that I love you so much.
Hi, Dad?
Hey kiddo!
Hey, uh...
if you guys can't make it to...
the base in the next couple of hours,
I need you to find...
some deep cover, okay?
A mine shaft or a cave or something.
Understand?
Yeah, I will.
I will.
I will do what can,
but I need you and Laura
to find a safe spot, okay?
Dad?
You know, If you want to get to that cave,
it's not gonna be a good idea for
you to try it out on foot.
That old truck of mine ain't much but,
but it ought to get you there okay.
What about you?
Come with us, you're not
gonna be safe here.
Where am I gonna go?
I've lived here my whole life.
I'll die here.
So this is the truck I was
telling you guys about.
Thank you so much.
No need.
Glad to help.
I was having a second idea here...
I'm thinking maybe only one
of you should go.
I think maybe she should stay.
Excuse me?
There's no reason for
both of you to go, really,
and I'd like for her to stay.
Besides, for the weather, the way it is,
Who knows if we even have tomorrow?
So what do you say?
I think maybe you and I could
really get to know each other.
I'll call you back.
Things bad or worse than expected?
I just faced my own mortality a
little quicker that I wanted to.
I'm not too
happy about that.
How are you feeling physically?
Look, I feel, like Atlas,
with the world on my shoulders,
only that the world is crushing me.
I want the leak,
I want whoever killed Moto found
Alright? Sweep the place.
Bugs, taps on my computer. Everything.
Yes, sir.
Right away.
We lost more time, huh?
Based on the speed of this latest bursts...
that's our new time.
At this rate we will have to
make launch to space platform
more quicker than I thought.
A lot more quicker.
Then I better finish the simulation
on that replacement panel.
You trying to test 'em?
When I'm in the platform mock-up
I want remote surveillance.
No security actually inside the hangar.
So if someone wants to come after me,
and find something out, that's fine.
We need to find out who they are,
and what they want as soon as possible.
We're running out of time.
Kelvin, Ryan, project head.
It's like the apocalypse is coming.
Wow, what's happening?
The gust keep picking up,
it's like flying into a head wind.
How much longer 'til we get
to this cave we're going to?
We should be there by morning.
I hope it's not that way.
Oh my God!
If we can't get off here,
we'll have to turn around.
- Look out.
- I see it!
Maybe we should do
what they're doing and...
go back.
We can't go back that way. We'll be trapped.
Okay, but do you see a cutoff or anything?
Look around.
I'm looking, I'm looking.
- There, I can see...
- God!
We're not gonna make it,
We're gonna make it.
Put your head down.
Let's get outta here.
Let's go!
Come on!
No attacker.
Well, we're not gonna
get another chance.
We got the word to move you to
the shuttle launch site in one hour.
It's the atmosphere.
It's getting more unstable by the hour.
So if we don't go up now,
we might not make it to the platform?
Any luck on getting a hold
on my wife and daughter?
Sorry, too much
interference.
Alright, you'd better pack up the
computer replacement panel.
I'm gonna have a word
with Dzerzhinsky and Ye.
Hey buddy, you okay?
- Yeah.
- You're gonna be fine.
That was a hell of an earthquake.
Bring a medical team down here, right away.
Roger that.
Somebody's gonna be here.
Just be calm.
Doc, you can you
give me a hand?
Yeah, let me put this case down,
I'll be right back.
Kelvin Ryan, project head.
- Are you alright?
- Where is Dzerzhinsky
In the control room, we've been
getting ready to leave.
Great!
All those satellites giving
us data are gone,
The only place to measure,
speed of supernova, is platform.
Hurry up; we gotta get ready to go.
There is no telling how
short time we have...
until the boom.
Have you been here the whole time?
Yes, I tried to get signal trough
to the platform but could not.
- For all I know it might not be working.
- Wonderful.
- We've got problems!
- More?
That earthquake was centered
30 km off the coast,
it may have destroyed
the shuttle platform.
Let us finish get packed up, just...
get us some transportation.
- Right away.
You okay?
We did it.
Let's go, kiddo!
Not beaten yet.
You think you can fix this?
We'll see, there's only so
much that can go wrong with
an internal combustion engine.
Will you go in the back
and see if there's a
a screwdriver or something?
Careful, careful!
Try it again.
Try again.
Go ahead and try
one more time.
Nice.
I've already told you.
There's no way we can do it.
The launch is scrapped.
But the shuttle is on the launch pad.
It could be launched and we've got
no other choice except to try.
That's just the problem,
it can't be launched.
The electromagnetic storm have wrecked
irrevocable havoc on all our systems.
- So it's the control panel?
- Gone. Nothing's working.
You still got power, don't you?
Well, the emergency generator system.
Alright, then hook it
directly to the shuttle,
create a makeshift control panel
and get ready to do it manually.
You gotta be kidding.
You know how many variables are
involved with the rocket firing sequence?
Just keeping them stabilized
is difficult enough.
You people have fired off enough shuttles
by now to be able to do it in your sleep.
Take the training wheels
off and do it manually.
Is it possible?
The earthquake could have damaged
the launch structure too.
I mean... I don't know.
It scares the shit outta me too,
but either way,
if we don't go up there we're gonna die.
Anyone else have a better idea?
Still believe in the
hand of God, Dzerzhinsky?
God’s great hand?
sweeping across the
universe to destroy all of mankind?
Why don't you just
let me enjoy cigarette
before I go blow myself
up in that machine?
All lines are busy.
If they can't complete this soon,
then it doesn't matter anyway.
She is very correct.
Just using,
acceleration factor of burst
so far is baseline.
I would have to say
that we have only about
eight hours 'till
supernova burst.
It's too bad our people's republic
space program wasn't further along.
Because we would have
planned this much better,
for us to not have
problems like this.
You may have had
better planning but...
you would still need Russian
engineering in order to do better.
As long as we're talking about planning,
I'd like to reexamine
where we're going to
explode the warheads.
That has already been decided.
It's already been decided based on numbers.
The electromagnetic and
molecular interaction
but not in how the
magnetosphere works.
We already know what you think about
how it will affect the earth.
I'm not talking about climate effects.
I'm talking about the best
way to use it as a shield.
Look,
we have two shields,
against the supernova burst,
the magnetosphere,
and the nuclear cloud shield.
Based on molecular interaction
with constant warheads explosions,
the nuclear cloud
will defiantly be the
stronger of the two.
against the supernova's
gamma radiation
And I agree.
Based on the numbers it will hold
together a little more strongly
if we position it inside
the magnetosphere.
Okay, but how the
magnetosphere works
its self-sustaining.
It can take smaller energy bursts
and to recover quickly.
Which means,
with the cloud shield outside of it,
then the magnetosphere will act as
a constant second shield.
to catch the radiation the
cloud shield misses.
But if the magnetosphere takes,
the full burst of the supernova first,
disrupting its flow
it won't be able to regenerate
and all that will be left
is the one shield, the cloud shield
- ... to protect the earth.
- This is what's important.
The strength of the... cloud shield.
The numbers supports it.
The scientific community agrees.
I don't think we should
change things now.
Even if we wanted to,
there's no time to program the
new sequences into
the launch computer.
- I still have...
- No!
We are sticking with the plan.
Are you ready?
No.
But that's not gonna stop us.
Alright.
If you really wanna do this,
Get your gear.
All systems?
- It's powered up.
- Check.
cabin pressure?
10.2.0 PSI.
Exterior air temperature, 134 degrees.
We're not supposed to launch
if it's over 99.
Seeing how we don't even know if the
platform's up there,
so that's the least of our worries.
We're all set.
Okay, commence countdown.
I'm proud to stand along with you
on this new battlefield
an arena we have
never encountered.
We sit on the brink
of annihilating
and I speak to you now,
not just as your president.
but as a fellow citizen of
United States and the entire world.
By now you all know the ensuing
supernova and the consequences it may bring.
It is an event this world
will not soon forget.
Let our hearts and
our minds guide us,
but not let them limit or consume
us with greed and selfpreservation.
but let us instead become infected with
goodwill and love toward our fellowman.
Let this be our finest hour.
if it is to be our last.
Remember hope.
Remember your loved ones
and those who came before us.
Remember the legacy and what
they have given us.
And if it be God's will,
may He preserve us all.
Rocket booster de-tatch.
Our trajectory is off by 2 degrees.
Without NASA control guiding us,
I'm pretty amazed we're doing this good.
- We are at the edge of the shield.
- The ship can make it...
It's coming apart.
What... what are you doing?
Increasing the thrust as it
get us through the ionosphere.
Electric storm is not good.
It's getting worse,
another charge,
I found the receiver.
The space platform.
It's...
What is it?
We ran out of gas.
Alright.
Let's see if we
can get some.
Hey, we ran out of gas.
Can you help us out?
There is no escaping this, is there?
We're all gonna die.
Stop it!
Listen to me!
We can make it.
We can. We have a really good chance
of surviving.
But if we gonna do that
we need to do it together, okay?
I need you to be strong and I need
your help. You can do that?
You can do that, right?
- Yes.
- Okay.
You have to make the adjustments
on the replacement panel!
Time before energy
burst hitting us,
tells me we only have 28 minutes before...
You know...
How long?
28 minutes.
Let’s hope this place
has 28 minutes left.
The panel is fried,
but there's still juice.
We got 27 minutes.
Okay, I think I got it.
Go ahead program the launch codes
while I get my laptop up and running.
Section B is not just breeched,
it's gone.
I got it closed down,
but no telling which one is next.
Hurry!
Okay!
The sequence couplings are frozen.
The missiles aren't gonna deploy
unless I do manually.
I think I got it.
Initiate the firing sequence.
Dzerzhinsky?
Dzerzhinsky!
Come on!
Dzerzhinsky?
You'll never change
launch sequence.
All I need is your eyeball.
Kelvin, Ryan,
project head.
Kelvin, Ryan
Switch to launch scenario B.
Set time and distance,
outside the magnetosphere.
I'm burning up.
I can't take this.
Ryan!
Recalculating.
Ordinance file malfunction.
8, 7, 6, 5,
4, 3, 2, 1.
Warning!
Computer, open the channel
to ground control.
Kelvin to Henreaux.
Henreaux can you read me?
It's Henreaux, go ahead.
Henreaux...
My systems are haywire up here.
- Do you have ordinance read-outs?
- Yes, it's affirmative.
How many did NOT deploy?
How many did not deploy?
Eight, Kelvin.
- Shit.
- Kelvin, listen to me!
The shield still may hold.
You need to confirm that
with Ye and Dzerzhinsky.
That's not happening, Henreaux.
We both know the
shield is weak as it is.
We know what
we have to do.
Tell my wife and daughter...
I love them, alright?
Kelvin, what are you doing?
Computer...
close comlink.
time to impact.
15, 14, 13,
12, 11, 10
9, 8, 7, 6...
Computer, detach the central spindle...
Come on!
3, 2, 1.
Mrs. Kelvin.
I had to come myself.
There is someone
you have to talk to.
Hello!
Ryan?
Yeah, I can hear you.
Supernova,
an exploded star.
The genesis of life itself on
a collision course with our planet.
Dzerzhinsky once told me it
was like God's great hands
sweeping across the universe.
intenting to destroying all mankind.
a cosmic broom meant to clear
the way for something new.
God's will or not,
it came from deep in space.
and felt terror
and isolation of being alone.
What does man do when its
back is against the wall?
Ye, tried to change the codes to
protect the eastern hemisphere more heavily,
helping to ensure the
perseveration of her people.
Thinking back, it's hard
to blame anyone for that.
When I returned to a hero's welcome
I said that Ye and Dzerzhinsky died
saving not only my life,
but the lives of billions.
We weren’t prepared.
We didn't see it coming,
but we found a way
The nuclear shield held,
but not without its own consequences.
The world has changed,
but we're still here.
And stronger for it.
When all the pretents melts away...
you're finally able to hold on,
to what's important.
Transcript from the movie by Knã.