Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
God.
Shit!
Who are you and why did you
bring me here?
Fuck. Bring you here?
Lady,
I just woke up.
Look. Look.
I was drugged.
Some arsehole
stuck me last night.
Come on. See, please.
Come on.
Is that where you woke up?
Yeah. You?
Next door.
A bunch of rooms out there.
Is it just us?
The first door I tried.
What's the last thing
you remember?
Gorgeous brunette
at the end of the bar.
- Ah.
- What?
Just because I'm Irish,
you think I'm a drunk?
I was having
a fuckin' ginger ale.
What about you?
I, uh, don't exactly remember.
Don't remember?
Well, forgive me
if that doesn't do it for me.
Because when it comes to
a syringe in my neck,
I tend to be specific.
Now you're my new best friend.
Oh, we're not friends.
Come on, give us a chance, yeah?
We'll be as thick as thieves
in no time.
I'm holding you responsible
for whoever's going
down with you. Hmm?
Right then.
After you.
Stop.
Relax. We're locked in here too.
I don't believe you.
You got one of these?
I said stop.
If you're trying to cut through,
it won't work.
- No shit.
- That thing burns hotter than lava.
You'll start melting the metal,
and you'll be burning
the whole place down.
How do you know?
My father's in the trade.
What trade?
Contracting.
Just coming over here.
What's on the other side
of this door?
A way out I was hoping.
You.
What's your name?
Kate.
I'm Rowan,
if anyone gives a shit.
We're here for a reason.
What is that?
A reason.
They're plans to a vault
inside the Matheson Museum.
- The what?
- It's...
It's in Cleveland.
Are we supposed to go
to Cleveland?
Wait...
are we in Cleveland?
What in the name of Jesus
are we doing in Cleveland?
- Where were you last?
- New York.
Arizona. You?
Toronto. Vacation.
Someone went to a lot of trouble
to bring us here.
So, whatever the score is,
it's gotta be worth it.
Score, huh?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
I'm a law-abiding citizen.
Contracting, right?
That's the one.
But if this were a score,
- what would it be?
- I don't know.
Great. Reality TV.
Kiss my bollocks, big brother!
High explosive.
Semtex, maybe.
Christ, it's enough
to take down the whole building.
Where the hell is it?
I guess we're supposed
to figure that out.
Why the hell do you keep running
toward all the scary shit?
- Who the hell is this guy?
- Hey.
Hey!
You wanna tell us
what you're doing here?
Same thing you're doing
I'd imagine.
Trying to get out of here alive.
You tried to escape.
Gerry, you're late.
And I have a schedule to keep.
You're cutting it awfully close.
You've had months.
Have you ever known me
to let you down?
This isn't exactly the plan
we signed up for.
Why you here, Gerry?
Because they're worried.
Because it's tonight,
and because I wanna make damn
sure our investment is safe.
Is it?
Look for yourself.
You know, I've been
doing this a long time
and if there's one thing
I've learned
it's that people
are who they are.
I look at this,
and I wonder
what makes you think that they're
going to do what you want them to do?
Well, because they have
no choice.
Because they are...
who they are.
What's this?
I'm not the one who's going to have
to pay if this doesn't work out.
Always nice to chat, Theo.
Lovely to see you too, Gerry.
No, thank you.
Anybody mind?
I was out in the hallway,
I was looking for a way out,
all hell broke loose.
You didn't feel like
coming out to say hello?
Oh...
let's just say I'm a bit shy
by nature,
and I wanted to know
who I was dealing with first.
You satisfied?
Entirely.
What's so funny?
Well, you have to admire
the humor of this situation.
I mean, four thieves
locked up
and we haven't even committed
a crime yet.
Thieves? You know,
I'll have you know
I'm a contractor.
Of course, you are, my dear.
Now, listen up, kids...
if you wanna know what's going
on, take a good look around you.
We're all players.
- Experts in our field.
- Get to the point.
You wanna
know the point, big guy?
The point is, we're all
career criminals...
and this is a four-man crew.
The mechanic. Rough, brawny.
And you, dear lady,
graceful, nimble.
You're the B&E specialist.
We called them cat burglars
back in my day.
And that leaves you.
You slick-fingered devil.
The safe cracker.
What does that make you,
smart guy?
I guess that makes me
the smart guy.
So...
anybody figure out what
we're supposed to steal yet?
You pricks did your homework.
Who are you?
Well, I'll start with
the more infamous first.
Boston Museum,
18th of March, 1990.
- Nah.
- Oh, yes.
The frames of the pictures
are still hanging on the wall.
No way that was you.
Grayson Bishop.
And it most certainly was.
In fact, I still have
one of the Van Goghs
hidden in a basement
somewhere to prove it.
So, an old-school
master thief, huh?
Maybe you're the one
behind this?
Teach yourself a few new tricks.
I seriously doubt there
is anything you can teach me.
Besides, do you think
I would try to blow myself up?
This doesn't make any sense.
Why us?
Well, I'm the very best
at what I do
and I'm assuming you are
as well.
Otherwise I would be
completely insulted.
It would be easier
to hire us, no?
Maybe.
Or maybe it's someone who knows
that we would never work for them.
Or better yet,
maybe it's someone
that wanted us fucked over.
Like who?
Do you got any enemies, kid?
Because believe me,
I have a long list.
Don't call me kid,
you old fogy.
You make me glad I'm an orphan.
And an angry one at that.
So what are we gonna do?
We live or we die.
Doesn't sound like
much of a choice to me.
Excellent conclusion, dear.
Harris.
It's so good to see you.
What's this?
Our border guy, he's reliable,
right?
He is.
We've used him before.
You paid top dollar.
He was instructed to turn off the
cameras, was he not?
Yes, sir.
By you?
Yes, I told him.
I'll fix it.
There is no fixing it, Harris.
I'll... I'll figure it out.
I'll talk...
I'll talk to him.
You weigh...
about 75 kilograms,
Is that right?
Yeah.
Shouldn't take too long.
And please,
just don't fight it.
It's easier that way.
See, Harris, every piece
has a purpose.
And every move has a meaning.
And if you can't follow
the rules...
everyone loses.
You're in charge now,
and be careful decontaminating.
We have to gain access
though the main elevator.
Then, we have to open a security
door with an electronic lock.
Next, we navigate a tunnel
secured by motion sensors.
Then, unbreakable
tempered glass.
Once through,
it's the vault room
which brings us to the custom
1970s Mosler.
Even if you could do all that,
which you can't...
What's your exit plan?
I was thinking I'd just walk
out the front door.
It's kinda the point of
not setting off any alarms.
That much security,
what's in the vault?
Gold.
Bonds?
It's diamonds.
- What?
- It's diamonds.
And it all started right here.
John D. Rockefeller.
Son of a con artist.
Became one of
the wealthiest men in America.
So, he had diamonds...
a lot of diamonds.
Hidden assets
from the government I assume.
Anyway, they're all stored
right here in the museum.
At least for now.
I mean, they move 'em around
from time to time.
It was last rumored
that they were in Italy.
Florence to be exact.
How do you know?
It's about the Mosler.
You see,
it's a bit of a legend
in certain rarefied circles.
It's never been cracked yet...
though it has been tried.
Sounds like a bunch of bullshit.
Could be. But our captor
believes it's true.
So then, what do they
want us to do?
Draw them a map?
They've already got
the blueprints.
- They want us to steal it.
- No.
They want us to pretend to.
How's that
for a slice of humble pie?
It's right this way, guys.
And why should I
trust you, pops?
Maybe you're walking us
to an early grave.
This whole place is a grave.
You shouldn't trust me.
I don't trust you.
I mean,
after all, we are criminals.
You're a real ray of
sunshine, you know that?
And you're a shoe size
passing for an IQ, dear boy.
There it is.
Would you look at that.
Just like in the blueprints.
They built a replica of
the museum?
They want us to
practice the heist.
They're gonna watch our every
move, and when we're done...
Boom.
And then?
and then, someone else
follows in our footsteps.
And we are all okay with this?
Do you have any other options?
Shit.
Well, I thought you were
the safe cracker.
This isn't a safe. It's...
a computer.
No, it's not. It's a puzzle.
It's a Henderson digital lock.
It releases.
The way it works, it has four
bolts from the door to the frame.
- Then we can use a gun.
- That's unnecessary.
Oh, yeah, why is that?
Because this particular lock
depends on a person. A person who
comes up with a four-digit pin.
Yeah, well, that's like...
a million different
combinations.
Permutations.
And it's 9,999,
give or take a fraction or two.
But you see, our advantage is
that Henderson keypads
use silicone with
positive printing.
What the hell does that mean?
What that means is that
the surface clings
to the oil
from our fingertips.
Move over, kid.
You're blocking the view.
All right.
Ah, this should be easy.
Twenty-four permutations.
Voila.
There it is.
How did you know
the combo?
I don't know the combo.
I know people,
and I know my keypads.
Yeah, but the keypad at the museum
is not gonna be the same code.
This is just a replica.
Well, then it's a good thing we'll
all be dead, and it won't be us
actually the heist then,
isn't it?
I'm assuming the real security
system won't have an off switch.
That's where it is.
That's where they hid the bomb.
They found the replica.
They're behind.
What about Grayson?
Played out just like
you said it would.
He got everyone on task,
and he cracked
the security code quick.
And now...
it's showtime.
I don't know why you
brought the whole tool shed.
There's nothing in there
to protect from lightsabers.
What's she on about?
I can do this.
Do what?
We need to redirect the laser.
Did you bring the mirror?
And see?
Now it's in front of me.
Your turn.
Shouldn't we be
motivating the others?
I was just...
looking for a weak spot.
It's hard work
leading a crew.
I'm not leading anything.
See, it's not just
about skills.
It's about personalities.
You know Mag,
she's strong and silent.
Bruised...
but very reliable.
And Rowan,
he's a joker
but he knows his shite.
And me...
I'm the wiseass wise man.
What about you, Kate?
What are you gonna
bring to the party
that's gonna take us
to the promised land?
I'm not taking you anywhere.
I don't know you.
I know you.
Should we cut the crap?
Excuse me?
Your Bingham Paxton's
granddaughter.
Corsica Cabal.
You don't know what
you're talking about.
Spoken like a career criminal.
There's no point
in us lying to each other.
We're all in this together.
You mind me asking,
how did he get pinched?
Your grandfather was a brilliant
man, and I was an admirer.
It was a job.
Italy.
I was trying to crack a vault
and I took too long.
Police were supposed to be
diverted, but...
I escaped with the rest
of the crew,
my grandfather
took the fall.
What kind of vault?
What kind of vault, Kate?
It's important.
- A Mosler.
This was your grandfather's
final score.
He died in prison,
didn't he?
And it's all your fault.
You think you have
the answers to everything.
Listen to me,
we do not have to do
what they want us to do.
You and I could figure
something out.
We don't have
to play their game.
I don't have to play
your game either.
I don't think you understand
the variables here.
We're pawns.
We're pawns in something
much bigger.
Hey.
We're ready.
Rowan's got an idea
for the glass.
All right. Here's the news.
Prorated 10-hour
tempered glass.
Steel can be cut,
stone can be broken...
but this...
This some new age
super-human shit.
It's the kind insurance
companies love to see.
Now the vibration might be able to
undermine the strength of the glass.
You said it would break.
- There's not even a dent.
- No.
What I said was,
we might be able to weaken it.
We need a minute.
Hell with this.
I'll join you.
I thought you were supposed
to be some kind of an expert.
Christ, will you back off?
Are all girls in Arizona
this mean, or is it just you?
I'm from Mexico.
Oh, lemme guess,
Cancun, Acapulco?
Hone your skills breaking into
rich tourist hotel rooms?
- Sinaloa.
- Oh, cartel country.
No wonder you're so friendly.
But I was raised
in the Magical Crew.
So, all my friends
are dead.
Fair enough.
This is not about me.
This is about Kate.
I overheard her
talking to Grayson.
She's Cabal.
You don't say.
- Granddaughter of the great Bingham himself.
- Hmm.
- And I do not trust her.
- Well...
trust is hard to come by
these days.
I think that maybe
we should keep an eye on her.
Well, I'm keeping
an eye on everyone.
You're an idiot...
if you are not scared of them.
You should be.
They could be behind this,
and we have the cub in our den.
And what exactly do you
want me to do about it?
I wanna show them
that we are serious.
Come up with anything?
Pass me the, uh, splicer there.
So, what did you
and Grayson talk about?
A score... you know,
what else.
Play poker?
- No.
- Well, you should.
- You're a great liar.
- What?
Quick!
What the hell?
You're working with them.
- Who?
- The Cabal.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
I overheard you
talking to Grayson.
You're Cabal,
and they are behind this.
Why would they do that?
They are the only ones with
the resources for this, no?
You're making a mistake.
We need each other
if we're gonna get outta here.
I think...
that maybe you need us.
And they need you
in one piece.
And maybe, if they're
worried about you,
they'll pop open the door.
Only if they know that we are serious.
What the hell is going on here?
Nothing important.
Just a small hiccup
in group trust.
- Don't be absurd.
- What are you doing?
Take it easy, old boy.
- We need her.
- She's Cabal.
So what?
She was Cabal.
She's not anymore.
Believe me
when I tell you this.
She is not the one
responsible for all this.
How do you know?
She would never we caught dead
working for scum.
The likes of Theodore Thurlo III.
Who the hell is
Theodore Thurlo III?
I mean, did we get kidnapped
by a knight of the Round Table?
He's the man behind
this current predicament.
And believe me,
indirectly he has
a deep connection to you.
Bollocks, mate.
You were born in Dublin,
weren't ya?
Yeah, I was.
Theo had some crews there
back in the day.
You see, the one thing
you have to know about our boy,
he doesn't like
to leave witnesses.
Even crew.
I understand there were a lot
of bodies left behind in Dublin
when he pulled out.
You did say you were an orphan,
didn't you?
And you, my dear...
you were part of
the Magical Crew.
Well, of course,
you don't have crew anymore.
They all went the way
of the bullet except you.
That's a terrible shame,
now isn't it?
A street kid like you
raised in the gutter.
I understand that Theo used to recruit
all the urchins on the streets of Mexico.
Only he didn't treat 'em
so good.
You don't know what
you're talking about.
Oh, I think I do.
In fact, I think Dickens
wrote a book about it.
Scooped up...
taught to steal...
taught to kill...
turned into something
that you absolutely despised.
And then betrayed,
and left for dead.
Hey. Hey. Hey. Hey.
It's okay.
Well, that's a hell
of a punch you got there.
How do you know Theo?
What did he do to you?
Well... it's more like
what I did to him.
The paintings.
Boston Museum,
you screwed him over.
No, I did not screw him over.
Let's just say I got the first
punch in and won the day.
And now he's
taking his revenge.
It's all bullshit.
You know that, right?
You don't know shit about us.
Well, then, let's just say I came
up with a good cover story for you.
You better listen up,
and listen to me
real good, people.
You're gonna have to be a lot
smarter about what you're doing
if you plan on
getting out of here alive.
Time to start phase two.
What are you doing?
What we should
all be doing.
Trying to find a way out.
You're wasting your time.
You're wasting our time.
What, you think they'd just leave
this open so you can climb up?
What do you know?
I know that someone
has their finger on a trigger,
not much else
I need to know.
Look, you don't like me.
- Fine. I get it.
- No.
No, you don't get it.
You don't get a fucking thing.
You're Cabal.
With all your rituals
and your rules,
and your lines of succession,
all of that shit...
You're just a bunch
of spoiled,
entitled, aristocrats
playing pirate.
You don't know what
you're talking about.
Everything that I know
I learned myself.
I didn't have no private lessons
in some European castle.
You know, I fought
and I bled...
and I'm gonna do the same thing
to get out of here.
This won't end the way
you think it will.
Not if we don't work together.
- Ladies?
- What?
What did you do?
Nothing.
Bullshit you did nothing!
Because I know I did nothing
and youse two are...
Wait. What are youse doing?
Not running around
like rats in a maze.
Oh, Jesus.
You sound like Grayson.
Can one of youse explain to me
- why we only have two hours left, huh?
- What?
That's not right.
We should have a little under three.
Well, you must have
pissed somebody off then.
- Now, can we get back to work please?
- Why?
- This whole thing is obviously rigged.
- Maybe...
but Rowan's right,
and we need your help.
There is no "we" here, okay?
There is today.
What the hell was that?
I smell smoke.
Where's Grayson?
Having a sniff
the last time we checked.
- What the hell?
- It's the blueprints.
What's he playing at?
Forgive the chicanery,
my friends.
- Damn it!
- Prick!
Fuck that bastard.
Do you know how to fix this?
Uh,
gimme a minute, will ya?
You always did have
a big laugh at me,
didn't you, big guy?
Well, it's nice to know
that today is gonna be
more of the same.
I know you can hear me,
you treacherous prick.
So, grab a handful,
asshole,
and pucker those lips
and start smooching.
He's probably looking for a way out.
We are too, you prick.
16,000 degrees of separation,
and I spit my last breath
in your face.
He's gonna burn
the whole place down.
Shit.
He might actually get though.
- Arm it.
- You sure?
Arm it!
Shit.
- Hurry!
- Shut up, will ya.
Why couldn't it be
his own bollocks?
He's gonna get us all killed.
Now!
You sure?
Wait.
I'll do it.
Son of a bitch.
Hey. Hey.
- What took you so long?
- Shh.
What the hell were you thinking?
Oh, just thought that
I'd give you guys
a head start.
You wanted to see,
so to speak.
I'm afraid it's up to you to
take 'em to the promised land.
Shh. Just... Just stay still.
See it through.
Go back. I wanna know
what he told her.
- Can't make it out.
- Well, try harder.
- I can't.
- Kei, try harder!
Grayson never was
a team player.
- I just meant he...
- The man was an artist.
He pulled off the greatest
art heist in history.
Show some goddamn respect.
Gerry.
Please don't try to tell me
that this was part of the plan.
It wasn't entirely unexpected.
I have no idea what that means.
What it means, Gerry,
is that he fulfilled his role.
And sometimes you have
to trade a pawn
to put your pieces
in the right position.
Just remember who
you're playing with.
No more sacrifices.
Get me those diamonds.
Grayson went at it alone
and look wat happened to him.
I'm not... We're not
gonna make the same mistake.
If we're gonna win this,
we need to get through it.
You have a choice to make.
I've made mine.
We either die in here,
or we get out together.
Try it again.
Anything we can use?
It's shite, garbage and junk.
Come on, there's
gotta be something.
Cut it sharper.
Again.
Okay, try again.
All right.
- Bring me the drone.
- Why?
The camera's got a memory card.
Again. Higher.
Try again.
We're not gonna have
time to make these adjustments.
Well done.
- Why'd you do it?
- Do what?
Rob those banks.
Was it for yourself,
or for someone else?
Let's just say
the Irish system
for young lads without
a family isn't all that great.
I'm sorry.
Pretty soon, you'll find your family on
the inside is worth a hell of a lot more
than whatever fucked up situation
you have on the outside.
Right...
got it.
A1 Charlie Swan.
Steel.
Tungsten carbide.
Cobalt... bollocks.
Nothing?
It's got an extremely high
surface compression
stress resistance.
- At least a nine on the Mohs scale.
- What's that?
Means it's hard as hell.
Can anything cut though it?
Diamonds.
But unless you got yourself
engaged lately
you're on the wrong end
of the vault for that.
Well, anything else?
Corundum, ceramic...
Where are you going?
Playin' wagon.
What about this?
What am I looking at here?
Spark plug. Ceramic tip.
- How did you know that?
- My grandfather.
Excuse me.
You have something to
hold this with?
Yeah... here.
Here we go.
Okay.
Wait.
See? A dent.
Smart.
Very good start.
Ceramic tip.
Thank you.
Excuse me, ladies.
Would you look at that.
Come on.
Now, let's see
what you can do.
You sure she can do it?
I'm sure.
How you know?
Because she hates me
too much to fail.
They all do.
How much time do you need?
How much time we got?
Thirty-three minutes.
Is it possible?
It'll have to be.
I'm sorry.
Sorry was three hours ago.
We're running outta time.
She needs our help.
She needs to focus.
Just leave her alone.
Alone? We're a team.
One of us goes down,
we all do.
Look, I...
I know you don't play
well with others.
You got the whole lone wolf act down.
I get that.
But you can't go through life
on your own.
I've gotten by so far,
so thank you very much.
Have ya?
'Cause it seems to me like you
need a hand up from time to time.
When you're on the ground,
in a gutter,
- you know who reaches for you?
- Who?
People who wanna use you,
take advantage of you,
who act like
you owe them your life!
Whatever happened to you,
I'm sorry.
But we need you,
and I'm pretty sure
you need us as well.
All right.
What about the liquid nitrogen?
Could we freeze the lock?
Maybe.
It's a long shot,
but it's worth a try.
Look, we have an idea...
liquid nitrogen.
No, it... It won't work.
There's a pressure
loaded firing pin.
It'll trigger the re-lock
and we'll never get it open.
How much time do we have?
Twenty-one minutes.
You can do it.
Forty-five.
Sixty-three.
- What the hell?
- What's wrong?
I don't know.
It won't... It's not...
Come on!
It should have opened!
I let you down.
Isn't that splendid?
- You sure they cannot see us?
- Looped the feed with the drone's memory cam.
All that prick's
looking at is Kate
sweating over and over again.
Do your thing.
Let's pack it up.
We're on the move.
The police?
Every cop for 10 miles
is headed to the warehouse.
This is our window.
How's our team?
En route.
You have a job to do.
I'll take care of it.
Let's try another garage,
shall we?
We're not the bleeding A-Team.
We don't have time.
Well, let's get going then.
I was just trying
to make it more dramatic.
Let's go.
We have some shopping to do.
You didn't buy anything?
Didn't buy nothing.
Better get going.
Hey.
We don't know
how many there are.
- If you find Theo's crew...
- When...
I find Theo's crew.
I'll take care of them all.
You just worry about
the vault.
You remember what
I showed you, yeah?
You sure you wanna do this?
He threw us in a hole
and left us for dead.
I'm not gonna let him
get away with it. Are you?
Or it could be a trap.
He thinks we're dead.
He's never gonna see us coming.
Not till the diamonds
are long gone.
- He's here.
- Who?
Theo.
Hold on.
We might have a problem.
Kate.
You look well.
Try it.
It's Mortlach, 1935.
Your grandfather's favorite.
I'm not here for a drink.
I'm here for the diamonds.
Aren't we all, darling.
Tell me something.
What do you see?
Wealth and privilege.
You know what I see?
I see the lies
they tell in the morning.
These people...
they're here to impress.
To make a mark.
- To be seen.
- I'm not.
What?
Here to be seen.
Dressed like that?
They think
it's an end to itself,
but I just don't
have time for that.
So what then? Hmm?
What do you have time for?
Well, I like to enjoy
the finer things.
But the acquisition
of those things...
that's for them.
I'm addicted to savoring
the subtleties, Kate.
I love the game.
Just don't much care
for the prize.
You really should try it.
The king-pawn endgame,
it's a difficult position.
Tell me something, Kate.
Will you become a queen?
I guess we'll find out.
Well, game on.
Oh, excuse me.
No, my fault.
Enjoy your evening.
Hmm.
I'm here.
Elevator is on its way.
Left you a present inside.
Mag, you there?
I cannot find Theo's crew.
Keep looking.
Rowan, I'm out.
You ready to go?
Ah.
Mag, is that you?
Who the fuck...
Rowan, what the hell
are you doing?
Rowan?
Mag, can you hear me?
Get in.
Give me the diamonds, Kate.
Oh, I don't have them
on me.
You never leave
the scene with a score.
My grandfather
taught me that much.
I'm not holding a carrot.
If you kill me,
your diamonds will be gone.
I promise you that.
So you don't care
about your own life.
What about Rowan's?
I just met Rowan today.
What makes
you think I care?
Because I know you, Kate.
It's why I picked you.
It's why I picked all of you.
It's why I allowed
you to escape.
- You knew we'd escape.
- Of course.
- But you tried to kill us.
- That was motivation.
- But the other team...
- There is no other team, Kate.
Just you. Every move you made,
every action you took,
you did it because I planned it
and I wanted it that way.
You were pawns in...
Is this another
chess thing again,
because I should mention
I'm more of a Monopoly girl.
- Thimble?
- Top hat.
I want the diamonds, Kate.
You kill me, you have nothing.
I have Rowan,
and we can make him
talk eventually.
But Rowan doesn't know
where the diamonds are.
It's just me.
And if I die,
your diamonds are gone.
That would be a mistake.
For you.
See, there's no way that you
financed this whole thing yourself.
So, I'm betting you had
a buyer.
A buyer who fronted you
enough for this whole operation,
the replica and all.
And I'm gonna bet
that this buyer
isn't the type to just write
this off if you don't deliver.
So... am I close?
The diamonds, Kate.
If I don't tell you
where they are,
no matter
what happens to me,
they'll come for you.
Are there dice in Chess?
Oh, very well.
Kei, call Vince.
Let's give Kate a little taste
of what's about to come.
Is there a problem, Kei?
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Mag, are you there?
Mag, can you hear me?
I'm heading to the rendezvous point.
- Mag?
- What happened?
Yeah, we gotta go.
Let's go.
Mag, what the hell
are you doing?
I'm sorry, Kate.
You don't have to do this.
It's not too late.
It is for me.
How much is he paying you?
I didn't pay her.
I raised her.
Kate, let's just stop this,
all right.
Make it easy on ourselves,
and just tell me
where the diamonds are.
The diamonds are the only
thing keeping me alive.
The diamonds are gonna
get you killed.
And is it worth it?
No.
But making you fail,
that's something I would die for.
- Shoot her.
- We should just take her and go.
She'll talk... eventually.
You know,
I don't think she will.
We need to reassess,
and we need to clear the board.
I don't want any loose ends.
Shoot her.
No, we need
to get out of here now.
This is not the time
or the place for this.
What did you say?
I'm just saying that
I think that there is...
- I'm sorry.
- For what?
Don't listen to her.
For what he did to you.
For what he made you become.
Magdalena...
do it.
Do it.
Do it!
I love you like a daughter,
you know that.
Like a daughter.
I'm sorry.
Okay, last chance.
What did you do to her?
What did I do to her?
I saved her. Okay.
Her family dead,
she was on the streets
and I gave her everything.
What do you care?
You turned her into a weapon.
I saved her from
becoming a corpse,
and you made me
shoot her!
I really didn't want it
to end this way, Kate.
I'm okay.
I come in here and save
your arses again, huh?
Take a seat there.
You left 'em in
a bleedin' bush?
- Thought you were smarter than that.
- Yeah?
I was hoping Theo would too.
You all right?
I take no chances anymore.
It's twist after twist
with you, huh?
It's like screwing on
a bottle cap.
Ow, it hurts to laugh.
Here, gimme a look at those.
You took a chance on me.
You didn't have to.
It wasn't a chance,
it was a choice.
You made one too.
Don't worry, we're good.
That was beautiful,
just gorgeous,
but, uh, Mag's just been shot,
I'm bleeding outside a church,
and you're holding
a bag of diamonds.
- So... I think we better skedaddle.
- Yeah.
There's a couple of things
I wanna take care of.
Surprised to see me?
Kiss my bollocks,
you baldy prick.
Game over.
- To Grayson.
- That cocky bastard.
Wasn't too hard
to find the painting?
Oh, I slipped through.
Thank you.
You got something for me?
- Done.
- That's it?
That's it.
Thanks for saving me a step.
Never liked that guy.
I'll be in touch.
So... what's next?
We all betray each other,
Kate turns out to be
Grayson's daughter.
We'll whip off the mask,
and it's Scooby Doo?
Maybe.
But first...
you ever been to Italy?
How's that?
I think just a little bit...
All about the angles.
It's good?
Just a little...
Just a little bit
to the right.
Oh, a touch...
There.
I think it suits the place.
It's like having a painting
of your face.
Where are we going next?
Italy.
We already decided in the last meet.
Remember?
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org