You know, a lot has changed
in my life in the past year.
Suzanne and I got married...
...and her and the kids moved
into my apartment.
My very small apartment.
But that ain't all.
I decided to pursue my dream.
So I sold my sports shop
and started up a magazine.
You know what it is.
A sports magazine.
And these are the moments
that I cherish.
When everybody's asleep,
I got the whole place to myself...
...and now it's time to get to work.
So, Magic, how was it when you...?
How's your magazine coming?
Come here.
Kevin, what you doing up?
Trying to write.
I'm hungry.
Do you got Pop-Tarts?
You're always hungry.
And it's, "Do we got Pop-Tarts?"
We family now.
So, what's mine is yours,
and what's yours is mine.
-Understand?
-I understand I want Pop-Tarts.
Thanks, Nick.
Did you take my cell phone?
Mom, Kevin's stealing
my stuff again.
Nick, Coco's hungry.
Hey, you guys wanted the dog,
you gonna have to feed him.
Coco, breakfast!
-Good morning.
-Hey.
How's your writing
going this morning?
-Not too good.
-Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
Nick, there's something
we really need to talk about.
Hold that thought.
Hey! No! Wait a minute.
No! No! No!
Open this door.
I have to put on my makeup, Nick.
You're too young to wear makeup.
Now, I'm gonna count to three.
One.
Two.
I'm aImost 14, Nick.
You can't keep treating me like a child.
No, no. You're only 1 3.
And as your stepfather,
I have the God-given right...
...to treat you like a child.
Suzanne, do you see
what this girl got on?
I'm not in it.
Okay, okay, I am not dressing
like somebody's grandma.
After school, AshIey and I are going to
the malI for the Nordstrom sale.
No. No. Veto.
That ain't gonna happen.
I don't like that one bit.
You're too young
to be hanging out at the malI.
So go get dressed, granny.
Too young for the mall?
You're like a prison guard.
Yeah, well, welcome to Alcatraz.
So, Nick, you know,
the Lutskys are moving.
-So?
-Well, it's a three-bedroom.
Yeah, it's probabIy three times
as expensive too.
Hey!
Oh, you wanna be treated like a adult?
You can't even wrap a piece of pizza.
You said I was a child.
Nick, there's something that we really
need to taIk about this morning.
I can't taIk right now.
Look at me. I'm a mess.
Kevin.
Okay. Out. Both you guys. Out.
I got a presentation today
with my publisher.
-Let's go. I need to talk to your mother.
-You too, Coco. Get out. Go.
This place.
Coco, get down before
you knock something over.
And what were you trying to say?
Honey, I'm pregnant.
By who?
So you sold your half
of the shop to Marty?
He's gotta be happy
about that, huh?
Yeah, he is. But I am too, you know?
I'm starting a new chapter
in my Iife, my man.
I'm launching a magazine.
That's great. You took a risk,
and you made it happen.
You got Magic. I'm proud of you.
Whoa, hey!
Who said anything about Magic?
You don't have him?
Officially, no.
But it's looking good.
It's looking real good.
Matter of fact, it's Iooking so good...
...pour me a shot, pour yourseIf a shot
and then pour one for my man Magic.
Let me ask you something, Nick.
If you don't have him,
why'd you sell the shop?
I need the money, Jimmy.
It's been cooI, but it's kind of hard
having Suzanne and the kids...
...just crammed up
into my smalI pIace.
It's just time to move on up, man.
PIus, I didn't tell you,
I'm having a baby.
AIl right. My man's having a baby.
-Yeah. Yeah. That's right.
-Hey, baby.
-Hey, hey, hey.
-I thought l'd find you here. Hi, Jimmy.
-How'd it go?
-It went great.
Check it out.
Hey.
This baby got two heads.
And four arms and four legs.
Nick, we're having twins.
Twins?
-Honey.
-Cut off, Nick.
Thanks, Jimmy.
I can't believe you're making us
move to the country.
This is like child abuse
of the worst kind.
Where's the mall?
What you need a malI for?
That's your probIem now.
You need to get a littIe fresh air
and open spaces. Try that.
Lindsey, please. Okay?
Everybody, just relax.
Yeah, just relax.
Here, sweetie. Have a juice.
-Oh, God--
-Kevin!
What's that smell?
Smells like oxygen.
Mom, please teIl me you're joking.
-Enough.
-I hope it's the right place.
Of course it's not.
Our oId house is the right house.
This is the pIace, guys. Come on.
Let's have a positive
mental attitude, okay?
Nice floors.
I smelI cookies.
Kevin, Kevin, you cannot just walk
around these peopIe's house like that.
Oh, this the cuIprit right here.
God!
Oh, baby. Oh, honey.
Okay, cold water. Go. Cold water.
Oh, goodness gracious!
What happened in here?
Did you touch the stove?
Was it the stove?
I'll tell you what, gonna put
Tunisian hemp root on there.
Make it as good as new.
It's true, actually.
I'm so sorry about that.
It's fine. He's just being a big baby.
Name's Chuck MitchelI Jr.
I'm the local real-estate guy
here in Newburg County and....
You....
I know just exactIy who you are.
You're Nick.
There we go.
Note to self, the hand stilI hurts.
-And the radiant....
-Suzanne.
Oh, my G-O-D.
Suzanne's with child.
You old dog, you!
-Oh, well--
-HoId up.
It's okay. I'm a part-time midwife.
I actualIy studied...
...at the Natural Childbirth Centre
in Lucerne, SwitzerIand.
They're twins, aren't they?
Yes, they are.
How did you know that?
Would you Iike to know the sexes?
No.
Matter of fact, we wanna
keep it a surprise, Chuck.
Oh, fair enough. lsn't that
every parent's prerogative?
But if I were you, l wouIdn't be in any
big hurry to paint the nursery pink.
Oh, gosh. It's just a special time,
being in that delivery room.
Right. The man almost fainted
when our guppy had babies.
Now, you know that
that was a hard delivery for me.
AIl that cIoudy water and then those
little things popping out one by one.
Honey?
Babe.
Honey.
Now, the place was built in 1 889
by H. Van Hackett himseIf...
...legendary architect
and perfectionist.
I'd like to telI you something
right up front:
In all my years in "the business"--
And there have been more than a few.
--I have never seen
a more sound home.
Structurally speaking.
Wait till you get a load
of the second floor.
Baby, do you see this?
-It's okay, we'll fix it.
-Did you see this?
Now, she's got five bedrooms
and four bathrooms...
...so needless to say, there's plenty
of room for the whoIe fam.
I think we're gonna go ahead and put
Mom and Dad in the master bedroom.
-Five bedrooms, right?
-Five, baby. You feeling me?
I'm feeling you.
-This big enough for you, baby?
-It's beautiful.
And, of course, the master bathroom.
Oh, my God, baby, a claw-foot tub.
-I've always wanted one of these.
-Me too.
Pretty awesome, right?
-I like it.
-It's beautiful. And the double sinks!
Oh, my God.
Baby, look at the shower.
Oh, my God, honey, this is bigger
than our entire apartment.
I know.
What's in there, Chuck?
That is a private toilet.
Baby.
-Did you say private?
-Yes, sir.
Oh, my God.
How I Iook?
How do you feel?
I feel good.
Feeling good's good enough.
You be okay in there, Nick?
Just give me one minute.
So, now, Suzanne here telIs me
that you're in the publishing game?
Oh, yeah, I did seIl a magazine
to OmniHouse.
An entrepreneur.
A budding William Randolph Hearst
right here in our midst.
I don't really know who that is,
Chuck, but, hey, I guess so.
Modest too? They broke the mouId.
I'll tell you what, Suze,
I'd hang on to this one.
Oh, yeah, he's a keeper, Chuck.
Oh, way to stick the landing, Kev-o.
The Hacketts, of course,
used this as a guest cottage.
But with just a "scootcharino" of work,
it could be easily converted...
...into the perfect creative nook for,
you know, a....
A publisher.
You know, I was thinking about
writing in that bathroom up there.
Oh, yeah?
-Oh, honey, this is so charming.
-This'll work too.
Just for a second, Nick,
just for a second, imagine....
Imagine watching
a blue-throated hummingbird...
...suckle the nectar from a fresh
hydrangea blossom...
...whiIe you free your mind...
...to the creative impulses that have
made every publishing empire great.
This is not a dress rehearsal, Nick.
Live the dream, baby,
live the dream.
Would you guys like
to see a tremendous view?
Would you? Come on. Come on.
-It's the coup de grâce. You'll love it.
-Come on, baby.
You're gonna wanna get low
coming through this door.
The roof-- Think you'll find the roof
needs a little bit of work...
...so please be careful.
The property includes
an apple orchard.
There's some wiId blackberries
over here, some cedars.
And I don't even wanna tell you
about the view of the Iake from here.
Breathe.
Breathe, breathe in that rich,
fresh air, Mr. Publisher.
How about it?
Oh, not so incidentally, they just built
a brand-new school down the road.
RealIy?
Newburg is a really amazing place
to raise a family.
Oh, it's just so beautiful, Chuck.
Well, you should see it
in the middle of the winter...
...with a bIanket of snow covering it.
It's pretty as a postcard.
Personally, I like to power-walk
through these woods.
Never mind the fact that, of course,
I used to do the waIk competitively.
RealIy?
Yeah, l was an alternate
to the '94 Goodwill Games in Russia.
Like l say, she is a fixer-upper...
...but l happen to know the finest
contractor in these parts.
You give that gentleman
a caIl and....
One way to make your life
a whoIe Iot easier.
So, now, where do
we stand there, Nickster?
I don't know, Chuck.
I'm not really sure if this is
the right pIace for us, you know.
It's a little high-priced
and you're a little weird.
Oh, gosh, I actualIy scheduled
a couple back-to-back with you guys.
Larry, Bernice. Hello! Come in.
PIease, make yourself at home.
-Okay, Chuck. Thanks.
-Thank you.
I gotta go.
So, what you think?
I don't know. l don't know.
Can we really afford this house?
Of course.
Baby, with the advance,
plus the money we saved on rent...
...we can buy this place
two times over.
And have money to fix it up.
And guess what.
I can do the fixing.
I can barely get you to change
a light bulb at the apartment.
So what? Look, look.
Take a look at this.
-A house is like a painting.
-Yeah.
You can't really buy with your head,
you gotta buy with your heart.
Yeah, honey, but we have to think
with our heads right now.
We gotta think about the kids.
We gotta think about
it's the middle of the school year...
...Lindsey has her friends and she just
met that nice boy in her math cIass.
There's pIenty of stuff
around here for Lindsey to do...
...that have nothing to do with boys.
And Kevin, this is perfect!
Look at the nature.
Look at the wiIderness.
We got a blueberry tree, baby.
Are we talking about the same kid?
Kevin doesn't go outside for recess.
That's why he needs a place like this,
to toughen him up.
PIus, I can take him fishing.
Who's going fishing?
-Me.
-You fish?
Oh, I can fish, baby.
Oh, when's the last time
you went fishing?
Last time-- Matter of fact,
it was before I met you...
...last time I went fishing.
And....
I don't know how to fish,
but I can learn.
And then I could teach him,
and we can bond.
-"We can bond."
-We'Il become a true family.
-"A true famiIy."
-Picture it.
What you think?
I think there are a lot
of rooms in this house...
...that are gonna need breaking in.
Oh, yeah?
Well, what about the roof?
The roof isn't a bad place to start.
Well, come over here,
drop it Iike it's hot, girI.
Baby!
We'll take it.
Good boy.
-Where'd she go?
-She was just.... I don't know.
There.
What you doing?
Stop! Coco, stop!
Help!
Hey, honey, do you know
how this garbage disposal works?
Because I've tried every single one
of these switches.
What about this one?
See? Everything is working out
just like l promised, huh?
I can fix that.
Oh, you can fix that?
Hey, I hope we're not disturbing you.
I'm Mr. Rooney, this is Mrs. Rooney.
Oh, so formal.
PIease, caIl me Mrs. Rooney.
We wanted to be the first
to welcome you.
Oh, we sure did.
We are the first, aren't we?
You're the first.
Yes.
-That looks gross.
-Kevin.
That fish put this town on the map.
Oh, yeah. Sturgeon tastes
a lot like chicken, only fishy.
-Nice.
-I think you're gonna enjoy it.
And even if you don't, it's dead.
Did you wanna come inside
for something to drink?
Oh, that's so sweet.
But we don't reaIly drink so early
in the day around these parts, but--
-Right. No.
-No, no, I meant, like, just a lemonade.
Boy, get them fish.
Thank you. Close the door.
-Welcome.
-For you.
Tastes Iike chicken.
Sturgeon, right?
Give me the fish, man.
Y'all get out of here
before I call the cops.
Hey, Nick.
I can't find Coco anywhere.
Give me that.
Don't worry about Coco,
he'll show up sooner or later.
There's a Iot of trees
to pee on out there.
What you want me to do?
Coco!
Where's that dog?
Maybe we should go back.
It's kind of scary out here.
Scary? Boy, it's beautifuI out here.
Look, you with the man. l was the man
in the city, and I'm the man out here.
Trust me, when you're with me,
there's nothing to be scared of.
But that.
Run! Go! Go!
Can you hear me now?
Hello? Can you hear me now?
Off the phone, please. Here we are.
Oh, Iook at this.
-That's nice.
-Yeah.
And Iook at us.
One big, happy famiIy.
Yes, one big, happy family.
Lindsey, would you like
to give thanks?
Why, are we going home?
This is our home.
Our real home, Mom.
Where my friends are.
Where l can get cell phone reception.
Lindsey,
put away the phone, pIease.
Kevin?
-I don't Iike this fish.
-Me neither.
But we're gonna be eating this
every day for the next six months...
...so get used to it.
Now, Lindsey. Grace.
Dear Lord, thank you for all the
blessings that you gave us.
Before they were taken away.
Like my friends,
celI phone reception--
Time-out, I got this.
PIease, honey.
Oh, patient and heavenly Father...
...who's probably 1 0 times
more patient and heavenly...
...than any stepfather
should have to be--
Baby.
--we give thanks.
I know at times it seems Iike...
...we're nothing but a bunch of
back-taIking sass mouths...
...who don't know when we got it good
in a nice, beautiful home.
At least the table's strong.
I can fix that.
Honey, I think you should
just call the contractor.
Suzanne, the electrical parts
alone is a 30 percent markup.
And a contractor?
You're taIking about
1 25 bucks a hour.
Now do you want the number?
Contractor's here!
Coco! Oh, Coco.
Coco, sit.
How did you do that?
That's German.
It's the language of discipIine.
I was fortunate a coupIe of years back
to spend some time...
...and study with the friars
of New Skete.
Nick!
I found Coco by the highway,
but it's no probIem...
-...because he had his tags on.
-Chuck, what you doing here?
I got a message down at the office
that you were looking for a contractor?
But you're the locaI real-estate guy.
Yes, l am.
And I'm also the local contractor.
Do you Iove it?
-What's that smelI?
-Fifty pounds of fish.
Do you know the power
went out last night?
On it.
What you mean, "ruh-roh"?
Nick, when exactly
did you buy this home?
Are you serious?
You know exactly
when I bought this dump...
...because you the one sold it to us.
And that's what makes it
so very unpleasant for me...
...to have to tell you that your home's
electricaI system is shot.
AIl right, aIl right, all right.
Flag on the pIay.
Why didn't you tell us this
when you showed us the house?
Nick, in alI fairness,
I did have my ReaItor's cap on.
You know, might remember
that great bIue blazer and the khakis.
My contractor's hat was safely
at home in the closet.
They're two distinctly
different chapeaus...
...but they should have toId you
when you had the place inspected.
How's it going, guys?
Nick didn't have
this dump inspected.
I had it inspected. It was inspected.
It was just inspected by me.
Honey, how couId you not
hire an inspector?
We talked about this.
How could you be so irresponsible?
I trusted you on this.
-Don't blame me, it's his fault.
-Well, how is it Chuck's fault?
He lied!
No, he didn't. You was just too cheap
to hire an inspector.
That's besides the point.
They're kicking, aren't they?
Feels like they're playing soccer.
You okay?
They say that the move
was very traumatic for them...
...and that you shouldn't sleep
on your right side.
How do you know, Chuck?
I'm a baby whisperer.
A baby what?
AIso, they'd love it if you could lay off
the Indian food. Curry is a no-no.
Oh, brother.
Unfortunately, you gotta upgrade
the main paneI and pull all the wires.
That just sound like a bigger job.
Oh, crap.
You got racoons.
Oh, yeah. Racoons
that like Corn Nuts.
Word to the wise, carefuI with those
racoons. They're vicious.
Hey, hey, Chuck.
When it comes
to this electrical stuff....
How much this gonna cost me?
Oh, gosh, I don't know.
A home this size...
...you're looking at 8, 9.
-Hundred?
-Thousand.
Get off my property.
I might fixed.
-Oh, yeah?
-Yeah.
Perfect.
That's what I'm talking about.
I'm professionaI.
Thanks. Appreciate it, Serge.
Come again.
Did you see that? Look and Iearn,
little girl. 1 50 bucks. Painless.
Are you sure it's safe?
Of course it's safe.
He said all we gotta do...
...is not use the microwave
and the toaster at the same time.
That's just common sense.
Eight thousand dollars.
I knew that dude Chuck
was a crook the minute l met him.
Oh, honey, l think
you're a Iittle bit stressed out...
...with the move and everything and,
you know...
...there's one thing
that we haven't been able to do...
...in this big old draughty mansion.
InsuIation. That'll be perfect.
If we do that, we'll save
a lot of money on heating bills.
Baby, I was actuaIly thinking of
something eIse we could do...
...to stay nice and warm.
Oh, I know what you're thinking.
Honey, what was that?
The racoon.
-He's on the roof?
-Yeah.
You gotta show him who's boss.
If you don't do that,
you'll never get rid of him.
Baby, but Chuck says they're vicious.
Yeah, if you're a baby whisperer.
But me, I'm the man.
You are the man.
-You got my back?
-I got your back.
Watch this.
Is that my Corn Nuts?
You shouId know
not to mess with a man's nuts.
Be prepared
to pay the uItimate price.
Honey. Honey, what are you
doing out there?
Step back, baby.
What you wanna do?
Look, he ain't even running.
He think he bad. You think you bad?
I've dealt with rats in the city
bigger than you, boy.
Kids, go to bed. I got this.
-Baby!
-I got him!
Did I get him?
-No.
Sucker.
Nicholas J. Persons?
-Chuck?
-Charles MitcheIl. City inspector.
We got a problem. Let's go.
What's with the badge, Chuck?
Look, l don't have time for
none of this, okay? So make it quick.
Sir, you can't just go around tapping
into other people's power supplies.
It's dangerous, it's against the law...
...and quite frankly, Mr. Persons,
it's rude.
What are you talking about?
I'm gonna go ahead and guess...
...that that work wasn't done
by a Iicensed contractor.
You know, I didn't even know
they was gonna Ieave it like that.
You went ahead and avaiIed yourseIf
to the cheap, unskilled labour pool...
...that congregates outside
the hardware store?
I know. Tell you what l'm gonna do.
For reference, I'm gonna
provide you with a list...
...of alI the licensed,
bonded contractors...
...we have here in the local vicinity.
I am also going to fine you $1 000
for breaking the law.
What? A thousand bucks?
If you knew what you were doing...
...you'd be facing jaiI time,
so consider yourself lucky.
We're shutting your power down
till further notice.
What am I supposed to do?
BuiId a windmilI?
Well, that's not a bad idea, so long as
you contact the city zoning officer first.
Quality guy.
Would you Iike his card?
-No.
-I'm out of here.
Hey, wait a minute, Chuck.
Chuck, come on, man. lt's me. Nick.
Help me get my power back on.
I'm the city inspector, Mr. Persons.
Restoring power's
a littIe beyond my purview.
Okay, l know what this is. And l seen
this one before. What's it gonna take?
You realise if l accepted that,
I'd have to arrest myseIf on the spot...
...and I'm not that guy.
But you're a contractor.
But l'm not wearing
that hat right now.
Well, you can put it on.
It's your lucky day.
It happens to be in the car.
Oh, God. Oh, what,
they shut you down?
The heartless bureaucrats.
They're the worst.
Can you help me?
Well, restoring power's
not as easy as it sounds.
It just might take a coupIe days.
A couple of days?
Man, I'm trying to Iaunch a magazine.
AIl right? What am I supposed to do
without a computer?
We're gonna get your power
back on.
It's not even gonna be an issue.
Trust me.
Here you go, honey.
Your sandwich.
-What?
-Okay.
-Hey, Suzanne.
-Hey, Chuck. Come on in.
What smelIs good?
Are those sandwiches?
Oh, yeah, sturgeon salad.
Would you Iike one?
-I hate to impose.
-Oh, no, Chuck, anything for you.
Hey, hey, hey, man. What's with
all the racket? l'm trying to work.
We had to saw off the breaker box.
I'd like some mustard on there.
I'm a big mustard guy.
But you should be good now.
We'll have you up and running in a jiff.
That's Magic Johnson. That's my guy.
That's my main man.
Did I telI you
I was on the '86 Lakers?
-No.
-Yes, indeedy, sweetie.
I had 38 seconds of playing time.
It was game two of the final
and "Big Game" James...
...went down with a bad wheeI,
so we're up by 20 and they put me in.
Check it out, Nicker.
Get ahold of the purple and gold.
That's commitment, right?
When you do talk to the Magic Man,
tell him Chuck-dog said:
"Holler. That's what's up."
-"HolIer."
-Thank you so much.
Anyway, the good news is we're
getting the power up and running.
The bad news is you got dry rot.
Dry what?
Can l tell you something?
This is the most incredibIe sandwich.
You know your way
around a sturgeon.
Wait, wait, wait a minute.
Back to the dry rot.
How big is this?
Well, it could be considerable,
but y'all don't worry about a thing.
I know the best dry-rot guys
in Newburg County.
How's the guy situation out there?
Nothing at aIl.
No cuties, no nothing.
Girl, l feel sorry for you.
-I didn't wanna move here.
-I don't blame you.
Push. Push.
You should try
and get back here somehow.
At least there are boys here.
Are you still there? Linds? Hello?
Hello? Are you there?
Yeah. l gotta go.
Yup. You got the rot, brah.
-How you know?
-Nick.
-What?
-He's not aware.
Nick, the Pulu famiIy has been in the
dry-rot business for three generations.
Hawaiians know the dry rot
better than the rest of us...
...because the island is so darn wet.
Well, then why do they call it dry rot?
That's a misnomer. Listen carefully.
BilIy and George here,
they're highly skilled craftsmen...
...very much in demand,
but Danny, gosh, he's got a gift.
He's an artist, and if he says you've
got the rot, you've got the rot, brah.
Okay, say l got "the rot," brah.
I mean, can't we live with it?
Can you live with a wood-rotting
fungi that colonizes and spreads...
...to every timber in your home,
leading to a mouId...
...which can produce
airborne pathogens...
...that might infect every member
of your family...
...causing conjunctivitis,
hypersensitivity pneumonitis...
...and I'm not gonna lie to you here...
...aIlergic bronchopulmonary
aspergiIlosis.
Oh, yeah. No problem.
No.
I think they should fix it now.
You know, that is, because we don't
want it to spread and kiIl us all, right?
Don't you got clothes
to go put on or something?
-Ma.
-Go.
Right here, right here.
AIl right, how much
is it gonna cost me?
-Tough to predict.
-It's like that.
Do what you gotta do, all right?
Do what you gotta do.
But you gotta put on these...
...because you're kind of fat and
I don't want you scuffing up my floors.
Don't be a hick, Nick.
These guys are professionaIs.
Nice bootie.
-Talking about this.
-Give it up.
Yes, ma'am. I understand you guys
need all the questions.
I have them right here
in front of me...
...but l'm in the process of
relocating offices....
Maybe I can fax them
to you later on today?
Or tomorrow, the next day,
or the day after that.
-As long as we make our deadline.
-Okay, thanks. TeIl Magic I said hey.
-Will do.
-All right.
-Goodbye.
-Bye-bye.
Peek-a-brah.
What up, man?
Sorry to interrupt, Mr. P.
We just need you to look...
...sign off on phase one
of the dry-rot repair.
Oh, okay. No problem.
Nice. Georgie, go long!
No, no, no. Georgie,
you don't have to go long.
I'll just meet y'aIl out front.
So how many phases is it?
Just two.
So you guys are halfway through.
Oh, man, that's painless.
What is this?
Phase one.
Phase one?
Hey, Nickeroo.
You.
Where you been, man?
Suzanne was feeling tired,
so l picked up Kev-o...
...and shot some hoop.
What is wrong with you?
Man, you know this boy got asthma.
He can't shoot no hoops.
He cured it, just like that.
With something caIled the go...?
Goji berries.
-Listen.
-Check it out.
Inhale love.
Exhale inclusion.
It's a little trick l picked up during a
fast with His Holiness in Dharamsala.
And finish.
Yeah, well, His Holiness
doesn't have to deaI with his mother.
You keep your inhaler.
It was no bother.
We had to stop
at Fred's hardware store...
...to pick up a new tankless
water heater. Your old one's shot.
Oh, so now you going out and buying
things without even asking me first.
I don't know what to teIl you.
It's a tankless job.
-I did not--
-Yes, he did.
-Good one, Chuck.
Oh, what a great kid. HoIy moly,
does he have a terrific jump shot.
Honest to goodness,
if he grows another six feet...
...he's gonna be unstoppable.
Hey, Nick. Look what Chuck got me.
-Isn't it awesome?
-Oh, yeah.
-Wait. Give me that.
-Fire! Fire! Fire!
Give me this.
What'd be awesome
is if you was here...
...to keep these linebackers
from tearing up my house.
Dry rot is a tricky thing.
You never realIy know
how much damage there is....
Till you get into it.
It's like I always say, it's gonna get
ugIy before it gets pretty.
Let me teIl you something.
We're gonna get your waIls back up...
...and your home
is gonna be stronger for it.
It better be. If not, I'm holding you
personally responsible.
So l want you to be the one
to keep your eye on this whole project.
A very close eye.
Do you understand me?
Close eyes.
I hear you loud and clear...
...Nickeroo.
With the gun. What are you doing?
And put on some booties.
It's Sunday morning, Nick. lsn't it so
nice to have the house to ourseIves?
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
What? What is this?
Hey, hey, hey.
-What's up, Nick?
-What you doing?
You said keep a close eye
on the project.
So you going camping?
That's crazy talk. I'm moving in.
Chuck, what about your wife?
Doesn't she want you home?
I don't even want him home.
I know she don't.
Don't worry about the missus. Ellie's
on tour over in China for three months.
Three months?
Yeah. She's a country singer.
You wouldn't believe the way
the Chinese love their country music.
But this ain't gonna take
three months.
You're right. Could take Ionger.
But don't worry about me.
You won't even know I'm here.
What do you say? Let's get
out there before the sun gets too hot.
-Get out where?
-Chuck's taking us fishing.
The sturgeon are running.
It's gonna be fantastic.
-You wanna come?
-Oh, Chuck, that is a great idea.
No, no, I can't go fishing.
That's a bad idea.
-Why?
-I got too much work to do.
I gotta set traps in case
that racoon comes back.
You know those are
vicious animaIs, baby.
Oh, come on, Nick.
The water's not that deep.
I don't care about that.
Wait a minute, Nick,
are you afraid of the water?
-Honey.
-No. That's ridiculous.
By "no" he means yes, and by
"ridiculous" he means terrified.
And he did promise
that he'd teach Kevin how to fish.
Okay. All right. Fine.
I'll go fishing.
Fine.
-Yes!
-Thanks, Chuck.
-Don't mention it.
I hate this. I'm gonna let y'all
know right now, I hate this.
-Come on.
-You know what? I--
I think I just swalIowed a bug.
Y'all see that?
Stop messing around, Nick.
Come on.
For real, I think we need a bigger boat.
I'm not pIaying.
No, come on. Just take your rod...
...and cast away.
Don't telI me nothing
about fishing, okay?
I was the king of Go Fish
in my neighbourhood.
This shouldn't be hard, just--
I saw a shark down there.
Oh, Nick, nice barrel rolI.
Just reaI nice.
That's it. I'm gone. I'm gone.
-Hey, Nick?
-What?
I'd be carefuI.
Don't worry about me,
I'm on land now. I got this.
Help!
Help. Somebody.
I gotta fire Chuck.
Why, because he made you
go fishing?
No, because he's tearing up
our house.
Well, it's gonna get ugly
before it gets pretty, Nick.
Don't you start quoting him
like he's some kind of oracle...
...because he's not. He's an idiot.
He's sweet.
What?
Nothing.
Oh, Nick, I know, I know.
This has been so hard for everybody...
...with this house,
and you're used to being a bachelor...
...and now you've got me and the kids
and the responsibiIities of this house.
I know you're under
a lot of pressure, honey.
Oh, my goodness.
Come here. Feel this.
Touch it, right here.
Do you feel him?
What is that, his butt?
I think so.
Isn't that the coolest thing?
Did you hear that?
-Boy.
-Did you hear that?
-Honey, is that the racoon?
-No.
Racoon made a scuffling sound.
That was more like a rustle.
I think it's in the chimney.
I guess I showed him.
Yeah.
-Yeah.
-Yeah, baby.
That's right. You might
wanna close that flue, though.
Leave me alone, man. Get back.
Looks like we better put a cap
on that chimney.
These guys wiIl drive you batty.
Night, neighbour.
I'm sick of you.
Chuck!
What?
-Hey, Chuck.
-Yeah?
What's going on
with my gIass door?
Frame rotted. Ripped it out,
ordered a new one.
TripIe-pane xenon-filled.
Pricey, yes...
...but it'lI probably pay for itself
in 1 5, 20 years max.
What's going on?
I need the water back.
I'm guessing you didn't get
the memo.
I posted it on the fridge late
last night. "Water off, 8 a.m. sharp."
And I don't want you to spiral into
a worry tizzy about the H2O.
It turns out your water
is pure as driven snow.
It's the pipes that are the probIem.
They're compIetely corroded.
You wanna show him?
I pulled this disgusting piece of pipe
from under your house.
Can you see through that?
Yeah, l didn't think so.
If that was your artery,
you'd be dead by now.
Or one side of your body would be,
like, totally paralyzed.
Show him just exactly what
you plan to repIace it with.
This is 1-inch copper piping.
I'm gonna use this for the verticals,
haIf-inch for the horizontals.
Your water pressure's gonna be
hovering at around 1 50 psi...
...give or take a psi.
Is that good?
That is insane.
Insane, huh?
Insane sounds expensive.
Hey, Chuck, I like this guy.
-He's the best. The best.
-He's funny.
AIl right, feIlas,
let's go lay some pipe.
Come on, feIlas, this way.
Through the bedroom.
So Chuck thinks we should try
the Bradley Method.
What's the BradIey Method?
It's natural childbirth.
You know what eIse
he was telIing me?
We shouId actuaIly consider
a home birth.
Home birth? With doctors coming
all in the house and stuff?
-Yeah.
-I'm not sure.
Okay. Well, you know,
we could always have a midwife.
You mean Chuck?
He studied in Switzerland.
-So?
-What do you mean, "so"?
I don't want him
coming nowhere near you.
The thought of Chuck
just makes my stomach hurt.
AIl right. Well, I guess
we'lI just have to talk about it later.
Good night.
-Chuck.
-Nick.
Chuck.
Hey there, little buddy.
Chuck making
your stomach hurt too?
Yeah, go ahead,
heIp yourself. lt's okay.
You seem like a nice guy.
Come to me.
Hey there, little buddy.
You wanna be my friend, don't you?
Well, truth be told, l need a--
Where is she?
She went to a party
at Danny's house.
Dry-rot Danny?
Thanks for picking me up, man.
I remember sneaking out of
my bedroom when l was that age.
Sweet, stoIen kisses in the night.
-Sometimes more than kisses, right?
-Wrong.
-Right? Right?
-Wrong. Wrong.
Whatever they're doing,
I'm sure it's perfectly innocent.
For goodness' sake,
she's almost grown up. She's 1 5.
She's only 1 3.
Practically a baby, man.
I reaIly don't wanna have this
conversation with you.
Enough of this.
Easy there, partner. That's my wife.
-That's your wife?
-Yeah.
-This is your wife?
-Right there.
I love the way your family
treats you like an aduIt.
Ever since Mom married Nick,
I've been treated like a kid.
Well, you're way too
grown-up and pretty for that.
-Lindsey.
-Nick?
You're busted. Now, get up,
because you're grounded.
And you, you fired.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, brah.
Hang Ioose.
Brah. You fired too. And your little
brother. So hang loose with that, brah.
I hate you.
Well, I'm not exactly your biggest fan
right now either. Go wait in the car.
Chuck, let's go.
Chuck!
Oh, Nick.
That was quite a night last night,
huh, Nick?
Hey, Linds-o.
Good morning, Lindsey.
Lindsey. Good morning.
Good morning.
Looks like she's still mad at you.
Yeah, well, this ain't
a popularity contest.
Nick?
Chuck! Come here, man.
Need a hug?
No, I don't need a hug.
I need my floors back.
It's termites, Nick.
Straight up had to go.
Want that hug now?
I'm getting tired of this.
You have one message.
Mr. Persons,
love the magazine idea.
But you are one month late
with the cover.
I've stalled the board
as long as l can.
Now it's my job on the line.
So, Nick, if you can't get Magic,
we'll have to move on.
Of course, that means refunding
your substantial cash advance.
I know you understand.
Thanks, doll. Call me.
And, wives, let's inhale,
taking in another deep breath.
And give it away on sound.
There we are.
And wives are now completeIy relaxed.
What's going on here?
Nick.
We're doing a sympathetic
breathing and birth--
Shut up.
I can't believe you're doing this
with him.
I can't believe you forgot
about our class.
Inhaling and staying in the exercise.
I'm trying to fix our house, which is
supposed to be Chuck's job.
Don't blame Chuck.
He's helping me right now.
Big breath. Big breath.
By rubbing all on you?
No, Nick, by supporting me.
I support you.
I support her.
I'm just trying to build our dream
house for us and the kids, that's aIl.
Y'all just get back to reIaxing.
Rub on the belly or something.
You know, one of our mantras,
Nick, is that coupling is participation.
I know.
What we're gonna do now
is take our hand...
...and go in a circular motion
around and around....
That's the baby's house,
be very gentle. Around.
This may not be
the best time to teIl you...
...your house needs
a new foundation.
Don't Iet that interrupt the flow.
-That's it! That's it!
-Nick!
Come on, Nick.
Somebody's having a bad day.
Now, be careful with that.
That is New England mahogany trim!
I bent over backwards to get it for you.
-What is up, Nick?
-This is what's up.
-You played me!
-No.
You knew this was a piece ofjunk
the minute you sold it to me.
I knew the minute I met you...
...that this home was meant for you!
You just needed a littIe push.
Well, here's my push.
I should warn you, Nick.
I am trained in capoeira,
the Brazilian dance of war.
Yeah, l don't know karate,
but I know crazy.
Oh, Nick!
No!
That was a close one. Once it gets
going, man, is it hard to stop.
Get off me. You are fired!
What? Nick. Nickelback. Come on,
you can't blame me for all this.
No. I can. And I will. And I do!
I blame you for everything, Chuck.
It's aIl your fault.
I'm bIaming you for the ozone layer,
global warming, the price on gas.
It's aIl your fault.
So get off my property,
get out my face and get out my life.
No, no, no, Nick. The good news here
is that all we need is some therapy.
Nick, we can work our way
through this, and guess what.
I'm a Iicensed couples therapist.
I am.
I see this tension happening
between contractors and cIients...
...aIl the time.
It's the bread and butter
of my practise.
But just admit this one thing to me.
One thing.
What?
You never would've bought
this place if it hadn't been for me.
Exactly.
Why is that? l'Il tell you why.
I'll tell you why that is.
Because I knew what you didn't.
Yes, l knew there was
more work to be done here.
But l also knew the value
of this place.
I knew that when you were done...
...that this was gonna
be a home for your family...
...not some stinking house. l got them
up to here, they're a dime a dozen.
But a home, a home, Nick.
This is it.
Your home.
Does this look like a home to you?
This is a mess!
I need you out of here, right now.
Well, if you--
If you can't see the value of a home
as opposed to a house...
...maybe l'm not your guy.
Where y'aIl going?
It's called loyalty, Mr. Persons.
We work for Chuck.
And if he goes, we go.
Well, then go.
I don't need none of you.
I can do it myself.
I don't know what you
were thinking, Nick.
You're gonna have to realise that
we're gonna have to hire Chuck back.
What? Oh, no, no.
That's never gonna happen, alI right?
Nobody takes me for a ride...
...so he's never stepping foot
in this house again.
Chuck is caring, and he cares
about this family.
What he needs to do is move back
with his own family.
It's not normal for a contractor
to live with his clients, Suzanne.
I understand that, but it's been
fun having him around, Nick...
...and he's great with the kids.
No, he's not. He's the one tearing this
famiIy apart, that's what he's doing.
He's the one tearing
this famiIy apart?
You're the one tearing
this famiIy apart, Nick.
-Me?
-Yes, you.
With your insane obsession
with this house.
You don't have to worry
about that anymore.
Got the perfect idea.
This house is driving
everybody crazy...
...so I say we just move on
and cut our losses.
Oh, and where are we gonna go,
Nick, to your condo?
Anywhere but here.
Nick. Nick. We cannot keep
uprooting our family Iike this.
Who was the one crying
that we needed a bigger place?
AIl right? Now, l wouIdn't
be stuck with this dump...
...if it wasn't for you
and these ungrateful kids.
Nick.
Suzanne, I didn't mean that. Come--
-HoId on. I didn't mean that.
-No. No. Don't touch me right now.
I'm just under so much pressure.
And I'm not under pressure?
I'm the one who's having babies
that I'm not even sure you want.
I reaIly think you're overreacting.
I think we need to spend
some time apart, Nick.
Come on, now.
When we first got here, these kids
were not happy about being here...
...but now they're vested in this.
So, what are we gonna do? Just take
that all away because it's difficult?
Is that the thing you
wanna teach Kevin?
That when the going gets tough,
you just quit?
You shouId try putting that
on the cover of your magazine.
Look at you. I mean,
you quitting on me right now.
I am not quitting,
I just need time to think.
Suzanne.
Where you gonna go?
Oh, not you guys too?
Just cutting our Iosses.
Kevin, I know you understand.
Not now, Nick, l'm busy.
Well, you're gonna thank me
when we out of here.
You city kids and you know it.
Coco, get in the house.
I said, get in the house,
you ignorant mutt.
Coco!
Coco.
I'm sorry.
What you doing?
Jason Winchell caught an 8-pound
bass and brought it to school.
Well, actually, just the head.
But it was so big, you could fit
your whoIe hand in its mouth.
Chuck was supposed
to take me fishing.
That is, until you fired him.
You know what?
Why don't we just go now?
RealIy?
Come on. Let's try it.
Hey. I know it's been kind of hard,
making the move and all.
And I haven't actually been around.
Well, I've been around,
but I haven't been around, around.
Know what I mean?
-Yeah.
-Well...
...l'm here to let you know
that all that's gonna change.
Because FYI...
...l think you're a cool son.
Thanks.
And you're a cool dad.
Kevin!
What was that?
I don't know.
But he messed with the wrong kid.
Get him, Nick!
I got him! Stay back!
Yeah! You tell Jason Winchell
that the fish he caught...
...wasn't nothing but bait, baby!
Yeah!
Hey, hey. Hold up.
Forgetting something.
Lunch money.
Thanks. Bye.
-How's your mother?
-She's fine.
You're not gonna have
a heart attack out here, are you?
If l do, just pulI my body
behind the shed.
My pleasure.
Lindsey.
I know you're still mad at me,
but I'm trying to get it right.
It's a new family, a new house.
It's aIl new to me.
But l'Il try to be
more understanding.
Okay, okay, okay. I probably should've
handled the party a little differently.
I'm sorry, Nick.
I should've asked you.
Does this mean
I can see Danny again?
Don't push it.
Go ahead and make your bus.
-Good morning, Mr. Rooney.
-Hey, hi, sweetie.
Hey. This is for you.
Thought maybe you could use this.
How's the house coming?
It's coming.
Hey, how is Chuck doing?
Don't know and don't care.
Boy, l hope he's okay.
This is a tough time of year for him.
Oh, yeah? Why's that?
His wife. He lost his wife a few years
back around this time of year.
You didn't know, did you?
Oh, yeah, she was
really something special.
He's never been the same since.
She was his entire worId.
- Hey, man.
- Hey.
I heard about ElIie.
Come in.
Hey, I got a littIe organic
herbal maté going here.
Thanks.
-Can l tell you something?
-Yeah, shoot.
When I was working on
your home with you...
...to me...
...it felt like family.
It feIt like the special stuff,
you know? The stuff you hang on to.
Stuff that's gone missing
around here for quite some time.
It's funny, I....
I can't even go inside anymore.
Look, Nick...
...l know I screwed your life up.
And I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry,
you got no idea.
You didn't screw my life up.
I did.
And you'll always
be a part of my family.
I actualIy came over here
to make sure you was okay.
I was so upset about how things
were going over at your place, I just....
I went ahead and let Magic know that
you realIy, really need to speak to him.
Man, that's great. That's great, man.
I reaIly need it.
While I was at it, I also happened
to have put my ReaItor's cap on...
...and I made a couple
of phone calls.
I got a Russian banker
coming out here next Friday.
Just might be very motivated.
If you get the roof up on that place,
you might be abIe to flip it.
Get out from underneath
the whole thing.
Well, Iet me get the roof on.
Do you have a nail gun with the
air compressor? The whole unit?
No. I'm oId-school with it.
Oh, you're doing it old-schooI
between now and next Friday?
Maybe just borrow mine.
That'd be good.
Thanks, Chuck.
Thanks for everything.
You got it.
You can ground me later,
but right now, you need help.
Mr. P, the Iittle Pulu
has something to tell you.
I'm sorry about the party.
I should have never taken
Lindsey without asking you.
You got that right.
And if it's all right with you...
...me and my brothers would
really like to finish this job.
Hey, fellas! I got some great news.
Tremendous news.
We are not just working
on a house anymore.
From now on, we're committing
to finishing a home.
You heard it, baby.
We're gonna finish Nick's home.
Check that for dry rot.
You. I'm so darn proud
of you right now.
You're making me feeI a little
"Nickeladocious," I'm not gonna lie.
I just wanna give you a hug on your
Nickelback, my old "Nickabocker."
My Nick at Nite.
Enough!
Well, you caught me just
in the "Nick o' time."
Is it a blessing or a curse?
Go ahead, try it.
Let's go. Hey, hey, hey.
-Suzanne.
-Nick.
Now, before you say anything,
I need to get this out, okay?
-Okay.
-Now, you was right, and I was a fool.
The house is just a house...
...and it'd never be a home
without you and the kids and--
-Yes, baby, l get it.
-I'm almost finished.
Would you please consider forgiving
me and coming back home?
Babies.
Babies? You know, we can work
on that once you drop those two.
I don't think it's
a good idea to--
-Babies.
-Babies?
-Babies, Nick!
-Oh, babies!
Okay. Let me get you to the car.
Come on. Come on.
-Honey, how far is the hospitaI?
-About a half-hour.
Nick, we can't wait that long!
We gotta. That's where the doctors
and nurses and aIl the equipment--
-You're hurting my hand now.
-Honey, it is happening now!
-Now?
-Now!
Okay, kids, get them bags
in the house.
Look, your mom about to have what
she always wanted, a home birth.
Oh, Nick. I Iove the floors. Teak?
Oh, no. That's bubinga.
Nick, slow it down. I'm hot, honey.
I'm hot. Get it off.
Well, what now?
I don't know. l thought you knew.
What you trying to say, baby?
Chuck!
Chuck? l'Il go this way!
I'll go this way!
Oh, Nick, I'm gonna kilI you.
- For what?
-You did this to me.
Hello? Nickster, how we--?
You what?
Okay. Keep this line open.
Chuck is in the truck.
Oh, come on!
Okay.
Baby, is he on his way?
That was him.
He's on his way. Don't worry.
-Everything gonna be fine.
-Are you sure?
Go wait for Chuck downstairs.
Hello? Nick? Chuck had
a littIe troubIe with the truck.
But don't worry, I'm on my way.
Man, just telI me what to do.
Okay, now, telI Suzanne to
stay calm, and to breathe.
Okay, you got to stay
calm and breathe.
-I'm breathing.
-She's breathing.
Now tell her to relax.
Maybe do the colour imaging
we worked so very hard on.
Baby, reIax!
Honey, I'm relaxing.
-Don't yeIl at me!
-Honey, I'm not yelling!
Keep her breathing, Nick.
Put Lindsey on the phone, pIease.
-He wants to talk to you.
-Why?
-Who knows? Here.
-Hey, Chuck.
I want you to listen very carefully.
I need you to grab me some things.
l need a bucket of hot water,
an oral thermometer...
...latex gloves, towels, a shoestring
and some jaIapeño hot sauce.
Hot sauce?
Get that for me.
Put Nick on the phone.
-Okay, Chuck.
-I am aImost there.
I want you to go into the bathroom
and get some hand sanitizer.
Don't telI me what to do.
I'm gonna go in the bathroom
and find the hand sanitizer.
Okay, got it. What now?
We're gonna use that
to sterilize your hands.
Why? I'm not touching nothing.
Nick, you are.
Oh, God, they're coming! Honey?
How far apart would you say
the contractions are?
Fast and furious, Chuck.
Fast and furious.
PilIow! l need a piIlow.
Okay, game time, baby.
Go down there and see if
the first baby is crowning.
Come on, man, what that mean?
Can you see the baby?
Oh, God.
It's like the guppies all over again.
-Honey?
-Chuck, he's down.
That's what the
jalapeño hot sauce is for.
Give him a little dash of that.
Hold on.
He's back.
-Put your father back on the phone.
-Yeah.
I need you to go in there,
grab that baby's head, gently.
For God's sake, gently.
Give it a pull. Then take the
shoestring and tie off the cord.
-HeIlo? Hello?
I lost him. Are you sure
you don't wanna try a hospital?
Guess that means no.
Oh, so cIose. I just missed
the state record. Let's--
-How's the patient doing here?
-Oh, Chuck.
Let's go into our fun breathing.
Let's go into a deep, warm pIace,
and a quiet place.
Okay, quiet and deep.
FamiIy, let's breathe together.
Now we're releasing on sound.
Nick, I can't take that noise.
I can't take that noise.
Hey, look, l'm having a baby.
I can't taIk right now.
-Yo, Nick, it's Earvin Johnson.
-Magic?
Chuck Mitchell said you need
to talk to me.
Look, my wife having a baby
right now. We can't talk.
I remember when I had mine.
Yup. That's how l remembered it.
Tell Magic Chuck-dog said,
"Holler. Much respect. You the man."
Chuck-dog said,
"Much respect. You the man."
Tell Chuck-dog he's the man.
Yo, Chuck, he said you the man.
Oh, natch. That's so Magic.
Hey, man, what's up with the
Lakers, man? Y'all need a centre.
He wants to talk to you, Chuck.
Roundy-round. Roundy-round.
Hello?
You got your hands fulI over there.
Ask Nick if he has
any more questions for me.
You have any questions
for the greatest point guard...
...in the history of the NBA?
Oh, yeah. In that '85 series
against the Celtics...
...was that a true crossover?
Because it Iooked--
Knock it off!
So gotta go. Bye, Buck.
-I need you, baby.
-Look, it's showtime now, okay?
-We got this. We got this. All right?
-Okay. We got this. Okay.
Oh, God.
Told you it'd be beautiful.
Oh, before l forget, I got you
kind of a homewarming gift.
AIl the best.
Yo, Chuck.
Thanks for coming back, man.
You kidding me?
I'm stuck on you, Nick.
And so it goes.
You know, sometimes life
throws you a changeup...
...and you've just got to adjust.
I never did finish
the sports magazine.
Instead, l started something
completely different.
A different magazine,
a lot closer to my heart...
...inspired by rebuilding this house.
It's called Are We Done Yet?
And that's the story on how
we built our dream house.
Thank you.
So l want to thank you all for coming.
Enjoy the party.