Hey!
- Hi!
- Hello.
Uh, Sara Hamilton?
Yeah. That'd be me.
Yeah,
well, this package...
...is for you.
Finally!
I almost gave up waiting for it.
Well, it's all yours,
if I can just get you
to sign right there.
You're a godsend.
If you hadn't turned up today,
it would have been too late.
I knew that.
Why do you think I'm here now?
There you go.
- Thank you, and enjoy...
- Thank you.
...whatever was so important.
I will. Thank you.
Thank you.
Humanity has had
the oddest habit
of turning a blind eye
to anything
that makes it uneasy.
In 1634, Galileo was declared
a heretic for daring to suggest
that it was, in fact, the Earth
that revolved around the Sun
and not the other way round.
And even though
this was one of the most
strongly supported facts
ever disclosed,
that assertion cost him
not only his reputation,
but it also cut him off
from society
right up until the day he died.
For centuries,
thousands upon thousands
of people
have experienced UFO sightings
and various forms of encounters
with extraterrestrials.
Even over 3,000 years ago,
the Mayans depicted
some of these occurrences
in their wall carvings.
But, of course,
it wasn't until
the advent of photography
towards the end
of the 19th century
that we were able
to actually record proof.
Physical proof
of these sightings.
But that was never
gonna be enough.
What with our ingrained
mockery and dupery,
which gave way
to incessant suspicion
and dogma,
which, of course, cast such
an enormous shadow of doubt
all over this proof.
At least for those...
- who chose to turn...
- Hello?
- ...a blind eye.
-  Hi, Sara.
- It's just your mom calling.
- Hi, Mom.
- How are you?
- I'm fine.
Listen, the reason
I'm calling is...
I wondered if you may be free
to come over for lunch tomorrow?
Oh, are you serious?
You know I can't.
I'm going away, you know that.
Sorry, love.
Yes, you did tell me.
I don't know why, I was certain
that was next week.
Oh, no, Mom. It's this weekend.
Couldn't
someone else from the office
at least go with you
to keep you company?
Mom, can we not do this again?
You know, this not work-related.
This is for my book.
I know, Sara.
Mom,
are you hearing yourself?
We're not in the 20s
anymore, okay?
Women can travel
around the world by themselves.
You really need
to accept that already.
You watch
your tone, young lady!
This is your mother
you're talking to.
And you make it sound
like I was around
when dinosaurs ruled the earth.
You are so like your father.
Mom, please tell me
you're not drinking again.
'Course not!
Anyway...
I wasn't gonna bring this up.
But I was speaking to your aunt,
and she said she read
all kinds of weird stories
about that place
you're so intent on visiting.
Oh, Mom, please.
Well, you do
whatever you think you should!
I can least expect
a call from you
as soon as you get there,
though, right?
No, Mom.
There's no signal in the forest,
and I'm pretty sure
there's no Wi-Fi, either.
Okay?
You know what?
I'll... I'll call you
as soon as I get home
on Monday, okay?
All right. Okay.
But please promise me
you'll be careful with the car.
Oh, yes, Mom.
Okay? I'll talk to you soon.
All right. Bye. I love you.
Look.
"And four living creatures
emerged from the center
of the image.
When the creatures moved,
the wheels rolled
along with them.
And when the creatures floated
above the land,
the wheels also floated.
Because the spirit
of those creatures
was in the wheels."
Ezekiel, chapter one.
So, as the prophet predicted,
humanity found itself facing
one of its greatest challenges
to date.
Having to acknowledge
the existence of civilization
from other parts of the galaxy.
We can only hope that this time,
unlike what happened
with Galileo,
we won't have to wait
all of 300 years
to authenticate the veracity
of the unmitigated proof
we will be providing today.
That must be it.
Excuse me.
Um, um, I'm headed
to the military barracks.
Is this the right way?
You'd think God
might at least do something
about our appearance,
and that... damn foul smell
when our souls
finally abandon us, right?
It's definitely not one
of his stronger points.
Twenty years on the force,
and the smell doesn't get
any kinder on the senses.
I don't know
how you do put up with it.
No different
to a deer or a boar.
You say so.
I just about
had enough of it, Joe.
This has got to be the only
nature reserve in the world
where the damn bears
choose not to hibernate.
What can I say...
The unpredictable mysteries
of nature.
Yeah, well, a fucking truce
over the winter
would be doing everyone
a favor, now, wouldn't it?
Sure, but like I already said,
the temperature affects
their behavior.
And besides,
people know all well and good
the danger
they're putting themselves in
by coming out here.
There are warning signs
at every entrance.
Not to mention
the permit you need
before you're even allowed
to step foot in this place.
Yeah, fucking waste of time,
if you ask me.
I don't why you all get off
on that red tape bullshit.
Well...
Looks like you've got your work
cut out for you.
You'd best get on with it.
Yeah, I best had.
Um...
You'll have to excuse me.
Call me or come find me
whenever you want.
Mi casa su casa,
and all of that.
Yeah, right.
Moron! How many times
I've got to tell you?
No taking photos around me.
Get the fuck outta here, now!
It's okay, boss. It's okay.
Jesus Christ!
Oh, my god
Oh, my god.
You're Joe, right?
Uh, yeah.
You must be the journalist?
Yeah. Something tells me
you knew that
before you scared
the hell out of me, Ranger.
"Sara Hamilton."
- Yup, that'd be me.
- Good.
Well, it's great to see
you've brought your permit
and turned up on time.
I wish everyone else
would take a leaf
out of your book.
Yeah, well,
I had no other choice.
Some guy on the phone
gave me strict instructions.
Otherwise, there was no way
I was getting in here.
Yeah.
Uh, that guy on the phone
might have been me.
Well, you can't be too careful,
you know?
Uh, sometimes people
are too smart
for their own good,
and they only realize
once it's too late.
Yeah, I got you.
We need to know
when people are gonna be here,
so we can be around
to keep watch over you.
Contrary to what
most people believe,
the biggest obstacle
isn't getting in here.
It's getting out...
alive.
Yeah. The bears?
Exactly.
Yeah. I saw the commotion
on the river bank.
Well, I hope
the man upstairs
doesn't give us any problems.
I think we'll be okay.
But we're gonna start
inside, so...
you don't have anything
to worry about.
Great!
What do you say
we do this already?
I'll follow you.
So, what do you think
of this so far?
It's amazing.
Can't wait to get inside.
Something tells me you're not
gonna be disappointed.
Humans need something
to hold onto, you know?
And when it's something
you can't
quite get your head round...
...you take your own ignorance
as the truth.
Well, that's a lovely
philosophy, Joe.
But there must have been
documented cases
of sightings and contact
before what happened.
Well, sure.
But there's no actual proof
of anything
from the moment
the barracks were built
until they were abandoned.
Official records, you mean?
Well, yeah.
I couldn't tell you
about anything off the record.
Although, I guess
I gotta warn you,
strange things still happen here
now and again.
Shit.
What's going on?
Okay, just keep quiet.
What?
Oh, my god.
Okay, Sara just do exactly
as I say.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Now, on three,
I want you to run out
of the forest as fast as you can
towards the barracks,
as if your life depended on it.
Wait. What about you?
No, don't ask questions now,
for god's sake, Sara.
Okay? Just run.
And no matter what you hear,
don't look back. You hear me?
- No looking back.
- Okay. Okay.
One...
Two...
Three. Run, Sara! Run!
Fuck. Fuck, fuck!
Help!
Come on!
Come out here!
You don't get the balls, do you?
Couldn't you have picked
a better time?
Can't you see we've got guests?
Come on! Come out here!
Where the hell are you?
You still haven't learned
who makes the fucking rules
around here, have you?
Oh, god. Oh, god.
Shit.
Oh, my god!
You're a
- fucking savage bastard!
- Joe! Joe!
- Joe! Watch out, watch out!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Jesus, what the fuck...
Jesus, Ed!
What?
You know him?
Yeah, of course, I do.
Everybody does. It's Ed.
Didn't I mention him earlier?
No. No, you didn't.
Oh. Well, he's as weird
as they come, but...
his heart is in the right place,
isn't it, buddy?
- Jesus, Joe!
- Yeah.
I caught it on the iron rails
on the fence.
We need to get you
to a hospital!
It's nothing.
What...
Yeah, all right.
Whatever you say.
Where's he going?
Uh, he's got
a first aid kit in his hut.
He's gonna stitch it up for me.
Come on!
You're joking, right?
No.
It's not the first time, either.
These sort of things happen
all the time.
Come on!
He lives down there?
No, of course not.
He lives in a caravan
in the forest,
on the other side
of the barracks.
But if we go this way,
we avoid having to deal
with that friend
of ours outside again.
Yeah.
And we're just gonna
go down there, just like that?
Come on.
It'll be more fun this way.
Yeah.
You could say Ed's
the real keeper of this castle.
He scares prying eyes away.
Even the damn bears
are scared of him.
But... What is he?
Mute or something?
Uh, not exactly.
He's just...
...not the most talkative
of people.
But he's quite the erudite.
You'll see.
Here's where
the officer's rooms were.
And at the far end,
Command and Captaincy offices.
And why was there a nursery?
Oh.
Some of the higher officers
lived here with their families.
There were stories
about how women became
more fertile in this forest.
It was a pretty productive time
for some of them.
Yeah.
Come on.
You're gonna like this.
Ah, leave it out,
will you?
Let me show her.
Come on.
What's his problem now?
Ah, nothing.
He's just
over meticulous is all.
See?
This was how they got
to the higher floors.
Up there was the library,
the living room,
and the bedrooms
for the noncommissioned
officers.
And down there?
Hell.
That actually
wouldn't surprise me.
Yeah, well,
the gateway at least.
Dr. Marshall's
molecular biology lab
and the weapons tunnel
were on the lower floors.
And...
if you stick your head in there
for a few seconds,
you can still hear the screams
of the long-lost souls
who were trapped down there.
You're making fun of me,
aren't you?
You be the judge.
Oh, my god, Joe.
What the hell is that?
I told you weird things
still happen around here.
Dude, what's really down there?
'Cause if you're not making
this up, I'm leaving right now.
Yeah, right, we're coming.
Keep your hat on.
He wants us to get a move on,
but pay no attention.
Well, true or not,
it's probably not the best idea
to be walking around here
on your own.
But I will put you
out of your misery,
and I will tell you what it is.
Yeah, something
that makes sense, please.
I'm serious!
And by the way,
do you really understand
everything that he says?
Um...
How do I explain this?
Let me break it down.
Have you ever had a dog?
Yeah, when I was a kid.
Chewie.
He was part
of the family.
Okay.
And even though Chewie,
all he ever did was bark,
you still understood
everything he said, right?
Yeah.
Exactly!
Well, imagine if you've had
a chance to share
a couple of beers with him.
I'm sure
your canine communication skills
would have reached
all new levels.
Well, I never thought
about it like that.
That's what I was trying
to say earlier.
More often than not,
the truth is actually a lot
less complicated than it seems.
You see,
that's what I was
getting at earlier
when we talked
about all those rumors
that were flying around.
Yeah. And...
What about those cries
we just heard?
Exactly.
What about those cries?
That's just the sound
of the north wind blowing
through the ventilation ducts
on the lower levels.
Well, that scared
the shit out of me.
Imagination can be
a man's worst friend.
Isn't that right, Ed?
Time to visit
the underworld, then?
Uh, not yet.
This is an exit
that leads directly outside.
The Tetis Region
was one of the hot spots
where various UFO activity
was witnessed,
following the Cosmic Call
as a result of the power burst
caused by the Hiroshima
and Nagasaki bombs.
One of the most bizarre
UFO occurrences ever recorded
took place right here.
On October 15th, 1946,
a manned alien ship crashed
in the rocky mountain range
you can see behind me.
The military swiftly moved in,
a 25-kilometer radius
extending from the crash site
was declared
off-limits to civilians.
It was impossible to gain access
to this forest
for the four decades
that the now abandoned
military reserve was operating.
But, on that October evening,
before the military even arrived
on the scene,
a local witnessed the event,
and he took a photograph.
That photograph
was published in the media,
which caused
the government to launch
a relentless campaign rejecting
and debunking the proof.
Now, in the photograph
taken by the civilian,
we can see the image
of the flying saucer
and two human-shaped figures
lying on the ground
whose body measurements
deviate considerably
from the human norm.
The official version
attributed the event
to a military jet,
which crashed during training,
caused by rotational energy.
Accordingly, society mourned
the death of these two pilots,
whose charred cadavers
were said to have been retrieved
near the fuselage.
Hmm.
So, what became
of this third figure?
When they wake up
after the winter lethargy,
they have one hell
of an appetite
and are seriously
sexually active.
It's their mating season,
so they turn aggressive
because of how few
females there are.
And why are there
so few females?
I guess we'll have to ask
the man upstairs.
The thing is, they think
they're the fucking kings
of the jungle, you know?
No respect for us humans.
Sara?
Come over to me. It's okay.
Come over here.
Ed?
Your friend's back.
Okay, okay.
Follow, Ed, okay?
It's gonna be okay, I swear.
Okay.
Go, Sara, go!
You heard the boss complaining,
didn't you, you bastard?
Huh?
Well, you're gonna be in trouble
if he finds out.
You're done for, you hear me?
You're done for!
You think he's gonna be okay?
Oh, my...
Oh, my god, Joe.
I thought you
weren't coming back.
I'm okay. Don't worry.
Okay.
Now this...
this they do
show little respect to.
I think it's run off home.
Ed!
You can get your sewing kit
out now, buddy.
Where are you going now?
Jesus, Ed.
Leave it!
Ed, I know what you're like,
and you'll both get hurt.
Hey!
Okay, do it your way, yeah?
Same as always!
Yeah, you can do
all the explaining later, huh?
- Is he going to kill it?
- No.
Well, at least I hope not.
He's gonna teach it a lesson
in his own particular way.
Shouldn't you go with him?
Well...
Oh. No hurry.
Do you want me
to help you with...
Mmm, no.
It's okay. Thanks.
Um, I can probably do
a brushing up
of my sewing skills
after last time.
Joe, can I take... a look?
Yeah, yeah, of course.
While the cat's away.
I mean, Ed doesn't really like
people meddling with his stuff.
You said, Dr. Marshal
was in charge of the lab, right?
Yep, he was.
And...
...he was Ed's dad.
He was what now?
Yeah. You heard me.
Ed was born and bred
in these here woods.
He's oblivious to the world
outside the forest.
Hence, his...
...kindred relationship
with the wildlife.
Everyone just assumed
he disappeared
in the explosion that...
...killed his parents
and destroyed
the military barracks.
But he was hiding in the woods,
and grew up
living like a caveman.
But what about his family?
Didn't he have
uncles or grandparents?
Someone?
Yeah.
I guess there must've
been someone,
but this was
the only world he knew.
That's the embroidery done.
Yeah.
I guess he just
didn't wanna leave
his memories behind, you know?
And he probably felt
it was his responsibility
to carry on his dad's work.
Can I take a look?
You're a reporter
with a scientific bent, too?
Yeah, of course.
No secrets here.
At least until
Ed gets back anyway.
Uh...
Stay here and don't worry.
I'll be right back.
Ed?
Where the hell
are you, buddy?
Hello?
Fuck. Fuck, fuck.
What the fuck is that?
Joe!
Show, motherfuck!
Sara?
Sara, wake up. Come on!
Sara, can you hear me?
Have some water. It'll help.
Oh!
Thank you.
I couldn't find you anywhere.
What?
Uh, I walked past here
like ten minutes ago
and you weren't here.
I don't know where you were.
What I'm saying is,
I think we've just experienced
an encounter...
- of the fourth fucking kind.
- Fuck.
Do you know
what that means?
An abduction!
Oh! Whoa, whoa.
Whoa. Whoa.
- What is it?
- Oh, my god. I don't know.
Oh, that hurts!
- Oh!
- Joe.
What the fuck is this?
- Oh, my...
- Oh, my... Oh, my god.
Oh, my...
I'm gonna try again.
Zenith to Base, do you copy?
Fuck!
Fuck! Fucking technology!
I've tried, like, 20 times
and nothing. It's fried.
What happened to Ed?
I don't know.
I lost track of him
after the gunshots.
I can't remember anything else.
I woke up back over there.
And, Sara...
there's a mark on my ankle, too.
You too!
We've got to get out of here,
we're way too exposed.
- Okay.
Okay.
- I know somewhere safer.
- Okay.
Wait! Wait, wait.
Where's my camera?
I got it, I got it, I got it.
Hey.
We've gotta go back
to the barracks.
Okay.
It's okay.
Come on.
Okay.
Just rest here.
Just try and relax,
and wait for me here, okay?
Joe.
I'm gonna go check it out first.
Please, please be careful,
please?
Hey.
It's okay.
Yeah?
I'll be literally two minutes.
Fuck.
The fuck have you done to me?
Must have dropped it.
Hello?
Shit.
Fuck.
All right,
here we are again.
I know. On the way.
I hate these bumps.
I hate that there's bumps
in the middle of the road.
Some people like you
will slow down.
- I always slow down.
- Yeah, I know.
I just think
that we take things for granted.
You know, it's as if
people think
they're gonna live forever,
but that's not the case.
- What?
- I mean, things can end
at any moment.
And take us, for example.
I mean, there's a purpose
for why we're in this car.
Yeah, of course,
there's a reason.
We went
to the same school together.
Oh, stop being a shithead, Will.
I mean, I read about this
in one of those self-help books,
and it says that it's nothing
but a simple countdown.
You read way too much.
Every day wasted
is like a slap in the face
- to your dreams.
- What...
Hello?
What's going on?
It is, and while
there's no predicting it,
our time here can run out
when least expected.
Bullshit, woman!
What do you mean "bullshit"?
Do you know
where my dreams start and end?
Where?
On the sofa.
Watching a game of football
and sipping an ice-cold beer.
- Hm.
- And I can tell right now,
that's something
I'll never be late for.
Ah, you're hopeless.
Hello... Hello?
- What's that?
-  Can anybody hear me?
Oh, fuck! Again.
...encounter
near the old barracks.
Help me!
Someone just help me,
please!
Help!
- Joe!
- Looks like those damned bears
have gone too far this time.
Well, they don't seem
too concerned about it.
They have the department.
Well, if it's up to me,
I'd sort that shit out
right away.
Base, this is 03,
do you read me?
We have a possible code 86
out by the old barracks.
Repeat. Possible code 86.
How shall we proceed? Over.
You know what?
Let's just head over there.
That's good. Yeah.
I'll enjoy catching
that cuddly toy.
And when I do,
I'll blow its brains out.
Base, this is 03,
awaiting instructions.
Do you read me?
Affirmative 03.
Old barracks
and surrounding area,
off-limits.
Please proceed
with your normal route.
Over and out.
Copy that, base.
Standing down.
What?
We will proceed
with the normal route.
You know, like I said, it's like
they don't give a shit.
Well, I...
I don't... I don't know
if we should continue.
What?
If we don't go, they'll just
turn up when it's too late.
Like they always do.
Hey, you know
I'm always careful.
Joe! Joe!
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
- Don't leave me alone.
- It's okay.
- It's okay. It's okay.
You're okay. Yeah?
I'm sorry, I just wanted
to find something, but...
Let's go. Come on.
You can come with me.
It's okay.
It tried
to attack me, Joe.
Where are we going?
Into hell, Sara.
This time, for real.
Are you sure
we're safer in there?
I think so.
That son of a bitch
is back.
Come on, quickly.
Can you manage?
Yeah. Yeah.
But I don't know
where I'm going.
- Shit. Shit!
- What?
Joe!
- Motherfucker. I'm...
- Joe!
Joe...
Joe! What the fuck is going on?
Joe! Please!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
It's me. It's okay.
Hey...
Hey, don't worry.
We're gonna be okay. Yeah?
Okay.
Oh!
We're gonna keep going.
Come on.
I don't know about this, Joe.
Sara, come on. Trust me.
It's gonna be okay.
That was not
a fucking bear, Joe.
No.
That was not a fucking bear.
Come on.
Do you hear those cries?
Yeah.
I think they're coming
from over there.
Yeah. Well, that's the direction
we're headed in.
- Okay.
- The north tunnel runs directly
to the vehicle entrance.
Hey. Over there.
Where?
Behind those bushes.
Don't you see it?
Will, I don't see anything.
Don't worry, Sam.
Leave me to deal with this.
All right?
I bet that son of a bitch
is about to catch that girl.
Will, I think we should call
for backup.
How the fuck are we gonna call
for backup now?
Huh?
That's the last thing
we can do...
You brought me here, right?
- I know, but...
- Yeah. Well, let me finish
what we started, then.
Will, this is crazy.
We should call for backup.
This is all wrong.
Base, this is 03.
Do you read me?
Requesting backup for a code 86.
Receiving you, 03.
Stay in the vehicle.
You should have proceeded
with your normal route.
We're sending backup. Over.
Hey.
Where are you? Huh?
I know you're there.
You wanna piece of me,
don't you?
Huh?
Come on!
Son of a bitch!
I know you're there.
Hey!
What? Where the fuck
are you? Huh?
Come on. Come on!
I know you're there. Help!
Fuck! What the fuck is that?
You wanna piece of me,
don't you? Eh?
Ahh!
Oh, my god.
Will!
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Yeah. I'm sorry.
What's wrong with me?
Hey, don't worry.
It's probably just nerves.
I'm sorry, Sara,
but we've gotta keep moving.
I know.
I know. I'm okay. Let's go.
Joe.
That's Ed?
No.
- Oh, my...
- It can't be.
I knew...
I knew there was something wrong
with him when I saw him.
I knew it.
There's no way, Sara.
There has to be an explanation.
Then why aren't you shouting
and running over to him?
Because I can't be
so sure now, either.
Men are so clueless sometimes.
That's the fucking thing
that attacked me, Joe.
- Oh, my god!
- Run, Sara. Run!
Oh, my god, Joe!
What the fuck was that?
No!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Whoa. It's okay. It's okay.
- Sorry, I can't help...
- It's okay. It's okay.
Hey. It's okay.
Hey.
It's okay.
We're safe. We're safe.
You can.
We're gonna be okay, yeah?
I'm gonna get us out of here.
We're gonna get out of here.
Yeah?
Yeah.
What?
Will!
God!
And the images
we're about to see
will prove,
without a shadow of doubt,
the types of experiments
the depraved Doctor Marshall
and his wife performed down here
in the depths
of the military base.
Although, I'm sure you're
probably asking yourselves,
"What happened
to that sole alien survivor?"
With not a shred
of physical proof
suggesting the fact
that it even existed.
Maybe it was simply
just destroyed
in the explosion
that killed the doctor,
and virtually,
every one of the soldiers
housed at the barracks.
- Fucking psychopath.
- Maybe it was. Yes.
Just as, maybe,
on the afternoon
of April 30th, 1946,
Magda Goebbels convinced
Adolf Hitler and Eva Braun
to fake their deaths and flee
to South America.
At this point, it's up to you
what to believe and what not to.
Each to their own.
What the fuck
is all this shit, Joe?
Sara.
Sara, come on. Come on.
I think it's gone.
What... Can anybody explain
any of this, Joe?
How the hell
am I supposed to know
what goes on down there, Sara?
Come on, Come on.
- Hey, look, it's just... Hey.
- No, I can't.
- Take my hand. Take my hand.
- Hey. Yeah, you can. You can.
- No, I can't.
It's gonna be okay. Yeah?
It's gonna be okay.
Come on.
On three, we move.
Okay?
One.
Two.
Three. Go! Go!
Run!
Joe! What are you doing?
I'm sorry, Sara.
I'm sorry.
You can't leave me here!
I'll come back for you.
I promise I'll come back.
Whatever happens, just...
just know I'm sorry.
Ed? It's dead!
You hear me?
- Joe!
- I'm gonna finish it
- for good this time.
- Joe, are you okay?
Oh, my god.
What have they done to you?
No. No.
No! No! No!
Oh, my god! Oh, my god!
Oh.
Get out of the way,
you good-for-nothing half-wit.
Oh, my pretty.
Hold her for me, son.
Oh, shut up, whore!
You wet yourself?
I'm sick and tired
of these damned hysterical girls
you keep bringing in, Ed.
Eh!
Eh, stop your squealing
like a little pig!
Now...
Looking good.
Goddamnit.
Oh.
This is gonna boost
your fertility
and make a real woman
out of you.
Ed, that's... Ah!
You're gonna enjoy this.
Just like I did
when I was about your age.
You can let her go now.
And let him know!
Now, that's more like it.
Teamwork and coordination.
Your daddy would be proud.
Help me up.
That's it.
Now, uh...
You stay here
and watch over them.
And don't you be
touching yourself.
Then come and help me.
I'm gonna check
on the other two.
Joe... Joe.
Joe!
Thank you.
So...
You must be Sara.
Yeah... Yeah.
You're the...
That's right.
I'm Mrs. Marshall.
Ed's mom.
Anything I can help you
with there?
Uh...
Uh, mm...
Maybe, I... I...
Have you seen the ranger? Joe?
Well, um...
I don't, I don't know
how to explain this
to you, but, um...
We were outside,
and... and a bear attacked us.
Hm. There are no bears
in my garden, little lady.
I would have thought you would
have been smart enough
to figure that one out by now.
I...
I don't... I don't know
what you're talking about.
Joe!
Ah, fuck.
What the fuck is...
Huh...
This is coming along
very nicely, dear.
Oh, it's a little girl.
Just like its mama.
What the fuck
are you doing to me?
Now, now, Sara.
Don't be ungrateful.
Honestly, didn't they teach you
any manners at school?
Let me go,
you fucking psychopath!
Motherfucker...
We have spent
the last three decades
trying to successfully breed
a hybrid female.
And at last,
it looks like we found
the right formula.
If only the doctor could be here
to witness it.
He'd be so proud
that we'll be bringing
two little girls into the world.
That's not happening.
Crazy bitch.
Hope you burn in hell.
Joe!
Sara, run.
Run and don't look back!
Where the hell are you?
Get out
of this hellhole, please.
Sorry, Sara. Please forgive me.
I'm not leaving
without you, Joe!
Sara, do not come in here.
What the fuck is going on?
Completing what God started.
Son of a bitch! You can speak.
We can all speak here, sweetie.
I'm sorry, Sara.
You're a hybrid.
Just like your daughter.
We are family now, Sara.
Just accept it!
No!
If my findings are right,
Dr. Marshall had three sons.
Two of which we have seen
running around the lab as kids.
The chubby one
and the one with the mark
on his face.
While the identity
of the third child is...
unknown,
it would seem safe to assume
that if--
Help! Help! Help!
Okay. All right.
All right. Okay.
All right. Are you okay...
All right. Calm down.
Look. Look. You can go to my car
but I have to get to work.
I gotta keep my camera...
Okay.
It's okay. I'll be right there.
All right.
Okay.
We'll get you somewhere...
...somewhere safe.
Some warm food.
Look, I told you
it's gonna be okay, okay?
Yeah.
So, uh...
Did you see the first episode
of the documentary, then?
- Yeah.
What did you make of it?
Great.
Yeah.
Good. 'Cause I've loved playing
with cameras ever since.
Ever since I can remember.
Any day now, I see.
You think?
Yeah! Yeah!
Yeah, it's a...
It's amazing how fast they,
they grow nowadays.
Well, you'll find out.
Oh, let me guess. Um...
He told you that
you had been abducted, right?
By aliens, no?
Yeah! Of course, he did!
Yeah, 'cause, man, he's
one fucking nasty piece of work,
that fucking guy.
He's a...
...a fucking goddamn hybrid!
Yeah. Yeah.
Now, with mother fucking helping
on... on...
on boosting fertility.
Ooh!
He has his way with everything
and anything that wanders out
into our little, whoo...
neck of the woods.
I mean, just think about it.
If we actually manage
to engender a, a female hybrid.
Oh, god!
I shudder to think what's next.
A new species, Mama says.
Yeah. Yeah.
"'Cause that was
your father's dream!
Yeah, that was
your father's dream."
Yeah, but that's
the fucking problem, you see?
That's the fucking problem!
Everybody is so fucking
wrapped up
in their own
fucking dreams, right?
And I'm telling you,
you have to be careful,
you have to... you have to...
you need to be careful
with what you wish for.
Because if it comes true,
and then you find out that it's
not what you actually wanted,
and then, you're fucked.
Then you're fucked.
That's it. It's over.
And then, then what? Huh?
Then what? Then...
There's no turning back.
That's it. That's it.
End of the story.
I mean, fucking goddamn hybrid!
Can you, can you imagine that?
Oh, god. They'd be worse
than fucking humans, man.
And the humans
are fucking bad enough as it is.
Don't you think?
Huh?
I mean,
how can anybody,
in their right mind,
think that the fucking
extraterrestrials
even wanna fucking come back?
Do they really think
they're that fucking stupid?
Huh?
And what the fuck would they
be interested in discovering
out here in our little piece
of shit corner of the galaxy,
populated by nothing, but a...
worthless,
miserable,
selfish,
fucking pathetic species?
Did you see what I'm saying?
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, okay.
You get it, don't you?
"Thou shalt not steal.
Thou shalt not...
bear false witness against
thy neighbor. Thou shalt not...
covet thy neighbor's wife."
Not their ass, their dwelling,
nor their ox.
"Thou shalt not kill."
What is that?
"Thou shalt..."
"Thou shalt not kill."
What the fuck?
Yeah. Oh, god.
Yeah. You must have been out
to fucking lunch
the day you left your fucking
underlings in charge,
to come up with us.
To create us fucking
human beings.
And they used all
the fucking shit
that they could find
around up there.
And it's fucking in us.
It's fucking in us.
Oh, god. Ah, fucking humans.
Oh, they are the fucking worst.
The fucking worst.
Okay.
All of it, it's just...
a matter of time now.
Oh, just a silly
little fucking waiting game.
I'm sorry I didn't...
I didn't mean to yell.
It's okay.
We're the good ones, okay?
All right?
It's gonna be okay.
We're gonna get you home.
Okay?
All right? So, don't worry.
All right? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay.
All right. Yeah.
Hey, be more careful! Jesus...
Christ!
No trace of Sam, sir.
Then he's probably taking her
back to his lair.
Help!
What the fuck?
Hey, calm down. Calm down.
Don't worry. Don't worry.
Hey.
All right.
What's eating you, little lady?
Those fucking bears?
No. Please.
- Please. Please.
- Don't worry. You're safe.
Look at me.
You're safe now.
Put her in the car.
And you give her something
to calm her down.
Now.
What the hell is going on here?
You still not finished
with that documentary, or what?
Yeah.
Uh, no. I'm working on a sequel,
so, um...
I guess, no. Um...
But, I, I don't know
what happened, Inspector.
I... I saw her over
on the other side,
and, you know, she was running
away from the barracks.
So what the hell happened
to her?
I don't know. I think
she's a little crazy, Inspector.
She was going on and on
about... about an abduction
and a woman
in a white nurse's uniform.
She's too Cuckoo.
Did you not see Joe up there?
Speaking of the devil,
there he is!
Can you wait for me
in the car, asswipe?
Yeah, well, I can't wait to hear
what kinda cockamamie
bullshit stories--
Get the fuck out of here!
- I'm really sorry.
- You're sorry?
What the fuck
happened here, Joe?
I mean, can somebody,
please, tell me
what the hell is going on?
I've got an agent
mauled to death.
Oh, and then some girl turns up,
making absolutely no sense,
whatsoever.
And going on
about some abduction.
It didn't occur to you
to call me?
Am I the only sane one
on this fucking planet, or what?
- Look, I'm sorry.
- Yeah. You already said that.
The guy's just got
a little too...
Oh, Jesus.
Well, it looks like you got
your work cut out for you.
You'd better get on with it.
Yeah. I best had.
You'll have to excuse me.
Come find me
whenever you want.
Mi casa su casa and all that.
Asshole!
Hey.