You never know when and
why you fall in love with someone.
That is what makes love exceptional.
This story is about a woman
who falls in love with man at the...
very first sight and her world
now revolves only around him.
Ram is coming for me..
From the minute I got to know about this,
Every second feels like a million years.
My heartbeat has increased.
When the person we love is coming
in search of us
We cannot express that feeling in words
Ram...
Ram, get up!
Ambulance...
What are you doing with that mobile?
I'm trying to search where can
we find tender's head.
We don't have food to eat and you want
an english girl to roam around?
Why are our lives so boring?
How many years should we stay here
in this country? I am fed up.
Whatever it is,
drinking raw is really difficult.
- Hello...
- Hey buddy!
It's me, Gopi from India
- Yeah tell me.
- What time is it there?
Idiot, you called me to know the time?
No buddy! I heard IPhone Max R
has released.. Buy me one.
Is that enough? or do you need
the back case and tempered glass too?
Why do you have to waste money on it.
I'll buy them here.
Idiot!
You think money in Australia
grows on trees?
We keep aside our respect and work
under all white and black people here
and you want Iphones and Ipads?
Shut up and cut the call.
Please buddy.
Idiot!
What is your problem?
Can't you just have the beer and enjoy
Happiness? Enjoyment?
We just use those words in our lives.
Frankly speaking no human being
on this earth is happy.
- Oh god! He is high
- Buddy...
Whole life flashes before our eyes
while we are drunk.
I'll ask you something tell me
the answer.
Did your parents feel happy
as soon as you were born?
Yeah
According to me,
we should cry when someone gives birth
and laugh when someone dies.
Really? Don't say all this nonsense logics.
I'm serious.
We should cry before coming into this world
as we will face all the problems.
And feel happy when we are dying
so that there will be no troubles.
Don't listen to him buddy,
he will keep wasting our time.
Drink guys.
[PHONE RINGING]
Are you still sleeping?
We were awake till morning,
tell me what's the matter.
Which record did you break by
staying awake till late in the morning?
I finished 30 beers in 4 hours and
broke my own record.
Wow! That's such a great thing.
Tell me why did you call for?
I have an important meeting in office
If you have an important meeting,
why did you call me?
Let me finish.
Yeah, tell me.
Someone I know is coming
from India today,
please go and pick her up
You need not call me for that,
you can directly book an uber.
Hey, she is a girl and new to this place too.
She is coming from India all alone,
Can't she come to your place
from the airport?
Don't tell me all these idiotic logics.
Look Malayalam master,
I have important meetings too..
Is it? What important meetings
do you have?
Breaking your 40 beers record?
Not you, we should scold that J.D
for giving you money
Not just drinking, I have other works too.
Stop it.
Whole Sydney knows that you have no work.
I will Whatsapp you her picture,
Go and pick her up. Okay?
You...
Hey...
- Come let's go to the airport.
- Get lost!
Hi
Amrutha, right?
Yeah
This is Ram.
Utham...
Utham is busy and couldn't make it,
he asked me to pick you.
Oh...
Okay
Welcome to solo world.
- Solo world?
- Yeah..
You might have stayed with your family
all this while,
here you are all alone.
By the way, why did you come to Australia?
Masters.
Oh..
From when are you staying here?
5 years.
What do you do?
Oh god! I finished masters, searching for a job
Oh...
Then I might need your help
What?
I mean...
Please guide me so that I can follow you
Hmmm.
Got a warm welcome as soon as
I stepped in Australia.
When I saw him, there was a fight
between my heart and my mind.
I heard everyone say
"Love at first sight is trash" but no...
By the way, What is your relation with Utham?
Nothing. We have grown up at one place.
Utham, I dropped her at your place
Hey, Let's go out for dinner tonight,
don't plan anything else.
- Okay
- Pass the phone to Amrutha
Just a minute
Hello, brother!
Hi Amrutha, how was your journey?
I felt I was on earth when I was
on the flight.
And when I got down,
feels like I am flying.
It is because of the long journey.
Yeah. Why didn't you come to pick me up?
Got a lot of work dear.
You take rest,
we'll talk in the evening.
Okay!
Your phone...
Thank you!
- Bye...
- See you!
- Yeah
New place, new weather,
everything feels good. I like it!
Look, he is here! Stupid
- Hi
All of you at one place?
What's the matter?
What?
- New car?
- Yeah, bought it few days ago.
Okay! What else?
Nothing much, everything's normal,
job searching.
Still job searching, how long?
Should I tell you something...
You were dependant on your parents
when you were in India,
but doing the same here too?
Look at me, I came here much later than you
but crossed all of you.
And you guys...
Yeah that's true.
We are atleast dependant on our parents,
not like you.
Let me tell you something,
Did we ever raise any questions on this?
We struggle hard to get jobs and
people like you take them away from us.
We don't say anything that doesn't mean
you can talk whatever you want.
Get lost!
Go!
Move... Move.
[DOORBELL]
- Hey Amrutha!
- Hi brother
- How are you?
Sister-in-law Varshini, She is sweet.
Brother, I need to make a call to India,
I need your phone,
give it to me immediately.
Give me fast, I need the phone
If you need it immediately...
You could've asked Ram for his mobile
[PHONE RINGING]
- Hello!
- Hi Siri, how are you?
I’m good! What about you?
How was the journey?
It was good,
but I need to tell you something
What? You didn't like it there?
You want to come back?
No, it is not that.
I saw a guy today morning,
he was so handsome.
Who is he? White or Black?
Telugu guy
Telugu guy in Australia too?
Why are you taking it seriously?
Nothing. Got bored looking
at those faces.
It would be good if you marry a white boy.
Shut up!
By the way, how does he look?
He was so hot,
he came to pick me up from the airport.
Is it? What is his height?
And how about his body?
I will call you back, you first cut the call.
He is here.
- Hello...
Bye... Bye...
Okay bye!
[DOORBELL]
- Hi...
- Hello...
- Utham...
- Yes, yes... Please come.
You guys are still not ready?
I am ready! Jyothi is taking time.
Your mobile.
You want some water?
No, thank you!
Impressed.
- Why?
You asked me if I need water.
Indian girls and their respect is very nice.
I remember hearing this in India
and again now.
See if she's ready, let's leave
Amrutha, tomorrow is your birthday, right?
Yeah, I don't even remember!
You don't remember your own birthday?
I remember everything until
I got down the flight,
as soon as I got down I forgot
lot of things.
She must have celebrated it
with her family every year,
but this time she’s here.
So she might have forgot.
Yes.
Advance Happy Birthday
Thank you!
Ok then, let's invite everyone tomorrow
and celebrate it grandly.
Yeah
No, I don't like such things please.
I anyway have everyone I like around me,
that's enough.
Atleast wish her dude
What is the meaning behind that smile?
I don't like birthday's
Why?
According to me,
it is the mistake of our parents
that we are here today.
No doubt, you were born
because of the same reason.
Why do you take it in a negative way?
Take it in a positive way.
We are here to achieve something.
He is not able to achieve anything
so he feels that way.
It is tough to understand my philosophy,
leave it.
You are getting mad day by day,
consult a doctor
Okay leave it.
Amrutha when are you joining college?
I have to join tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
I have a meeting tomorrow
So...
She is a girl, how can she go alone,
she is new here that too our Indian.
No no, stop it! I'll take her.
Wow... It looks so good.
All these are common here.
I am a nature lover,
can you take me to some nice places here?
I need not leave my work and
show you all these.
In few days you will get used to it.
Sir is mad at me.
I shouldn't have said that.
Okay!
I'll take you whenever I have time.
- I thought you are always free...
Hello...
I didn't mean it that way.
Brother told me this.
This Malayali guy is here
only to spoil my name
Sorry.
I am really sorry!
That was my fault,
how can I take it back?
I'll do 100 situps on the road?
Or should I sit on ice for an hour?
If this is not enough, I'll write a letter saying
you are not the reason behind my death
and jump from top of that building.
You smiled?
Thank god that means you excused me.
"Rain drops falling on me..."
"My love for you is eternal..."
"I don't know what this feeling is..."
"Is this happening because
this is my first love..."
"Lightning thunders are now enough..."
"Listen to this girls feelings..."
"My heart wants me to be with you..."
"That smile is all enough for me dear...
"I came for you with all the love..."
"I am giving all myself to you..."
Ram... your love, your anger,
your happiness, your sad moments,
everything should be mine.
I don't think you and me are different.
I want to be all yours.
You are like a drug.
I'm getting addicted to you,
Are you able to understand that?
From when?
- What?
- I mean exams?
Oh exams? From tomorrow
- Hi, is everything ok?
- Yeah.
Surprise…
- Wow!
It definitely is a surprise
Got a glass for you also….
Ofcourse...
Enough enough,
For you?
You are my only high.
Ram...
This is a really good evening
- Is it?
- Hmmm.
Here with you, like this.
It is too good.
How is it?
- Generally I won’t get high for the first peg.
But maybe because you gave me,
First peg is getting me high.
What is the matter?
Nothing.
Wanted to spend some time
with you like this.
- You want a cigarette?
- You have one?
Yeah...
Take it.
I have.
Ram...
My family, friends everybody took
good care of me since childhood
and I used to be really thinking
that is what life is.
I was always first in college and then
and they were so many guys behind me
and I got so many proposals
but never liked any.
I never spoke to them…
But as soon as I came here,
I liked you.
Travelling with you for these many days
made me realise what life is.
Destiny is unpredictable.
We were born in India
but met here in this country.
We think of something and life gives us
something else.
I hope you understand
why am I telling you all this.
Ram...
Get up!
Unnecessarily I got him drunk
Hi...
Sorry, I got high last night.
You were telling me something,
I didn't understand. Tell me now
Is it?
Actually...
- I don't remember it.
- What?
I got drunk and you forgot things?
Ya I don't remember.
Oh god, he is very near yet so far.
Tell me
Okay! I'll take leave, I have to go.
Hey.
Amrutha listen to me. I cannot act.
I am not like everyone else.
I can only understand love
but cannot give it back.
"Can I kiss you,
leaving all the boundaries behind..."
"Will I not pamper you forgetting
all the limits..."
"I will just stay in your arms..."
"I will promise that now I am all yours..."
Do you like cigarettes so much?
Sometimes... but why is it a problem
for you?
Why did you ask me to come here?
Because the nature is good
Yeah it is good
- Your lipstick is good too.
- Thanks.
- I applied it for you
- Why?
- So that you can spoil it.
- Why will I spoil it?
Okay, I'll only spoil it
Why do you want to ruin it
when it is looking good.
Okay!
You ruin it then
Sure?
I did it
Will anyone spoil lipstick like this?
"Every minute in your love I keep flying..."
"Next minute I'll be in your arms..."
"I will win your love..."
"Our hearts have become one..."
"Our togetherness will be affectionate..."
"I am asking the dreams to become true..."
"You are all over me now..."
"Just come to me..."
"Our love will float all over..."
"When we open the doors of love..."
"It should be on us just like the rain..."
Why is this man on call all the time?
What brother? Is it love?
Hey, we ourselves don't have food to eat.
Do we need all this now?
Not us, it is about you.
Not today, but I will definitely
find a job that suits me.
How can you say that?
Listen, we all love money,
but will it give us back that love?
But if you love people
they will give it back to us.
People don't understand this logic
and spoil their lives.
Did you find him?
No brother.
This idiot is not even picking up my calls.
I will cut him into pieces once I find him.
- Will you throw them to crows and eagles?
- No, I will throw them to Kangaroos
- I guess Kangaroos doesn't eat meat.
You cannot bring that idiot,
but you tell me all these
nonsense dialogues.
Let's go!
Ram... I want to do a part-time job.
Let me know if there's anything
Oh why not, will find out tomorrow itself
What... Really?
Yeah
Thank you, Darling!
[PHONE RINGING]
- Hello.
- Ram, tell me
Nothing sir, I want a small help
Tell me what it is
One of my friend needs a part-time job
at our restaurant sir.
- Is there any vacancy?
- Yeah yeah definitely,
ask her to join tomorrow.
Thank you sir, Bye!
Which Ram? You know him
What does he want?
One of his friend wanted a job. I said ok
Okay!
Ram...
Ram... I got a job at your friend's
restaurant as an Accountant.
Weekly pay is $400, which is 20,000 rupees.
That means
it will be Rs. 80K monthly.
Wow! If I earn this much for part-time,
I would be getting more for full time.
Thank you so much!
Thank you so much baby!
One more time
Enough, stop it now.
Hi!
- This is Abhay!
- Hello.
I am the business advisor
for this restaurant
Oh nice to meet you, I am Amrutha
- Nice name.
- Thank you!
- You are from?
- Hyderabad. And you?
Vizag. Your neighbouring state.
We are separated for name sake.
But we are all still united!
Yeah! It will be good if we are together.
What?
I mean it will be good
if our two states are together.
Call me whenever you want anything
in Australia,
I will resolve it in minutes.
I mean your problems.
Thanks!
- Ram...
- Yeah
I'm thinking off to move
out of brother's place.
Is it? Why?
How many days will I stay with them?
They might also feel uncomfortable
As far as I know, they don't feel that way
I know that
Then?
Because I need some comfort
Okay!
Brother agreed to this. All set!
Oh. Where are you shifting?
I found a house near my work place.
- House?
- Yeah! Owners moved to India
House will be ours
- What?
- Yeah
Who all will stay there?
You and me.
I need some comfort with you
Comfort? Really?
Yeah...
Comfort
"Krishna, you please come quickly!"
"You flow like a dream wave inside me...
"I look like a blooming flower
when I am with you..."
"You are my wish and breath..."
"You just came into my life
like rain fall..."
"You are my desire and fire..."
"My soul and life is only for you..."
"You are there in my wishes..."
"You are the meaning of my life..."
"Eye contact is intimating..."
"Body touch makes us feel excited..."
"My heart belongs to you..."
"Please listen to me.."
"Krishna, you please come quickly!"
It works because this is Australia
and not India
Yes!
That family who stays up,
when will they come back?
What?
Please tell him clearly in english
- When will they come back?
- I don't know
- He doesn’t know itseems
- Thanks!
Hello... Listen to me,
Let me know if they come back.
If you give me the exact information,
I will give you money.
- Got it.
- You...
Stop it!
Language is not needed to talk
about money.
He understood the matter. Let's go!
Hey! Come here.
- Did Ram come to you?
- No brother, it's been many days.
Do you have any work with him?
I gave that idiot Rs.10K
with Rs.10 interest for 10 days.
Those are not Indian Rupees,
they are Dollars.
I am unable to take that money from him.
So decided to kill him.
Why do you have to kill him
for such small thing?
Will you give me that money?
I don't have money with me now. Take it tomorrow
What? I don't understand
why are you clearing his debts
He was once my friend, brother
- Now?
- Now, No.
Why?
I pointed out his mistake and
he cut off with me.
- What did he do?
- What all he's doing is not right
Tell me the matter,
Otherwise I'll kill you with same knife
that I got to kill him.
- No, it's ok!
- I will do the mistake now
I asked him not to be irresponsible,
and he didn't like it.
It is not his mistake, it is yours.
You should not give anybody
good suggestions these days.
Tell him if you find him
or else you come and give my money.
Do you get it?
Hmm..
Abhi...
- Thank you very much Abhi.
- Why? He is my friend.
Atleast you try to tell him.
How many days will he roam like this?
Will anyone who has come this far
will be like this?
If I try telling him anything,
he shuts me up.
Ask him to join us at work
and stop doing all this nonsense
He is lucky to have a friend like you.
I'll try to speak with him.
Thank you once again. Bye!
Hi...
You came home early today?
You have any work?
No, nothing!
Is anything wrong?
Nothing wrong.
Ram... Can I ask you something?
- Yeah
- Who is JD?
He is the worst fellow
in our Telugu community.
He makes cash out of our Telugu people's
imcompetence.
Waste fellow!
When you know he isn't a good man,
Why did you borrow money from him?
I was in a bad situation
so I had to take it.
Why are you asking all this?
I don't need to know it, Ram
But I will feel bad when people
around talk about you.
Why should I care about all that?
I didn't take that money for my needs.
My friend in India was in a serious condition
so I sent him that money.
I'm not saying what you did was wrong,
But you give him his money back, Ram
Yeah! I will give him.
Can we just not discuss about this now?
Don't get mad at me. Please listen to me
Hmm, what is it?
How many days will you be idle?
Why don't you start working?
Getting a job immediately that suits
my interest is not easy
Why can't you do something else
till you get your favorite job?
I can't do any other job.
I will only do something I like
Why are you so stubborn?
It sounds stubborn when I say the truth
No Ram, listen to me.
There is a job at my work place.
If you join there,
you can clear your debts in 3 months
What the hell. You are helping me with job?
I picked you up at the airport recently,
suggested you a job and now,
you are giving me these suggestions?
That too in a restaurant like that?
It is not like that, Ram
I know what to do and
how to take care of things.
Stop giving me suggestions.
Everyone likes to give suggestions.
He is right, it was my mistake.
He came here before me,
he knows more than me.
Ram!
Sorry… I will not say anything
like this again, I promise.
Hey…
Sorry.
Please please please.
Please smile...
My baby.
Oh God!
Ram, what happened?
- I cannot do it.
My body isn't supporting me
This is why I ask you not to smoke.
I will stop. But jogging, not cigarettes
Okay, sit here.
I will finish one more round.
- Okay!
- Bye.
Ram...
- Hey...
- Hey... How are you?
I'm good
What's up?
- See ya! Take care
- Bye!
- Come, let's go?
- Yeah!
For the first time I'm mad at him.
Any girl in my place will feel the same.
I heard that boys are not genuine
like girls.
And now I experienced it.
Should I ask him?
Or wait till he tells me.
I can't wait, I will ask him.
Hey, Why are you silent?
Nothing. I am normal and fine.
Ram, Who was that girl?
Girl? Which girl?
You just now hugged and kissed each other.
You forgot already?
Oh Sophie? She's my old friend
We say Hi or shake hands with friends.
Do we hug and kiss them?
She said she's in love.
With you?
With her boyfriend. I know him,
So she was telling me the same thing.
When she's in love with someone.
How can she hug you?
All this is common here
It might be common for you,
but for me it is jealousy.
She has a boyfriend
Then ask her to hug him and not you
Hugging doesn't mean there
is something between us
You should've asked her to wait
and introduce me
You want me to introduce her to you, right?
Wait!
- Sophie...
- No Ram
- Don't embarass me. Please don't.
- You shut up.
Hey, she is Amrutha my girlfriend.
Oh Hi!
Wow, you are so beautiful.
Thank you!
Oh god! You guys make a good couple.
- Thank you Sophie.
Ram is amazing,
I never met anyone like him
- I hope you guys be happy together.
- I got to go! See you.
Okay bye!
Bye!
Amrutha...
- Where are you?
- Room. Why?
- Pick me up please.
- Where?
- Lakeview Gardens
- What are you doing there?
I'm begging. Come idiot.
Cut the call
Mad female, look how is she holding
my husband-to-be
- What happened?
- Torture has started friend.
Will there be any happy days in love?
First tell us the matter
She's mad at you for this reason?
If she's a girl from this country,
she would've encouraged you.
Hey, she is an Indian.
That too a Telugu girl.
They are like that.
You face all these problems
when you stay together.
Live separetely and meet once in a day,
you will not face such issues.
When you sit together the whole day
and talk everything,
You become dry and start fighting
for small things.
Yeah! What he said is almost correct.
What should I now?
It is a long weekend from tomorrow,
we are all going on a long drive.
You also join, there will be a gap between
you both and everything will be fine.
She is already upset with me.
If I tell her this now,
I don't know how will she react.
What is this dude?
You are someone who doesn't fear of anything.
But you are afraid of a girl now?
- Fool…
It is not like that. I don't want to hurt her.
Don't overact.
Look at him, he changed so much.
You took so much time to call back?
I was waiting for your call
You could've called me instead of waiting
Okay. Tell me
- What?
- Sorry
Why?
Because you did a mistake
Oh for that?
Should I tell you something else?
- What?
- Love you!
Okay! Where are you?
- With friends.
- Come soon, I want to see you.
Okay!
Not like this, I will tell her directly.
- I'll meet you tomorrow. Bye!
- Bye...
Hey…
Let's go inside atleast.
Someone might see us.
It's ok, let them see.
You can hug some random girl on road.
But you get conscious when you hug me.
Lift me up!
Why are you crying?
What happened?
Nothing. I like you so much.
I am mad about you. What to do?
Why are you mad about me.
Be normal and practical!
No! I can't.
I am like this. It felt bad all this while
Please don't fight with me ever again
I can't take it.
Madam, you were the one who fought
So? You will not talk to me unless I do?
Don't you love me?
I do. But you never gave me
a chance to prove it.
If you really want to prove it
you would've done it
I will, I will. Everything will fall
into place when time comes.
I will not give you that chance.
I will be the one who dominates.
- Is it?
- Yeah
Okay wait, let me get some water
I'm thirsty
Sit...
Don't leave me
Oh god! She isn't allowing me to move.
How should I tell her about
tomorrow's outing?
Baby...
I'm going on a longdrive with friends tomorrow.
Will be back in 3 days.
What?
3 days outing?
Yeah.
I couldn't stay back without you
for 2 hours.
You want to go out for 3 days?
It's been so many days since
we all friends went out.
They asked me and I confirmed.
Now, If I don't go they'll feel bad.
And you don't care about my feelings?
It is not like that baby.
We used to go on weekends
I will also join you
Only boys are going. So...
You mean it is not possible, right?
Yeah
Okay go.
But you need to be in touch.
Sure baby
At what time are you leaving
tomorrow?
7 in the morning.
One...Two...Four...
There are only 20 hours left.
Please stay with me all this while.
Bye
Bye, careful.
- Okay!
I miss you
I miss you too.
Keep calling
Promise!
Take care baby
Eat on time
Okay!
Come on lift the call.
Don't! Why did you come here
with us if this is the case?
Always on phone.
Idiot!
- Hello
- Hi baby
What? I will call you back.
Cut the call.
[PHONE RINGING}
Ram, where are you?
It is weekend, we came for a long drive.
- When are you coming back?
- Tomorrow, why what happened?
Amrutha fell down from stairs
and hurt her leg.
I got her back home from hospital
Why didn't she call me?
Because you asked her not to call
and disturb you
Oh is it? I will start back right now
What Amrutha?
You keep telling me everything,
but you didn't inform me about this
I didn't wanted to disturb you
when you were enjoying your tour.
Is that tour more important than you?
Is this what you know about me?
Don't worry baby.
I will be with you until you're fine.
Oh my dear I want you...
Slowly...Slowly...
Just keep quiet.
Are you feeling better now?
Yeah...
Sit down
Don't cry friend. We'll figure out something
There is no time or patience
to do something
- Then, what will you do now?
- What can I do? I have a friend in India.
He will do the funeral
Buddy, come let's go to JD
Hey, he won't handover the passport.
And if he sees you there will be
a lot of fights
If he doesn't give, let's break his bones.
- Come, let’s go
- Buddy, trust me.
You will get your passport back.
Let's go!
Move.
What is good, what is bad,
What is hell, what is heaven
What is truth, what is consent
Everyone who is alive will die someday.
But as far as I know,
every human being dies everyday.
Thinking how is this possible?
Look at me, I always die for money
and all these people die for me.
And you die for job.
Like this every human being is almost
dying daily.
He is already dead.
Why are you supporting him?
- No brother.
- Hey!
For me killing is very easy.
I'm asking you very gently
Give my money and take back
your passport
We cannot adjust so much money
immediately brother
Then leave it.
When napkins are not there,
I am tearing my cloth and cleaning stuff
Just in case if we meet a Pakistani guy
we help him if he in trouble
We are from same country,
same place and that too Telugu people.
Who will help us
if we don't help each other?
Last time too you told me all these
and borrowed Dollars from me
Brother, I will clear everything
with interest in 3 months.
How can I trust you again?
How should I make you believe?
Passport, go and get your passport
Go.
Here, take it brother.
Exactly 3 months,
If I don't give back your money tear it.
3 months, that's it.
Your time starts now.
Go.
Buddy, call me once you reach India.
- Sure.
See you.
Take this.
- No dude. You already did so much
Wait, you are my friend.
Who else will I support
- Thanks dude, see you.
- Careful.
Take care.
[BEEPING]
God, please save him
Yes sir...
His condition is critical,
His vital science are unstable.
The major complications and death...
maybe imminent
Maximum 24 hours.
Talk to the Indian Embassy,
finish the formalities
and plan how to take the body to India.
We are helpless.
Sorry!
Brother...
Amrutha, Did you meet Ram?
Are you happy?
What happened?
Why are you crying?
- What did you do?
- I did Masters in IT
Did you work before?
No, I just finished my graduation
and I am looking for a job.
- Okay.
We will think about it
Okay, Thank you sir!
Don't worry about anything. This job is yours.
How are you so confident?
It is about the confidence I have on you.
You will definitely get this job.
Let's see
- All the best.
- Love you.
- Bye.
I completed masters in
Sydney Internation College in 2017.
And I am looking for my level of job
- Ammu…
- What?
I got the job
Wow, congrats. When should you join?
In next 2 days
Thank god.
You have been waiting for all this while
and you got what you wanted
Yeah! Nobody believed me all these days
But today I proved it.
So many people here thought
I was a fool including you.
- Me?
- Yeah.
You suggested me about that job
in Restaurant
No!!
I didn't mean it that way Ram
I will now show everyone what Ram is.
- Hi... Good morning!
- Good morning.
Hey Hi
Hello, I am Ram
Where are you from?
- I am from India
- I love India
- Really?
- Yes!
Gandhi, Shahrukh, Pawan Kalyan, Baahubali..
I know all of them.
- Wow! You lot about India
Ram...
Hey...
Where is your car?
I don't have a car. I use public transport
It's ok. Get in, It's on the way.
Thank you!
How is the first day in office?
Yeah, it's nice
Are you married?
No, I am not.
- What are you doing this weekend?
- Me? Going out with besties.
Okay! I thought we could do
something together
- We shall plan some other time
- Okay definitely.
Ask me when you need any help
in your work.
I don't mind
So nice of you.
Give me your phone number, I'll call you
Sure
Yeah! This is my phone number.
- Okay.
That's my stop, could you please pull over
Why is he getting down here? Who is she?
Oh god! She saw me.
What should I do now?
Hi Baby...
What are you doing here?
- Who is she?
- Who?
- The one who dropped you
- Oh she is Tana my colleague
If she is Tana, what are you?
What are you talking?
She came to me while I was walking on the road.
Gave me lift, how can say No on her face
You have asked her to drop you home,
Why did she drop you here?
She will be going in this route,
so she dropped me here
I want to spend some time with you.
Come, let's go!
Why are you crying so much?
She just gave him lift
Today she just gave lift
Tomorrow, she might lift him too
That will not happen
I trust Ram
More than I trust Ram,
I don't believe in girls here.
Also, fair skin
That will not happen.
You are thinking way too far
Why can't it happen?
She is much beautiful than me
You mad girl! You think Ram loved you
because of your beauty?
I don't know what he liked in me
I know
What?
Ram loved you for your innocence
How do you know?
He told me this when he came to my place
- Really?
- Yeah!
Stop thinking all this and be nice to him
He really loves me so much?
Yeah!
He really likes you
Okay, I'll leave
How could you lie so easily?
Whatever I say, she will not understand
anything now
Why?
As a girl I can understand
what she's going through
Ohh, what position is she in?
You will not understand
Ram...
Sorry.
Sorry? For what?
Just like that
You will not just say it
without any reason. Tell me what is it.
I said nothing
I understood a bit
Tell me what did you understand?
Yeah! It is about Tana.
Stupid female!
How dare she told you bye.
What? No one should talk to me?
They can speak. But I should know them.
If not you should introduce them,
I will see what their character is
and then decide
What is this condition?
You take it however you want,
I will be careful.
You are so handsome.
What if someone snatches you away?
- You are mad. I am not handsome
I'm just an average guy.
Guy I loved is be handsome.
You will understand it
if you see through my eyes
Exactly like you said.
I might look handsome to your eyes
not for everyone.
What if someones sees it?
Don't you think this is too much?
Noo.
Hi Tana
Hi
Ram, can I ask you something?
Yeah sure.
What do you think about me?
You are matured, talented, beautiful
Ohh nice.
You know I'm married.
Really? You don't look like that
I am divorced
Oh sorry! Sorry for you
That's ok.
I just wanted to tell you.
I am lonely here.
My mom and dad live in Adelaide.
So you can keep me company
Okay!
Brother, 5000 dollars
What about the rest money?
I will give you soon
Okay
Hi...
- What's up?
- Did you get the ID card?
Is your blood O negative?
Yeah
Okay
I am hungry, let's eat something
Where shall we go?
- Your wish, where ever you want to go
Okay.
"I know you are mine..."
"I gave you all my heart,
I will be with all your life..."
“We both are one now and will be like this
for the next 100 years…”
"I get all new dreams because of you..."
"You gave me new dreams,
that I never dreamt of..."
"You've become mine breaking the loneliness
that's around me..."
"I know you are mine..."
"I gave you all my heart,
I will be with all your life..."
- Drink this one.
- No, I don't want that.
Drink it, It makes you warm...
I don't want that
"My heart wants you more than me..."
"Can I live without even for a minute..."
"Am I not just yours?"
"I will just be in your arms..."
Ram...
Yeah!
Let's get married
Why? Is that needed? We are happy now.
What?
You might not need marriage, but I do
Okay get married. Did I stop you?
What?
"On those sweet lips..."
"I will remain like this being yours..."
"I know you are mine..."
I gave you all my heart, I will be with all your life...
We both are one now and will be like this
for the next 100 years...
Wait for 2 minutes
Here it is!
Your coffee
Somebody texted you, check it
Who is it?
Ram.... Talk to me
What should I talk?
I cannot keep something inside
and behave normal.
I asked you what I felt.
What is wrong in it?
It's not your mistake but mine
Sorry, I will not touch your phone ever again.
I am really sorry.
Hey, come here.
It is not like that baby
Don't tell me anything.
I trust you!
[PHONE RINGING]
- Hello Ram.
- Hello Tana.
How are you?
- I am not feeling well for sure.
I think I have fever
Did you take the medicine or not?
I don't have the energy to take
the medicine.
Can you drop by?
- Sure baby, text me.
Bye!
Why is here?
Where is he going?
Whose house is this?
Why did he come here?
What is he doing?
Take these medicines.
You need to drink a lot of water
Sure Ram.
Tell me Ram, What do you want to drink?
No it's okay
But you have to take something
Coffee
It's not time for coffee.
I'll tell you why...
See.
- But you said you’re not well.
- I wasn’t…
Until you came.
I'll go get the broom.
Hey, are you okay?
Yeah okay
Sit here!
Ram, can you take me to the bedroom
Okay! Put down your leg carefully
Got you!
- Hi…
- How is Ram?
He got his favorite job, he's happy
Yeah! He is very happy.
You can't even imagine how happy he is.
Sorry!
Not just that, he did so much.
I'm showing you the censored version.
You trusted him madly. See what happened
I'll leave
What the hell?
This is recent one.
Amrutha...
All that is in the video is not true.
I saw it with my eyes, and you're saying
it is not true.
Why are you cheating on me Ram?
I've trusted you so much!
I loved you so much,
I thought you are all mine.
Ammu, I am always yours.
Don't try to convince me
Hey, why don't you understand?
Why should I even convince you?
Who sent you this video?
Abhi...
Waste fellow. Come with me
Ram no, please no fights. Please
Shut up and come with me.
Get in.
Tell her the truth.
- I’ll tell you…
Amrutha come and listen to him.
Tana, what are you doing?
Tell me about yourself
What do you want from me?
I need you Ram.
- Are you serious?
- I think I am in love with you maybe
- You are kidding me, right?
- No Ram, I am quiet serious.
- I think you are too…
- Yes, I am but not with you.
What?
Yeah!
Her name is Amrutha
Is she beautiful?
If I see from my eyes,
she might not be as beautiful as you.
But If I see her with my heart,
after my mom I can only see Amrutha.
I am not just in love with her.
Her love is more pure than mine.
Comparing her love with mine is foolishness
Wow! She is so lucky
- I am lucky.
- You guys are made for eachother
Ram... Come here!
Say sorry to Amrutha for me.
Sure. I will
Hey...
You proved that you are genuine in your love.
But is she the same?
- What are you talking?
- Not me..
But if you listen to what I say, you will...
- Hey you...
- Ram...
Job which you're doing now
is recommended by her.
She knows that you are useless
Amrutha, what he's saying is true?
Ram...
Listen to me
Amrutha, Just tell me if that is true
Ram...
Hey!
Is is true or not?
Don't worry about anything,
this job is yours.
How can you be so confident?
It is about the confidence I have in you
I know that I will be getting
this job one day.
No one believed me.
Please open the door.
Ram!
Ram please open the door.
Ram...
Ram don't go please.
I cannot live without you
Enough is enough.
You cheated once I don't want this to repeat
How is this called cheating Ram?
- Why are you taking it in a wrong way?
- I will take it however I want.
You didn't even wanted to inform me
about the job?
I know you wouldn’t agree to it.
So I didn't tell you
I loved you so much. I never thought
I will be cheated so easily
This is not cheating
You played with my emotions,
you didn't even give some respect
Why are saying that Ram?
Am I not your girl?
Yeah! Even I felt the same.
But you didn't
That is the reason you didn't tell me
about your job
Be yourself, however you want.
But don't leave me Ram, please.
Stop this nonsense.
Go tell your friend that
I am resigning this job
You are mad at me.
Why do you have to resign?
Wait Ram, please
Not just mad, I hate you!
I cannot kill my self respect
and stay back.
I don't need you nor your fake love.
- Hello
- Sorry brother.
I am not in a position to give you
the balance amount.
I need some more time.
- Why?
I lost my job brother
I think your girl knows that
you will lose your job.
She cleared the payment but
asked me not to tell you.
I couldn't control
so told you about it
See you.
Ram, listen to me Ram please
You made a fool out of me everywhere
No Ram...
Ram please...
Ram.. Please!
Please Ram.
- Hey, why don’t you understand?
- Please Ram…
Please don't go Ram. Please Ram
Get lost! Why are you behind me
like a dog
I am ok with whatever you say or scold,
but please don't go Ram.
Ram...
Open the door Ram please, don't go
Please Ram, open the door.
Don't go Ram, please.
"Is this called love?
Will it give so much pain..."
"Should I just cry that you are not here..."
"My tears are floating like a river..."
"Will I be able to see you in my dreams?"
"I am waiting for you to call me..."
'As you are not coming back, I feel lost..."
"There is no life without you..."
"Who said there is no love,
I am standing here today"
"like a bird with no wings..."
"Should I just tell you my feelings
behind my silence..."
"I will be standing on a curved road
all alone..."
"Do you know that these are written
with tears in my eyes..."
"This pain in my heart is hurting me
so much..."
"Should I shout that I am nothing
without you in my life..."
"I am alone just like a star
with no light..."
Did you find Ram?
I thought you would ask me
Why am I here as soon as you wake up
Where is Ram?
Do you know what is your condition?
You've been lying here
since 2 days without food.
It is good that we came here on time.
Where is Ram?
Are you mad?
He is not here, nobody knows
where he is.
- Everyone is searching for him.
- Where did he go?
- When can he come back?
- Amrutha…
If you're love is true
he will come back
If you stop eating like this you will die
before he is here.
You know what is more painful
than death?
Loving someone wholeheartedly
Amrutha, think before you do something.
We all know how much you love Ram.
He might have done that because
he was angry.
[Phone Ringing]
Amrutha, Ram is at Shepherd court.
Ram, why did you do this Ram?
Why did you leave me?
You know I cannot live without you
Leave me!
Please Ram. I know it is my fault
Please forgive me
I will not repeat this ever again baby.
Please! I cannot stay without you
I cannot live without you, I can't...
Amrutha, leave me. It doesn't look good
Let them see, I don't care
Why are you behaving like a Psycho?
I will really become mad
if you leave me Ram.
Be however you want.
I will not question again.
You need not work also.
I will take care of everything
Don’t do anything, just be with me.
That's enough
You mean that I'm still a useless man, right?
I didn't say that, Ram.
You will look after me?
- I didn't mean it in that way
- Then, why did you say that?
I said that because I love you
Yeah that same love made me
stand on this road.
There is no freedom,
You must like all that I do.
You change everything as per your wish.
Understanding each other feelings is what love is
You shouldn't force people into anything
I've been observing ever
since we met each other.
You keep poking into everything
and call it love.
I cannot do this anymore.
Please leave me
Hey...
Ram, please don't say that.
I will not repeat this Ram
I'll stay however you want
I will whatever you want me to do
I will prove that my love is true
Please give me one last time, Ram
Will you really prove it?
- Yeah, I will
Then don't show me your face again.
And then I will trust your love.
Just leave!
Is this your final decision?
Yes.
What happened?
Where are you going Amrutha?
I am going back to India
Why? What happened?
- Will you really prove your love?
- Yeah, I will
Then don't show me your face again.
Just leave.
Amrutha, you going India in
this condition is not good
I cannot stay here brother.
If I stay back I cannot stop myself
from meeting Ram.
I cannot face all that
Will you spoil your life for that?
A person should never take a decision
when they are angry, sad or happy.
As you both have been together
for so many days,
He might have got irritated a bit
but love will be the same
If you want to win his love
You should first lose.
Stay away from Ram for few days
Things will settle.
Trust me Amrutha, time heals everything
What is this buddy?
why are you doing this?
What did I do?
Don't ask me that.
How many days will you stay away
from everyone?
I think I'll be peaceful staying away
from people for few days
You mean, you were not peaceful
all these days?
I didn't mean it that way
We all know how much she loves you,
Why are you not understanding that
If you are here only to talk
about Amrutha, please leave
What? You want me to leave?
Before I leave, I'll talk
everything clearly.
First tell me something?
What is Amrutha's mistake?
Mistake? It is a very small word.
She cheated on me
Cheating?
Loving you so much is cheating?
Thinking about you always
is called cheating?
Leaving everything behind
for you is called cheating?
She wanted to live with you,
die with you, Is all this cheating?
She cared for you more than your parents
If she really cared about me so much,
Why didn't she inform me
about the job
She clearly knows you would never agree to it.
If this is called cheating
Then what you are doing with her now
is called betrayal.
Is this called betrayal?
Is that called betrayal, then?
You got that job because
you attended the interview
Because of your talent and
not because she recommended.
Okay, let us keep that aside.
She made a fool out of me by paying back
to JD. Isn't that a mistake?
Are they any great people for you
to become a fool?
She gave money back to JD and
asked him not to irritate you anymore.
She didn't make a fool out of you,
but instead saved your dignity .
And coming to that Abhay,
we both know about his character
Since the day Amrutha came here,
She only had you in her priority list.
It is your luck that you have her
in your life.
Girls are horrible these days,
and you've got her in your life
Please stop it!
You are just talking about
Amrutha continuously,
Not just her even I loved her
wholeheartedly.
My love is genuine too.
Then why can't you forgive her?
She wanted her love to win so she did this mistake,
why can't you forgive and move on?
Why should I compromise?
Why can't she do it?
- She was doing the same till now.
Whatever the situation is,
She was the one who always compromised.
Sorry, I am really sorry.
It was my mistake.
Sorry sorry, I am sorry.
Please forgive me.
If you want the relation to be strong,
You should also know to forgive people.
Amrutha is a girl who only
knows to give love.
The day you understand this
you will go back to her.
This is not my philosophy,
it is Nature's philosophy.
It is your wish now.
"You made my imagination come true with your love..."
"Our souls have become one..."
"Everything was so good when I was with you"
"I'm the one who left you,
it is my mistake..."
"Not having you in my life is giving me pain,
and I'm unable to bear it..."
"It is all you everywhere
when I close or open my eyes..."
"My world is empty without you..."
"I've realised there is no life
without you..."
Utham...
Where is Amrutha, I want to see her
Harrison Street, Landsdale,
Melbourne.
[PHONE RINGING]
- Hello...
- Hello Amrutha...
Hi brother, How are you?
I'm fine, but guess what
Ram is coming for you...
Yeah Amrutha! He has totally changed.
- What?
He wants to see you,
He is coming in search of you
I told you know,
time heals everything Amrutha.
Thank you Brother...
Ambulance...
Yes, yes sir.
His condition is critical.
The major complication and death
may be imminent
He has got multiple fractures in his body,
Mainly his heart is damaged.
It's called Cardiac Tamponade.
His heartbeat count will be decreased
to 20 times per minute from 70-80.
It is very tough for him to survive.
Maximum 24 hours.
Talk to the Indian Embassy,
Finish the formalities and
Plan how to take the body to India.
We are helpless, Sorry!
Where is Amrutha?
I'm talking to you, where is Amrutha?
She is not here
Where did she go?
She has gone to India
I know she will not leave me
in this condition and go.
Tell me where she is.
Tell me the truth.
I'm not lying!
I can see it in your eyes Utham.
What you're saying is lie.
How many days can I hide the truth,
You must know it someday or the other.
What truth?
Where is Amrutha?
Hello brother.
Doctor, this is a developed country,
Well developed science
with advanced medical treatment.
Can't we treat a person who is
still alive with all these equipments?
There is one small chance.
But I don't think it'll work.
We can replace his heart
with someone who is brain dead.
or someone who met with
an unexpected accident.
There is a chance for him to live
if we replace his heart with them.
But we don't have a chance now
As it should be done in the next 24 hours.
Finding a heart with the same blood group
immediately is impossible.
So, you better take him home.
Doctor, can I see him?
Sure
Ram...
This doctor is talking all nonsense
He says your heartbeat isn't normal
But your heart will be fine and I know it
Love can solve any problem in this world
If your heartbeat stops, my love will have no meaning
You will be fine, Ram
You will be fine.
I always thought love is all about you being
how I like and me being how you like
But I understood it isn't like that
Love is all about being happy together
I thought pure love is only
about giving life,
but no, It is about loving someone truly
I still remember how my heart raced
when I first saw you
It is love at first heart for me
Love is two words and mad is two words
I love you madly,
and I can end my life for you
People kill themselves
and make their love win
You've given me place in your heart but today
if that heart stops beating,
How will my heart work?
The minute your heart stops beating,
mine will stop too
So, I've decided to become your heart
I feel lucky for doing this, as no girlfriend
will ever get this opportunity in her life.
Not just happiness
but sacrifices are also a part of love
I've decided to do this to prove
that God can't tear us apart
Hello
Hello.
Royal City Hospital
Yes!
I got an information that you guys are
looking for heart transplantation
Yeah!
Someone just met with an accident
at Mantrait Caston way
Can you please send an ambulance
as soon as possible
Sure
Thank you!
People generally fear death,
but I am loving it today
It's time for me to end my life
and save my love
"You left me proving that
love never ends..."
"This merciless death took you
away from me..."
Ram, please don't cry!
If you cry, you know that
I'll feel bad.
We are not two different people,
we are one now.
I will be with you in every
aspect of your life
No one can ever take me away from you
I am your heartbeat every second now
Your problems, your happiness
everything has become mine
This is something no girl
can ever experience
Lovers can never come into this world
together or leave together
But for us, we both got a second chance,
We will live together, die together
I've made you all mine from today
You gave me a chance to prove my love
You made me a part of you
and gave my life a better meaning
I love you so much Ram...
"Did the earth just crack open..."
"Did the cruel life steal you from me..."
"Did the compassionate Gods forget me..."
"My love, won't you return..."
"I feel empty without you..."
"No matter how long,
I would still wait for you."