Satellite
measurements of the Mesopotamian.
Basin show that radioactivity
levels remain high,
and with the oil spills in
Arabia still burning, the world's
total reserves of petroleum
have dropped even lower
making gasoline all
but unobtainable,
except for governmental agencies.
Food riots have continued
into the third day,
and marshal law was declared
for all of greater Detroit.
Army units and the National
Guard have been called in
to restore order and the
military commander from Michigan.
That all looters will
be shot on sight.
The migration into the
countryside continues,
and once-peaceful rural areas
have become a battlefield
as roaming bands of what
can only be called bandits
raid farming communities for
well-hidden supplies of fuel,
as well as food and ammunition.
The most notorious of these
groups is lead by the renegade
army colonel Straker who
travels in a heavily-armored
vehicle and has so far eluded
all attempts for capture.
With most of the law enforcement
agencies fully committed
to the cities, it looks like
his mobile reign of terror
will continue for some time.
Hey, you hear that?
What's that noise?
It's just the wind.
- No, I can hear something.
Imagination.
Holy shit.
Come on, move!
God damn!
Come on, damnit!
Move, move!
My god, they're moving,
for god's sake hurry up!
Come on, move!
Move it!
Discard your
weapons and stop immediately.
Hey, Boss, they got diesel!
Morning.
- Morning.
Where'd you boys
get all that stuff?
We're just driving
along, we saw these drums
on the side of the road,
someone must've left them them.
I'll take you there no problem.
I know where it is, sir.
Take you there.
Thank you very much.
Yeah, yeah.
Hey, where's he takin' us,
this place is radioactive!
It's okay, the signs are
only there to keep people away.
Keep on goin'.
Open the gate, Bone.
I'm not going in
there, it's dangerous!
Open the gate.
You'll be sorry when
your skin turns green
and your teeth fall out.
- Just drive the truck.
There's nothing here, sir.
Listen, I'm sick of burning
garbage in my truck.
It gums up my turbines, I
want that diesel, understand?
It's in the other
quarry round the back.
I'm telling you truth, honest!
That's good.
If you were lying, then I'd
have to give you to Willie.
He has a few games
he likes to play.
They work real good on dogs.
But dogs don't have
nothin' they can fears.
I'll show you, it's the
truth, I promise, I promise!
There's nothing here,
I'm gonna kill him!
You heard the boss, he's mine!
If there's anything left
of him, you can have him.
Knock it off.
Where is it?
- Out there!
It's underground, I'll show you.
It's not booby-trapped, is it?
No.
No way.
- Good, then you show me!
They got 50,000 liters, sir.
I like this place, we could
stay here for a long time.
Set up camp.
Bone?
- Sir.
Distribute some home brew
to the men, they earned it.
Sir.
Hey, set up camp!
Yes, Willie?
- Him, Boss?
Bring the girl.
How long you boys
known about this place?
My old man was a quartermaster.
When the government collapsed,
we sort of inherited it.
You were very lucky, weren't you?
Yeah.
- For a while.
What do you mean?
- Tie him up.
What?
Hey, wait a minute!
- Gag him.
Hey, Boss.
Corlie.
You're getting old enough to
take a little responsibility.
Now, this man is a liability
to us for various reasons.
Do you understand?
Good.
So I want you to do something.
Kill him for me.
It's a new world, Corlie.
With new rules.
Learn them.
Bloody drunk,
you're weak, come on!
Get your hands off me.
This place would
make a great base camp.
Yes, but we're in a valley,
so I want complete
perimeter protection.
Set up a field of
fire along this ridge.
Automatic weapons
here, here, here.
Sentries outside the
gate, inside the gate.
500 yards up the road,
you have lookouts.
Patrols leave
through this galley,
through the high country,
returning here every four hours.
And most important, I want two
men guarding that fuel module
around the clock.
Yeah, well it all
belongs to us now.
Of course, Bone,
it was inevitable.
The generals were just too
chickenshit to make a decision.
Wars are not won by men of
political ambition, my friend.
There's too much lipstick
and not enough napalm.
What was that?
- Your imagination.
Corlie!
Jackpot!
Hey, Corlie!
Corlie!
Have a cocktail.
I hate you, Willie!
Why are you running away, Corlie?
Don't you like us anymore?
Poor little didum,
you hurt yourself.
Leave me alone, Willie!
We've gotta get him, come on!
Come on, you guys!
Ho, what a prize he'll be!
Yee-ha!
Hey!
Wait!
Be back for you, Corlie!
Quick, shoot the bastard!
Save the bike!
Get off.
Who were those guys?
I don't know, I
was lookin' for food
and they came up over the ridge.
You got people around here?
Family?
Friends?
Anybody?
- No, my daddy died.
And then my horse ran
off with all my stuff.
Have you got any food?
Get on.
Suit yourself.
Give me that hose, will ya?
What is it?
Methane, make it
out of chicken shit.
Don't you ever
get lonely up here?
Don't care much for people.
Did you fight in the wars?
Yep.
Bet you nobody ever
bothers you up here.
Nope.
I better have a look at that leg.
No, I'll be alright.
Maybe.
Sit on the bed.
Gotta watch every
scratch out here.
You never know what
it might turn into.
Most things get better,
if you give 'em the time.
Not gangrene.
That bad?
I'll be more careful.
What was your father like?
He was a saint.
Everybody loved him.
We'd travel around and
help people, fix things.
This is gonna hurt some.
And then one morning
he just didn't wake up.
So I kept on goin'.
That's what he would've
wanted, I guess.
We gotta go.
- Why?
'Cause that needs sewin' up.
Take you down to Clearwater
Farm, they got a healer there.
Medicine.
But I feel much better.
- Come on.
Wait, let me stay here a while.
I can take care of the chickens.
I'm a hard worker.
Not lately.
Yeah, but I can if
you give me the chance.
You need people, I don't.
Okay.
Okay, this is it.
Just knock on the gate
and ask for Rusty.
You're not coming in with me?
It's not my kind of place.
No.
Goodbye.
Thank you for saving my life.
Hunter!
Damn.
I wanted to show him
that new shortwave
I've been workin' on.
Picked up a signal from
Radio Mecca, prayers mostly.
Damn!
My name's Rusty.
I'm Corlie, Hunter
told me to ask for you.
You're lookin' to join, are ya?
Yes.
- Good.
Good, well, come on in,
I'll show you around.
Hunter's brought us
some of our best people.
He sure gets around a lot.
Yeah, we're always shorthanded
here, even in the winter.
But there's plenty to
eat if you like turnips.
Yeah.
- It's a strict democracy.
A little old-fashioned,
but it seems to work.
That's my workshop
right over there.
Over there, that's the main
dome wall, that's where you'll
be sleepin' till we can fix
you up a place of your own.
Well, that is if they
vote to let you in.
But that shouldn't be too much
of a problem, because women
are, we have a lot of
bachelors, are you single?
Yeah, very.
Good, good, well don't, just
be really nice to everybody,
but not too nice to any one
person until after the vote,
if you get my drift.
- Okay.
Rusty, where are you taking her?
This is Corlie,
I'm just showing her...
You could be carrying
her with a wound like that.
Wound?
- Come on, honey.
Don't you worry, I'll have
you fixed up right as rain.
There was no doubt that it
was a perfect fit, and then,
before the two ugly sisters
could show their surprise,
Cinderella's fairy godmother
appeared before them,
and with a wave
of her magic wand,
she changed Cinderella's
ragged dress
into a gown of golden silk
which made the ugly sisters
gasp in jealous anger.
"Go now," the fairy
said to Cinderella.
"The coach outside will
carry you to your prince."
So, Cinderella found true
happiness at last with her prince,
and the very next day
they were married,
and lived happily
ever afterwards.
The end.
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
That's lovely,
where did you get it?
It was a present.
Here.
No, I couldn't.
- I want you to have it.
Okay?
Okay, everybody, can
we start this meeting?
As you all know, Hunter
has brought us someone new,
and I think you've all had
a chance to meet Corlie.
Are there any questions?
- I've got a question.
About Hunter.
You said you went to his place.
Where is it?
- I don't know the area.
I was only there
for a few minutes.
I think we should
respect Hunter's privacy.
I've been there,
Corlie's been there.
I just don't see the point.
If it came down to him or
us, whose side would you be on?
That's out of order, Judd,
it will never come to that.
Now, all those in favor
of taking Corlie in.
Fine.
It's unanimous.
Welcome to Clearwater, Corlie.
- Thank you.
I promise, I'll work very hard.
Nice to meet you.
Good to have
you with us, well done.
Thank you very much, thank you.
Hi, Corlie.
- Hello.
How're you feeling?
Very well.
Say, would you like
to take a walk tonight?
Maybe.
It's just that
there's a full moon.
We could take a
walk up the canyon,
and watch it rise
through the Devil Peaks.
Well, if I'm not too tired.
Maybe.
Okay, great, I'll see you later.
You shouldn't discourage him.
It doesn't look like the
discourages too easily.
How are your hands now?
They're still a little sore.
Where you came from,
didn't you do any work?
Not this kind of work.
So how did you live?
Differently.
Charlene, I...
Corlie?
Corlie, what's wrong?
There you go.
Everyone back to the village!
It's just a stranger,
it's probably nothing.
But it doesn't
hurt to be careful.
Do you know what this is?
- Leave her alone, Judd.
I said, do you know who this is?
Look at her, she
recognized it right off!
Judd, forget it!
Come on, Corlie.
Come on!
Everyone back!
Run, Corlie!
Come on, we're nearly there.
Alvin!
Let me go!
You don't understand
what's coming.
Let go of me!
- You'll be safe in here.
It's not gonna stop!
Stop firing.
Or I will completely
destroy this village.
Corlie, stop,
they'll just shoot you!
Come out.
Come outside where I can see you.
Everyone throw down your weapons,
and put your hands on your head.
Move.
Good morning, my name
is Colonel Straker,
and I have come to free you
from this anarchy and chaos.
Under my leadership,
you will relearn the arts of
discipline and excellence.
Nothing less will be acceptable.
So, you can plant your taters and
you can grow your sweetcorn,
but you will do this
at the direction of,
and for the purposes
of your leader.
This ain't no democracy, kiddies.
Who's in charge here?
Hey, wait a minute,
you can't come in...
Who's in charge here?
We all were.
Kind of a democracy.
Bone.
Sir.
Detail the men to
inventory and requisition.
Yes, sir.
Hey, Willie.
Inventory and requisition.
Loot, loot!
I'm taking your weapons,
ammunition, medicine.
Any furs, precious metals.
A sewing machine if you
have one and half your food.
We're gonna
need that for the winter!
Don't mumble when
the man's talking.
I will not abide disrespect.
By the way.
Where do you keep the women?
In the dome behind you.
Charlene, it's me, Judd!
You better open up, we
haven't got much choice!
Get in!
Please let the children go.
Stand up!
You.
- Sir?
Take the children to
a different building.
Yes, sir.
Wait.
Just a minute.
Where did you get this?
- Corlie.
I'll keep it safe for now.
Willie!
- Coming, Boss!
Yessum, Boss?
- Take the women now.
All of 'em?
Well now, ladies.
Shall we join the, gentlemen?
The gentlemen!
Have you been
harboring a girl named...
Corlie, yeah, we tried to
kick her out, but
everybody here's afraid of
the guy that brought her here.
Where is she?
Well, if she isn't here,
she must've run back to him.
That guy, Hunter.
How do I find this Hunter?
He's up in the
mountains somewhere.
No, Bone, easy.
Thanks.
I'll tell you who knows.
Rusty.
He and Hunter are as thick
as, they're good buddies.
I must have a talk
with this Rusty.
Bone?
Are you alright?
What happened?
Are you hurt?
No, yeah, I mean...
They'll kill them, they will!
Who?
The people you saved me
from, they're at Clearwater!
Hey, get control of yourself.
No, you don't understand!
- I think I'm beginning to.
No, I'm one of them!
Did you warn the
people at Clearwater?
What good would that've done?
Nobody can stand up against 'em.
There's always a
way to fight back.
Anybody follow you here?
- No.
Okay, come on, you
stay here tonight.
In the mornin', I'll go
out and scout around.
See what they're up to.
Get some rest, you're exhausted.
It's alright.
Why do men have to fight?
It's always been
about who gets more.
It has to change.
It's been that way
for thousands of years.
But it must change.
Good morning.
- Shh!
Get dressed.
- What's the matter?
We've got half a
minute to save our ass.
You know how to use this?
- Yeah.
Use it when the time
comes, I'll be back.
Hunter, this is Straker.
Send the girl out and
you will not be harmed.
Go!
Hi, boys.
Come on, get dressed!
- I'm ready!
Get on the bike.
- Okay!
Come on!
Hang on!
Don't shoot, you'll hit the girl.
Bone!
Yes, sir!
That sucker isn't
gonna live here anymore.
Get in.
Clear the area.
Faster!
Throw this.
Try again.
I got him!
Throw it by that tree!
He always leaves
a garrison behind.
Yeah, he's a real pro.
What'd you do to this?
I looked through them.
That'll teach me not to
loan out my binoculars.
Get off your ass and
help these people, come on.
Move, move!
Where's he sleep?
Locked up inside the truck.
If he didn't, he'd get a
knife through his ribs.
Okay, I've seen enough, let's go.
Why didn't you tell us the truth?
I couldn't.
Five good men
died because of you.
Maybe Straker'll go
easy on us if we send her back!
That's it, we'll send her back.
You're not sending
anybody anywhere.
We can't sacrifice the whole
community for one person.
He would have come here anyway,
but if you don't want
me here, I'll go.
Wait a minute, you're
not goin' anywhere.
You people better make up your
minds what you're gonna do.
I know what I'm gonna do.
I thought they'd killed you.
Well, we got a
couple of them instead.
I told 'em where to find you.
I know, you were
the only one who knew.
They, they took
my hand and put...
I just wanted the pain to stop.
Forget it, Rusty, I know torture.
Nobody holds out.
You could've.
- No.
I'd have done the
same thing you did.
Maybe, maybe not.
No blame, understand?
No blame.
I'm gonna need your help,
you're gonna have to make me
some kind of
light-armored vehicle.
Can you still make explosives?
Yeah, sure.
Yeah, I got some sulfuric left,
and I can make a
still for the nitric.
My hand.
Use mine.
I've been watchin' real close,
I can do all your stuff.
You always said I
have good hands.
Alright.
Alright!
Follow me.
We'll take this
manifold into the shop.
Corlie, grab a hold of this.
Here, take this spring too.
Come on, Hunter, grab
that spring, let's go!
I think I've got
some bulletproof glass
around here somewhere.
Hunter.
I've been thinkin'.
- Yeah?
You're right, we've gotta fight.
I'd like to help you,
if you'll have me.
There's plenty to do.
We've been right
through that area.
Nobody's been in there for years.
Motorcycles don't
grow wings and fly away.
I want you to find him.
Hey, Boss!
I caught these dirt-eaters
tryin' to sneak up on us.
What're you boys up to?
We live around
here, what's it to ya?
Well, that's fair enough.
Shoot 'em!
He's only jokin' ya.
Go on home.
What a mess.
That son of a bitch!
Be sure it's not damp.
- It's not damp.
I hope you're right.
Those firing pins are
pretty unpredictable.
I got it.
Did you get the...
I didn't knock
in case you were asleep.
I hope I didn't frighten you.
No, it's just that I
thought you were Hunter.
He should be back any minute.
Yeah, he's been
workin' like a dog.
We all have.
Would you like a cup of tea?
- No, thanks.
I came to apologize.
I'm ashamed about
the way I acted.
Do you forgive me?
I suppose so.
Hey, maybe I will
have that cup of tea.
You know, I used to have
such a different life.
We all did, before
it all fell apart.
If I'd only met you then,
we might've really had somethin'.
Yeah, hee-yah, hee-yah!
More water, get
some more water, somebody!
Alvin!
- Corlie's in there.
Corlie!
- No, no, Alvin, no!
We've gotta get her out!
- Corlie's not in there!
She was kidnapped by Judd.
Bastard!
- Come on, save the barn!
Give me that!
Where's Corlie?
- Don't worry, she's alive.
Judd took her in the truck board.
How long ago?
- Hours.
Yee-come on!
Yee!
We have unfinished
to take care of.
I guess that's the
last we'll of him.
Hee-yah!
Giddup!
Get out.
- Hey, take it easy.
I've come to see Straker.
- Yeah?
I've got a little surprise.
Open the gate.
Hee-yah, come on!
Morning, sir.
- News from Clearwater.
So what does my little
bird have to tell me today?
I thought you'd like
to know Hunter is dead.
Is that right?
So?
Well, he tried to stop me
when I was bringing
you a little gift.
Sir.
Bone, take her to my quarters.
Hell, why don't
you just let her go?
She's more trouble than...
Yes, sir.
Sorry, sir.
You know, you're a very
clever fellow, you know that?
I'm awfully tired
of smelling manure.
Well, I can understand that.
You know, my mind
is wasted on those people.
Let's go in here.
I'm wanna tell ya,
I have some plans.
Some great plans.
Why have you done this for me?
- I knew you'd appreciate it.
How'd you get
the scratches on your face?
She resisted!
How dare you touch her.
If you ever so much as even
think you're gonna look at her,
I'm gonna cut you in little
pieces and feed you to yourself.
Do you hear me?
- I promise, I promise.
Let go of me!
So...
You wanna join my little band?
Welcome to the club.
Right here, it's
right here, slow down.
Right down there,
right down there.
I know I hit him, I saw
him fall right there.
Nothin' there now, mate.
Do I kill him, Boss?
He rolled all the
way down that hill.
He was dead, I'm tellin' ya!
- Come on, handsome.
Hey, Hunter's back!
Hunter's come back!
Quick, carry him inside.
Judd did this?
- Yeah.
It's lodged.
- Yeah, I know.
Hang on.
It's a septic wound, isn't
there any alcohol left?
No, they took it all,
and the sulfur powder.
All we've got left
is creek water.
You might fight off the
infection in a week or two, but...
No, I've gotta be
on my feet tomorrow.
They'll be after
me, might come here.
I can cure arthritis and boils,
but this is a deep septic wound.
Cauterize it.
Maybe it'll heal all by itself.
No, Alvin, he's right.
Are you ready?
Thanks.
I'll never stay with you.
You can't own me.
Kill me or let me go.
Your beauty is from your mother,
but your fire and your
passion, those are from me.
I can't stay with
you, you know that.
No, I don't.
Hunter will kill you.
Don't be a child.
I wish I could kill you.
We love to kill, so
we kill what we love.
Is that it?
No.
Or are we mirror
images, you and I?
My blood.
My inheritor.
My immortality.
I don't know anymore.
I believe you
lost this, princess.
How do you feel this morning?
When will it be ready to roll?
Well, we need some
time for some tests...
How soon before the engine runs?
A couple hours at least.
Just get it
running, I'll test it.
Hunter.
Are you crazy, you've lost
a lot of blood, you know?
Just get that
engine runnin', okay?
And the automatic choker's
shot, so I put in a manual one.
But the methane
heats up pretty quick.
Now, the tack's not calibrated,
so do your RPMs by ear.
I know how to drive, just
be there when I need you.
We'll be here!
Don't you worry about us, you
just make sure you're there!
I hope it holds together.
Bye, Hunter!
What the hell was that?
Hey, you, shoot it!
I'm off!
Bone, Bo!
Shit, what's goin' on?
The truck, Willie, get
up, come on that truck!
Where's Straker?
Look out!
Bone!
Get the gun crewed, wind
her up, we're rollin'.
Where are we goin'?
- I'm gonna kill him!
Willie!
- Yeah, Boss?
Get in the truck,
we're goin', Willie.
Faster, I want more.
She's doing all she can.
- I said more!
She's not gonna make
it, I'm not gonna let you
do it to her, you're not
gonna wreck my truck.
It's not your truck, dumb-ass,
you're just the driver.
I think he's right, Boss, I
think he's right, I'm scared.
Not now, Willie.
- The truck might blow.
Not now!
Come on, Bone, come on!
- I can't push her anymore!
She's coming up to overheat now.
I never had a chance to
pull that service on her.
Shut up and drive.
- I know, Boss, I know.
If we go back... Shut up, Willie!
But if we go back and
go round the other...
Knock it off, jelly belly,
I got a gut full of you!
Now, shut up, do you understand?
Drive!
Rusty!
He fell for it, meet you on top!
She's overheating, we
gotta pull the turbines.
Keep rolling.
- He'll come back for me.
And he'll beat you
because he's better.
Over my dead body.
Now for the rocket launcher.
- Your wound's open.
Hurry up, it's comin'!
I got that, get
that other rocket.
Shit!
Reload.
Where is he?
Do something!
- Shut up.
Do something.
- Get off, get off!
Put that fire out.
They've just blown the roof.
Keep going.
You're running away.
- Don't be stupid.
We're going to
flatten Clearwater.
Help me on with this.
- You can't, you're too weak.
What're you gonna on a
bike against that truck?
Whatever it takes.
He's taking the turnoff.
I guess that's the
end of Clearwater.
Good luck.
I'm not gonna let
that bastard run my truck.
No, it's my truck, Straker!
You drive.
Drive!
Keep it on the road.
I saved you, Boss, didn't I?
I saved...
Your time is over, old man.
Not yet, kid.
Kill him!
Hunter, kill him!
"Old man,"
I'll show you.
No!
Daddy, would you stop it!
Stop it!
Let's get outta here.
Now!
I'll kill you!
Goodbye, my friend.
Thanks.
Look after yourself.
I really thought you'd stay.
I'll be back.
When?
Sometime.