[clock ticking]
[typing]
[man] We are going through
the most profound change
in communication technologies
in all of human history
right now.
[chattering]
Printing press,
radio, telegraph, television.
All very important.
But I believe we're going
through the most transformative,
purely on the basis
of three technologies.
Mobile, social media
and cloud computing.
They share one
very important characteristic.
And that's the amount
of private information.
Information that used to
be in our desktops
or filing cabinets,
even in our heads,
that we now
entrust to third parties.
[whirring]
Data that we are conscious of,
and deliberate about,
like the e-mails we send
and the tweets we post.
But it also includes
a lot of information
that we're completely,
or mostly, unconscious about.
So if you take my mobile phone,
even when I'm not using it,
it's emitting a pulse,
trying to locate
the nearest Wi-Fi router
or cell phone exchange,
and within that beacon is
the make and model of the phone,
the fact that it's my phone,
because my name is attached
to the operating system,
and most importantly,
the geolocation of the phone.
[drone humming]
[man speaking Portuguese]
[Deibert continues]
We are leaving
this digital exhaust
that contains
extraordinarily precise
information about our lives,
our social relationships
reduced to
trillions of data points
that form now
this new ethereal layer
around the planet
that's only growing
in all directions.
[ticking]
Capabilities are being put
in the hands of policy makers,
five years ago,
they'd never imagine
that they would have.
This is where big
data meets Big Brother.
[ticking]
[buzzing]
-[folk music]
-[chuckles]
[man with accent]
Should be here.
[American man]
It is kind of in a rock,
I think.
[American man #2]
Yeah, the entrance is in a rock.
-[speaking over each other]
-Or a bunker.
Oh, yeah, the bunker.
It is down there!
[driver]
There is a bunker
under here.
-[man] Yeah.
-It is between 33 and 39.
[Deibert] Right there.
Look at that door.
[driver] Yeah.[Deibert] Yeah, this is it.
Bahnhof.[driver] Okay.
[beeps]
[door squeaks]Hey, I guess we just go in.
[electronica music]
[servers whirring]
[electronica continues]
What's your favorite
part of the building?
I think it's here.
I mean, I love it.
Yeah.[loud whirring]
All the energy down here.
The noise and stuff
like that.
It's kind of a...It's like being in a hive.
Yeah.Yeah, exactly.
Many people believe that
you have this cloud services
that are floating around.
People think, "Okay,
it's a cloud server."
But this is
the actual physical location
of the Internet.
[whirring, clicking]
[Karlung continues]
It's a constant struggle
to protect data.
[voices echo]
The Swedish Security Police
wanted to install tools
to automatically
log in to our data
and get out the information.
So I invited them
to our facility,
and then I had a microphone
which I was provided
by the Swedish Public Service,
national radio.
[speaking Swedish]
I taped this conversation,
and they were so angry.
And they also wanted us
to sign a paper
where they said that
we could not say
anything about it.
It should be total secrecy.
They said,
"If a terrorist attack happens,
it's your fault."
[click, buzz]
[man speaks Swedish]
[Karlung]
It's, like, a creepy feeling.
Nobody can say that
any facility is safe.
There are always possibilities
to go in and find data
and take it out.
People say that,
"Oh, I don't have
anything to hide.
They can read my mail.
I don't have anything."
But it's not that
which is this problem.
The problem is, without secrecy,
there can be no democracy.
Without secrecy,
there can be no market economy.
Right.
There is an obvious candidate
for the Nobel Peace Prize.
Really?And that is Edward Snowden.
I mean, yeah.
Does the public enjoy
the same right to privacy
that we have in the past?
Are we still private citizens,
and then public officials,
where the government knows
very little about us,
but we know
everything about them?
Why are we, the public,
becoming disempowered
at the same time
that governments
around the world,
corporations around the world,
institutions around the world,
are gaining greater
and greater leverage over
the range of our activities,
their knowledge of what we do?
[Deibert] The Citizen Lab
is an unusual place.
[cell phones ringing]
We're a research unit
at the University of Toronto.
We combine the skills
of engineers,
computer scientists
with social scientists.
We collaborate with people
from all over the world
to do the field research
that we do.
And we do this
to advance research
on global security,
cyberspace
and human rights.
The world is
a very dangerous place
as we saw recently in...
in tragic incidents
in Paris,
and you want to
have security agencies
be well adept at discerning
what those threats
are over our horizon.
But is it okay
that the government sets up
a giant digital X-ray machine
over everything that we do?
Because that's effectively
where we're headed right now.
[typing]
[continues]
We've been a kind of
digital early warning system,
scanning the horizon.
And what we've seen, frankly,
has been really disturbing.
[digital chirping]
[typing]
[praying, chanting]
[chanting in Tibetan]
[man, in Tibetan]
It was around 4:30.
We had just finished praying.
Sixty or 70 police arrived along
with 300 or 400 soldiers.
They forced their
way into the monastery.
[chimes playing]
[Golog, in Tibetan]
They started ransacking
the monastery.
All the monks were asking,
"Why are they here?
What are they doing here?"
Everyone was nervous.
I had a sinking feeling.
One of the monastery's artists
was arguing with the police,
and I tried to intercede.
Suddenly my phone rang,
so I quickly switched it off.
I switched off my phone.
We could hear the police outside
talking in Chinese
on walkie-talkies.
Then the police searching inside
were called out.
I could see one of them
looking closely at a photo.
But I couldn't see
if it was a photo of me or not.
Then they came back in
and pointed a gun
to each of our heads,
and we were told to put
our phones down on the ground
in front of them...
as they kept us all at gunpoint.
So I switched my phone back on
and put it down
in front of them.
[vibrates]
Just after I switched it
back on, my phone rang.
The police asked, "Whose phone
is this?" I said, "It's mine."
-[shouts]
-[blows landing]
They started beating me
with their rifles,
striking me with the points
and the butts of their guns.
-[shouting in Tibetan]
-[blows landing]
Then a bunch of them grabbed me,
and dragged me away.
[beating continues]
[stops]
[Golog]
They had complete records
of all our phone conversations.
They knew everything.
[vehicle horns honking]
[woman, in English]
Tibetans are watched from every
angle and from every corner.
It's in their homes,
it's in their offices,
it's in the streets.
In Tibet,
certainly in central Tibet
and around
the capital city of Lhasa,
Chinese authorities,
together with
Chinese corporations,
telecommunications companies,
they've integrated
the ability to spy on people
via their mobile phone,
via the last communications they
may have had over the Internet.
Down to the closed circuit
television camera
on the streets.
The Chinese so strictly
control access to Tibet,
it's just like a black hole
for media,
for independent observers,
for international agencies,
for anything.
[Golog, in Tibetan]
Ever since I started being
politically active,
I never gave a thought
to my own security.
I just see it
as a responsibility
that comes with being Tibetan.
[woman speaks in Tibetan]
[Golog]
How I escaped is a secret.
[light music]
[Tethong]
People
are incredibly courageous.
People inside Tibet will
send out news and information.
And they'll say,
"I want this story to be told."
They could be imprisoned.
They could be tortured.
Their family
could pay the price.
[music continues]
We on the outside have to decide
how to walk this very,
sort of, fine line between
protecting people's security
and honoring their wishes
about getting news
and information out.
And we know for a fact,
thanks to Citizen Lab's report,
that we are being
successfully targeted.
[music stops]
A new report has been released
from a group
of digital detectives.
From their computers in Toronto,
they've tracked
a high-tech spy ring
that reaches around the world.
[typewriter clicks]
[reporter] For the past ten months,
these computer experts have been working as cyber sleuths
hot on the trail of a massive electronic spy network.
They say it has taken control of nearly 1,300 high-level computers
in more than 100 countries.
A discovery that could have major political implications.
They can extract any
document they wanted.
They could turn on web cameras,
turn on audio devices,
so that they could,
in effect, use the computers
as a listening device
in the offices.
[reporter] The web of intrigue started with the Dalai Lama
who thought his computer had been hacked.
Up until about 2007 or 2008,
I'd never really heard
of malware.
You know, I'd heard
of viruses, obviously,
but I hadn't really heard
about targeted malware attacks
affecting
the human rights community.
[clicking]
First time I heard about it was
in the context of the Tibetans.
Gradually
we started piecing together,
they are under surveillance.
The surveillance comes
from groups within China.
They're using malicious software
and socially-engineered e-mails.
E-mails that are crafted
to get them to open it up
to get inside their devices.
[reporter] Nart Villeneuve, a computer wiz,
figured out how the operation worked
by getting the attackers to hack into his computer.
We're monitoring these groups
for long periods of time,
and you're essentially waiting
for them to screw up, right?
And when they do,
you take advantage of that.
Sometimes it takes a long time.
You could be monitoring a group
for a year and get nothing.
Then one day,
they just use a server
that they don't lock down
and all the data's
just sitting there.
I was at home.
It was pretty late.
[typing]
[Deibert]
Nart was scouring through it,
trying to figure out
what actor is responsible
for getting inside
the Dalai Lama's office.
And there was
a 22 or 24 character string
that kept coming up
that he couldn't figure out,
"What is the meaning of this?"
So on a whim, he just copied
and pasted it into Google.
One website came up,
and it was Chinese characters.
So he clicked on it.
[mouse clicks]
To my surprise,
what came back
was the actual page
that the attackers used
to interface
with the compromised systems.
So they set up a website
where they could monitor
their victims.
But they didn't
password protect it!
So it was like a window
into everything they were doing.
[electronic music]
[Nart]
This wasn't just targeted
at Tibetan organizations
or human rights organizations.
This was global,
a pretty wide range
of institutions
that showed that
these attackers were...
were quite busy.
There was huge pickup
in the media.
It was all over the world.
And it put us on
a different kind of footing
in terms of our credibility.
In the cyber security community,
we were novices at that time.
We were kind of outsiders.
[no audible dialogue]
So we were kind of
calling it on the fly.
Like, what do we do?
What's the right thing to do?
Who do we notify?
I knew that publishing it
was important.
We had to redact
a lot of the information
to protect people.
Should we notify the government?
Should we notify
the Canadian government?
How do we notify
other governments
that are being victimized?
At the time, you know,
we didn't want
to completely disclose
everything that we had done,
because we
wanted to do it again.
[Deibert]
In some of the communities
I mentioned, they loved it.
But I got the feeling from,
certainly inside
my own government,
there was a lot of weirdness.
[interviewer]
Are we allowed to speculate?Well, I think now we know
because there's
a Snowden disclosure that
explicitly references the fact
that the Canadians
and the Americans,
our signal's
intelligence agencies,
were piggybacking
off the GhostNet network.
So, in publishing the report,
we basically broke up
their party.
From our initial samples from
the office of the Dalai Lama,
they were actually compromised
by two distinct groups.
The GhostNet group obviously
got the most attention.
But there was another group
that was also active.
The GhostNet group
shut down their operations,
but the other group, um,
they're still going.
[birds tweeting]
[Tibetan horns]
[chattering]
[horns continue]
[gong rings]
[chanting in
Tibetan through megaphone]
The vast majority of Tibetans
inside of Tibet use WeChat.
But it's both
a blessing and a curse.
[woman speaking Tibetan]
[Golog]
QQ is Chinese-made.
WeChat is Chinese-made.
All these social media apps
come from China.
If someone in Lhasa
or Nagchu were to post a photo
of His Holiness on WeChat,
they would be caught
immediately.
In our research,
what we see are acts of war
that take place
against citizens,
using these very technologies.
Getting inside
the computers of Tibetans
and then arresting them,
and possibly executing them,
is a kind of act of war.
[speaking Tibetan]
[Deibert]
We see this sort of thing
every week, right?
Minor to major versions of it.
Everything on the site
is correct except this.
So this... The last log-in on
the C panel was from Korea.
Mm-hmm.Do you guys have any work
in Korea?
Is there any...No, no...
So who actually accesses
the website to update it
and all that sort of thing?
It must be
someone unauthorized.Yeah.
[bell ringing]
[ringing rapidly]
[stops]
[chanting]
[speaking Tibetan]
For me, Tibet is a memory.
It's like a reoccurring dream.
This photo is full of memories.
If I close my eyes,
I can see it all vividly.
This is the hall where
we prayed and made offerings.
On this side are
all of my classmates.
This is one of my best friends.
[in English] One, two, three,
four, five, six,
seven.
[in Tibetan]
I use these different phones to
contact Tibetans inside Tibet.
I don't use my personal phone.
I'm constantly switching
the number that I use.
If you call too many times
from the same number,
it will get blacklisted.
Then, when they catch you using
a blacklisted number,
they'll investigate.
Who's calling?
And who are they calling to?
Since 2008, I've kept contacts
in Tibet so I can find out
what's happening there.
Most of the news I receive
regards peoples' suffering.
For example,
people being killed,
arrested, disappearing.
Children being separated
from their parents.
When the parents of
a child are arrested,
often the children are left
with no one to care for them.
[Tibetan horn]
[horn continues]
When somebody self-immolates,
communicating
is even more dangerous.
Even though it makes me uneasy,
I have to ask for details.
If I don't get
the whole story out,
it's a great loss.
[horn resumes]
This video was received by
a friend of mine through WeChat.
[screaming]
[shout][gunshot]
[screaming continues]
[man shouts]
[stops]
[indistinct]Hmm.
This video was aired
by BBC and Al Jazeera.
A lot of news agencies aired it.
It's only a few seconds,
but it proves that
many of the things we've been
reporting are a reality.
And now it's documented.
You can Google it
and find photos.
It's everywhere.
There's no risk of losing it.
[typing]
[talking, quiet]
Not that long ago,
the government of Pakistan
put out this tender
for proposals for a nationwide
Internet filtering system.
They wanted to solicit proposals
from companies to build,
effectively,
the Great Firewall of Pakistan.
Today if you visit Pakistan
and you get online
and you try to access YouTube,
this is what you'll see,
a blocked page like this.
I'm in Islamabad,
putting in a SIM card.
First and foremost,
I'm really excited
to see Shahzad.
I first met Shahzad and
the organization Bytes for All,
eight years ago, I think?
And he's been involved,
in one way or another,
in Citizen Lab research
ever since.
[mouse clicks]
[chattering]
-Hi, Shahzad.
-Hello!
So great to see you.Here we are.
Here we are.
[both chuckling]
[Deibert]
Bytes for All does what they do,
fight for Internet rights
and advocacy-based
approach to Internet freedom
under extreme duress.
So they're operating
in a country that,
specifically around media
and free expression,
has got to be one of
the worst places in the world.
Uh, journalists are
routinely kidnapped, murdered,
uh, offices firebombed,
et cetera,
and they've experienced
all of that.
Death threats,
staff members kidnapped,
his own son beat up and
thrown to the side of the road
as a warning to Shahzad
not to do what he's doing.
In my opinion,
Internet has opened up
so many opportunities...
for the people to express,
and that is the sole reason
that we are fighting
for open Internet.
They lost their public spaces.
They lost their ability
to go out freely.
So, as they are putting controls
and curbs on physical spaces,
they are doing exactly the same
in online spaces as well.
So precisely the reason
we are standing out there
to reclaim those spaces.
And we have to at some point,
and we'll continue to do that.
Oh, my God. [sighs]
The government has the ability
to ban specific pages.
[speaking foreign language]
[in English]
You ban all of Facebook,
businesses are suffering,
people communicate.
I mean, you can
laugh and joke and say,
"For a few days people
won't play FarmVille,"
but it's not about that.
It's about your fundamental
rights being snatched from you
and no government,
in my opinion, should have
the ability to do that.
[woman] Right.
Not only that, they banned
Wikipedia for a little while.
-Yes, mm-hmm.
-YouTube.
Uh, about several thousand
websites were affected.
I think the Internet is
this vast, unregulated,
wonderful, democratizing space
and no matter what anyone does,
people will find a way.
[sitar music]
[typing]
[music continues]
Hi, I'm Sabeen Mahmud,
and I'm the director
of Peace Nation,
a non-profit organization.
I've always believed
that technology is
always the driver of change,
not business, not government,
but technology.
And gender-based violence
has always existed
but with the advent
of the Internet and the number
of social networking tools,
I think it's
a great mobilization platform.
[mouse clicks]
[sitar music]
[anchor] Sabeen Mahmud
was leaving a Karachi restaurant
when the gunman
attacked her in her car.
Her mother who was also
accompanying her was wounded
and now is in a critical
condition.
Mahmud was taken to a hospital
where she was pronounced dead.
[sitar music continues]
[inaudible]
When she spoke
in physical spaces,
nothing happened.
When she was
carrying on her campaign,
she was not targeted.
People were amused or they
ignored her,
or they just walked past.
But when this whole, sort of,
campaign
hit the Internet
and the social media,
that's when
the lynch mobs gathered.
And one of
the reasons I find is,
that speech
in a physical space lasts
only as long as you're speaking.
But once it is uploaded onto
the Internet on any platform,
it is there forever.
And then your attackers or
you know, whoever opposes you,
they gather,
and then they spread it further
and more and more
people join that group
of people who are attacking and
it takes on a life of its own.
[chattering]
[Deibert] We're going through
a demographic revolution.
The center of gravity
of cyberspace is shifting
right before our eyes.
From the north
and the west of the planet,
where it was invented,
to the South and the East.
The vast majority of Internet
users today and into the future
are coming
from the developing world,
for whom these technologies
are empowering.
What should we expect then from
these next billion digital users
as they come online
in the post-Snowden era?
[inaudible]
-[cheering]
-[horns blowing]
[siren wails]
[shouting in Portuguese]
[screaming]
[cheering]
[man on PA]
[shouting in Portuguese]
[in Portuguese]
This is a Midia Ninja
transmission.
Midia Ninja
will cover the World Cup
and the protests in the streets,
and we'll bring you interviews
with people we encounter.
I'm sure that FIFA
has been bad for Rio de Janeiro.
There's no education,
no public health,
and people are dying
at hospital doors.
For 250,000 families
who were displaced,
there is no World Cup.
For 190,000 without electricity,
[shouting]
TwitCasting, live transmission,
enables us to communicate
in real time
in a very honest way with people
who are following the events
from their computer.
Midia Ninja emerged
from this new "digital culture."
YouTube and other
social media networks
facilitate a shift to,
"We are the media.
The media is us."
[speaking Portuguese]
[in English] Once we started
with Midia Ninja,
and we went to the streets
and tried to do live streaming.
There was a mobile station
with an electric generator
using gasoline, you know,
a 4G modem, a laptop,
a camera, a video switcher and--
-[imitating vibrating machine]
-[synthesized music]
It was impossible to
push a 100-pound cart
with a potential bomb
between your knees.
[Silva] It was good
in the first two or three times
in more calm demonstrations.
I remember
there was a discussion,
and then Carioca said,
"No, I found an app.
Its name is TwitCasting
and maybe we can try it."
[electropop]
It was a Japanese free app
used by teenagers to hang out,
you know.
[in Portuguese]
It was a low-quality image,
but it could be transmitted
nonstop.
That's why TwitCasting
was perfect.
[chanting][speaks Portuguese]
It's a very delicate moment here
in the Saens Peña square.
People being prohibited
from walking to
or to leave the square.
This image we are seeing here,
a corridor of police
encircling the protest.
[singing in Portuguese][indistinct]
Looking at Brazil,
this is one of those cases
where you have
a sporting event, in this case,
which triggers all sorts of
extra concern around security
and the control of information,
much of it legitimate.
But what often happens is that
the layering of surveillance,
extra-legal measures that
happens leading up to
and during these events
doesn't just disappear.
It becomes part of
the permanent architecture.
[chanting in Portuguese]
Can you tell me
what this is?
No, I can't.Why not?
It transmits live video
to the central command.
That's all I know
about this equipment.
[chanting in Portuguese]
[Deibert]
Mobile phones are prevalent.
Everyone has one in their hands.
And the police
now use a technique
where they set up fake
cell phone towers that captures
everyone within the vicinity
and gathers up
identifying information that's
emitted by the cell phones,
which they then
use to track people
and associate them
with each other
and being at specific
physical events like a protest
and the government
can go back in time
and recreate
every facet of your life
on that particular day and hour.
With whom
you were communicating.
Not only
what you're broadcasting
but what you're saying privately
and use this to incriminate you
down the road.
[in Portuguese]
Nineteen people accused
of planning acts of vandalism
were arrested today in Rio.
[woman] It was just dawn
when 30 police left to serve search and seizure warrants in Rio.
They confiscated computers, cell phones,
gas masks and one piece of wood with nails and other objects.
Inside the police station here,
there's a new operational unit,
which is
the Internet Crimes Unit.
They attempt to transform
our youth, who want to see
a different country,
into a gang
of marginalized criminals.
Surveillance of the Internet,
mobile phones,
manipulation of evidence.
They are monitored,
phone-tapped and followed.
Including the Ninjas.
You can be sure their phones
are all tapped.
That includes us as well.
This surveillance,
this espionage,
this paranoia
that's been imposed.
People realize there's
some hidden mechanism of power
going on through surveillance.
And you begin to suspect, maybe,
this device you can't trust.
Maybe the state's in here
or it's in my mobile phone or...
And as that kind of
seeps out there,
people become much more
unwilling to take risks.
You know, even in our own work,
we're much more cautious
about what we say over e-mail,
worried that
somebody's listening and so on.
It's like sand in the machinery.
It kind of slows things down
and everything becomes
much more complicated,
just to communicate
basic instructions.
You're like, "Oh,
first I have to encrypt it."
All these technologies too,
cryptography things,
they might be getting cheap,
but if we consider
in terms of time,
they are expensive.
You know,
people are being murdered
every day in the favelas.
The military police
are still running.
So it's complicated now
to stop the machines
and adapt our system
to a more safe mode.
[crowd booing]
[in Portuguese] These days
the media can police more
than the police themselves...
by reproducing this idea
of the protester as enemy.
The truth is tough to swallow!
Globo supported
the dictatorship!
[Bentes] History of O Globo,
started during
the military dictatorship,
it was the media arm
of the dictatorship,
and they think
they're as powerful
as the government.
We say if you hate the media,
then become the media.
♪ Oh, my, oh  I'll go for what you know♪
♪ Who I owe  Why own when you can just♪
♪ Sell it♪
[in Portuguese]
We've just had many bombs
explode.
There were many aggressions
we just witnessed,
many rubber bullets shot
one on top of the other.
As soon as the bomb exploded,
the arbitrariness commenced,
the physical aggressions
during searches.
No one is being aggressive.
No, you are talking smack!
-No one was
physically aggressive here!
-Let me report what I've seen.
You've already unleashed
such a shitload of violence.
And you're not going to
revoke my right
to free expression,
my right to do my job
as the free media,
the media activist that I am.
My name is Felipe Pecanha
if you want to know.
[man]
♪ Those gloves  Just take 'em off♪
♪ Move before  The city moves to us♪
There behind me, yet another
situation of pandemonium,
people screaming.
♪ To us, to us♪
[explosion]
-[horns playing]
-[helicopter flying over]
[shouting]
[shouting in Portuguese,
indistinct]
What are they doing downstairs?
I got beat up down there!
[woman] Open! Open!
What's happening
in there?They are beating up everyone.
Don't touch me!
Sit down!
Did they beat you?
Yes, a lot!
I was trying to protect myself.
The police have no shame.
No shame, committing
these savage acts.
Whoa, don't take me.
Whoa, brother.
What's going on?
They're arresting me!
They're kicking me!
They're crushing my phone!
What is this?
I was just attacked by
eight of you, ten of you,
big, armed men in uniform.
I didn't do anything wrong
to any of you!
I am transmitting live
on the Internet
with a cell phone.
This is not
any kind of violence.
This is not a crime.
This is a constitutional right
of the citizen.
The military police here in Rio
are a disgrace.
[crowd applauding]
[Deibert]
So at the same time
that you have so many people
able to communicate to
a global audience at an instant,
governments, in ways that
they weren't 20 years ago,
are really ramping up
information controls
because they see...
And when we say "governments,"
we're really talking about
entrenched powers,
institutionalized, uh, you know,
forms of capitalism in the state
that see, you know,
this type of
unpredictable citizen activism
as a threat to their interests
and are developing ways
to counter it.
[announcer] You have new challenges today.
Sensitive data is transmitted over encrypted channels.
You need more.
You want to look through your target's eyes.
You have to hack your target.
You have to overcome encryption and capture relevant data.
Being stealth and untraceable.
Exactly what we do.
The vendors of
these products and services
market them to governments,
usually at trade shows
that are only open
to accredited law enforcement
and intelligence agencies.
Actually, I've got
a big binder that I can...
So, if you ignore the bag,
actually which...
[chuckling]
...someone, uh, deposited
these in as a gift to me,
but I think
was hoping to disguise it
in the kindergarten bag.
These are brochures
from the type of trade shows
that we're talking about,
products and services that allow
cell phone detection,
uh, insertion of malware...
tracking,
social media monitoring.
In many ways, the way to
think about this market
is that it's
the commercialization
of cyber crime.
You trick somebody into
installing a software program
that contains malicious code
that exploits some vulnerability
in the system,
which then allows the attacker
to do anything they want.
Turn on the webcam,
listen in on the microphone,
record keystrokes,
record the location,
the movement.
It operates without
much accountability,
certainly no corporate
social responsibility,
ripe for abuse in a place
like Sudan or Ethiopia.
We've seen in one
case after another,
how this ends up being used
to target civil society.
Aha.
Gamma Group.
Maker of the notorious
FinFisher spyware.
[cars honking]
The whole history...
my personal history,
my family history
and my organization's history
is written with surveillance.
In Ethiopia,
there is only one server.
Every telecommunication
connection
passes through
the Ethiopian
telecommunications server.
And that server is
highly controlled.
When you talk to a friend,
you know that somebody
is hearing.
When you write an e-mail,
you suspect that somebody
might have read it
and that somebody
wants to hunt you down.
And when I came to the UK,
there was a total liberation
of that stress.
I felt,
"I am living in a free country
where the privacy of individuals
is respected
and my privacy is
also respected."
But I was wrong.
Sometime in 2013,
we started to find
some of the things that we
discussed among a small circle
in open media
and in unfriendly medias
of the Ethiopian government.
You don't want to
suspect your friend,
but you have to.
And we keep on wondering
how they could find out.
We got the answer
from a totally unexpected area.
A certain group of people
goes to Citizen Lab.
And they published a report.
And in that report
there was my photograph,
and they used it
to attach with the spyware
and distribute it
among the Ethiopian community.
The attacker has to socially
engineer or convince the target
to open a file or to,
you know, click through
some security warning,
um, in order to become infected.
We had found a document
that had pictures of Ethiopian
opposition leaders in it,
and it looked like
it was targeted
and designed to appeal
to members of
the Ethiopian diaspora.
Uh, but in fact,
the file was cleverly disguised
to look like a document
that's actually
a computer program,
an executable file.
So when you run this,
it will install software
on your computer
even though, you know, they
changed the icon and everything
to make it look like
this is a document
or a picture.
This is actually a program.
After that,
I just tried to scan...
people who were arrested
after my departure.
I had a friend in Saudi Arabia
who was sent back to Ethiopia,
and arrested and
sentenced to 18 years.
And I started to question,
probably it was because of me.
And he's not the only person.
I was able to look at the memory
of an infected computer.
In other words,
what's going on inside
the computer when it's infected.
And I was able to identify
several interesting artifacts
in the memory,
including a bunch of strings
that said "FinFisher," "FinSpy,"
very clearly attributing this
to the company.
Ethiopia is
one of the poorest countries
in the world.
Internet users in Ethiopia
are less than two percent.
It is the lowest in the world.
But they spend
millions of dollars
for FinFisher.
For spying on people like me,
who are trying to do...
to bring a better future
to Ethiopia.
You don't have to be the NSA to
get inside somebody's computer.
Um, instead you can
exploit their curiosity,
their, um, need to communicate.
And of course,
journalists, at the very heart
of what they do,
is engage in communication
with a lot of people
and a lot of people that
they don't know and trust
necessarily.
Because they're engaged
in outreach and communicating
constantly with sources.
[crowd shouting]
[cheering, whistling]
Fifty years ago,
nobody would have known
what happened in Syria.
But in 2011, when it started,
everybody had Facebook.
Everybody has e-mails
and everybody has WhatsApp
and Viber.
So you just can't stop people
from telling
what is happening to them.
So when they besieged Daraa
at the beginning,
they shut down communication,
Internet, land lines
and even electricity.
But they did not know that
in the 21st century,
people have their ways.
People were charging
their mobiles from their cars
or generators,
hand generators,
um, manual generators.
And people were using
satellite connections.
You don't need to use
the country, uh, Internet
to be connected to the Internet.
You can use anything.
And they were able to tell
what was happening to them.
Um, so the story got around.
[man speaking foreign language]
[sirens blaring]
A few years ago many of us
celebrated the Arab Spring
as the paradigm of what
these technologies could do.
Remember
we called it at the time
"liberation technology."
It would bring about the end
of authoritarian rule.
[man speaking Arabic]
Unfortunately,
Syria has become the
Arab Spring's dark aftermath.
[explosion]
[boy shouting in Arabic]
As groups
sympathetic to the Assad regime
have employed
off-the-shelf malware crime kits
to infiltrate social networks,
arrest, torture and
murder opposition groups
and even target
their air strikes.
[rifles cocking]
[shouting]
[gunshot]
[man] From the beginning,
we believed that the camera
is the most powerful weapon,
and it was actually
the only weapon we have
to deliver our own message
to the whole world.
This is interesting.
Baraa?
[speaking Arabic]
It's a pleasure for me
to introduce
one of my best friends,
Mr. Baraa,
he's one of the most activist
people inside Syria.
He came a few days ago
'cause he has...
He has... many broken
bones on his body.
[gunfire]
He was there and covered
the battle in Daraa City.
And in the afternoon,
they get a tank shell.
[explosion]
He was with his friend,
whom has this camera.
And that good guy, you know,
he gets killed
by one tank shell
from the regime's side.
[gunfire]
This video, you will see now,
a remote control car and
it exploded, a huge explosion.
It was filmed
by this camera.
[explosion]
After that,
the rocket launchers
started to hit the place
from the regime's side.
So our activist, this media guy,
he gets killed in here
in this exact... this place.
Now here.
He was standing here.
And people found
the camera with him.
We took out the memory card,
and we post this...
as, you know,
in memory of Hussain.
[wreckage clattering]
So now, Mr. Baraa here,
just a few days just to heal.
He paid a visit
to some hospitals
to check out himself,
then he will go back into Syria
to keep working.
There is a war on Facebook.
Uh, every side is using Facebook
to promote themselves.
They say on Facebook
that the army now controls
a certain area.
So the rebels all go to that
certain area. Even though
it's still rebel-controlled.
They start bombing it, even
though it's under their control.
Then they withdraw from it.
The other way around,
the regime will say,
"We will occupy this area.
We will take over this area."
Then the FSA would leave because
they're afraid of bombardment.
It's just a game.
Facebook is a game.
[Wjd]
It was just a silly joke I made.
I didn't hurt anybody.
I didn't insult anyone.
It was not political.
It was not racist.
There is nothing
that they could hold against me
with a thing that
I wrote on Facebook.
But still,
at a time of war...
people get crazy.
They did not drag me
in the street or kidnap me.
They just asked me to come
to ask me a few questions.
This is what they said,
so I signed the paper
that I'm coming.
I went
the next morning at 11:30,
to the detention center.
The security guy came to me.
He's like...
He's like half of my height.
He blindfolded me,
and I was like,
I was okay with that
because I thought, it's some...
it's confidential secrets
of the country
that they don't want me to see.
And then I was presented
to the detective
or the interrogator.
I never saw him.
He told me,
"You're a computer engineer.
Please be seated."
And I sat next to him
and he started reading
all my Facebook posts.
I was like, "Oh."
One of the posts
that I wrote was,
"No praying, no fasting
until the regime falls,"
which was actually
making fun of both sides.
And I laughed and he's like,
"I'm not kidding with you.
I'm not joking with you."
He kicked me on my chest
and then he requested
the same short guy,
because he was
there in the room,
to bring something called
the "flying carpet,"
which is a torturing machine.
It's a wooden board,
like the door,
but it has joints in the middle
that can flip.
And I had to lay on it.
They tied my wrists and
they tied me from the middle,
they tied my legs.
And they just closed it
so my knees touched my chest.
He took off my shoes
and my socks
and started beating me
with a metal,
uh, with a metal whip.
The pain is unbelievable.
You just can't take it anymore.
You just can't endure
this amount of agony.
What we saw in Syria
was a lot of use of, say,
off-the-shelf remote access
tools.
So this is sort of software
that you can get from
underground message boards
or maybe purchased
for not so much money.
Maybe $200-300 that
give you the ability
to record someone's keystrokes,
read their e-mails,
even look at them
through their webcam.
Record via
the computer's microphone,
conversations that are being had
around the target's computer.
Frequently what you would see
is it would be bundled
with some type of lured document
which showed
a deep understanding
of the psychology of the people
they were trying to target.
For instance, one of
the documents that was sent out
that I keenly recall
was a list.
A purported list
of insurgents identified
by the Syrian government.
So of course what happened was
that this was promptly passed
around
to all sorts of very
interesting groups in Syria
because everyone wanted to know
if they were on this list
or not.
So the actual spyware
payload itself wasn't
particularly sophisticated
but the social...
the social
and social engineering side
of that operation,
um, was quite smart.
Internet entered almost
all countries in the region
before it entered Syria.
Yes.
Government in Syria,
we are not as developed
as Canada, for example,
or not as developed
as United States.
In Canada
they can monitor people
and control people
and spy people in
a very intelligent way.
And even they don't
feel that they are...
spied on.
But in Syria,
of course you go to old ways.
They untie me and then I was...
and then he asked me to
sit next to him, and he said,
"Let's start talking."
And I told him,
"I don't want to
talk to you anymore."
He said, "I want you
to admit you work with the Free
Syrian Electronic Army."
I was like,
"I don't know what that is."
He said, "You like their page.
You like their page
on Facebook."
I told him,
"I like their page on Facebook,
but there are too many pages
on Facebook that you can like.
I also like Assad's page
on Facebook."
Well, that did not convince him.
So his boss came
and he told him,
"What is going on?"
He told him,
"This is the Facebook guy,
and he's not cooperating."
So then his boss told him to,
"Send him down to the basement,
peel his skin off and just
remind me of him after a month."
And I was like, "Can we go
back to the flying carpet?"
[chuckles]
I stayed there
for almost a month,
and then I was released
with a presidential amnesty.
So I went in a taxi,
covered with dust,
dirt, shit and blood,
all over my face,
my clothes.
And then the taxi driver
felt pity for me,
and he gave me a cigarette.
I remember
that was the first time I cried.
And I went to my flat in Latakia
where I used to study,
and my roommates
were shocked
to see me alive.
And then, like,
two weeks after that
I fled the country.
I came to Jordan.
I am a journalist now.
[man] With Syria,
a lot of the bad things
that are happening
are happening to people
who don't look
like Westerners.
The bad things happening to
these people through technology,
through the risks
inherent in technology,
are not different
than the kinds of risks
that we may face,
um, although they look
different.
We see in the news
almost every day,
a report of a breach,
some kind of a large hack.
Data being exploited somewhere.
It's the same problem,
but in Syria,
it looks very different
and because there are
dark skinned people,
uh, and there are guns
and a foreign language,
it feels, I think to many,
exotic and different,
and it couldn't happen here.
And I think, in fact,
what you're seeing in Syria
is this is what happens
when the risks get higher
but the technology is the same.
They're using the same Facebook
that we are.
[chattering]
[in Portuguese]
My name is Bruno,
for those who don't know me.
[man beat boxing]
I'd been attending protests
for a month,
a month full of protests.
It's good to have protection,
in case police repression
is very strong.
When the professor asked
the class what they thought,
people were
against the protestors.
I improvised a chest protector
with aluminum.
I said, "Whoa, you didn't
even go to the protests.
It's not like you describe it."
So I decided to make a video,
to document a protest
for those who didn't attend.
[chattering]
I'm arriving now
at Largo do Machado.
[woman shouting in Portuguese]
Lot's of different people here.
[singing in foreign language]
[shouting on microphone]
[man shouting in Portuguese]
They have shut down
all the lights
to intimidate the crowd,
but we're not going to leave.
Only when the people become one!
And not two peoples...
where the rich
use the poor against the poor.
Because we are strong!
We are not weak!
[upbeat intro]
♪ Satisfied♪
[gunshot]
[man singing]
[glass shattering]
[all shouting]
[screaming]
[sirens chirping]
[Teles] I hadn't done anything,
but police pursued me.
I'm a pacifist.
I don't like violence.
But I'll defend myself
if I have to. So I ran.
[woman speaking Portuguese]
What is this? This is surreal.
[singing continues]
[clapping rhythmically]
[singing continues, indistinct]
♪ Satisfied♪
[shouting]
[shouting in Portuguese]
-[shouting]
-[shutters clicking]
[news intro]
[in Portuguese]
The protest took place
outside
the governor's palace.
It started peacefully
but ended in confrontation.
[man] A battle began. On one side, rocks being thrown,
on the other side, rubber bullets.
The masked bandits threw Molotov cocktails at the police.
One policeman was hit by the fire.
The military police found a bag with Molotov cocktails.
-[police officer]
You should film this.
-[reporter] What is it?
Molotov cocktails.
These kill cops.
[shouting]
He threw the first
Molotov cocktail! He threw
the first Molotov cocktail!
I wasn't even there!
I wasn't carrying a backpack.
Someone attacked me.
Don't say anything else,
my friend.
[sirens wailing]
[shouting]
[in English]
Lots of people were there,
by 7:00 in the night,
and we were live.
[Carioca] We are here
transmitting live to 5,000
viewers with a mobile phone.
[Silva]
Suddenly a man came to Carioca,
and he asked to interview him.
[Carioca]
Whoa! Can I speak here?
What is this?
[Silva] And then
the military police came
to Carioca, searched his bag.
And then they said
he should be taken to jail
as a preventive arrestment,
to be searched and inquired.
[Carioca]
They're taking me away.
I don't have anything in my bag.
How this information
was being virilized
was really amazing.
Like sharing, sharing, sharing,
tweets, tweets, tweets,
mention, mention, mention.
"The Ninja is being arrested."
And suddenly there was,
like, a small crowd.
Like 5,000 people.
And all of them was
screaming together,
[in Portuguese]
"Hey, police,
where is the Midia Ninja?"
[chanting] Hey, police,
where is the Midia Ninja?
At the police station,
there were some lawyers
to help us, some activists.
That's where I met Bruno Teles.
[man speaking in Portuguese]
[woman speaking Portuguese]
-What's your name?
-My name is
Bruno Ferreira Teles.
[Teles]
The Midia Ninjas appeared
right when I needed to speak.
They gave me a voice.
They asked me if I wanted
to give them an interview.
I said I want to. I need to!
As we interviewed Bruno,
Globo broadcast that
he threw the Molotov
and had been arrested.
It was Bruno Ferreira
who was caught with a backpack
full of Molotov cocktails.
The police officer who was hit
with the Molotov cocktail
suffered burns to the thorax.
The big media in general
were all against me.
They associated me
with vandalism,
with violence.
[shouting]
I want to ask you
to help me to find the video
of the moment
where I ran from police.
They took me in,
and they are saying
I was there with bottles
of Molotov cocktails,
and I was not.
That's all I'm asking,
that you search out these videos
and collaborate.
[Silva, in English]
Then we posted this video from
the mobile, like, real time,
and it virilized very fast.
[Carioca, in Portuguese]
Our in-box exploded.
5,000 e-mails in 24 hours.
A ton of images and video
that showed Bruno's innocence.
[glass shattering]
[vocalizing]
[video sound distorted]
[vocalizing continues]
[glass shattering]
[woman] What is this, people?
This is surreal.
[woman vocalizing]
[vocalizing]
[shouting]
[music distorting]
[gunshot muffled]
[electrical crackling]
[crackling continues]
The video was just getting
bigger in the social media.
Bruno Teles became a character.
[crowd shouting]
Within a day,
Globo reversed their position.
They said I was a student,
a good kid.
Everyone likes him.
Contrary to information
released by the military
and civil police,
the student Bruno Teles
did not possess explosives
at the time of his arrest.
[Silva] They said
that Bruno was innocent,
and they used Midia Ninja image.
And they credited Midia Ninja.
It was the first
time that we were seeing
Globo recognizing
a free media collective
as a legitimate player
in the communication game.
It was a next step.
[crowd shouting]
[gunshot]
[explosion]
[glass shattering]
[woman]
Oh, he's changing his shirt.
[shouting]
[woman vocalizing]
[Orlando]
This is an old strategy.
When police infiltrate groups
and appear as activists,
they legitimize
the police violence.
[explosion]
For the population,
if the protestors
are launching explosions,
the police must do
whatever is necessary,
even on the margins of the law.
[Bentes]
The best form of security today
is to live stream everything.
If everyone knows where you are,
then you're safe.
The French word "surveillance"
implies watching from above.
In this case "sub-veillance"
is more accurate.
Bottom-up. The crowd
surveils from all angles.
[crowd chanting in Portuguese]
Hey, undercover cops,
go fuck yourself!
Are you an undercover cop?I'm a protestor, idiot!
[shouting continues]
[crowd booing]
It took only
the time for the video
to circulate online and on TV,
then habeas corpus was filed,
and he was released.
[woman] Bruno! Come here!
[woman crying]
[Orlando]
What if we didn't have
these images?
[shouting]
How many others
don't have the good fortune
of being filmed?
[crowd chanting]
Ninja! Ninja! Ninja!
Ten people are still inside,
some of them Ninjas.
[crowd repeating]
And we will not leave...
...until they are all released.
[cheering]
[crowd] Ninja!
[crowd chanting]
[digital pop music playing]
I've always been a fan
of the terms "hacking"
and "hacktivism."
Especially "hacktivism"
which is the combination of
hacking and political activism.
And those combined
are pretty powerful to me.
It's about encouraging people
not to accept technology
at face value.
We need to encourage people
to think about
what it is that surrounds them,
to question authority
in a sense of the authority
being the technological
environment around them
and to realize that
when you start pulling back
the layers of all of this,
that's where
the exercise of power is.
So if we want liberal democracy
to flourish,
we need people
to start lifting back the layers
and understanding
what's going on.
[clicking]
[Snowden] I think ultimately
it comes down to understanding
what your values are,
because how do you
develop your thoughts, right?
How do you determine
what it is that
you truly believe?
How do you determine what
it is you really want to say,
if you can't even
keep notes safely?
If you can't
have some private space,
some space for thought,
some space to enjoy the product
of your own intellect,
to share that with people
close to you who you trust.
Whether they're family,
whether they're colleagues,
whether they're compatriots.
[Deibert] One thing
that I see a lot is, this idea
of technology as a solution.
It's a natural thing.
Okay, technology
is under threat.
Let's find
a technological solution.
There are so many projects now
around secure communications,
platforms, chats,
instant messaging.
But it's only one component
of a solution set.
And I think often overlooked
are the legal and political
dimensions.
If we're talking about
protecting and preserving
all of this,
as a secure and open
communication space,
that means holding governments
accountable.
It means holding
companies accountable.
Putting in place rules and laws
that ensures they can't
do things that infringe
on our freedoms and rights.
That to me is, uh,
such a critical foundation
of a digital democracy today.