♪ Brown girl in the ring ♪
♪ Tra la la la la ♪
[woman]
My people lived in peace
on the mainland of Toronto
until 2030, the year
I was born.
The wealthy stole Toronto
for themselves.
[screaming]
Riots erupted.
[police radio chatter]
[whistle blows]
The new regime built a wall,
barring us from the mainland.
[police sirens wailing]
They exiled my people
to a forsaken island off
the coast of Toronto.
[wind blows eerily]
Our spirits hunger for a home.
An evil sorcerer, Rudy, rose up
from the Aches of the Burn,
using Buff
and creating Crack to rule us.
[whip cracking]
My grandmother, a priestess,
called on the spirit
Mama Ache to heal the Burn.
[sings in foreign language]
Mama Ache...
she is light.
[continues singing]
She is love.
[singing continues]
With her help,
we grew.
‐But Crack silenced Mama Ache.
‐[whip cracking]
So Mami called on Papa Legba,
the destroyer.
[shouting and screaming]
Papa Legba
demanded a young priestess
as a conduit for his power.
I watched
as my mother tried to
open to Papa Legba.
[crying]
Open to me!
[Mami]
Don't be afraid.
Ah!
Let Papa Legba's power in
or the fear will kill you.
Ah!
Open to me!
Open your eyes.
I open to you.
‐Yeee‐‐
‐[mother screams]
Mami, stop, you're hurting her!
[sobs] I can't!
Child, open your eyes,
don't be afraid.
[shouts]
Stop it, Mami,
you're hurting her!
[sobs]
[mother]
Mami, I can't.
Open your eyes!
[Mami]
You can save our people
with his power.
Open!
[shouting]
My grandmother
watched helplessly.
No!
I watched as Papa Legba
killed my mother.
No!
[sobbing] No!
She was too afraid
to receive his power.
[girl]
No! No!
I am next in line.
I, too, am afraid.
Where my mother ends,
I begin.
[panting]
[grunts]
[shouts]
You the one gonna
change everything for us.
For the good of our people,
you must sacrifice yourself!
No!
No.
You're seeing the past again.
Your mother?
Yes, the visions
are getting stronger.
[whimpering]
Mama Ache tells me
your powers will be great.
[whimpering]
You will see before it happens.
You will heal others
by taking on their pain.
You must open to Papa Legba
and destroy Crack.
Then, you can release
Mama Ache's power.
[rustling]
Mama Ache, you
playing tricks on me?
Or is somebody in need
of food or healing?
[grunts]
Stay inside, Ti‐Jeanne.
[rustling]
[man]
Gracie! Gracie.
You OK? There's nothing there.
There's nothing there.
You've heard of
Mistress Hunter.
I found her wandering
around the Burn.
Look.
Little warning from Crack.
Follow Rudy, or else.
You see them blue bottles
ringing the yard?
No demons can pass
through the blue bottles.
You're safe here.
We're gonna fix you up.
Mistress Hunter,
Gracie doesn't speak.
Take her inside.
Yes, ma'am.
OK, come on.
[Mami]
Crack hurt that girl.
You're the only one
can stop her.
I can mix aloe for her, Mami.
‐I can heal.
‐Yes.
You're a better healer
than me, it's true.
But that won't rid
Gracie of her scar,
and healing won't stop Crack.
We need fresh water
for the wound.
[water sloshing]
I should be a Mami follower.
Spend some more
time around here.
I don't believe in Obeah.
It's not "Obeah."
It's a religion.
Oh.
So you believe?
I can see the spirits
that walk among us.
[laughs]
You sound like
my crazy aunt.
I'm not crazy.
Gracie is resting.
Jax gonna come for
her in the morning.
Thank you, we're good.
[Ti‐Jeanne] It's late, Mami.
Why doesn't he just stay here?
[Mami] You have your bike there.
You can be back to your side
of the Burn in 15 minutes.
Well, you know,
Mistress Hunter,
I could run some
errands for you.
My aunt used to be a
follower before she died.
That's right.
I remember her.
And you as a child.
‐Tony.
‐Yes.
If I work for you,
it sends a message to the Burn
dwellers that I'm on your side.
To Crack, too.
Rudy should've used his spirit
training for something better
than making a
monster like Crack.
All right.
Come in the morning. Early.
Thank you, Mistress Hunter.
See you in the morning.
[Mami] Ti‐Jeanne,
get in the house.
Crack is whipping children.
We're running out of time.
In two weeks, you'll become
Papa Legba's vessel.
Your training starts now.
Lay your head down
before Papa Legba.
Honor him.
No!
Possession killed my mother.
You want it to kill me, too?
Take the cloth off.
Be the priestess your mother
was meant to be.
No.
How many will die if you don't?
It's too big.
I can't lose you, too,
Ti‐Jeanne.
Study.
Study so you're not afraid.
[Ti‐Jeanne]
Jab‐Jab.
He guards the gateways.
[gate creaking]
[bottles clinking]
Jab‐Jab is actually Papa Legba.
He's a trickster.
A shape‐shifter.
He takes on many forms.
[Ti‐Jeanne] Rudy.
He conjured up Crack.
Rudy.
He is evil.
He created Crack to
terrorize our people.
Crack getting her power
from Rudy.
You're scaring Gracie, Mami.
You sure it's Gracie
I scaring?
Study.
[Ti‐Jeanne]
Crack.
[Mami]
Crack is up to something.
Hey, Gracie.
Hey, OK.
Oh, Gracie, Gracie, Gracie.
You frighten me,
running off like that.
Mami said Crack hurt you.
Oh, it's OK.
[woman]
It's OK, Gracie.
We got you.
[Ti‐Jeanne]
For the kids.
Respect.
Pi.
Come say thank you.
[Pi] Thank you.
Crack preying on them now,
can't roam and scavenge freely.
You know Tony.
[Mami]
Evil eye.
Help keep evil at bay
if you point it
in the right direction.
Sorry I'm late,
Mistress Hunter.
No matter how boar
hide under sheep's wool,
him grunt still betray him.
Um...
Translation?
[Jax]
You can't keep your word.
Here, Jax. Help protect you and
those three kids from Crack.
You could stay up here.
Freedom in our going.
Gracie, Kia, Pi.
Time to go.
Hey, hey, hey!
What's the rule?
We don't steal from
anyone that helps us.
It's OK, Gracie.
Bye, Gracie.
Get these and are gone.
Study.
Go and cut some branches
for Bruk Foot Sam
for some new crutches.
He been asking for it
for over a week now.
You know how to use this?
Tony!
There's a stand of
young trees over there.
Some of them you could
cut into good crutches.
You want me to go into
the jungle in there?
Man going into the
jungle to do some
dangerous work with a machete
needs a kiss for good luck.
[sniffing]
[chuckles]
[laughs]
Ti‐Jeanne,
you're smiling like an idiot.
[electrical buzzing]
You should be studying, not
tinkering with solar panels.
Bruk Foot Sam will have these
made into crutches in no time.
He can make anything.
Tell Bruk Foot Sam
I hope the cream works,
I don't know what else to try.
Yes, ma'am.
You wanna work for me, Tony?
It beats working
for Crack and the boss.
Rudy is not the boss
of the Burn.
Sorry, ma'am. I didn't
mean no disrespect.
Ti‐Jeanne could die if
she don't prepare properly.
Stay away from
my granddaughter.
He's not the path for you.
Locking me up isn't gonna
bring my mother back.
Don't backchat me.
Stay away from Tony.
[Tony]
What do you, uh...
[Ti‐Jeanne]
Shh...
♪ Slowly ♪
♪ You're turning away ♪
♪ Turning ♪
[laughs]
♪ Away from me ♪
Hey.
I made you this solar‐powered
light for your bike.
For me?
Well, you know what?
You're all the light I need.
[laughs]
Paula, Pasha.
What's wrong, Ti‐Jeanne?
Ti‐Jeanne's opening
ceremony is tonight.
19th birthday.
Ti‐Jeanne,
we need you.
Meet me down the hill tonight.
[stammers] What about the ce‐‐
Go on, Tony. We won't need
you for a couple of days.
Yes, ma'am.
[fence creaking]
[Mami]
Time come.
[electrical buzzing]
Clean yourself.
Meet me at the barn.
[Ti‐Jeanne]
Mami, I'm scared.
I could die tonight.
[Mami]
I know, child.
I frighten for you, too.
Keep your eyes open.
[bottles clinking]
[panting]
[Ti‐Jeanne whimpers]
[Mami]
Mama Ache.
Mama Ache,
I offer you life‐blood.
‐[sings in foreign language]
‐[all] Mama Ache.
[singing continues]
[all] Mama Ache.
Mama Ache.
Mama Ache!
[singing continues]
[Mami] You can have
Mama Ache's powers.
Just open to Papa Legba.
[screaming]
[sobbing]
[groaning]
[Mami coughing]
Are you all right?
It just take me longer to
come back sometime.
Please don't make me do this.
I have no choice, Ti‐Jeanne.
[metal door creaking]
Prepare for Ti‐Jeanne's
opening ceremony.
No.
[sobbing]
[Ti‐Jeanne]
Tony!
‐Ti‐Jeanne!
‐We have to go.
Ah! Mami!
I gonna put mal'jo upon you.
You wouldn't put the Evil Eye
on anybody‐‐
Shut up, Ti‐Jeanne!
Only one bull can rule
this pen, and that's me.
Move!
This is the only way.
Let go of his hand.
Mami, I'm leaving.
You're our only hope Ti‐Jeanne.
Come on.
Come on. Come on. Come.
This is it.
Come, I'll show you
why I live here.
Come on.
[electrical buzzing]
[Tony]
The Burbs.
Maybe we'll be the first ones
to break through
that invisi‐wall.
The year of the riots.
The year the army walled us in
to protect the wealthy
Burbians from us.
The year I was born.
Not all bad, then.
[Ti‐Jeanne]
Mama Ache.
[group]
[singing in foreign language]
It's Mama Ache.
[singing continues]
Don't bring any of that
spirit business here.
New start.
Come on.
[electrical buzzing]
Anyone else live here?
No. Not in this part.
It's good.
I just need to bathe.
There's, uh,
the water tap outside
by the latrine.
But, there's also a...
a tub of clean water in there.
[chuckles]
You're sure?
[chuckles] OK.
[no audio]
[panting]
[grunting]
‐You must sacrifice yourself!
‐No!
[electrical buzzing]
[water dripping]
[deep breath]
Rude. Don't turn
your back on me.
Are you afraid of
an old man like me?
You will call me Papa Legba.
No, I want nothing to do
with the spirit world.
Open your eyes, child.
Many would love to be
chosen by the Oracle.
What do you want?
You don't address me like that!
I know Mami taught you that.
Yes, Papa Legba.
My purpose needs
your human form.
Crack is growing more
powerful than me.
Bow your head and open to
me as your guardian spirit.
No, Papa Legba.
I'm not strong enough.
Think of power
like water.
You go through the tidal wave.
You don't fight it.
Your mother fought it.
Is that why she died?
I could teach you
to take that power.
Now, look at me.
Good.
Open your eyes
when you are afraid
so you can see what to do.
Now, bow your head.
Open!
[screaming]
I can't, I'm not strong enough.
You're frightened of me.
Don't it?
[electrical buzzing]
I'm gonna fix that.
[laughs]
[electric static]
Bruk Foot?
Bruk Foot!
Bruk Foot Sam!
Bruk Foot Sam,
it's me, Ti‐Jeanne.
Who's yelling like that?
It's Ti‐Jeanne.
Mami's granddaughter.
Ti‐Jeanne.
With my bad foot,
I haven't been to the farm in,
it must be seven years.
I haven't seen you.
You're using Buff, now?
Oh, I use Buff for
the pain in my foot.
I tried everything Mami
gave me, but nothing worked.
‐[bell chiming]
‐Whoa.
Good reflexes.
But you don't listen.
Where were you?
Had to barter with good
old Gurjeet for this.
Trying to impress
my new boss.
You can't just
wander out here.
I can't be locked up.
[Bruk Foot] Crack posse.
We don't need no
posse business.
[Ti‐Jeanne] Tony's bartering
with Crack's posse now?
Come on, Ti‐Jeanne.
I'll walk you home.
[singing in foreign language]
That was me a couple
of days ago.
[singing continues weakly]
[electrical buzzing]
No one in the Burn
is a match for Crack.
Not even Mami.
[man grunts]
[Ti‐Jeanne]
Crack's Buff is
killing our people.
[singing resumes]
Datura.
I can use Datura to stop
the addiction to Buff.
Create a potion and stop Crack.
Crack won't stand for that.
Propane.
[Ti‐Jeanne]
I'm gonna try doing
some healing for barter.
Fine.
[Ti‐Jeanne]
Why don't we just
cook with wood fire?
You know what?
I like the sound of
banging pots in the kitchen.
Sounds like home.
[Ti‐Jeanne]
A real home.
Ti‐Jeanne!
Good barter today.
For your foot.
Thanks.
♪ So come music ♪
♪ Won't you take me ♪
♪ Take me back to
my island, yeah ♪
[laughs]
♪ So come music ♪
Buff.
Please.
This will break your
body's need for Buff.
He's 23 now.
"I'm going to the Burbs."
Come back tomorrow.
A heater?
You must've fixed a lot
of bikes to get this.
Oh, yeah. Just the right one.
The posse's bikes?
He promised me it worked.
[sighs]
I'm pretty good
with this stuff.
You know what, I can just
ask Bruk Foot Sam to fix it.
He's a master.
I can do it.
I just want to do my part, OK?
I'm sorry for getting mad.
With my healing business,
you won't have to fix
the posse's bikes anymore.
[chuckles]
[laughs]
[Papa Legba]
Love sweet you, don't it?
Enjoying your freedom?
The healing is working.
Address me properly.
Papa Legba.
The people in the Burn
are turning away from Buff.
Yes.
It's true, child, you have
become a good healer.
But you haven't stopped Crack.
I can do it.
You will make Crack angrier.
You open now
or you turn your back on
years of hope and power
placed on your shoulders.
Give me a chance to
practice my healing.
People will die!
[grunts]
[Ti‐Jeanne] Looks good.
And your helper's name?
Gracie, meet Bruk Foot Sam.
You laughing after my name?
Strong silent type, huh?
[snickers]
Gracie's helping me while
Jax and the other kids
move to a shelter
near the dawn.
[Bruk Foot]
Further from Crack?
Still not taking Buff, are you?
Aren't you too young to nag?
Datura's lethal when
it's mixed with Buff.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Sounds doctor‐y.
Mmm! Yummy.
You know...
...you could make the
Buff mark disappear.
I'm a healer. Not a priestess.
You're good to go.
And here's some ointment
for your foot, too.
Huh.
‐You don't even need it.
‐It's working.
‐I don't need no crutches.
‐[both laugh]
[footsteps]
‐Hey, yo, it's me, Jax.
‐I thought you were...
Never mind.
Hey, Gracie.
It's all right, we got
the evil eye pendant now.
How's Mami?
She misses you bad.
So you're staying
here with Tony?
Yeah.
I made a potion to stop
the addiction to Buff.
Less people under Crack
means more followers for Mami.
You must be careful, Ti‐Jeanne.
Rudy has given her the power
to hear from very far away.
[Jax whispers]
Come, Gracie. Better go.
Come.
Hm, watch, watch, watch.
Bye, Ti‐Jeanne.
[bike bell rings]
[Tony] With you,
I feel like I'm something.
I'm someone.
Love is so quiet.
Hey, hey, hey!
‐Oh, I'm sorry.
‐Don't be an idiot.
Come back with that.
‐I'm hungry.
‐Oh, OK, you know what?
Get back over here.
Right here.
That's right.
Yeah.
[Ti‐Jeanne]
Melba!
[whip cracking]
[Crack]
Melba, stop.
I was this close to being
Rudy's right hand,
and then, you had
to go run away
and miss your doses.
[gasps]
Crack.
16 and a half more
Buff injections,
and I will deliver a
smart slave to Rudy.
Docile, but
coherent enough to
follow directions.
Rudy won't call
my experiment stupid
when he sells you to the
wealthy Burbians, Melba.
He called me old and stupid
wasting his Buff.
Oh.
No, please.
Give it back!
Your son is in the Burbs.
Only way to get there.
[Papa Legba] Open your eyes
when you're afraid
so you can see what to do.
[grunts]
[wristband chiming]
[Rudy]
Don't scar her.
[whip cracking]
Stay away from Melba.
[Mami]
You have to stop Crack.
[Ti‐Jeanne] Bruk Foot?
Ti‐Jeanne.
I saw Crack.
No one sees Crack.
She wouldn't dirty herself
coming around here.
Bruk Foot.
Crack is using Buff
to make a smart slave.
She showed herself to you?
Yes.
Crack's lost favor with Rudy.
She's desperate.
Open up to Papa Legba.
Open your eyes to see.
I left that behind.
I'm a healer now.
Those who reject their
gifts cause more havoc
than those without.
[Mami]
Ti‐Jeanne.
Ti‐Jeanne, you have to stop it.
You can't stop Crack
on your own.
You need the power
of the spirits.
[Ti‐Jeanne]
No, I'll die.
[Mami]
Be the priestess your
mother was meant to be.
[Ti‐Jeanne]
No!
[electric static]
[Papa Legba]
My purpose needs a human form.
Melba?
Melba!
Melba.
I can help you.
[Crack]
Baby girl.
You young people, you think
you're never gonna get old.
And Rudy likes shiny things.
But you, too,
will soon be obsolete.
[Ti‐Jeanne gasps]
Rudy's order.
Stop your healing.
It's working too well.
Unless you want to share your
little techniques with him.
Hm?
Not yet?
This whip doesn't have
to touch your shiny skin
to cause pain.
[Ti‐Jeanne] I need water now.
I need water now!
It's OK, OK?
Don't worry about it.
No, no, I need water so I can
make my anti‐Buff mixture.
Anti‐Buff?
Crack isn't gonna like you
messing around with
her Buff business.
Who's side are you on?
Yours.
‐Always yours.
‐Then act like it!
Help me!
What is that?
Ah, you know Sam. He's always
tinkering with something.
What's wrong?
So no more bike repair.
She put the word out.
I'm worried about you.
Crack shutting me down must
be to send a message to you.
So stop making your
anti‐Buff potions, please.
Posse came by.
They want me to do
deliveries for them.
[Ti‐Jeanne]
No, Tony.
Not Buff. Just
general deliveries.
First, you fix their bixes,
then general deliveries,
and then, you're dealing Buff.
We can beat Crack.
Where's your bike?
Posse stole it.
Their way of responding
to my "No, thank you,"
for not delivering for them.
What do you want me to do, huh?
‐Believe in me.
‐Believe in you?
‐Believe in me!
Ti‐Jeanne, believe this.
You're asking me to watch you
die by not working for Crack.
Papa Legba lives here.
Papa Legba? No one lives here!
Ti‐Jeanne,
you're talking crazy!
I'm not crazy!
Papa Legba lives here!
[Tony] Ti‐Jeanne, stop.
No one lives here!
We promised, OK?
We promised no spirit business.
[Ti‐Jeanne] We made
a lot of promises.
No working for Crack.
[Tony] Well, what do
you want me to do?
Not the heater.
Barter the propane stove.
Not yet, Ti.
Not yet.
[no audio]
[Ti‐Jeanne] I was wrong.
We need help to stop Crack.
How?
Papa Legba.
My aunt put me on a raft
and we tried crossing
that toxic lake.
It tipped. She tried
to save me by diving
back into that water and
carry me back to the shore.
The toxins finally ate
her when I was 14.
OK, don't tell me the
spirits are gonna help us.
Did they help my family?
Melba.
Melba! Melba.
[groans]
It's still reddish.
‐You haven't taken Buff
recently, have you?
‐No! No, no, no.
You have to help me.
Please.
[sobbing]
This is my last bottle,
I'm sorry.
Hide, Melba.
Melba?
No. No!
No, no, no, no.
[whip cracking]
‐You killed her.
‐No, you killed her!
You can't mix Datura with Buff.
I thought she had
stopped taking Buff.
Liar!
She wasn't yours to mess with.
She was mine.
She was my experiment.
I am gonna deliver you
to Rudy as a follower.
Won't that be a coup.
Mami's granddaughter
on his side.
Papa Legba! Papa Legba!
Papa Legba, I killed Melba!
You're learning to address
me with respect.
I killed Melba.
You're ready to open now?
I'm scared.
Is that what you're studying
when your people are dying?
The less you are afraid,
the stronger conduit you are.
If I face my mother's death,
I would be more
open to you, right?
Less afraid.
Yes.
Ask Bruk Foot Sam to help you.
OK.
I'll do that first, Papa Legba.
[Bruk Foot]
Why am I here, Ti‐Jeanne?
Help me conquer
that memory.
You were there.
Yes, it will
make you stronger.
Open you eyes, child.
That night,
Mami tried to...
Mami tried to prepare your
mother as best she could.
I want you to go back
to the youngest age
that you can handle, Ti‐Jeanne.
[Bruk Foot]
See, child.
See it all.
I'm here, Ti‐Jeanne.
[Ti‐Jeanne]
I'm not ready.
No! I can't.
I stopped following Mami
after your mother died.
I wanna help, Bruk Foot Sam.
But I don't wanna be
controlled. I don't wanna die.
The old ways need changing.
[Ti‐Jeanne]
I'm like my mother.
Not strong enough.
We're never gonna
get to the Burbs.
You're right, Ti‐Jeanne.
We're not going
to make it there.
If you're going
to fight Crack,
I'm going to steal
water from her.
You can't risk that, Tony.
She knows who you are.
[car engine starts]
[whip cracking]
Tony.
Tony!
[whip cracking]
[yelling]
[Tony screams]
You are gonna stop
stealing my water, yes?
I need fresh water
for his wound.
Please.
Turn it on!
There's always the lake water.
It'll cool that cut.
But so toxic.
The permanent code for the
water is on the injector.
And you will stop your healing.
‐[electrical fizzing]
‐[Ti‐Jeanne yells]
[chuckles]
Your mother was weak
and afraid, too.
You are gonna do deliveries
of Buff for me.
Deliveries and dispensary.
Free‐flowing water,
that's the deal.
Good boy.
You will follow Rudy.
[wristband chiming]
[Rudy]
Good girl.
On time.
This will make you sleep.
[Jax]
Ti‐Jeanne!
Ti‐Jeanne.
‐Ti‐Jeanne.
‐[Ti‐Jeanne] Jax, what's wrong?
‐Gracie is gone.
‐What?
She's gone.
It's Crack! Just go, Jax.
Take the other kids.
Hide them!
I'll find her.
Papa Legba!
Gracie's gone!
Crack took Gracie!
Papa Legba!
Help me to find her!
I will open to you!
[Bruk Foot]
Wait, Ti‐Jeanne!
‐Wait!
‐Papa Legba!
‐Wait, Ti‐Jeanne.
‐I will open to you!
Ti‐Jeanne! Come here.
Here.
It's a shield I made so
you can control your
guardian spirit power.
Wait, wait,
I haven't tested it yet.
I'm out of time.
It needs to work.
Papa Legba needs to
show me where Gracie is.
All right, all right.
Stay still.
You turn the power on,
Papa Legba possesses you.
You turn it off, no power.
You control.
You are the conduit,
but, Ti‐Jeanne,
you still have to invite
Papa Legba in to become
the power.
Stay with me, Bruk Foot Sam.
Stay with me.
I'm here, Ti‐Jeanne.
[Papa Legba laughs]
Open up to Papa Legba,
Ti‐Jeanne.
Papa Legba!
I'm ready!
[gasps]
[yelling]
[singing]
[screams]
[Crack]
Shut it down!
[chuckles]
That's all you got, baby girl?
[Ti‐Jeanne yells]
Papa Legba! Papa Legba!
[Mama Ache singing]
Papa Legba, you used
Bruk Foot Sam to trick me!
You are stupid, child!
You're like your mother,
weak and afraid!
I am not my mother!
‐[singing]
‐[yelling]
Is that all you got?
I need more power
to stop Crack.
Ready, I ready!
Give me all you got!
[Papa Legba]
Open your eyes, child.
Child, open your eyes.
Open!
[screaming]
[sobbing]
[Papa Legba]
I don't want to kill
a chosen one.
I want to give you the power
that you were meant to have!
[Ti‐Jeanne]
Then give me the power to see.
Show me Gracie!
Help me to find her!
[Papa Legba]
See, child.
See it all.
[Gracie whimpers]
Show me more.
I wanna see, I can take it!
[Gracie whimpers]
Gracie.
Crack. No.
‐[whip cracking]
‐[yelling]
[Ti‐Jeanne]
No! Show me where she is.
The trees near Mami's farm.
[grunts]
‐[whip cracking]
‐[Ti‐Jeanne groans]
No!
So you do have what
Rudy covets so much.
The power to see.
[wristband chiming]
I thought you would've
found us sooner,
chosen one, before
little Gracie had scars.
It's a perfect dose in there.
Just slam it into your neck.
Have Rudy's mark and
this little girl goes free.
Never.
[Papa Legba]
Open!
[screaming]
Go! Go!
No, run, Gracie,
I'll get it. Run!
[Ti‐Jeanne grunts]
[grunting]
[yelling]
[Ti‐Jeanne yells]
Obsolete.
Gracie.
‐Get in!
‐Gracie!
‐Go!
‐Come!
Weak
and afraid.
All right, come on, come on.
[Gracie whimpers]
Come on.
Oh, baby. All right.
Hold this tight.
Oh, my God.
Mama Ache, let me use
your power for good.
Let me take Gracie's pain.
Ti‐Jeanne, what are you doing?
[Mama Ache sings
in foreign language]
[gasping]
[moaning]
All her scars are gone.
[singing continues]
[Ti‐Jeanne] You need some rest.
[electrical buzzing]
[sobbing]
I'm so sorry, Ti‐Jeanne.
Don't be.
This is who
I'm meant to be.
It fits.
Gracie,
she's ready.
She's a priestess.
["Brown Girl In the Ring" plays]
♪ Brown girl in the ring ♪
♪ Tra la la la la ♪
♪ There's a brown girl
in the ring ♪
♪ Tra la la la la la ♪
♪ Brown girl in the ring ♪
♪ Tra la la la la ♪
‐♪ Now show me emotion ♪
‐♪ Brown girl ♪
♪ Come on ♪
♪ Brown girl in the ring ♪
♪ Brown girl ♪
‐♪ Brown girl ♪
‐♪ Brown girl in the ring ♪
♪ Tra la la la la ♪
♪ Brown girl in the ring ♪
‐♪ Brown girl ♪
‐♪ Brown girl in the ring ♪
♪ Tra la la la la ♪
‐♪ Brown girl ♪
‐♪ Brown girl in the ring ♪
♪ Tra la la la la ♪
♪ Show me emotion ♪
♪ Come on, come on ♪
♪ Wave your hands ♪
♪ Come on, baby, hey ♪
♪ Brown girl in the ring ♪
♪ Tra la la la la ♪
‐♪ Now show me emotion ♪
‐♪ Brown girl ♪
♪ Come on ♪
♪ Brown girl in the ring ♪
♪ Brown girl ♪
‐♪ Brown girl ♪
‐♪ Brown girl in the ring ♪
♪ Tra la la la la ♪
♪ Brown girl in the ring ♪
‐♪ Brown girl ♪
‐♪ Brown girl in the ring ♪
♪ Tra la la la la ♪
‐♪ Brown girl ♪
‐♪ Brown girl in the ring ♪
♪ Tra la la la la ♪
♪ Show me emotion
Come on, come on ♪
♪ Wave your hands ♪
♪ Come on, baby, hey ♪