Episode 5: We're Almost Home
The guys are halfway through the
European run.
In addition to a lingering
sense of fatigue,
each day seems to bring
its own set of logistical challenges.
Yea, where are we pushing it?
Streets are small, parking is
non-existent.
so we detached the trailer in the middle
of the road and pushed it over here
Now we're waiting for a van to put all the
gear in so we can take it across the street
so we can set up which is supposed
to start an hour and a half ago.
Everything's pretty straightforward
on the US headline run
Here it's just, who knows. There's a
lot more variables a lot more unknowns.
Every day it's like kinda figuring out
figuring out a lot more things on the fly
We are in some dirty-ass loading dock in
Manchester, UK.
We entered some kind of time-warp
that made us fucking six hours late.
We should have been here a long
time ago but Holger stopped
and everybody was asleep and
everybody slept through it.
He seriously stopped at a truck stop
for five hours
and didn't empty the piss tank
and then get's to the venue and
empties it all over the fucking street
I'll run down, maybe have to
pull it down from downstairs
I'm washing my underwear in the venue
because we haven't seen the laundry
for days and I'm out of clean clothes
and this is rock 'n roll
What is it? Is it Tuesday night?
Is that what it is?
Who gives a fuck.
We're in Islington and we've been
discussing the election of
Kaiser Orange the 2nd.
The guy won the presidency.
That really fuckin' happened.
We should literally tweet Egomaniac all day
Like once...
on the hour just do hashtag Egomaniac
Yeah it's been an exciting fucking 24 hours
just watching the world
possibly come to an end
or not or who knows?
It's a great, great time to be a nihilist.
This European run consists of 14 shows
in 18 days but that doesn't mean they
have four days off. Any day without a
performance is scheduled because the
next gig is just too far away to make it
there in time to perform.
The guys take in the sights as they can
but most off days are typically spent
nearly entirely on a bus,
van, train or airplane.
So we're in Glasgow, Scotland. Michael's
hometown, Mic's hometown which is cool.
In this land where I can say what the fuck
I want and people understand me.
*SPEAKING SCOTTISH*
I flew in a day before, yeah, to catch up
with family and my best friend
so I caught with her and my other cousin and
my mum and my aunt... so that was really nice
This is my mum
You alright?
This town was the fuckin'
spearhead of the Industrial Revolution
The 70's... was fuckin terrible...
rife gangland violence in Glasgow man
You ever heard of the ice --cream wars?
Yeah that was pretty fucking bad too
CAMERAMAN: Doesn't sound bad
They weren't fighting with ice-cream
Jason, does this look like
something that's important?
Yeah it used to be an old cinema here
and it used to be a circus before that
When they were excavating
Prospecthill up the road
They found elephant bones and
they got a fuckin' archeological team in
to fuckin'...
"there was elephants in Scotland?"
No there was a circus at the ABC
and when the elephant died they just buried
it up the road and didn't tell anybody
GERON: How long is Mic going to
talk about the history of Scotland?
until I finish wiring this fuckin' plug,
dick.
Thank you for calling Advantage customer
service we're closed at this time.
Our normal hours are 8am to 7pm
That's the second time that's happened
to me I can't figure out the time zones
What time is it?
Okay Scotland
I fell asleep,
to be awoken by a large bang.
Bam bam, and I fucking see out of the
corner of my I, like, stuff flying
As the bus driver was fleeing the
scene of the crime so to speak
Actually, not so to speak,
that's exactly what he did
And we didn't stop, we just kept going
Yeah, I don't know why but I'm
in a shit mood today though
Just in a fucking shitty mood.
Yea everyone's fucking sick of it.
I'm kinda nervous 'cause..
We have like 2 weeks left and..
like everyday is just
exponentially getting greater
my disdain for this trip.
And I want to just get
home as quick as possible.
And everyone feels like that
Like band and crew, the shows are great.
Everything's great, we're just fucking sick of it
Let's have a great.. a great
show.
Deep in the heart of a long tour
run, patience frays
and otherwise charming quirks
of travel begin to wear you out.
Ahh, another gig.
A good touring family expects this and
works together to keep spiri ts high
and maintain a sense of humor even
through the exhaustion and monotony
Yup, I remember when that happened
The guy's say goodbye to the bus and
head out for three "fly gigs" in Russia
and Ukraine. Two markets they've been
looking forward to playing for a long
time. However the band's draw in those
countries is completely unknown.
We are in Cologne, Germany
No we're not. We're in Dusseldorf.
Oh yes, we are in Dusseldorf, Germany. We were in
Cologne. We went to sleep and we woke up in Dusseldorf
We're flying to St. Petersburg,
Moscow and then Ukraine - playing Kiev.
Yeah it's pretty exciting. There's a few places
where you actually legitimately did not expect to
end up playing shows in when you first
join a band
You interpret what I say into Russian.
Actually I'm very excited to go to Russia - a little
nervous because of the election that's been going on
But seems like... (translating in Russian)
I'm always going to talk over you
so you just have to keep going
I'm pretty fucking excited to be here. I
wasn't expecting all this snow. I mean I know
it's Russia but it's only November
How cold is it?
"Fuck you" cold
Okay so I'd like to make a toast but in
the Russian tradition "zakuski",
You should take a shot and then follow it
up instead of a lime like tequila you put a
little piece of garlic or pickle
or this garlic bread
it's very exciting we're in like a
traditional Russian restaurant
on our first night here, it's pretty cool.
Thanks so much for bringing me on this week
And I'll do my best to stay out of trouble.
We're in St. Petersburg walking to the
hotel. Just had a great russian meal.
We're about to pass a little grocery
store, a sex club, a sex shop
And then our hotel.
Let's see if we make any detours... cut.
Where are we Jesse?
Am I covered in snow?
You are, yeah
We're on a bridge in St. Petersburg.
I wore the wrong jacket.
I didn't realize it was snowing out.
but yeah it's quite a sight.
We're having fun with electricity today
See that, that side's fucked
*Teaching Russian pronunciation of St.
Petersburg.*
Go click on her profile picture
Jesus, Geron, look at that girl, dude.
Go to Alexandra again.
She has a "marry now"
button on her profile.
Holy shit, Geron.
I love Russia. Russia's great.
*Teach Russian*
You literally just say "Kak"
Just like "Cock"
Ok, Cock.
*Speaking Russian*
Did you get all that?
Ticket price, venue location, night of the
week, or a conflicting sporting event can
mean the difference between selling out
a venue and playing to a half full room
As they play their first shows ever in
Russia and the Ukraine they are
optimistic but do not know quite what to
expect.
JASON: There's more
people here than Germany.
GERON: Are there?
GERON: yeah probably.
GERON: Germany?
JASON: Cologne
JASON: last show, two days ago
GERON: I don't remember that... oh yeah.
Yo, Mo.
That was a top 10 crowd.
Nostrovia!
You totally killed it.
Sorry I'm like sweating like monkey.
So hot in there - oh my god
It's about 6:00 in the
morning I think.
We're leaving, going to the
Ukraine to play a show in Kiev.
How much sleep did you get?
uh, 3 hours.
About the third show in a row
today, been a long day.
Watching these guys load
the gear is very tiring.
The show in Kiev was also a hit but the
guys only have a few moments to reflect
on success in Russia and Ukraine before
having to pack up and move along once again.
It's midnight, we are loading
the luggage room with gear.
We have to unload it at 5:30am tomorrow
and fly to Barcelona.
The last 3 shows in Europe are in Spain - another
new market for them with an unknown fanbase
They also remain in limbo with their
record label back home.
So what's our actual plan?
We've not heard back from the guy.
They're saying go hard at radio.
We've not communicated with our radio
team, they apparently have gone to radio..
whatever that means...
If we don't hear from them today or tomorrow..a
full week after writing a letter like that...
then that's not only a week...
That's a month, 5, 6 weeks after um..
saying we want off the label and we
still haven't heard anything from them
How do we give this song a
shot because I actually believe in it.
Well we don't have an another option. You
can't force people to do shit when you're
halfway across the world.
We've got the single going to radio, we're hoping
for some good data in the next holiday period
If that doesn't happen, it's dead
It's one thing to say "no let's go big let's
go to radio hard", but what the fuck does that
mean after they've killed a campaign and
we're going back six weeks later to the
same PD's asking them to play the same
song that we just pulled away
from. So it's one thing to say that but
it can potentially harm us going big if
there's not an actual strategy and plan.
I'm tired
Talk about divide and conquer - they're
actually doing that to us by turning
this entire thing negative.
They have killed music for us.
Is this a 100 watt one?
Yea I mean let's do a Bassman for the wet, I
mean yeah, Bassman for wet and this guy for dry.
They have a shitload of amps
that are....almost right.
Despite a number of presale
tickets sold, 15 minutes to Showtime
the crowd is surprisingly sparse
The thing here, the people wait until
More or less the end to grab some
beers outside because it's cheaper
To get some food outside
because it's cheaper too
JASON: Then they show up.
We have to do it dude, there's whatever 30
people..turn that into 50 or 60 the next time
By the time I'm 45 I'm gonna have this
career off the ground dude.
Dude, your funny bone...
I'd hit that.
Right on cue, the crowd showed
up as the band took the stage
That was definitely, that was most
improved from expectations to actuality
I was expecting the worst show of the tour.
MVP's
It may still be the worst show of the
tour but it was still pretty good.
The band has one more show in the
coastal town of Santander before the
final show of the tour in Madrid
CAMERA: Hey mo!
MO: Fuck off.
CAMERA: How's your day going?
Hey Danny
CAMERA: Fucking creepy, his eyes are open
Danny.
Is he ok? Hi
Danny we're doing soundcheck
DANNY: Oh my I'm fucking tired.
Although Santander was one of the
smallest cities they played,
the show provided one of the most memorable
moments of the tour
I think everybody's faces last night was
a fucking gem to be honest with you.
The band played the show, it was great. They
decided they weren't going to play the encore.
So they said play the house music,
we turned the house music on,
we brought the lights up in the room
and the crowd just wouldn't shut up.
They wouldn't leave.
There's only 60 70 people here but they
were going bananas for them
JESSE: Guys come back.
They had to come back out again.
Honestly the sooner I get off
that fucking bus, the better.
CAMERA: Are you excited to go home?
Yes very. Very excited to go home.
When was the last time you were home?
I can't remember
I think this tour was absolutely worth
it you know we lost a lot of money on it
a lot of fucking money
Overall it was probably worth the
money that we spent to come here
You know, very small shows but I think we
actually started something here.
A base for us to come back to,
particularly in Eastern
Europe, Russia, Poland
Hey Danny, uh is he in here?
Oh hi, hey go through Dylan's space and
go downstage to your position or
else you're going to be really fucked
JASON: We get to go home
JASON: Last one.
DANNY: Forever?
JASON: No, no just for a week or two.
Good morning..it's not morning if you
don't go to sleep yet
CAMERA: What time is it?
5am
It's Sunday the 20th of November, we are
going home.
After four months on the road, playing
60 shows in 30 states and 10 countries
The guy's head back to the
US to close out the year
with two more weeks of
playing radio festivals.
But with no single on the radio, the future
of the album remains unclear
Next time on Bus Call.
We are at our South African
childhood home in Johannesburg
We'll be working but at the same time we're
gonna try to show the crew a really good time
Its Oppikoppi Day.
Three days of just
people losing their minds
Now, now what do we do?