Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
I's a beautiful
sunny afternoon
here in the Cowboy state.
We've got partly cloudy skies
clearing by sundown
and for you stargazers tonight,
the Geminid meteor shower
is set to put on
a once-in-a-lifetime show
between 6:00 pm and 2:00 am.
So set your sights to the
North-Northeast high in the sky.
The National Weather
Service says temps
could dip into the mid-60s,
so you have a beautiful night
to sit out with a sweetheart,
kick back, and put
something on the grill.
And her's a fun fact from
Wyoming's Meteor Research Center
at Hopkin's Air Force base:
only twice in
the showe's history
have we seen a shower lasting
longer than two hours,
and this one goes late,
late into the night,
so it sounds like i's
going to be quite a show.
Don't go to bed early!
And I did't know this, but our
weather guy is saying to me
that these falling stars
are actually debris from
an asteroid that orbits the sun
every year-and-a half...
I's named... how do you
pronounce this?
"Fay-eh-thoon?"
Phaethon, is that it?
Sounds close enough.
So, we wo't be able
to see that tonight but
plenty of shooting stars will
be dancing across the sky.
Keep it cool, keep it fun,
keep it safe.
Definitely be ready
for a fireworks display
from Mother Nature to go
with your rock n roll.
Currently 68 degrees and a
jam-packed line-up at KYOS...
What began as excitement
has turned to concern
in rural Wyoming this morning.
Reports have been flooding
in from NORAD
and the International
Space Station
of some unusual activity
related to a meteor shower
mostly-viewable
in the Northern U .S.
Observatories around the
world are coordinating efforts
to assure the meteor that
made ground late yesterday
was one isolated incident.
Mount Wilson Observatory
in Southern California
is closely monitoring
a group of 58 meteors.
They want to reassure the public
that there is at this point
no cause for alarm and that
they are keeping a close eye
- on the shower as it intensifies.
- Notches road, Notches road.
Let me know when you see it.
Stand by for more
breaking news and reports
here on KYOS Wyoming.
Next dirt road on the right.
Why do meteors always land
in the middle of nowhere?
I hate those country roads.
I think we are here.
100 years, 'm like,
my great-grandfather
built that barn, you know?
I's all I have.
I's all the money I have.
Let's see what
we got here, huh?
Well, let's go say hi.
How you doing, guys?
Hello. Hi, hi.
Officer Pritchard.
- Nice to meet you.
- Kurt.
Yeah, at first I thought
it was a jet
from the Air Force Base
that caught on fire
or maybe it was a missile
that flew out of control.
But until we got your call
to shelter in place,
this town was in a panic.
Yeah, well,
tha's understandable.
A meteor traveling
10 times the speed of sound
will frighten anybody.
So are you the poor woman that
just got her house destroyed?
- Yeah.
- Uh, yeah.
She was pretty shook up,
but she keeps mentioning
how happy she is
that you guys are located
just a couple miles up the road.
Yeah, are you the folks
that study the, uh, UFOs?
Uh, no.
We actually study meteors.
Meredith, this
is Dr. Kurt Siegel.
H's from the base.
H's their lead meteorologist.
Tha's for weather, Brian.
Actually, w're
called meteorists.
Those weather people
claimed that cool name,
unfortunately,
so here we are.
Oh, yeah.
I mean, this was my house.
I just put
in fresh juniper bushes.
That explosion
even fried my radio.
So do you mind
if we go ahead
and take a closer
look at things?
Yeah, feel free.
I's a sad sight. Come on.
All right, this way.
Watch your step.
Just got to go around here.
There's too much damage
on the other side.
All right now.
Watch your step here.
I's kinda tricky.
- Here.
- Okay.
All right.
So it came from right over here
and crashed the top of my house
and landed right over there.
Go ahead.
Here, watch yourself.
Watch it.
All right.
Watch your step.
Watch yourself.
Look at that.
Well, this does't make sense.
What?
The size of it.
I's way too big.
Why?
What did you expect?
About a fraction of this.
Tha's about six foot.
What do you think, Mara?
If this was the size
of an actual missile,
what would it do?
Well, Geminids travel what?
20,000 or 30,000 miles an hour?
Tha's right.
Okay.
Well, even without a payload,
a small ICBM
would generate the force
equivalent to a ton of TNT.
I mean, this size...
Speed?
This whole town should be gone.
Shit.
How do you explain that, doc?
I'm not sure.
The only plausible explanation
is that this meteor
was traveling
at a much slower speed than
it should have.
W'll need a second opinion
on this.
I gotta make a call.
Hey, Gwen, it's Siegel.
Yes, 'm at that crash site.
There are a few things
that just don't add up here.
I think we could really
use your expertise.
Oh, you're on your way?
Good.
Because I need you and Beth
down here STAT
to run some element profiles.
I can't figure out
for the life of me
how this thing survived
the atmosphere...
or if there will be more.
W're gonna need to dig
into this thing.
I hope you have
your field kit.
Okay, see you in a minute.
She asked if we could take
the helicopter to save time.
And I told her
w're not breaking
transport protocol ever again.
Please do't tell me
you taught her
how to fly a helicopter.
I had a heart attack
when I found out
you taught her
how to fly a jet.
Boy, I wish I had
a chauffer to fly me around
in a helicopter.
Title's Heavy Weapons Analyst.
But, yeah, I can
get people where they need to go
from time to time.
Especially if they wanna
blow stuff up.
My apologies.
To be fair, I did teach Gwen
the basics of flying an F-35.
And I told her
the next time w're up,
she can take the controls.
So is Michael coming with her?
Michael? No.
I's just her and Beth.
- The're here.
- Yeah.
Gwen, I understand
your husban's
a hot shot colonel
now at the base.
But we do still need you in
the field from time to time.
Sorry I'm late.
Beth is with us today.
Beth, good to see you.
Yeah. So, no, I'm late
because I had to start
the spectral imaging process.
I told you that
was unnecessary, Gwen.
My predictive models call
this a meteor shower.
Yeah, well, we should
talk about that.
Yeah, we should.
- You gotta take a look at this.
- Okay.
Kurt, did you happen
to see all those dead birds
in the drive in this morning?
Yeah. Tha's not uncommon
in a meteor shower.
Yeah, no,
but it seemed different.
Gwen, what is it?
Beth, would you mind
giving us a moment?
Thanks.
Kurt, I'm telling you,
I'm concerned
about this meteor
cloud's density.
If four objects aggregated
from the center,
it could indicate
something much larger,
more dangerous that's
affecting them.
Gwen, I understand
you're being cautious
because of Russia but I ran
a complete threat matrix
and everything looked fine.
Yeah, but what
if we were wrong about
Phaeton's disappearance
in that solar storm?
After that asteroid's
last perihelion,
it never came back out
from behind the sun.
That was the biggest solar
shower in decades.
Unless we just ca't see it.
Can't see it.
Gwen, no.
Gwen, come on.
The crate's this way.
Beth?
So, Gwen, Beth,
this is Brian
and next to him is Meredith,
the unfortunate home owner.
Hey, Brian, Meredith, this
is our lead astrophysicist.
Oh, my God!
Gwen Armstrong!
I read all about you
in Wired Magazine.
Looks like you have a fan.
Oh, God, 'm so sorry
about what happened to those
poor people who got injured
in Chelyabinsk, Russia.
Thank you.
I've read every single
one of your books. Seriously.
When I saw it happen on
TV after your prediction,
I felt so sad, you know?
And it said that the U.S.
got the coordinates
completely wrong.
And by the time they warned the
Russians, it was just too late.
Was that you?
Were you the one who got the
coordinates completely wrong?
That was me.
I'm sorry.
Sorry that it happened.
Thank you.
Thank you for your kind words.
Hey, Brian, Meredith?
Can I borrow you guys
for a second?
I want you to tell me all
about what you saw
when that meteor struck, yeah?
Hey, Mara, why do't
you go radio base
and tell them w'll be here
about another hour?
Copy that.
You okay?
Yeah.
I just want to get this sample.
But if 'm being
completely honest...
this whole Russia thing
is still haunting me.
Sorry.
I don't mean to dump
all of this on you.
I know yo're here
just to learn.
Uh... Dr. Armstrong?
Mm-hm?
I don't mean
to overstep my bounds.
But for what it's worth,
your theories are taught
all over the world.
Your husband, Michael,
just got promoted
for helping redesign
a nuclear launch system
and you get to work
with him every day.
If I even had a fraction
of those things,
I'd think my life
was pretty incredible.
Thank you, for all of that.
Okay, i's time to focus
on the task at hand, huh?
All right.
So I need you to put these on.
I want you to monitor the meteor
cloud as I take the sample.
I've never done this before.
You said you want to work
in this industry, right?
Absolutely.
Well, right now we need
to make sure that
this meteor shower
isn't a meteor storm
or something more dangerous.
Okay, put these on.
I'll walk you through it.
Okay, so the first setting
is just your basic telescope
that you look
through the lens.
The second rendering
closes the aperture
and gives you a
real VR rendering
from the Pentagon's database
in real time.
Here you go.
Try that on.
Oh, wow!
This is incredible!
I's like 'm standing
above earth's orbit.
Yeah. Pretty cool.
And the third setting
just freezes the frame
and gives you
an interactive model.
But you don't need to worry
about that right now.
What I need from you is
to tell me if you see
meteor dust in the center
of that meteor cloud or
if it's something solid
like an object.
Oh, it kind of just
looks like a blob,
like it keeps shifting
and changing around.
But I can't really focus on it.
Okay.
Well, reach out your hand
and pull up the menu bar
on the right hand side.
Squeeze your wrist
and open it up, okay?
And what is the density in the
center of that meteor cloud?
Um, six objects
per square mile.
Six?
Yes, it says six.
Do you remember
how to do a process?
Yeah, I can do that.
Okay, okay.
Okay.
There you go.
Hey, Gwen?
Wha's the ETA on that sample?
Uh, 30 seconds.
Okay.
I don't understand why
he keeps rushing you.
Maybe if he'd given
you more time on
your spectral imaging
theory in Russia,
all of those people would't
have gotten hurt.
No. I had enough time.
But your spectral
imaging theory revolutionized
the way we do things
in the industry. I mean...
Do you remember
that asteroid
that we found off
the observatory in Hawaii?
Yeah, it was 40,000 miles
off of earth.
Mm-hm.
Well, we found it
because of Kurt's algorithms.
H's the best
at projecting algorithms.
Wha's that process say?
59% iron and 31% silicates.
Both iron and silicates
are fully crystallized.
But if Dr. Siegel
ran his algorithm tests
on something better,
something worthwhile
like the Braeburg Effect?
I don't think that
Anton Braeburg is someone
that you should want to
model your career after.
H's kind of a laughing stock of
the science community right now.
Okay.
Hey, what's the core
temperature?
400 degrees.
Are you sure?
Yeah, it says 400.
Um, okay.
W've got to take
another sample.
That ca't be right.
Hey, Gwen, how we coming
on that sample?
Uh, 30 seconds.
What is that, Gwen?
I's a composite drill,.
I's a a combination of a
diamond and a laser.
It can cut through anything.
W've got to get this back
to base immediately.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Hey, guys!
A.M.S. site just
reported meteor made ground fall
12 miles due south.
We gotta go. Come on.
We have to get to base now!
This is much worse
than we thought.
I'll check in with NWS.
No!
Oh, no!
- You okay?
- I'm fine! I'm fine!
Just get us out of here! Go!
Get us out of here.
Where's Gwen?
Gwen!
Come on!
Kurt!
Where did you get this car?
Owner got killed
by a meteorite.
Go, go, go!
No!
Oh, no.
Beth is back there.
No, Beth!
Beth is back there!
- We gotta go back!
- Beth is gone, Gwen!
Gwen, Beth is gone.
Leave her!
Damn it.
There's no signal.
There's no signal anywhere!
Mara, what do you got?
What do you know?
Last update I got
was one minute ago.
Meteor strike outside of Dublin.
This thin's global.
Oh, my God.
Do you have anything?
No, the network's jammed.
You know what?
Let me try the satellite radio.
Oh, my God!
Reverse! Reverse!
- Go back!
- Go, go, go!
Go!
Good, good, good.
Mara!
Okay, that was close.
Everybody take a breath.
W're okay.
We made it.
- Okay. You okay?
- Yeah.
Guys, if the ground fall
spans the entire hemisphere,
there's no way the Pentagon got
off a full response, no way.
You know, the're
definitely gonna add
a Level Five nuke strike
for good measure.
Probably.
Well, if they've
already launched Level Five,
then we're too late.
Because those meteors
will detonate those nukes
long before i'll reach
the asteroid.
Then we'll have nothing
left to destroy it.
What about NASA, JPL, GSS?
The've had to have
seen something!
No one can see it.
I's hidden inside
the meteor cloud. Remember?
I's the needle in a haystack.
- I know.
- Hey, we just need to get there
and we need to tell them
to stop a Level Five.
Stop a Level Five?
The're not gonna react to us.
The're gonna think we're giving
flawed data because of Russia!
And if we need proof,
we do't have it.
So what are we gonna do?
I don't know, Mara.
This contradicts
my entire threat matrix.
I'm at a loss.
Gwen, help me out!
Okay. First things
first, okay?
We have to make sure that
they launch the EMOD, okay.
The evacuations, meteor shield,
the ordinance and
the orbital drones, okay?
And then, Kurt, you know what?
I want you to take that this.
Flag the center of the mass
in the meteor cloud.
Mark it as an APB and
let all the departments know.
At least that'll give
them a fighting chance
at least of IDing it.
I got it. Got it.
Okay? Good.
Okay, keep driving.
And Level Five?
As far as Level Five,
Kur's right.
The're not gonna delay
a threat response.
And if we want them
to stop the launch then,
the data needs
to come from somebody else,
someone like Michael.
H's now Lieutenant Colonel
and h's got
nuclear defense clearances.
Yeah, but even if the order
comes down from him,
he still has to get vetted
by Singh wh's at base.
Yeah, and Singh's not stupid.
H's gonna know that order
is coming from you, Gwen.
Not if he breaks
the chain of command
and goes straight
to the Pentagon, okay?
There's no vetting, there's no
agencies, there's no red tape.
Michael still blames
me for Russia, Gwen.
H's gonna think your
breaking protocol
to save time for some
back intel I gave you.
Look, we all know
whose fault Russia was.
It wasn't yours.
I love him, but today h's
just gonna have to get over it.
Yeah, well, what if
Michael's unable to do it?
Well, if he's unable to do
it, then you know what?
I'm going to take
the spec rendering
straight to the Colonel,
straight to the
Command room right at base.
Right.
We have to stop
this launch, okay?
So just get us to the base
and I'll get the proof.
Yes, ma'am.
W'll get you there.
- Michael?
- Gwen?
There's a two-mile
wide asteroid hidden inside
this meteor storm.
W've got approximately
two hours and 29 minutes
until it hits.
Any nuclear response needs to
be saved to strike the asteroid.
Gwen, you know
I can't do that.
Colonel Singh has to approve
any protocol changes.
I mean, I can
flag incoming threats
on the defense database system.
But I need a commanding
officer to clear it.
But none of the other agencies
can see the asteroid!
Michael, this is the worst
case scenario.
The only reason I know
i's there is because
I was able to examine
this mornin's meteorite.
What is that?
Meteor debris.
Shouldn't be that big.
It is.
Oh, my gosh!
I's creating a dust cloud.
Keep going!
Keep driving!
No, no, no, no, no!
- Damn it!
- Oh, no.
Oh, no.
Are you okay?
Wha's going on?
Yeah, yeah, I'm okay.
I's just that our
vehicle stalled.
Meteor debris
choked out the engine.
Oh, no.
Damn it!
Well, let's go fix it.
Okay...
Okay, okay.
What do you think it is?
I's the belt chain.
Belt chain.
Okay.
Gwen, you gotta get
out of there right now.
This meteor storm is escalating!
The DOD has already approved
a Level Five launch
and there's gonna be a meteor
shower right in your area.
Get out!
Michael, listen to me.
I can't stop this nuke strike,
but you can.
Defense protocols
are cleared
for rank Lieutenant Colonel
and above.
Okay, call General Ambrose
at the Pentagon
and tell him it was
you who personally
identified this
as an asteroid.
We have to save the nukes
for the asteroid!
I'm not gonna lie
to a commanding officer!
It is't a lie.
I's a mass inside a cloud
that you or anyone
can see easily on radar.
It just has't been
IDed as an asteroid yet.
The observatories
can't tell what it is
and the DOD isn't
listening to me.
Is this from some intel
that Mara gave you?
No, Michael.
You can confirm it personally.
I's as if you've captured
the dimensions
through
spectral imaging, okay?
You're asking me to stop a
nuclear strike in mid-launch?
W're gonna leave
the whole planet
vulnerable to
a meteor storm.
If you launch that strike,
this storm will detonate
every one of those nukes
before it reaches the asteroid.
Only use conventional weapons
on the meteors.
The drones have plasma
cannons that can melt tanks.
And the satellite missiles?
Well, the're bunker busters.
And the meteor shield
is woven crystallized carbon.
And if the nukes strike
in the upper atmosphere,
w're talking fallout
on a global scale.
At its current heading,
the nukes will strike it
right outside the mesosphere.
Fallout will be high enough just
like any other nuclear test.
Gwen...
I could go to prison
for the rest of my life.
We both could.
There's no time!
Break the chain of command!
Okay?
You have to stop this launch!
Michael, you have to believe me!
Wha's our mark?
Two hours, 16 minutes,
south-southwest.
I love you.
So yo're a mechanic.
Tha's nice.
I got it.
You got it.
Right.
Yeah, come on.
This just in: the
Geological Society of America
is now weighing in on
the growing threat of what
is now being called a
"Meteor Storm".
Reported gravitational anomalies
and impact zones
are stirring up
geologic activity,
including hot zones of volcanic
activity in our national parks.
Carbon dioxide, monoxide and
methane levels in the atmosphere
are spiking nationwide.
This is beginning to impact
the wildlife in the area,
with reported injuries
and deaths being seen
as far north as Canada.
The Department of Defense
is involved as well as the U.N.
and NATO in preparation for
a potential nuclear strike
on the meteor storm.
Standby by for
further instructions
from the Emergency
Broadcast System
and in the meantime,
please remain indoors.
Wyoming!
I just received a terminate
signal from you!
Hang on!
I'm putting you on com!
There had better be a
good reason for this!
Sir, this is Lieutenant
Colonel Michael Armstrong, sir.
Under Colonel Singh in Wyoming.
I have full confirmation
of an incoming NEO
backed by radar GSS.
Incoming coordinates outlined
by radar are as follows:
tha's ID number 3200 Phaeton,
vector southwest, sir.
Sir, we need to stop Level Five
countdown immediately
and retain as a defense
against the asteroid.
We did not copy, Lieutenant!
Repeat, we did not copy!
I repeat!
We have an incoming NEO!
It will strike in T-minus
two hours, 16 minutes, sir!
We are aware of the
meteor storm, Lieutenant.
However, your alarm regards
a global response.
Is this signed off
by Colonel Singh?
Colonel Singh is
responding directly
to a situation
in the field, sir.
But I have direct orders
from the colonel
to terminate Level Five, sir.
Lieutenant, we have
all EMODs active!
Terminate Level Five, sir.
We are confirmed on
the meteor threat, Lieutenant!
I re...
abort le... Five, sir!
Level Five, abort!
Do you copy, General?
We are initiat...
Nice of you to join us,
Lieutenant Armstrong.
Apologies, sir.
It wo't happen again.
Daniels, what's the status
on the meteor shower?
Incoming,
Vector 20, Delta 909, Kentucky.
Incoming.
Vector 919, Epsilon 30,
South Dakota.
Washington confirms
drones are in place,
meteor shield deployed,
orbital missiles engaged.
Level Five Strike at
T minus three minutes.
We have a terminate
switch active
on our global response, sir.
Is this accurate?
This phon's dead.
Get me Ambrose on the line.
Yes, sir.
This is gonna be a long
day, Daniels.
Armstrong, what's the status
on that phone?
IT is working on it, sir.
We should be back up
in a few minutes.
We are still on track
for launch.
Nuclear response in T minus
2 minutes 30 seconds.
Even if we ca't get in touch
with the Pentagon,
we are following our last
known orders.
Daniels, check the targeting
array is still aligned.
Sir, we have a
full system crash
in the western half of the U.S.!
Colonel, we just severed
our apparatus to the Pentagon.
Our missile systems for the
whole region are failing.
Sir, what did you do?
Lieutenant Armstrong,
step away from the com
and disarm now!
Private Daniels, get DOD
back online
to initiate that
launch right now.
Sir, all of our coms are down.
Our landline and
backup feed are down.
Lieutenant Colonel Armstrong
crashed the system, sir.
Subdue him now!
Get the system back online!
Daniels, get me communication
with the Pentagon now.
I's our new
guidance system, sir!
Armstrong cut off
half the country,
and a meteor just struck our
bas's satellite dish, sir.
Okay. Repair the dish and
run an auxiliary patch
straight to our ground lines.
You may have just killed
millions of people.
Stick him in Holding
or 'll kill him myself.
Colonel! I had no choice but
to cancel the Level Five!
You just severed our
defenses to a global threat!
I confirm when to call off a
nuclear strike!
I will skin him alive for this!
Sir, EMOD live
and engaging targets.
All nuclear
capable countries have confirmed
participation Level Five.
Give me a Level Five mark.
We are live.
Targe's engaged.
Okay.
Give me a real time kill ratio.
Keep me appraised Level Five.
Standing by for kill ratio
and Level Five standing by.
Have we restored communication
with the Pentagon?
ETA, 30 seconds, sir.
EMOD kill ration at 6%
and climbing. 7%. 8%.
Gwen, check with VR,
see wha's happening.
Did the meteor shield deploy?
Mm-hmm.
Looks like we still have
incoming meteors!
Level Five launch
in T minus 30, 29,
28, 27,
26, 25...
Gwen?
The meteors are still
coming through.
Wha's going on
out there?
All batteries are deployed.
Defense systems are firing
but tha's not enough.
Oh, shoot.
18, 17, 16...
15, 14, 13, 12...
Phalanx one through four down!
Phalanx eight through 12 down!
Launch orthogonal 90 degrees!
Sir, nuclear assets
in the entire
western hemisphere are offline.
It seems like
the've been crashed
from a program out of Wyoming.
Do we have backup?
Launch backup as soon
as it's live!
Gwen, wha's
the status on that response?
Only 12% of the meteors
have been destroyed.
Twelve percent.
Still no sign of
the nukes.
East Coast backup system
is restored!
T minus 0 and launch.
East Coast is go.
Russia is go!
India is go!
U.S. arsenal, 50%.
No!
No, no, no, no!
What? What? What?
What is it?
The nukes.
The've detonated the nukes!
I have VR confirmation
that they've launched
from the East Coast along with
all the other nuclear countries!
This is Dr. Armstrong.
Come in.
Wha's our percentage of
airborne nuclear missiles?
50%.
All other countries have
launched their full arsenal.
Orbital weapons?
All ordinance and drones
are completely destroyed.
W've also lost four out of 20
of our communication satellites.
The only thing we have left
is the shield, sir.
Yeah?
Michael, why did you let
them launch the nukes?
Dr. Armstrong, your husband
has been arrested
for a breach of
national security.
His attempt to take down
the nuclear guidance system
was stopped but we were only
able to fire half our payload.
Colonel, sir?
I assure you that Michael was
just forwarding the message...
If yo're involved in
any way in any of this,
you will never see
light of day again.
Now return to base immediately
and report to me in Command.
Michael's been arrested
and Singh wants me to report
to the Command Center
as soon as we arrive.
But you can't report to Singh!
If he has you arrested,
you're done!
W're all done!
Mar's absolutely right.
I can run predictive
algorithms all day long.
But spectral imaging, that is
your area of expertise, Gwen.
By the time I compile the data,
it would be too late.
Her's what we're gonna do.
As soon as we arrive
at the security checkpoint,
I want you to report
your injuries.
Under Code Blue, they cannot
arrest any injured personnel.
Right.
The'll definitely have
MPs looking for you
all over the medical bay.
I imagine they will, but 'll
find my way to the lab, okay?
I'll get the proof and 'll
meet Singh in Command Center.
Got it.
Defense alarm.
Hey, what have we got?
No!
No, no, no.
The strike is complete, sir.
All nuclear weapons
from all countries
have detonated in orbit, sir.
Wha's our kill percentage?
25%, sir.
What?
Tha's not possible!
Meteor shield taking
heavy fire, sir!
Sir, the entire shiel's
coming apart!
Son of a bitch.
I'm good, I'm good, I'm good.
Let's go. Where is everybody?
Why are there no guards?
I's protocol to secure
all personnel
inside the facility
during a launch.
Looks like the cameras
are down. Thanks, Michael.
Code Blue!
Where's the OR?
OR? Why?
What happened?
Please!
I've lost a lot of blood!
- How? What happened?
- I was hit by a meteor!
Come on!
We do't have time!
- Where do you need to go?
- OR!
Come on.
Code orange is now in effect.
All medical personnel report
to your designated
emergency response locations.
I'm all right,
I'm all right.
Oh, God, I should wrap this up.
Yeah, I'm okay.
Don't worry about me.
- Give us a minute, please!
- Thank you.
I'm fine, I'm fine.
Just get the gauze.
Wrap me up.
We gotta go.
Just grab anything.
Wha's wrong with you?
- I'm fine.
- Mara, what happened?
I'm fine.
All right, come here.
You have to help me.
- Hold on.
- All right.
Are you sure yo're all right?
Okay. Sit down.
I'm sorry.
I's all right.
Just a quick wrap.
- We gotta go.
- I know.
Mara, you sure
you're all right?
I'm fine.
Hey, thank you.
Yeah.
We have to go talk
to Colonel Singh.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Let's go see Singh.
Okay, all right.
Let's get you going.
Pop up.
Where's the screen here?
There.
All right, so...
Tha's good.
And these coordinates.
47...
Nine...
Okay.
This database.
Around the meteor cloud,
the density.
600...
Let's find you.
Officer Pritchard.
Dr. Siegel.
Colonel Singh, sir.
As soon as the storm passes,
we will be disbanding
your department.
The incoming is so heavy,
we can barely get damage
report from the field.
Colonel, sir!
Dr. Armstrong thought
the threat was big enough.
She doesn't give orders!
I give orders!
Where is Gwen Armstrong?
Sir, she left us as soon
as we arrived.
Well, she needs to be here
at this com
to be questioned
by me personally!
People are dead
and dying, Dr. Siegel!
- Sir.
- Officer Pritchard?
Sir, 've been working
the field with Dr. Armstrong
for over seven years now
and her input concerning
this storm
is critical to our survival.
Mm-hm.
I'm aware of your work
with Dr. Armstrong.
Her husband has't
been shy about reporting
your failures in Russia.
Here...
There.
There you are.
Yep. I knew it!
Okay, okay.
Yep.
You know what?
Gwen Armstrong has been flagged
as a national security risk.
And I cannot have her
wandering this base.
Colonel, sir, you must
let her complete her testing
- before you speak...
- Dr. Siegel, I respect you
and I'm trying
to respect your team.
But after the Russia incident
and today's failed
orbit defense,
you are no longer cleared
to advise this base.
Are you with me?
Where's the power reserve?
The last impact carried
an electromagnet pulse!
The reserve power's
offline, sir.
Engineering's en route
right now to repair it.
And the communications?
Engineering's running
a dedicated line
to both the dish
and the Command Center
that goes all the way to D.C.
Engineering's doing
their best right now.
Sir, please.
Detaining Gwen
is a grave mistake.
No one is more steeped in
this research than she is.
We are dealing with
global threats right now,
not on Gwen Armstrong's latest
free-association.
- You're team is relieved.
- I's an asteroid!
I have proof,
undeniable proof.
I just needed to wait
for the information
to come in to create
a spectral image.
There over 100 observatories.
The observatories
can't see it.
And it wo't show up on radar
until it emerges out of
meteor cloud that's covering.
And then it's gonna hit earth.
I don't see how
a rainbow reflected back
from a meteor cloud can create
an image like this, doctor.
We kept picking up
a dense section on our radar.
It failed to yield
anything definitive,
but I knew that something
was acting on these meteors,
slowing them down.
So I took a sustained
spectrometer reading and...
There it is.
So yo're telling us
this asteroid
is cloaked
by its own meteor shower?
This is the sun, okay?
During it's last perihelion,
Phaeton was knocked off course,
causing it to go back
into the meteor trail.
When it finally caught
up with the meteors,
it exerted its own
gravitational force,
causing the meteors to slow down
and making them safe
to actually enter into
our own atmosphere,
which is what's causing
the meteor storm outside.
So even if we were to
destroy all of the meteors,
we still have a 2.6-mile
asteroid to destroy.
Where will it strike?
Difficult to say,
which is why Dr. Siegel
has run a sequencing
algorithm. Kurt?
Its trajectory places
it on the northernmost tip
of Manitoba, 1,538 miles
west of the bay.
Fortunately, I was able
to upload its vector
to a priority list before
the last power outage.
I's far from
a populated area.
That does't matter, sir.
The force will be equivalent
to one million Hiroshimas.
So that's why you fought
so hard to stop Level Five?
Exactly.
Now with what we have,
we need a surgical response.
- Surgical?
- Mara?
We have about
2,000 warheads left.
At 50 megatons each,
tha's 100,000 megatons,
- 50,000 per stage of attack.
- Good.
So it has't reached
a million megatons yet.
We need to use half
of our remaining nukes
to dissipate the meteor cloud,
then shoot the other
half straight
at the asteroid to destroy it.
Sir, we're back online.
All systems are active.
Daniels, you need to get
Joe Ambrose on the phone.
And, you, go get your husband.
Copy that.
Michael?
Oh my God.
- What are you doing here?
- Oh, God.
I was so scared.
I was so afraid
you got hurt out there.
Is there any update?
They need you in Command.
W've proven that
there's an asteroid.
Is Colonel Singh working
with the Pentagon?
He is and he needs
you and me, the entire team.
- Come on.
- Let's go.
Let's go.
Sir, we just
received a priority alert
on the data cloud.
So has every other
major observatory
across three continents.
Who's sending this out?
NASA, JPL, AMS and FEMA
just forwarded it
from our base in Wyoming.
I's a live vectoring model.
What do the vectors target?
We do't know, sir.
I's a field, sir,
with precise measurements,
2.18 miles,
1.31 miles, 2.62.
I have Ambrose
on the line, sir.
Ah...
General Ambrose?
I's Colonel Singh. Wyoming.
Our research team just confirmed
a million megaton, sir.
Mm-hm.
We have a Near Earth Object
with all intel
uploaded to DOD's data.
General!
W're calling for a two-stage...
Phew!
General, we have to
launch these missiles now!
Phaeton's gravitation field is
accelerating the meteor shower.
I's only gonna get worse!
This whole place
is gonna blow!
Sir! Wyoming has been hit!
Without the orbital shield,
Phaetho's projecting
meteors straight at us.
Do we have any communication?
Sir, we have a signal, but
it keeps cutting in and out.
Colonel Singh would't
have called
unless he was requesting
a severe response.
Keep working to get the
remaining of our nukes operable.
Copy that, sir.
All right, the main
evacuation rout is this way.
Come on.
Oh, we ca't leave until
we make sure that Ambrose
has the proper information.
We ca't stay, Gwen.
The base has been compromised.
I's too dangerous.
Come on!
I need to see this through.
Okay, I'm not leaving until
I'm sure that
the're gonna launch everything
according to plan.
Sir! Come on!
We have to evacuate
to Washington now!
Gwen, we need to leave now.
Please?
Michael, no!
You okay?
Yeah, yeah.
- Okay, where do we go?
- Okay.
All right, we need to exit back
through the Command Room.
- Come on.
- Okay. Let's go.
You okay?
Yeah. You?
Michael, wher's
the Control Room?
Straight this way.
All right.
W'll go through the wall.
W're not going
through that wall.
Tha's solid concrete
six inches thick.
W'll cut straight
through with this, hm?
Almost there.
- You through?
- Yep.
- Go for it.
- Here goes nothing!
Yep.
- Good.
- Nice job.
The roo's collapsed here, too.
We can get there through
the annex bridge.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
Thanks.
This way!
Wyoming!
Go for Ambrose!
General, this is
Gwen Armstrong.
Do you have a
confirmed target?
I's an asteroid, sir.
Two-square miles.
I've sent you all
the data.
What is the ETA to impact?
One hour and 15 minutes.
The strike requires
a two-step response,
50% into the meteor cloud
and 50% directly into
the asteroid.
No! Gwen!
Whoa!
Babe, you okay?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You?
Yeah.
Go! Get to the entrance!
Mara, go, go, go, go!
Just get to the entrance!
I'll come.
- Colonel, go!
- Go, just go! Go!
Help the others,
I'm right behind you.
Gwen, come on, baby!
Okay, okay, w're coming.
Oh, man.
Come on!
Gwen, come on!
Here! Take my hand.
Come on! Let go of the bag!
No!
I can lift you!
I shoul've listened
to you from the start.
Oh...
All right,
ladies and gentlemen.
Our two-mile wide field
is an incoming asteroid.
Sir, are we talking
about the one
that disappeared behind the sun?
Phaeton?
Tha's affirmative.
We need to use the rest
of our nukes
on a stage-two
Level Five response.
We need to set our
targeting system
so that the first wave
of nukes all hit
the exact same spot
of the meteor cloud.
That will create a compound
wave to dissipate the cloud
and reveal the bigger asteroid
so we can target it.
Tha's brilliant, sir!
This is Gwen Armstron's plan,
and yes it is.
Sir? We just lost two more
communication satellites.
But we do have communication
with other surviving bases.
Prepare for the first wave!
Yes, sir.
Stand by!
Level Five!
Level Five is go.
50% response! Go!
Heat signature at 4%, 2%.
Sir, it's working!
The cloud is beginning
to dissipate.
Heat signature one percent.
Level Five, stage two!
Target that asteroid.
50% Go!
The asteroid is still intact.
The nukes were ineffective, sir.
They were unable to make
contact with target.
Damn it!
Impact estimated
at 38 minutes.
Make sure the President,
Congress
and Joint Chiefs of
Staff are evacuated
- to the Doomsday Bunker.
- Yes, sir!
We are now being informed
that the mission
to destroy the incoming
asteroid was unsuccessful.
A general evacuation order
has been issued
for the entire East Coast
of the United States.
W've also received word
that the presiden's motorcade
is being redirected to the Raven
rock bunker in Pennsylvania.
God help us all.
Gwen?
- Gwen!
- No! We have to go!
No! W're not having another
Russia incident!
Michael, with all due respect,
you were not there!
She did what she was
supposed to be doing.
Did she? She had 15 minutes
before that order came in
to ground those planes!
Gwen! Are you okay?
I gave her
the orders, Michael.
It was my fault, okay?
We were supposed
to meet Kurt in Russia!
I'm the one that told her
to stay behind.
It was my fault, Michael.
She stayed because of me.
Well, they didn't have to
pin the whole thing on you.
Michael...
Okay! How much time
do we have left, Gwen?
We have 34 minutes.
And we already launched
Phase One and Phase Two
of the nukes, right?
So what's Plan B, guys?
Plan B is we make
our way to the airfield
about a mile from here.
Now there's two birds
on the ground.
We evac to safety, all of us!
No, no, no.
W're not gonna evacuate yet.
Look, there could be
a solution here.
I's a long shot,
but it could work.
The Braeburg Effect.
Braeburg?
Come on, Gwen, enough of that!
You know he's a laughing
stock of our community!
Okay, but, Kurt,
listen to me, okay?
The last few hours,
I've been noticing
that all this meteor impact
has displaced methane
into the atmosphere.
When you add
an electrical force to methane
it turns into plasma vapor.
Now the tests I took this
morning of that meteor,
it proves that it
has magnetic force.
So if we somehow find
6,000 megawatts of electricity
and create an electrical arc
up into the atmosphere,
it could actually displace
that electromagnetic force
and then....
And the nukes
and the meteors
and the asteroid all
crashing together.
Yes, and destroy them.
Okay, I understand that,
but where are we gonna get that
power, that wattage?
We do't have that.
There's a power plant
not far from the airfield.
Can we use that?
Yes, but we would
need some sort of...
A massive controlled
explosion!
Exactly.
One of those F-35s has
to be stocked with missiles.
Okay, okay.
Let's go to the hangar!
Let's go! Let's go!
Okay, let's get
to the airfield!
Let's go!
Come on, come on!
Okay, the base
is through the field!
For those of you at home
or hopefully
having found shelter,
we have an update
from Pentagon officials.
Raging fires are widespread
throughout North America
as a result of
the massive meteor shore.
Hundreds of thousands of home
have been damaged or destroyed.
Injuries and deaths are
estimated to be in the hundreds.
The national weather service is
now reporting that this storm
is due to a
gravitational slowdown
from inside of the meteor cloud,
caused by
two-mile-wide Phaethon asteroid
which is due to impact
Earth within the hour.
Come on, guys!
Come on! Come on!
Come on!
Let's go! Come on!
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Come on! Move it! Move it!
Let's go, Kurt. Come on!
Whoa!
Come on! Come on!
Let's go!
This way, this way!
Whoa!
Okay! I can see it!
Another 300 yards
and w're there!
Let's go! Come on!
Move, move, move!
Keep moving!
Down, down, down!
Get down! Down!
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Okay, okay.
Mara, you scour this field.
Find that jet.
Let's just pray
that puppy is armed
with striking capabilities.
I got it.
Now this incoming
w're experiencing,
I can only imagine
is gonna get worse.
So, Kurt, you go with her.
You ensure her success, okay?
- Yeah.
- Okay?
- Copy that.
- All right.
Gwen and I are gonna
locate a power source.
The transformer is on
the other side of the
airfield, due west.
Okay, perfect.
Meet back here.
Okay, go! Go! Go!
Gwen, come on!
Okay, go! Go!
Go! Go!
Okay, okay.
Gwen? Come on.
There!
There it is.
I see it! Let's go!
Okay.
Okay, go.
Okay. Hand me the iPad, Gwen!
All right.
Oh, God!
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- Here you go, Michael.
Hold it.
Okay.
- You got it?
- Yeah.
Okay.
Oh!
Please make this fast, okay?
I'm trying, I'm trying,
I'm trying.
- W're in!
- Okay.
Okay.
My security clearance should
give me access to the main grid.
Okay, I'm redirecting
all kilowatts
within a 100-mile radius
to transformer 47.
Okay. 47.
What are those coordinates,
Michael?
Give me a minute.
Ah!
Are you okay?
Are you having fun yet, doc?
Am I having fun?
You're crazy.
Come on. Come on, Mara.
Come on.
Come on, Mara.
Almost there, come on.
Okay. You're okay.
There's the entrance
to the hangar.
Let's go, go, go, go!
Got'em!
Sending to you now!
- Okay, great.
- You got'em.
Plugging those in, the equation.
Let's see if this works.
Put that here.
Put this...
So with that frequency,
those coordinates,
that dimension,
at that speed...
What do you got, baby?
This is gonna work...
Michael, it's gonna work.
Okay.
- Come on, Gwen! Come on!
- We gotta go!
Let's go!
W're gonna have
to taxi this jet.
Yeah.
Who's the chauffer now?
Mara?
There's no missiles.
We gotta go tell 'em.
Let's go tell'em.
Come on.
Come on
Damn it.
Come on.
Mara! Kurt!
F-35, end of the tarmac.
- 10% fuel.
- I's okay.
Gwen, there's no missiles.
Shit!
- Um...
- Tha's it.
What?
I's over.
There's nothing we can do.
There's got to be.
Okay.
There's nothing
left we can do!
The jet becomes the missile.
By taking off,
the jet becomes the missile.
I just take off and fly it
straight up into the air
and come down at Mach speed
to that electrical plant
and hit it right in the
center...
Gwen, what are
you talking about?
No on's getting
inside that jet!
Tha's a suicide mission!
And you know what?
There's gotta be another way!
You're not thinking straight.
No.
No on's getting into that jet!
I's over.
Just get me into the sat com.
I'll figure it out.
Just link to help me back up
with the nukes.
Okay, you can do that
through the computer.
Here we go.
The fuel is at 10%.
- Gwen? Gwen!
- Gwen! Gwen!
Michael stop, she's gone.
Her best bet will be
to parachute into an open field
We gotta get to an open field.
We gotta get to an open field!
Come on, le's go!
Move it!
- Let's go find an open field!
- Come on, come on!
Initiate flight sequencing.
On, engaged.
Engine one, on.
Flight time: three minutes.
Let's do this.
Okay, come here!
She's gotta land here, okay?
This is the only spot
that she can land.
All right.
Gwen, do you copy?
I read you five
by five, Michael.
Engine engaged.
Sir, our radar is
detecting an object
moving the speed of sound
flying up out of Wyoming.
- Do we have an ID on it?
- No.
We do't know
what it is yet, sir.
Starting ascent.
Gwen!
Come in, Gwen!
Gwen, come in!
Looks like it's one of ours,
sir, an F-35.
One minute, three seconds.
T-minus 1 minute.
Engaging F35 dive
in 5, 4,
3, 2, 1, now!
Gwen, you get outta there!
You make sure you get
outta there, Gwen!
Gwen, do you copy?
Make sure you get outta there!
Come on, Gwen.
45 seconds!
I'm getting high level
radiation warnings.
Damn it, come on.
Really starting to feel
the Gs, here.
Ejecting in 10, 9...
Eight, seven, six...
Five...
four...
Three...
Gwen, do you copy?
One.
They did it!
The target!
The target has been neutralized!
You heard correctly,
ladies and gentlemen!
The asteroi's been destroyed!
W're clear!
W're all clear!
Oh, my God.
Lieutenant Armstrong,
we can confirm
Phaeton has been eliminated.
Is your wife all right?
Where is she?
Gwen!
Lieutenant Armstrong!
Do you copy?
Where is she?
General, this is Dr. Siegel,
no sign of her yet.
Where is she?
There!
We have a visual on
Dr. Armstrong, sh's alive!
She made it!
Woo! Woo!
She's coming in for a landing.
Oh...
Hey, doc.
You're crazy.
I had to.
What was the probability
of that happening, huh?
We did it.
You're crazy... you're crazy.
You did it...
Dr. Braeburg.
Shh. The world does't
need to know.
- The world needs to know.
- No, no, no.
No. The world is safe now.
Kurt! Mara!
Woo! Woo!
What a team!
Well done, Colonel... sir.
Phew!
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org