Oh, hey.
Welcome to Danny's house.
I was just having the most
craziest vivid dream.
I was getting married,
and the reception got ruined
for some reason.
I thought everybody
would be cool with it,
but they got pissed.
So, I jumped out the window
to escape.
Then I started getting chased
by this gigantic spider.
Then the spider's teeth
fell out,
which,
according to dream analysis,
that means he's insecure.
Then I got worried.
What if I was
in a spider's dream?
Man, what does
dream mean anyway?
Are we in a dream right now?
Are we always dreaming?
Probably not.
Aaaaaaaaaaah!
Whoa, that was crazy, man.
I just had a dream I was doing
the opening for my show,
and I had lobster claws
for hands.
More cheap props?!
Aaaaaaaaaaah!
I'm not doing this shit again.
Feed it to the cats.
Oui, oui, oui!
You never wrote jokes?
I never sat down and wrote.
But you're going to put them
together in your head? Yeah.
Like Jay-Z?
Exactly.
I was just in jail dreaming
about jacking off.
A jack off within a jack off
within a jack off.
Within a jack off.
Damn.
Everybody has fun
at Danny's house.
Hey, what's up, Chef Hat?
You ever dream?
Ah, bonjour, Danny.
It has always been my dream
to be on the head
of the greatest chef in Europe,
but I realized,
I could be the greatest chef
in Europe,
so I got myself a chef hat.
My dream was to be
Chef Hat's chef hat.
Man, that's great.
I guess you guys are living
your dream then.
Chef, you got a favorite food?
Ah, I wish I had a favorite food
but alas,
I have no taste buds
and no stomach.
That does not sound healthy.
Oh, please, Danny,
tell me what food tastes like.
I mean...
Well, I guess some stuff good,
but some stuff, I don't like.
Ooh, that vague description
is making my mouth water,
Monsieur Danny.
Wait, wait.
I thought you said
you ain't had taste buds?
I...
I do not.
But if I could eat anything,
it would be a dish
from beautiful scenic Austria.
Well, I ain't never been
to Austria before.
Allow me to take you there
through your taste buds,
Monsieur.
What I have prepared
for you today
is the traditional
Vienna sausage.
Man, that just looked
like you opened up
a can of little sausages
and dumped them on a plate.
How **** dare you!
I slave in this kitchen
night and day,
and you just come over here
and act like you work for Zagat!
Do you know hard it was for me,
a chef hat without
any arms, or legs, or feet
to accomplish
this culinary feat?
You know, I could have been
a chef hat at P. Diddy's,
but I said, "No!
Let me go to Danny's house,"
and what do I get for it?
All manner of disrespect!
If you ever insult me or one
of my special cuisines again,
I will **** end you!
Okay! Okay, man!
I was wrong, man!
Oh!
You are too kind, Danny.
Save some for your first guest -
acclaimed comedian and actor,
the toast of Vienna,
Gilbert Gottfried!
Oh, look,
it's Gilbert Gottfried!
What's up?
Yes, yes.
How are you doing?
Oh, Gilbert Gottfried!
I love to prepare for him.
We've been talking about dreams.
Do you have any weird dreams?
Well, there's -
there's the obligatory
being somewhere
without your pants on dream.
All dreams are weird.
Do you have any wet dreams?
Uh, well, no.
Those I like
when I'm wide awake.
You think people
have wet dreams about you?
Constantly.
I-I think -
I think everybody
who watches me.
Do you ever have dreams about
you doing stand-up?
I'll have those classic
actor's dream,
where it's, like,
a full-packed house,
and they can't remember
any of their lines.
You know, that happened
to me in real life.
I actually went on stage
and ready to do my thing,
and once I got out there,
literally my whole brain
just went blank.
Couldn't think of one word.
Couldn't think of one song.
Has something like that
ever happened to you?
I used to smoke
whatever it's called.
In my day, it was grass,
they called it. Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
We call it dope.
Kush.
And - Yes, and - Fire pack.
Get loud.
So I used to smoke that.
Mm-hmm.
Sometimes I would smoke
and have a drink
before I got onstage.
Mm-hmm.
I would write a bunch
of real funny things.
You think you're great
no matter what
you're doing there.
Yeah.
Then you look at it onstage,
and it's like, "hat sandwich,"
and it's like, "What?"
So I quit that.
So, do you think, like, dreams
mean anything?
Do you remember
those little books
that would define your dreams?
You'd look up, "Oh, if you dream
a bug is on you,
it means this."
I guess the crazy dream
like that,
in some sense,
like, I don't know.
I have, like, a random baby mama
I ain't never seen before.
Yes, that happens to me
all the time.
Yeah.
Random baby mamas.
Yeah, I'd be like,
"I've never seen this person
in my life,"
but then we have kids.
In fact, in the book...
And we doing all type of shit.
...it said, "If you dream
about a random baby mama..."
Baby mama!
What does that mean?
It means you like
to go roller skating.
Yeah.
I thought you were about
to say go raw dog.
Like, sometimes you have, like,
dumb, simple dreams.
Like, you could just dream of...
I don't know, just, like,
a boat floating in the ocean
with, like,
a piece of shit on it.
Ah, yes.
Freud used to talk about that.
That one dream everyone has...
is a boat floating in the ocean
with a piece of shit on it.
Yeah.
Yeah, you need to shit
on a boat.
Do you have, like,
nightmares and stuff?
I do.
One dream I had as a kid.
Okay.
When I eat a pizza,
I wouldn't eat the crust,
for some reason.
I tossed the crust away.
Mm-hmm.
And then I had a dream
that I was -
I think I was walking
through the park,
and all these crusts
of pizza jumped...
Attack of the pizza crust?
Yes!
Oh, my God.
And they were like snakes.
They had eyes and mouths.
So, why would they want
to... with you
when you were saving them?
I know. It's...
See, this is why...
pizza crusts are
very unappreciative.
When I was a kid,
February was, like,
a real hard month for me.
That's because it was
Black History Month,
and I would be in school,
and they would always show us
these civil rights movies
and shit every day.
Every day, mother...
getting bit by dogs,
spraying them
with hoses and shit,
and I would go home,
and I had to sleep
in a bed with my mama
'cause I would have nightmares.
Why was
Martin Luther King's dream
my nightmare?!
Yeah, well, I...
Yeah, I think they should get
rid of Black History Month...
...for that because it's -
it's -
It gives people bad dreams.
What do you think people in jail
dream about?
Uh...
not being in jail?
You ever wrote a joke
in your dream?
Not a good one.
Oh.
So, in that way, jokes are...
in my dreams are like my jokes
in real life.
You ever wonder what
celebrities dream sometime?
I wonder about it all the time.
I want to play a game with you
where I'm going
to show you a picture,
and I want you to tell me
what you think
this celebrity dream about.
Okay.
Check out this guy right here!
What you think
he's dreaming about?
Mark Zuckerberg!
He's dreaming about
what it would be like
to have an actual skin color.
He has the look
of a total loser,
but that guy could get any woman
on the planet.
I think he just dream about
mayo sandwiches for some reason.
Yeah.
Just wake up out of bed...
Something with no substance.
...just grab a mayo sandwich,
and put salt and pepper
on the top of it.
Ha! Next!
We got Gene Simmons.
What do you think
Gene Simmons dream about?
All the things he could have
been doing with that tongue
if he wasn't stupid enough
to get married
and have a family.
You think a mother...
with a tongue like that
want to be eating pussy
all the time?
I - I think just to show
how good you are at it.
Man, he's getting old.
That neck ain't holding up no more.
He just can't be waggling
that mother... around.
For some reason,
I just think Gene Simmons
just think about just being
the only man on Earth.
That's what he dream about.
He don't want no other niggas
around his bitches.
Next up!
Oh, shit.
We've got this mother...
What you think he dream about?
Um...
You want me to take this one?
Yeah, yeah,
you can take this one.
I think he dreams about being
in a big-ass white house
with a whole bunch of grass,
and just a whole bunch
of big booty black bitches.
Yeah, I just think he dream
about being a slave master.
I've had that dreams
a few times.
Haven't we all?!
Goddamn it! I'm black,
and I dream about that shit.
Gilbert Gottfried,
that was a great time.
I had a lot of fun talking
about dreams, man.
Thank you, man.
Bam! Bam!
Oh, perfect.
Ha! Ha!
Why exactly am I going up
to your bedroom?
This is very frightening.
Sherm!
I ain't order no pizza.
I know.
This is a surprise pizza
to celebrate
the 1-year anniversary
of the fourth time
I ever delivered pizza to you.
Most people don't
celebrate that.
Thank you, Danny.
So, because it's
a special occasion,
I made you your dream pizza.
Here it is -
a pepperoni, popcorn,
chicken nugget,
cookie center, T-bone steak
and Fruit Roll-Up crust pizza
with plastic army men on it
for decoration.
Sherm, that's got to be
the nastiest shit
I ever saw in my life.
Wow, Danny.
I appreciate the honesty.
Back to the old drawing board.
But please,
keep this dream pizza
as a souvenir of our friendship.
Maybe I should have
left the pepperonis off.
This pizza is nightmare.
Hold on, wait. No, wait.
Hold on, wait.
Oh, look who's here!
It's Quelle and Jean Grae.
Yoooooooo!
If you could jump in somebody's
dream, who would it be?
Oprah.
That's a good one.
It's Quelle and Jean Grae!
- What the... up?
- Nothing.
- How are y'all doing, man?
- Hi.
Oh, this is my favorite
married hip-hop couple -
Quelle Chris and Jean Grae.
I will go to fish market
and find some delicious food
for them,
so I must bid them adieu.
We've been talking about dreams.
Mm-hmm.
And I've been having
a lot of weird dreams lately,
man, recurring ones.
Do your teeth fall out?
You ever had the...
My teeth did fall out.
...that old...
That's why I had
to get them fixed.
Why did I ask him?
You all have any nightmares?
My nightmares are all,
like, about mediocrity.
It's, like, I can fly,
but I can only get,
like, as high as,
like, street lamps.
It's lame flying. Like, she can't really...
It's very lame.
Like, you feel like
you're getting a discount dream,
and it's like, I want the full dream.
Yeah, and I feel very mediocre.
My shit just be, like, a snap.
A snap.
It's, like, a snap,
then I wake up.
It's daylight and shit,
like, damn,
I don't even ever remember
even going to bed,
and if I do dream,
it's me cooking pork chops
or some dumb shit like that.
How many pork chops?
No, it's, like, a whole pack.
Hold on.
You should lean back. I think we should
unpack this. Yeah! How about this -
Yeah, 'cause what does
the pork chop dream really mean?
So, where you get
these pork chops from?
I go to the...
I go to the grocery store.
Oh, that's all in the dream?
Yeah!
Danny, your dreams
are so boring.
Mm-hmm.
Like, have you had
any weird dreams
where you hooked up
with somebody weird,
like Hillary Clinton
or something?
There was a period of dreams
where there was,
like, a few, like,
Muppets, like...
You was hooking up with Muppets?
No, no, I wasn't hooking up,
but they...
I was like, we're about
to find out a lot today, man.
No, no, no.
There were a few Muppets that,
like, had a crush on me.
Which ones?
Think it was Miss Piggy.
You sure it wasn't Gonzo?
He... the shit out
of somebody with that nose.
I don't never had
no dream like that.
So, what's the last dream
you can remember,
besides your pork chop dream?
The last dream I -
What stays with you?
The last time
I think I had a dream
was just went to sleep,
and then I woke up.
There was a piece of shit
on the bed.
No, no. See, okay.
I mean, it's a dream.
It's a dream.
It's a dream, so it doesn't matter.
No, but it wasn't a dream.
Oh, this wasn't a dream.
I thought I was dreaming, but I woke up...
Oh, the shit was real.
...and the shit was real.
Mm-hmm. But it wasn't my
shit, and I was by myself,
so where the shit come from?
So you were by yourself -
They have a conspiracy theory
saying I might have
pulled my pants down
and just shit on the bed,
but I was wearing
a motocross suit, too.
It's a lot to get out
of motocross suits.
Yeah, but you...
But now it's to the point
where I have dreams of that.
Right. So I wake up, like,
always in a panic, like, aah...
So you're having, like, a...
...and I'm looking for the shit.
...post-traumatic
shit disorder, yeah.
Mm-hmm, yeah.
Damn, dog.
We've definitely been
talking about this shit
for too long.
Yeah, no.
So, Quelle and Jean Grae,
I want to play a little game
with you guys.
Okay. We're going to
figure out how much
y'all mother...
really know each other.
Y'all want to do this, or what?
Yeah, I don't want that shit.
Not particularly,
but we're gonna.
We're gonna.
So, Jean Grae,
I got this nice
little sleep mask...
Oh, my gosh.
...personalized for you right here.
Okay, I'm in.
Come on, let's go.
Let's go.
Oh, no.
Quelle, you ready for this?
What up?
Who you think is
her celebrity dream crush?
Celebrity dream crush...
I feel like this one should be easy.
Damn, pass.
Let me get the next one. Let me
come back to it. No, you can't pass!
I can't... I mean, I'm-a come back to it.
You've got to answer something!
It's like -
It's like "Price is Right."
I'm-a come back to it.
You can't!
It's not the way
this game works, Quelle!
Oh, shit, I don't know.
I'm just going to say
Lionel Richie right now.
Lionel Richie?
Of course it's not.
I think she will be
very excited for that.
Lionel a cute mother...
He light-skinned and shit.
All right.
Who you think
her dream feature would be?
Like, who would she love
to collaborate and work with?
Um...
I'm having a brain fart
right now.
What's her name?
Used to play with like...
sing with Funkadelic
and all that?
Black chick, what's her name?
The... is her name?
What does she sing?
...it. Say...
Say old girl with the 'fro
that be doing
the funky-ass music.
Old girl with the 'fro that be
doing the funky-ass music.
That's a good answer.
Next!
Hit me.
What would her
four ingredients be
on her dream deli sandwich?
Shit, let's go with pastrami,
some mayo, some lettuce
and some, like,
a good, nice mustard
or something.
All right.
That was the last question.
Ain't going to lie.
It's a little sketchy.
We gonna see how this works out.
You ready for this
marriage counseling?
I feel like this is not
the show I signed up for.
I was like, "Shit,
I didn't come prepared."
No!
Should I be nervous?
Definitely.
Oh, God. All right.
So we're gonna
figure out how much
you mother...
know each other.
The first question was,
who is your dream celebrity crush?
Mm-hmm.
Jean, who you think
he said for you?
I always liked
the State Farm guy, Mayhem.
I said Lionel Richie.
He said Lionel Richie.
But I was just throwing
some shit out of there, yeah.
Oh, now you are!
All right.
Who would your dream feature be,
and who would you really love
to collaborate with?
Who do you think
he said for you?
It's Lionel Richie.
No, he said,
"Old girl with the afro
that do the funky shit."
You know who I'm talking about.
I was...
I was having a brain fart.
It's the truth.
We couldn't think of her name.
Old girl with the afro that...
Oh, my god.
The black lady.
Mad black ladies in the '70s
that got funky.
That is, like, every black woman...
No, no!
With the fro...
But I mean, I was thinking...
Oh, Betty Davis.
Betty Davis!
Betty Davis, okay.
Thank you, dog.
I mean, you guys are 0-2
right now, so...
All right.
Jean Grae,
what's the four ingredients
on your dream sandwich
from the deli?
Um, there's bacon.
Mm-hmm.
Pastrami, salami, a cheese,
maybe a pepper jack.
And you're just gonna eat that shit dry?
It's just meat and cheese.
It's just meat and cheese,
and maybe some mayo. Man!
You're gonna choke to death on this...
sandwich. Maybe some mayo.
Well, I said...
I did say, "pastrami,"
but then I said,
"A good mustard, a mayo,
lettuce or tomato
or some shit like that."
So just a pastrami sandwich,
pretty much.
Yeah, I mean, you gave me four ingredients,
shit. I guess our marriage is over.
You can't build a sandwich
with four pieces!
God damn.
You can't build a sandwich
with four pieces.
So many lies happened today.
And we're done... up people's
marriages...
...over sandwiches!
Oh, we're going to be talking
about this for a long time.
Yeah.
Thank you guys
for coming through, man!
Thanks.
It was so much fun.
Yeah!
All right, G. We'll see you.
All right, dawg. Peace.
I want you to...
I want you to work
through those dreams.
I am. I'm trying my best.
Yeah.
'Cause that one bothered me.
Yeah, that one was
kind of weird, right?
So how does shit get through
the motorcycle jacket?
It doesn't, babe.
He unzipped the whole thing,
and he shit on the bed.
Breathe easy.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
That's nice.
Ah-ha!...
I just need to run a couple
of bits by you.
How did you find me?
So, what did we learn today?
Well, if you're having
trouble sleeping,
you can just take a Xanax,
but you might wake up
with a turd in your bed
and diagnosed with
post-traumatic shit disorder.
Some people can
control their dreams,
and they have wild sex orgy
with celebrities,
but others can't,
so they just have boring dreams
about doing frying pork chops
in their underwear.
I'd like to give a shout-out
to my guests, Gilbert Gottfried,
Quelle Chris, and Jean Grae
for coming to the crib
and kicking it with me
and, remember,
wet dreams are better awake.
All right, y'all,
I'll see y'all later.
Hello?
Danny?
Hey, it's Calise.
We still meeting up so I can run
my new jokes by you, right?
Yeah, I'm actually in my car
right now heading to you.
How can you be in your car?
Didn't I call you
on your house phone?
I've got a house phone
in my car.
Come on, man.
Are you lying to me.
No, no! I'm on my way.
I'm on my way.
I can feel the lie
through the phone.
All right.
Fine.
Mr. Brown,
we're ready for you.
All right.
Right this way.
Ahhh.
It's feeling better, improved.
It's one of them knots -
Ah-ha!
I just need to run
a couple of bits by you.
All right?
Please, it's for tonight.
What the hell.
I have a show!
How did you find me?
I need a new joke for tonight.
Listen...
I'm just trying to get a massage.
You don't even know.
Like, Sunday, I almost died.
I was choking
on an avocado toast.
My boyfriend is white,
and he reacted so quickly.
He was like...
That's all he did,
but it was so quick,
and it was perfect because
he, like, let out a little yelp.
He was like.
It was just enough
for a real man
to overhear it and come save me.
Come on.
He's laughing!
Come on, man.
You're not helping, man.
Excuse me.
He's so sweet.
You should just relax a little.
I'm trying to relax lately.
My mom told me
that I should eat weed.
She doesn't want me
to take antidepressants,
and it's crazy to hear my mom
say that, right?
Because she's a retired
police lieutenant
and ex-D.A.R.E. cop,
but now that she found out that
weed has medicinal purposes,
she's using CBD oil
for her knees,
and she's furious
with the entire police force.
She's like, "All that time
we were locking up people
for marijuana.
I find out it's good
for my knees?"
Isn't that great?
She's 70 years old.
It's nice to watch her grow...
weed.
She's growing weed
in the basement
with my brother.
Mm.
He lives there still.
Does that feel good?
You know this is stressful, right?
I know, right?
That's why I need you to listen
so that I don't get uptight
for the show.
It's hard to do comedy.
If you could just relax,
you'll feel the humor.
Honestly, I need this.
I have a show tonight.
Could you let me have the rest
of this session?
I have a show tonight.
Can you let your chiropractor
touch me?