- That is so rare
and that I've gotta have.
Eight!
- Eight, we have eight, I'm at eight,
now nine, ninety, nine
- Thirteen.
- Thirteen, $1300.
- What the hell?
This thing here was called a face puller.
Isn't that awesome?
My name is Steve Santini.
I buy and sell the darkest, most gruesome
artifacts on the planet.
Welcome to the Dark Side.
Whenever I'm in this area, I
like to drop into Jim's store.
There's no telling what
I'll find with each visit.
Everybody comes in and
they know and they think
they're gonna get something for nothing.
I can't get them for nothing
and I'm not selling them for nothing.
- Oh, hey, check that out.
Titanic.
- That's pretty cool.
Check this out.
- What's that?
I've seen these before.
It's a locking collar.
- Yeah.
- It's an antique iron
collar with a built-in lock.
You see, the thing is,
these things show up
all the time at auction.
People think they're slave collars,
but they're actually dog collars
and they've sold for thousands of dollars.
- Morning!
- Good morning, sir!
- Jim, been a while.
How you doing?
- Pretty good.
- Yeah?
- You?
- Good, hopefully better in a few minutes.
Well, I found this old dog collar.
Kind of wondering, you
know, what you want for it.
- Put $425 for this.
- Can you do any better?
- You just want things too
damn cheap, that's all.
- What's the best you can do, Jim?
- $325
- How about $125
- Oh no, that's ridiculous.
No, no, no, get your
numbers up there a bit.
- My final offer $150.
- No.
- Give me your final best.
- Two and a quarter.
- $175.
- $200.
- $180.
- $205.
- You're going up!
I know.
Trying to get you to realize
that it's worth money.
- $190.
- Five.
- $195.
- Deal.
- Haggling with Jim is
a pretty humbling experience.
Every time I come here, he beats me down.
- Those packages going out or coming in?
- No, those are going out.
That's the human jaw
bone and the lead cross.
- Ah, from the plague pit, right on.
- But, you know what I do
have for you coming in?
- Ah, incoming is always good.
- Checks!
Historic jail exhibit check.
I think this is one of the titanic ones.
- Yeah, it's an exhibit
I designed for them.
- I spoke to a woman on the phone
and she has a Victorian
cat o' nine tails for sale.
- Awesome!
- She said that we could come by
and take a look at it.
- Well, you know
that they're very rare?
So, if it's real, I mean, I'd pick it up.
I'm not holding back.
- You wanna go take a look?
- Oh, yeah, absolutely!
Hey, I'm off to the bank.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait, no.
You have to take your daughter Shayna out
to buy her dress for this dance.
You've been avoiding it and
you can't avoid it any longer.
- For me, I collect torture stuff.
Going to a mall is torture.
- She wants her daddy there.
- She wants her Daddy's wallet.
- But, you have to go.
- Tell you what, if I'm
going, you're coming, too.
- All right.
- But first, I need to check out
these cat o' nine tails.
Oh man, what the hell?
- Welcome to the playroom.
- I mean, this is wild.
Check out these tables.
Okay, hey, so you're a dominatrix, right?
- Retired, which is why
I'm selling this stuff
and I thought you'd like these things
that are rather dark.
- What's the story with this table?
It looks pretty old.
- This is a 1950's operating table.
People died on this thing, side
rails held the arm pieces. -
- It's sickening.
- And, this one right here.
I don't know it's just me,
but I'm getting a deeper,
darker vibe from this one.
- This came from a turn of
the century women's asylum.
- A psychiatric hospital.
- Like a sanatorium.
Women were tied to this thing.
- No way.
- If you woke up with a headache,
your husband could send you there
for as long as he wanted back then.
- You know, at the risk
of sounding old fashioned,
I kind of like that idea.
Just kidding, just kidding.
This is great.
I came for something else.
Stef tells me you have an
1800's prison flogging whip.
Can I see it?
- Yeah.
- Whoa, that's awesome.
That is incredible and it's ancient.
- It is a Victorian-era British
prison cat o' nine tails
for beating the convicts with.
- Do you know how rare these things are?
They were often destroyed
because the prison system
didn't want to admit
that they'd used stuff like this.
- Yeah, you're correct.
- This cat o' nine tails
flogging whip is amazing.
It's a staggering find.
Hey Rob, come here for a second.
- What?
- You often wonder how
prisoners felt back in the day
when we're researching this stuff.
- Yeah.
- Well, you're gonna get to find out.
You're in good hands.
- You're so evil, so evil.
- This is gonna be great.
- Yes, I am and I'm going to
be loving every minute of this.
- I really don't know about this, guys.
- I do.
- Oh, Jesus!
- No more coffee stops!
Now I know what it feels like.
- Oh, nice!
Right on, I enjoyed every second of that.
I've gotta get down to business here.
What's your price?
- I'd like $1600.
- $1600?
Oh man, I was thinking somewhere
along the lines of $! 200.
I'm gonna put this in an exhibit
that I'm gonna put together
and assemble and tour
of ancient justice instruments.
I have to keep the cost down
because I have to make the money back
by admissions as this tours.
- But, if you own it a long time
and exhibit it often, then
you will make money on it.
$1600.
- Nah, you know what?
I'm really stuck at 12.
- I'm stuck at 16.
- Really?
You know what, I hate to
say this, because I likely
will never see another one in my life,
but, you remain the custodian of the whip.
- You sure?
- Yeah, I've gotta stay at 12, thanks.
Carolyn ran a really hard bargain,
so I took a big chance
and walked for the door.
- Wait.
- You'll take 12.
- No, 13.
- I'm not gonna quibble over $100.
I've been after one for ten years.
Done, $! 300, thank you so much.
- Nice, nice.
- That's awesome.
- I'm really satisfied with
the price I paid for this
and, truth be told, I probably
would have paid a lot more.
The last authentic one of
these I saw selling at auction
went for over $4000.
Today was a great day!
Stewart McLaughlin in a prison officer
from Wandsworth Prison in the UK.
He's also the author of
several prison-related books
and, actually, I got very
lucky that he was in town
and made time to meet with me.
When I inquired what the oral history was,
that this is a British
prison flogging whip
that was used on inmates for
infractions or punishments.
What do you think?
- Looking at this piece,
it's not like any official
cat o' nine tails that I've seen
in any archive or museum.
It's certainly not
something that would have
been used in a British prison
in pre-1870.
The handle itself is way too short.
- As bit by bit, Stewart stripped away
everything I believed about this whip.
I mean, the measurements were wrong,
the history was wrong.
It wasn't a prison cat.
I mean, I started to feel
like a bit of an ****.
I'd paid money on this, my own
research, my own knowledge.
It wasn't right in this case.
- But, I know, in
British in penal colonies
around the globe,
the smaller version of the cat,
certainly serves as the boy's cat.
- Something like this.
- Could be something like this.
I think you're probably
looking at something
which may even be mid-1800's.
- Stewart pointed out that
this was actually used
for flogging prisoners.
Maybe not in British prisons,
but in penal colonies.
This is still a rare piece
and it's possibly earlier
than I ever thought it was.
- Hey, Steve.
- Yeah?
- You're gonna be happy.
- Oh?
- I got your invite to
the annual invite-only
Dark Relics Private Auction.
- Yes, once a year I wait for this.
- And, I printed you out pictures.
- Awesome.
Knee restraints.
- Oh, I like that.
- Spiked arm bracer to cleave
in someone's face with.
- Look at that!
- Oh man, that looks
like an antique coffin.
- It looks Victorian, maybe.
- Yeah, I'd say about the 1800's.
- That is awesome.
- You know what?
I'd look great in here if I could win it
because you know who else go after this.
- Oh money bags.
- Yep, it's always the way.
If I want it, you know it's gonna happen.
- Yeah, anything you want, he'll want.
- Yeah.
This guy I call Money Bags.
He's a new guy on the scene,
collects the same stuff that
I do and has got deep pockets.
He really pisses me off.
- And, he has more money than you, so.
It's true.
- You're fired.
I want to know if this cat o' nine tails
was ever used on human beings.
So, I'm having a blood test done on it.
- Interesting
thing about blood stains
is that often at a crime scene,
they're washed out or bleached
and thankfully, these
chemiluminescence agents,
they allow us to see what is not there.
Would you mind turning
off the light please?
- No, certainly.
- Thank you.
- Awesome.
Finger's crossed, here we go.
Okay.
- There it is, saw it.
- You see it?
Wow!
Check it out and over there, too
and, look at the one
strand, it's dripping down
in three drops.
- It's lighting up a like a neon sing.
- It is.
Look at that; It's insane.
Now we just have to find
out if it's human blood.
Can we do that next?
- Yes, that's the next
test we're gonna do.
Okay.
- This is the moment of truth, I mean.
That was a lot of blood.
Man, this is awesome.
We always believed this
was a flogging whip
for human beings and this
could be it right here.
- I'm gonna put my sample with blood on it
in the container.
- Okay.
- And, once again, snap it off,
close it back up again,
shake it all up.
- Finger's crossed.
One line is the control.
- One line is the control.
- And second line is...
- Second line to
see if it's human or not.
What do you see?
- Two blue lines!
That's amazing.
This was used to draw blood.
- Yes.
- That's incredible!
Wow, thank you so much.
This cat o' nine tails tested
positive for human blood
and that's amazing,
but I still don't know
where it was used and when.
I'm gonna take it to another expert,
but first, my 13-year
old daughter is going
to her first major
school dance with a boy.
I'm not exactly excited
to be here dress shopping
with her, but it's gotta be done.
One-hundred and 50, 200 bucks.
This one I love.
Ta-da!
How about this?
It's like 100 bucks;
It's got good coverage.
- This is nice.
- No!
Look at how short the skirt is.
No way.
- Whoa, sexy.
- Wrong word, change.
Now that is super.
- It's horrible, it's
ugly, it's granny style.
- It's elegant.
- It's fun shopping with my Dad
cause he pays for everything,
but at the same time, it's annoying.
Dad, you're embarrassing.
Why don't you just go?
- I could hunt for dark
artifacts and torture instruments
all day, but looking at
dresses, forget about it.
- Just go.
- Nothing skimpy, no leopard-skin.
- Trust me, trust me.
- It's on you see ya
- Bye.
- The day I've been
waiting for is finally here.
The preview of objects from
the Dark Artifacts Auction.
I mean, it's one thing to
see pictures of these things,
but to see them in person, it's amazing.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
That's amazing, eh?
Check it out.
That, I've gotta have.
Check this out.
This is so rare.
It's an actual hangman's hood.
It's made out of leather.
- Why is it so rare?
- Because they disposed them.
Nobody wanted them.
- No way.
- Bad luck, man.
The man that looked through
that took your life.
That could go through the roof though
if people here realize what
that is the way I realize it,
it could go really high.
Gotta have it.
- Okay.
- It's a really competitive business.
You have to make a plan in
advance and stick to it.
- So, do you want everything?
- I'd like it all, but
there's a few pieces
in particular that I want.
One is the coffin and the other one is
that executioner's hood
because that piece is so rare.
Think of how cool that coffin
would look in that corner.
- Right behind my desk.
- I'm really excited about
this upcoming auction,
but first I want to meet
with one more whip expert
to see if I can finally get to the bottom
of where and when this cat
o' nine tails whip was used.
Hey, Peter.
- Hey, I'm an expert because of 50 years
of collecting, reading
and writing about whips.
- You know, I noticed
you brought a big bag with you.
I'm hoping there's more
than clothes in it.
- No, I brought you some
whips from my collection
of 1,000 whips.
- Awesome, whoa!
- Some stems from the
Peter Frisk collection.
- Oh my God!
That looks viscous.
It is actually a rhino-hide.
It's from the belly of a rhino.
- Could you imagine getting hit with this?
- And, that's what called a sjambok.
It's from South Africa.
It's probably about 100 years old.
- That was used on people?
- That was used on people.
This one here is a cossak
whip, from the 19th Century.
- A true cossak whip.
It's meant to be used for
horseback and cossak riding
in the Russian army would
have carried a whip like that.
Probably an officer.
- This has caught my
attention immediately.
This is awesome.
- What's that.
- This is bone?
- It is bone and carved stone
and there's a knife in the handle.
- Check it out!
Would this be for stabbing?
Was this like a weapon?
- It might be for eating
your dinner actually.
- Really, like this?
- It's very rare; It
should be in a museum.
- Should be, well, it is.
Yours.
- Yeah, mine.
That's right.
- Seeing your expertise and
your incredible collection,
we came to the right guy.
I mean, I imagine there's
nobody on the earth
that likely knows more
about whips than you.
This cat o' nine tails tested
positive for human blood
and that's amazing, but I still don't know
where it was used and when.
- Yeah, this is a fascinating whip.
There is wear on them and age patina.
I'm also looking at
the work of the joining
and the style of those is 19th-Century.
I have seen Australian
convicts flogging whips
from the 19th Century that resemble this
Now I would add another possibility....
- Okay.
- It also
resembles a photo post card
from the convict ship, Success.
- The Success was the most famous
and notorious prison ship of all time
and, when she retired, they toured her
from port-to-port around the world
showing people the horrors
of the British penal system.
- This sticker is very, very important.
It's a collection number,
which appears to confirm
that it's either in a museum, on the ship
or somewhere else.
My theory is that is was on display,
set up in the convict ship, Success.
Everything's consistent.
It all fits in with Success.
- This is killing me.
I don't mean to interrupt you, I have to,
what's it worth?
- It's worth a lot of money.
If it can be proved to be from Success,
it should be in the range
of possibly $10,000.
- 10,000 bucks?
Even a 1800's punishment
whip used on convicts,
if we couldn't nail down
the ship certainly...
- Even if you couldn't nail that down,
it's still worth three or four thousand.
- Oh man, this is great.
- So you have
a very valuable item.
Peter gave me some amazing
information about this whip
and now, armed with that, I know
that if I ever want to sell this thing,
I could more than triple my money.
Wow.
- Take good care of it.
- Oh I will and, you know what,
if I ever decide to get rid of it,
it'll go to your collection.
- I'd buy it from you, but
I know you wouldn't sell.
- Not yet.
It's amazing to be
invited to this auction.
I looked forward to it the whole year.
- Okay, we're gonna start
off the auction here
with the slave collar
here, nice little collar,
it's a dungeon collar, folks
Sold, $300
Next item up for bid here
is the iron paddle wagon.
Sold it!
Two and a half.
$650.
Sold her.
$2100.
Late arrival here, there's Dan.
Hey Dan, I hope you brought
your thick wallet tonight, sir.
- I started seeing this
guy about two years ago
showing up at auctions
and even bidding online against me
and people have told me later
it was him that had done it.
- All righty,
folks, change your tune.
We're off to the two-star
items in the show.
Executioner's hood and the coffin.
Nice piece right there.
Who's gonna start me off
there, anybody want $1,000?
Five hundred, wow, couple
hundred quick, four,
four, now to five, five and
a four now five to a five,
seven, I'm at a seven, now eight, go eight
- Eight hundred.
- I'm at an eight, now nine to a nine.
- Thirteen.
- Thirteen!
- I'm at a 13, now 14, get
to 14, do the 14, go 14.
Now I'm at a 13, now 14,
go 14, sold it, $1300.
- I'm pissed off that I
didn't win that coffin,
but, you know what, now I have more money
to go after that executioner's hood
and I'm going home with it.
- Next item up for bids here folks
is the Scottish hangman's hood.
Very, very rare, most of these
were destroyed right after
the executioners retired.
Who's gonna start me off
on the bidding on that
in about $2,000?
Wow, 15, 1,000 and holding.
- 1,000
- I'm at $1,000 now to 11
to 11 do I hear 11 and 12?
Will 12 gets 12 do 12.
- Thirteen.
- Thirteen and 14, 14 and
15, I'm at 14, can we go 15.
- Fifteen.
- Fifteen, 15, now 17
and 1/2, hear 17 1/2,
17 1/2 and two.
- Twenty one.
- Now I'm at 21.
- Twenty five.
- Twenty five, 125 now
3, now 3 go 3 get 3,
think you good, think you
should, think I would,
now bid 25 and 3.
Sold!
- Yes!
- $2500
- Right on!
What an auction, I mean,
I didn't get the coffin,
but I did get the Scottish Hangman's hood
and that for me, means it
was a score and a great day.
Now I have to switch gears
and get into another mode.
A young man is coming
by to take my daughter
to her first dance.
- You must be Mr. Santini
- This hat.
Respect.
Tell me a bit about yourself.
Do you collect anything?
- Um, no.
- I do, I collect ancient torture devices.
This thing here was called a face puller.
It went right over someone's face
and they'd pull the
face right off a person.
Isn't that awesome?
You know, when you shake a
man's hand, it's a sacred bond,
but, back in the day, they had this.
If you broke your word like, for instance,
what time you get home at night,
they'd crush your fingers
between those plates.
Do you agree that promises
are very important?
- Yes.
- Yeah, that's good, you know.
This thing here, check it out.
It's got these spikes on the inside.
First they'd take a person's hat off,
so this could fit over top of the head.
See all these sharp points?
They'd twist the handle and the entire top
of the person's head would disconnect.
- Awe, sweet!
- Oh my God, where's the limo?
- So much better than a limo.
- I think this is your limo.
- This is your ride, kids.
- She's gonna kill you.
- Yeah, probably.
- Thank you.
- Hey, Hayden, just
remember man, 11 o'clock.
I'll make it 10:50, sir.
- Sir, right on, good boy, smart kid.
- Have fun, guys.
- Have fun, man.
- Bye.
- Dance the night away.
See ya!