[MUSIC PLAYING]
[EERIE WIND BLOWING]
[WILDLIFE CHATTERING]
[HEART BEATING]
[DISTORTED MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
OK, do it again.
[BLOWS]
Not bad.
You learn pretty fast for a cop.
[CHUCKLES]
Yeah, well cops may be
slow, but, uh, at least
they're fast on the take.
I guess I've just been taken
by one of the best, huh?
He is not one of
the best Mr. Man.
He is the best.
Well, look who's here.
And I suppose you're qualified
to know who the best is?
Can an elephant skate?
What is it of your business?
Rapport, now tell me about it.
All right, all right,
I get the message.
I'll see you when you get back.
Oh by the way, how long
you going to be gone?
Oh man, a week in
fabulous downtown Hong Kong
followed by a week of
improvement for body and soul.
And then, back to the States.
We're going to have a master
in the neighborhood, huh?
You know, uh, that
could be a very
valuable asset to the force.
Listen, I know.
But don't play with me, man.
You're getting lessons
from me and that's it.
You can come up on
that morgue of yours
just as long as you come as a
student, but the next time--
the next time you try to recruit
me into that pig pen of yours
is the day I stop pulling
my punches and ice you.
OK, don't get excited Luke.
Don't blow your cool.
My apologies, all right.
Just have a good trip.
I don't know why that
pig honky come up here.
Because I owe him a favor
and that's all it's about.
He stuck his neck
out for me when
I was busted for almost killing
that pusher on 116th Street.
Plus, he keeps his
appointments, which is more
than I can say for you, mister.
You're late.
Where were you?
Some dude in the
Deuce was splash
in a big roll on St. Nicholas,
so I helped him to his crack
game for a quarter, you dig?
So then he wants to do me
in, because he drops it
all at once a refund to boot.
To make a long story
short, he whipped a piece
and he takes the whole pot.
Well, at least he tried
to take the whole pot.
Me and Tom put a showstopper
on him and got the bread back.
We didn't hurt him too bad.
We let him go.
Chinks of plenty.
He was Chinese?
Yeah.
And while he was driving away
he yelled that he'd get us.
You should have been, Shifu.
You would've laughed your ass.
He was cursing is
that not funny accent
there saying that he was going
to get-- can you dig this--
the Tongue after us.
He was looking
where he was going,
and he ran his car right
into a garbage truck.
He tore up his whole front end.
But he kept going.
I thought I'd never
stop laughing.
The Tongue can lay
something on you.
Naw, me and Tom
know too many of them.
They'd never bother us
to something like this.
Which reminds me,
I've got some business
done in that part of town.
I'll see you tonight.
Wait a minute.
What about the trip?
Are you packed?
What packed?
It takes a minute.
Look, bro, I'm
counting on you.
This is really important.
Don't get waylaid.
I wasn't planning on
getting laid, Shifu.
I'll see you later.
[ENGINES WHINING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[INAUDIBLE]
Brother.
Master Leone.
Hi Shifu.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
What's on your mind, man?
There's nothing
on my mind, Shifu.
Nothing.
Don't hand me that.
You've got an attitude.
I don't have an attitude.
You still thinking
about New York?
Naw.
I just hope that it doesn't
affect your performance.
Don't let it
hassle you, Shifu.
This is easy.
It's light stuff.
I don't believe
what you're saying.
Do you know what this means?
Yes, Shifu.
Well, you know that
isn't light stuff.
Where you coming from?
This is what you spent years
of your life building for.
I can pull through it, Shifu.
You know I'm in good shape.
Yes, but you need
your mind and your body.
Either one alone is not enough.
Rodan, what I'm
telling you is basic.
You know all this.
Admit it, you still thinking
about getting at those guys
back in New York.
Naw, Shifu.
You got it all wrong.
You got me all wrong.
I just want you to
understand one thing, Ro.
What goes around comes around.
The situation in New
York is temporary.
You're in China now,
and what you do here
is going to stay with you
for the rest of your life.
So let's get it together
and stop dreaming.
I can understand where
you're coming from, Shifu.
I can dig it.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MASTER: Now that your physical
power is of the ninth degree,
it is time for your
mind and spirit
to ascend to the same level.
To achieve this, you
are to choose a place
known only to your spirit.
You will recognize it
when you come upon it.
There you must retreat
into meditation.
You must let
nothing disturb you.
From your companions
here, you must choose
a guardian to protect you.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
This cat has been
in a trance for hours.
What the hell does
he think I am?
A Watch dog or something.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SNAKE HISSING]
Rodan!
Rodan, where are you?
[EERIE WIND BLOWING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Rodan!
Rodan, where are you?
RODAN: Down here, Luke.
You won't believe
what I just found.
Hey, weren't you
supposed to be watching me?
You know, Luke, you may
be better stuff than me when
it comes to fighting,
but that don't
mean you can tell me nothing.
Let's get outta here.
This place has strange vibes.
RODAN: Sure.
Sure.
We gotta be in Hong
Kong by morning to leave.
I'll be right with you.
[ANIMALS CRYING OUT]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[EERIE WIND BLOWING]
[POUNDING]
[BIRD CAWING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SCREAMS]
[HORNS SOUNDING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
TICKET SELLER: Hey,
man, where you going?
[DISTORTED MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
Blew that.
Burn, burn.
It's time to make some money.
All right, you call
them and I'll follow.
Hey, where's your man?
There he is.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Got it.
See you in a bit.
Hey, go get him a car.
Thank you.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
Hey, let's have the package.
RODAN: What is this,
some kind of a setup.
Let's say that a certain
mutual friend of ours
was not satisfied with
his winning this morning
and wants to get
back his investment.
The cocaine please.
RODAN: Did you see
me at the crap game?
Why I'm gonna break your--
Cool it, Rodan.
Cool it.
The man's got a ride.
Let's get it together
and then come back.
OK.
Now Cool it.
Give them the stash,
give them the stash.
I'm gonna get ya.
Your little ass is--
MAN: Cool it!
Cool it!
Come on, dog.
Come on, let's go.
Let me go, man, let me go.
All right, let's
go show the suckers
who they just fucked with.
KID: Hey, Mike, come on,
we're late for school.
OK.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
SINGER (SINGING): Just
when I need a helping hand.
Someone to understand
I always turn to you.
You're standing there
with outstretched arms
as shelter in the storm
that I can sail into.
You see me through.
And when the tables turn
and you're feeling sad
I'll be best refreshment
you've ever had.
I'll make you glad.
That's why you and I
believe in each other.
That's why you and I believe.
That's why you and I
believe in each other.
That's why you and I believe.
It's true we sometimes
have our fights,
but even that's all
right because it's
turning now.S You seem to
make my life worthwhile.
You keep me in a smile.
That's what I need most of.
My precious love,
I want to share
my every treasure with
you, and be a never ending
pleasure for you.
You want that too.
That's why you and I
believe in each other.
That's why you and I believe.
The Chinese brothers
and third world people,
they're not our enemy.
Why you coming down
so hard on them?
Why?
Just get the two that hit you.
Because they all want
to get in on the act.
Besides, they got it coming.
- Give me my money.
- What money?
Listen, man, we don't
have go through this no more
if you give me my cash.
I told you, I'm not
going to give you any money
because I don't owe you.
- What do you mean?
You're gonna tell me you're
not gonna give me what's mine.
This kind of hassle can
turn into an all out war.
The gang fighting isn't working.
That's not what martial
arts is all about.
I'd lay low for awhile.
What lay low?
You should've seen
those cats, bet
they were a bunch of faggots.
Right on, man, they
took one look at our faces
and split, law and why?
They'd rather fight a gorilla
in a phone booth just to mess
with us.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
Hey, I've told you to
calm down a little bit
or otherwise you're
going to have to get out.
Man, give me my
money, all right?
I mean, that's all we need.
You'll have the pigs
coming down on our head
busting up our score.
And since they know
we're martial artists,
they'll come in with shotguns.
No way they can
pull that shit.
I'll put an end to it and fast.
We're together and we better
anything that comes up down.
This isn't time.
Hey, what's that you
got around your neck?
I gave my money, man.
Hey, man, don't
walk away from me.
[MEN YELLING AND ARGUING]
Now I told you, and I've
asked you nicely several times,
keep it down.
This time I'm telling you!
Or I'll put both you're
asses out on the street.
Hey, I told you to
stay out of my business.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[CROWD CHEERING AND RANTING]
They should have known
that that fine sister
was a karate expert.
Now they do.
[DISTORTED MUSIC PLAYING]
[GROWLING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
RODAN: Hey, man.
What do you say, man?
What's going on, man?
I've had some static with a
bunch of Chinese niggers man.
MAN: Yeah?
RODAN: And I'm take the Bjs
to smoke their ass tonight.
I'm going to take this fist
and punch him in his yellow--
[DISTORTED MUSIC PLAYING]
[HISSING AND SNARLING]
[SCREAMING]
[MUSIC PLAYING WITH RHYTHMIC
DRUMMING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MARK: Hey, Al.
How's it going?
How's the business running?
Ah, not bad.
Same old thing, you know.
Yeah, I figured
since you're divorced,
you'd be a real swinger by now,
hitting all the single joints.
Nah, that's not my style.
How's Jo anyway?
You hear much from her?
Well, besides canceled
alimony checks, not much.
You know she moved
to Philly, so we
don't see much of each other.
Oh, Chris, I
forgot to tell you.
This sad sack--
Christopher, how do you do?
Nice to see you.
I can tell we're going
to be great partners.
- Great what?
- Partners.
With my degree in criminology--
And my degree in patience.
[CHUCKLES]
We'll be another
Watson at Holmes.
Nice to see you.
I've Got to go see the chief.
What the hell was that?
I was going to tell you, but
that's Mike Rothburn's son.
They sent him up here
and you needed a drivers.
A driver not a joker.
Mike?
Mike Rothburn, Mike Rothburn
from the complaint department?
Aw, come on.
Well, why not?
CHRIS: Aw, come on.
Now take it easy.
It's good for
departmental diplomacy.
Politics, you know.
Politics?
That's what's wrong with
this goddamned department.
Hey, Chris, give a trial.
I'll give him a trial,
I'll give me a trial, right,
but I know what he's
going to be giving me.
[PHONE RINGING]
Alan's office.
Yeah, Hey, Chris, it's for you.
Yeah?
When?
OK, I'll be right over.
Mark, you better get
our, uh, new recruit
out of the Chief's office.
Looks like he's going get his
first chance to play Watson.
What's up?
Uh, subway, looks
like murder one.
To smell this bad,
he'd have to been
dead for a couple of days.
Yeah.
Why didn't we find it sooner?
I don't know,
Sam, I don't know.
The question is, how did he die?
I mean, the body looks
like it's been mangled
by uh, by a meat grinder.
OK, boys.
Take him away.
And, uh, make sure I get
a full autopsy made, huh?
Hey, Chris.
Who's your new friend?
Sam, my, uh, new driver.
Ed, local school reporter.
How do you do?
Nice to meet you.
Well, uh, what's the
theory, Mr. Super sleuth?
Ed, the last time
I gave you a hunch,
you had every suspect out
of town in 15 minutes.
Now just give me a
week to get an autopsy
and get some details down,
and then maybe, just maybe,
I might give you a statement.
Right now, do me a
favor, and get lost, huh?
Aw, that's no way to
talk to a journalist.
Hey, you know what the
penalty is for impersonation
in this state?
Go find yourself a corpse.
Nice to have met you.
[SIGHS]
Christopher?
Yeah?
Do you really have a theory?
No, not really.
But there is a possibility that,
uh, there's a gang war going
on between the black gangs
and the Chinese gangs,
and that guy was
definitely no WASP.
You know what I think?
I think the best move
to make is keep an eye
on each end in this town.
Right now?
Right now.
Oops, sorry.
Hey, wait!
Wait!
Hey!
Hey, you driver, wait.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
WOMAN'S VOICE: Please,
help me, somebody.
Please, help me.
I can't move.
My foot is caught.
Please, help.
OK, OK.
I'm-- I'm coming.
WOMAN'S VOICE: Hurry,
it's dark in here.
I'm scared.
Where the hell are you?
WOMAN'S VOICE: I can see you.
Gosh, damn, dark in here.
OK, OK.
Coming.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
WOMAN'S VOICE: Over here.
[MAN SCREAMING]
May the peace of the
Almighty be with you.
May your soul rest in peace.
[PUKING]
May the peace of your
life with you forever,
and ever, and ever, amen.
[GAGGING AND COUGHING]
You all right, Sam?
Yeah, I've just never seen
anything like that before.
Yeah, neither have I. Looks
like two murders in two days
in the same station, Jesus.
Well, looks like your
murderer wasn't greedy.
They say they found
a full wallet on him,
so that leaves out robbery.
That's good thinking, Ed,
that's very good thinking.
Guess what, I wanna make a
statement about yesterday.
OK, just a moment.
OK.
That, uh, body that
was found in the subway.
Yeah.
It was definitely dead.
And the department figures that
the probable cause of death
was murder.
Thank you.
You wanna know what I think?
Yeah.
About four years ago it
was a story in the papers.
It seems that when they were
building the old subways,
they had to break
through the sewers.
And it seems that
a lot of workmen
broke through the sewers and
were attacked by animals.
These were animals
that had become
mutant, dogs, cats, rats,
alligators, all the throwaways.
And they developed
senses that other animals
didn't have, fangs, claws.
They're wild.
They lived off each other.
Survival of the species.
And they attacked the workmen.
Now I think it's very possible
that those workmen did not seal
up the sewers where they
should have been sealed up,
and that those animals are
roaming through the subways.
Hey, thanks.
You're welcome.
For the story.
Hey, come on.
You're not gonna
print that are ya?
Sounds like an Edgar Alan
Poe story for Christ sakes.
Hey, look, Sam.
Let's start using some
rational logic, huh?
And lesson one, keep your mouth
shut in front of reporters.
Save the horror
stories for the kids.
Come on.
Magmore, stay
here with this body
until the guys from
the morgue get down.
Police point the finger
at underground animals.
According to a
well-informed source,
the recent subway murders may
be attributed to mutant cats,
rats, and dogs
inbred and inhabiting
the subways for several years.
Christ, that's all we need.
We'll have every little old
lady who sees a mouse asking
us for protective custody.
Well, I got carried away.
Well, next time
don't get carried away.
Now, we've got definite
reports on fighting
between the Chinese
and the black gangs
in the same areas
as the murders.
Now this first guy was Chinese.
The other guy just may have
been some unfortunate bystander.
But the way both
bodies were mutilated,
I can't help thinking that--
well, anyway, this is
what we're going to do.
OK, I put men on stakeout at
every subway station from 168th
Street down to 96th Street.
That gives us a Cordon
around the entire area
where the murders took place.
I've also got a hotline to
a team of social workers
down in Chinatown
that'll keep us informed
of any unusual movement.
If anything happens,
we'll know about it.
Hopefully, we'll know
about it in time.
Christopher, what about
my theory about the, uh--
Don't worry about it, Sam.
Even one of your
saber-toothed rats
won't get through
the net we've put up.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Hey, man, there's
two chinks at our back.
As if I didn't know.
Come on, let's
get out this cage.
Oh, wow, we got
ourselves some static.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
I know you.
[SPITS]
He's wasted, let's
get outta here.
Yeah.
Great.
Ah, let's see what we got here.
Christopher, I got an idea.
Yeah?
Why don't you come up
to the club this weekend.
We'll play a little tennis.
Nah, nah, that's not my day.
Besides, we got a
case to work on.
Ah, It'll be good for you.
It'll get your
mind off the case.
Bleh.
I don't play tennis, Sam.
What-- what do you mean
you don't play tennis?
What I said.
I don't play tennis.
Everybody plays tennis.
DISPATCH OFFICER (OVER
RADIO): Car 701, proceed
to 135th Street and Lenox.
Car 701, proceed to
135th Street and Lenox
This is 701, what's up?
DISPATCH OFFICER (OVER
RADIO): Possible homicide,
Oriental, medium height,
medium-weight, gang member,
Red Dragons.
This is 701, have
604 take this call out.
OK, Sam, let's go.
We're going to Luke's place.
Aren't you gonna play that?
What for?
The jacket and location
tell me all we need to know,
and, uh, I wanna speak to Luke.
I think he might know
something about these murders.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[HEART BEATING WITH EERIE MUSIC]
[SCREAMING]
[PASSENGERS GROANING]
Take your money here for
nothing, goddamn subway.
Too many people,
too much pollution,
too much of everything.
How you, what are you doing?
You crazy kid, what
are you smoking for?
He doesn't know what
he's doing, this kid.
This kind of place
makes you crazy.
They call me crazy.
Who are you anyway, huh?
What's the matter, huh?
Huh, huh, huh, huh, huh?
The women here, they
wear such short dresses
with their crotch sticking out.
I don't know know what the hell
is the matter with the people
these days.
Look at her, look at her, oh my.
Look at her.
Who the hell do
you think you are.
Oh, it's what's the matter, huh?
Don't you like my looks, baby.
I was prettier than you, believe
me, I was prettier than you.
Yeah, to hell with her.
I don't know what they're
doing in New York.
Colleges take the money,
they raise the rates.
You know what they're doing now?
They're ticketing $0.50 cents.
They should drop
dead with the money.
Children, who needs
children in this world.
Oh, look her.
Oh, honey, honey, you do
it for love or for money.
I never saw a guy with
his crotch so closed.
I can't stand this place.
I'm getting outta here.
I'm going to Coney Island.
[SCREAMING]
[SIRENS WAILING]
DISPATCH OFFICER (OVER
RADIO): Car 701, Car 701,
proceed to IRT station
137 Street and Broadway.
Damn it, they don't give me
a chance to breath around here.
Sam, call headquarters and
tell them I'm stuck right now.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Yeah, brother.
The governor of Jersey
has legalized the numbers.
They even showed a damn results
on television during the news.
In Jersey?
Mhm.
What?
They won't let us have nothing.
Ah, damn, the numbers.
Man, you know what--
Hold on, brother.
The man.
Well, my, my, if it ain't
the guardian of the piece.
Are you lost or are you looking
for some desperate criminal
that may be seeking
refuge in here.
That's funny.
That's very funny.
Now why don't you go back and
tell Luke that, uh, Lieutenant
Alan wants to see him.
Say, man, we don't run
no messenger service.
So why don't you just go back
there and tell him yourself?
Sam, wait here.
I'll be right back.
Sure.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Bartender, could I
have a large Coke,
please with just to
squeeze of lime, please.
Of course, are you
sure you can handle it?
Of course he can handle it.
He's momma's big man.
And you figure all these
murders tie-in with my school.
Get your facts together before
you start accusing me, my man.
Look, God damn it,
I'm not accusing anyone.
I just got news of the
fourth victim in two days,
all within a 10 block radius,
and two of them were Chinese.
Now what the hell am
I supposed to think?
And I'll tell you
something else, Luke,
if any of these murders
involve any of Rodan's people
there's going to be a
hell of a lot of trouble.
I'll bust ass all over
the God damn place.
Look, jam, you do
not come to my turf
talking about busting ass.
You gotta bring
some to get some.
Now look god damn it.
I came here asking you for help.
I think we'd all be a
lot better off if we
work together on this thing.
Take your hand off of me.
Look, I've been under
a lot of pressure, man.
These murders have been messy.
There-- there's something
inhuman about them.
Outside of Sam's
cat theory, the only
other possibility I have is,
well, you know what that is.
Look, Luke, I'm
begging you for help.
Can't promise you anything.
But if I hear anything,
I'll let you know.
That's all I'm asking.
So there are alligators
down there that are twice
as the size of
ordinary alligators
with fangs that would
chop a leg off like that.
They're rats the size
of cats down there,
and they live off each other.
The dogs, the cats--
Hey, hey, you're Sam Spade.
To get off it and go, huh?
Hang on.
Anyway, um, I gotta
leave, ladies.
Duty calls.
[WOMEN GRUMBLING]
Y'all come back now, you hear?
So exciting.
Yeah, I wanted to
hear the end myself.
[DISTORTED MUSIC PLAYING]
[EERIE MUSIC WITH RHYTMIC
DRUMMING]
[SCREAMING]
Shut up.
Shut up Shut up I said.
Hey, lady, you're
looking real good.
Let me go!
Shut up, one word out of
you, woman, one word and you're
a dead piece of ass.
Take your filthy hands
Off a me!
What's the matter?
Don't you like it, huh?
[SCREAMING]
Help!
Lady, come with me!
Somebody, won't
somebody help me!
[SCREAMING]
God, help me!
All right, all
right, calm down.
CHRIS: Now what was
it that attacked you?
Hm?
Um--
CHRIS: What was it,
if it wasn't human?
Who was it that was killed?
It wasn't real.
Some deformed monster--
CHRIS: Some deformed monster.
Well, I think it got him.
All right, all right,
it's going to be OK.
Just calm down.
Sam, take her out and get
a full statement made.
[PHONE RINGING]
Alan's office.
Well, at least one part of
her story was right anyway.
Our friend got another
one, same story.
This guy's so that
he can be identified.
Looks like a lion got him.
That's five murders
in three days.
Four in the subway.
It, that's what she said.
Like it was some
kind of monster.
I don't think these subway
killings have anything
to do with the, uh, gang wars.
I think this is
some kind of maniac.
Mark, I want 135th and 145
street stations blocked off,
all trains going through
there to be express.
I think it's time you went
down and smoked this thing out.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[HORN SOUNDING]
[SHIVERS]
It's cold.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[GASPING]
[ELECTRICITY ZAPPING]
[CROWD MUTTERING]
Shit, I warned them.
What happened?
A gangland killing.
A member of the Blackjacks.
They just brought another
one out of the subway.
Who?
I don't know.
[CROWD MUTTERING]
Jess, clear these people back.
We have three cars
over here, and we
have people posted all around.
OK, fine, beautiful.
Who is it, Sam?
Who is it?
All right, get back.
This god damn gang fight.
It's time for me to
take a trip downtown
and settle this
once and for all.
Now, Luke, listen to me.
Tom may have been killed
by the Red Dragons,
but I don't think Rodan was.
There's somebody else
down there and we're going
down there to smoke them out.
Take it to court, Chris.
I got enough proof right here
to tell me who did this number,
and I'm going to fix it.
Now hold it, Luke.
I'm telling you it
wasn't the Chinese gangs.
You're just going
to make things worse
by getting blood on your hands.
Like I said mister, you
do it your legal white way.
I know who did
this to my brother,
and I'm going to fix
it, and I'm going
to do what's got to be done.
I said no.
I told you before,
stay out of my life.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
GANG MEMBER: Are you
out of your mind?
Where's your leader?
GANG MEMBER: None
of your business.
Then I want you.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Now before I punch your face
in, I want to know just how
you killed my student, Rodan.
What kind of rules do
you fight by cornering
Rodan in the subway.
I do not understand.
Your friends there, they
stole cocaine from Rodan,
and now you've killed him.
Wait.
There's a rule among
us, that we all must
fight to defend our brother.
But if we had known that your
brother would dishonor any
of us, we wouldn't have fought.
They have caused two deaths,
one of yours, one of our own.
They will be dealt with.
However, as for
Rodan, your brother,
his death is not our doing.
What do you mean?
First you iced Tom.
Then you cornered
Rodan in the subway.
No, it was not us.
Then who?
GANG MEMBER: Come with me.
It is time you
found out the truth.
I'll go with you, but I
warn you, if it's a trick,
I'll get you first.
[HORN SOUNDING]
He will help you.
Does this have something
to do with China?
Does it, Mr. Curtis?
How'd you know my name?
Because of this.
LUKE: The Amulet of Mendow.
I told him to put it back.
I thought it might be
sacred, but why would
your people kill him for it.
OLD MAN: Please, Mr.
Curtis, let me continue.
This amulet holds the
answer to all that
has happened in recent days.
It was brought to me by a
number of the Red Dragons.
Unfortunately, the killer must
have thought he still had it.
That is why he is dead.
You come 10,000 miles, and
to be foiled in a search.
There's still hope.
It is amazing.
I don't understand.
2,000 years ago
the sorcerer, Master
Lung-ton would allow seven
men to be possessed by demons.
And these he would use to
terrorize villages and cities.
Master Chang-dao produced the
emerald in which he trapped
the spirit of the demon.
This is the amulet
your friend took.
From this, the monster is
released into the world.
As long as this amulet
exists , the demon
is deprived most of his power.
Even though he is still strong,
he is unable to tolerate light.
That is why your subways is a
perfect place for him to hide.
In my head, your story is
fantastic, but in my heart,
I know that you
speaking the truth.
The demon will stop at
nothing to regain this amulet.
By destroying it, it
will be free forever,
immortal, and indestructible.
In a way I feel
responsible for this.
I chose Rodan to go with
me in the first place.
What must I do?
You must wage the combat.
Our only chance is this amulet.
Challenge the demon.
Defeat him and we are saved.
Lose and the demon
will eat the soul
of the man who challenged him.
The demon or try to
attack your mind.
He can assume the forms
of those you love most,
and those you fear most.
It will use every
trick at its disposal.
I shall try to help
in the only way I can.
While you are fighting, I
will place my mind with yours.
Perhaps together we will
be stronger than one alone.
This is for those
rats underground.
Squeaking, squeaking,
squeaking, squeaking, yes.
And then, all of you,
God is nobody's fool.
Can't you see?
LUKE: This is the only
thing that can stop him.
I know you can't buy it.
I couldn't buy it either.
That's right I can't buy
it, especially the part
about you going down there.
I don't need any dead heroes.
I've got four guys
to take care of that.
Chris, you won't
be able to hit it
with anything that can stop it.
As a matter of fact,
you're going to be
picked off alone or together.
If I don't make it,
then you can in.
Spiritual leaders at best.
Moses is dead.
Mohamed is dead.
Buddha is dead.
And I'm feeling so--
That's my job.
So for the last time,
the answer's no.
Christopher, let's go.
OK.
Wait here.
I'll be right back.
Pestiferous rats,
shrieking, squeaking,
lusting to sink their
teeth into your weak heart.
Big, black rats.
[CHIMES TINKLING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Where's Luke?
Sam.
[DISTORTED MUSIC PLAYING]
Down this way.
[DISTORTED SPEECH]
[DISTORTED MUSIC PLAYING]
Luke.
Why don't you come with me.
Luke, make love to me.
[MYSTICAL WHISTLING]
[DISTORTED HOWLING]
[DRAMATIC MUSIC WITH GRUNTING]
Show your face!
[MAGICAL MUSIC]
[HIGH PITCHED MUSIC WITH
DISTORTED ANIMALS GROWLING]
[DISJOINTED MUSIC]
[GASPING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[HIGH PITCHED WHISTLING AND
DISTORTED RATTLING]
[DISTORTED VOICES]
Come on.
How are you feeling, brother?
Fine, man.
I'm glad you came.
Killer Curtis.
How you doing?
It's good to see you buddy.
Killer, huh?
Hey, um, whatever
happened to the, um--
Demon?
Yeah.
We didn't find anything
but you down there.
And as for that, uh,
fancy piece of jewelry,
well, uh, the
amulet, we're letting
the priest take care of that.
Yeah, it's my first miracle.
No more murders, no more demon,
and your amulets on a slow boat
the China.
[LAUGHTER]
That's funny.
That's the title of a song by
Cole Porter and George Gershwin
I think.
[MUSIC PLAYING]