Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Jessica?
I'm in here.
Gosh, you still like this one?
Are you kidding me?
That is my favorite
tattoo, I got that
- the night we met.
- The night we met.
Best night of my life.
Oh, hey, don't forget
we got dinner tonight.
Last chance to act
like normal people.
Wouldn't miss it for the
world, I love you always.
And forever.
Got your
blood work back.
And?
And everything looks
good, growth rate is normal
and your alpha-fetoprotein
came back negative.
I don't know what an
alpha-feta-beta-tron is,
but is that a good thing?
Is that a good thing?
Yes, yes, dear,
it's a good thing.
Sorry, I'm just
a little nervous.
First-time parents, I'm
sure you're used to it.
Actually, my wife is
pregnant with our first
and I can tell you it is
much more nerve-racking
on your side of the table.
Congrats.
Thank you, but you guys are
doing all the right things.
Keep taking your
prenatal vitamins
and stay on track with
your low-impact exercise.
And with that, we'll
see you guys next week.
And please, do not be shy.
If you have any
questions, give us a call.
Will do doc, thanks.
See ya next time.
Tell me I am done for the day.
I have a hot date tonight.
Oh, you two are so cute.
Yes, we are.
Dr. Matthews, I'm so sorry
for running late, the bus.
Miss Smith, always
with a graceful entry.
Come on back.
Everything okay?
Yeah, sorry, just, this
place still makes me nervous.
Well, we can play some
smooth jazz if you'd like,
dim the lights,
light some incense.
You're 39 weeks along,
everything all right?
Yeah, I've been all
right, just trying
to get used to doing
this on my own.
On your own?
Allen, seems he'd rather
work things out with the band.
Everything okay?
Oh, it's fine.
Things have been a bit
stressful lately but luckily,
this little guy hasn't been
fussing around too much.
How do you mean?
Oh, he's just been mellow
for the past few days.
He must know Mama needs a break.
Well, usually
it's pretty normal
they calm down
right before birth.
Why don't I have you lie back
and we'll see how your
little man is doing?
Okay.
Yeah, my mum was right.
"Don't tattoo your
stomach," she said.
I have a few, my mom
hates them as well.
Wow, look at you, Dr. Ink.
Let's see how your
mellow man is doing.
Honey, I'm really
sorry about Allen.
Are you gonna be okay?
Nothing lasts
forever, as they say.
But I picked up an extra
job to pay for expenses.
Work?
Honey, you're supposed to
be taking care of yourself.
I am, I just like being busy.
Hm.
What is it, is
everything okay?
I can't find the
fetal heartbeat.
But like I said, sometimes
it slows down before birth.
We'll take you to
the radiologist
and we'll get a better look.
And you can't do it here?
Normally, yes, but, our
machine's out for repairs.
Honey, it'll be okay.
I'll take you over
there, all right?
Okay.
Radiology.
Yeah, hi, this
is Dr. Matthews.
I have a patient 39 weeks
along, no fetal heartbeat.
When
are you bringing her in?
We're on our way now.
- All right, we'll be ready.
- Thanks.
- Hey.
Where you going?
Radiology, I have to let
Jessica know I'm gonna be late.
Nope, get outta
here, I got it covered.
Oh, no, it's fine, man.
No, remember what
happened last time?
She'll kill you,
until you're dead.
True, uh, you're sure?
I'm here all night anyway.
Young female, no fetal
heartbeat, I owe you.
Yeah, you do.
Thank you.
Dr. Peter
Can you tell me something,
is everything okay?
I'm sorry, honey.
Your doctor will have to be the
one to give you the results.
I'll go ahead and
page him right now.
Excuse me?
Oof.
You okay?
Oh, yeah, she's
just busy today.
- Thank you.
- I'll get this for you.
Yeah.
Hey, where are you at?
I'm just thinking
about my last patient.
We couldn't find the
baby's heartbeat.
It's scary.
Scarier now, huh?
Yeah.
Well, I think it's good
that you still worry.
It's what makes
you a good doctor.
It's what makes me love you.
And I love you, always.
And forever.
Ms. Smith?
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Where's Dr. Matthews?
He had to step out tonight.
- But he's my...
- Sage,
there's no easy way to say this.
Your baby died in utero.
There's nothing you
could have done.
I'm terribly sorry.
I'm so sorry, Sage.
Oh, Sean's gonna
cover me tomorrow
so I can be home when
the crib is delivered.
You okay?
Yeah, no, my chest
just feels tight.
Maybe our little girl's not
as big of a fan of Tommy's
- as we are.
- Right?
Ooh, oof.
What is it?
Ooh, oh my God.
- Jessica?
- Oh, no, I don't know...
- Hey, hey.
- Ah, no, no, no...
Hey, hey, hey, come
here, just sit here.
- Careful, careful, careful.
- Okay, okay, okay.
- Sit back, sit back.
- Okay, okay.
Oh my God, it really hurts.
It's okay.
- Okay, okay.
- Sit back, you're okay.
Ooh, oh my God.
I'm gonna call an ambulance.
I'm gonna call an
ambulance, you're fine.
- You're okay, just relax.
- Okay.
- You're gonna be okay.
- I'm really scared,
- okay, okay.
- You're gonna be okay,
you're gonna be
okay, just breathe.
Okay, okay.
Hey, you're okay.
Stay with me, Jess.
Look at me, look
right here, okay?
So there's no one,
no family we can call?
You know, we've tried, but
I don't think there's anybody.
Dr. Matthews just called.
There's something
wrong with Jessica.
Come on, let's get to the ER.
Okay.
Luke, Luke, what happened?
She said her chest
hurt, and then,
there's just blood and,
- I gotta get a...
- Hey, hey!
I'm not gonna let you
do that, all right?
We don't have time for this,
this is not a debate, it's not...
- No!
- Hey!
I got this.
Doctor,
she's flatlining.
All right,
she's in V-fib.
Put the crash cart on now.
Let's go, charging 360.
Charged.
Clear, shock.
All right, feel for pulses.
All right, she's still in V-fib.
Gimme epi, one-milligram IV.
Luke,
we have five minutes to get
this baby out or it's too late.
Luke.
All right, everybody, we're
prepping for a crash C-section.
Let's go, somebody glove me.
Come on, people, let's move.
Hi, Sage, how are you feeling?
I can't sleep.
I need pills or something.
I can check with
the night nurse
and see if she can
bring you something.
Sure, whatever.
Is there anything
else that I can get you?
My baby.
Honey, I know
it's not my place,
but if you'd like to say
goodbye to your baby,
arrangements can be made.
You're right, it
is not your place.
Sweetheart,
where's your daddy?
Luke?
Hi.
Oh my God.
Is that how you
greet your mother?
What happened to this
place, it's a mess.
What happened to
the help I hired?
I fired her.
You fired her, why?
She wanted to be
a live-in nanny.
That's the last
thing that I want.
Why not?
You've got the room.
I don't need someone
watching over me.
I think you do,
look at this place.
Did you come over to judge
the cleanliness of my house
or did you actually
need something?
I came over to see my
precious little granddaughter.
And my son.
We're fine.
Oh, I think you're
floundering at best.
When's the last time
you took a shower?
I said we're fine.
Luke, if you're not
gonna help yourself,
then you're forcing me to
stay here and help you both.
And how exactly are
you gonna help, Katharyn?
Well, you need
to go back to work.
Work is the best thing to help
you get out of this slump.
Slump?
I didn't lose my job or get
kicked off a baseball team, mom,
my wife died!
Keep your voice down.
I lost my wife and became
a father in the same hour.
If that's your idea of a slump,
I would hate to hear
your idea of a crisis.
I don't mean to make
light of the situation, son.
But these things will
not fix themselves.
So I will stay here
for a little while,
but you are hiring help.
Yeah, he
was always
in their relationship.
Oh, that reminds me.
Your mother sent us a postcard.
Where from now?
She has her moments.
That is why
you're gonna be a good mother.
I love you always.
Forever.
You look tired.
Good morning to you too.
I couldn't sleep.
We need to start looking
for full-time help, son.
I'm working on it,
I'm just not ready yet.
Well, when are you
going to be ready?
Because I'm running outta time.
I'm on it, see you later.
Okay.
I mean, I'm happy
with everything...
There he is.
What's happening, brother?
Good to see you, man.
Luke, so good to see you.
Ya look great.
Yeah, well, thanks.
Did you get your new
phone or something?
I called you and texted
you like 1000 times.
Yeah, I saw, I saw, I just,
I've been busy, you know?
Hey, how's that
little lady of yours?
I can hardly wait to see her.
Yeah, she's good, just
lots of poop and drool.
Well, she takes after
her old man, then.
Who's with her now?
My mother's in town.
Katharyn's in town?
Temporarily, I'm looking
for full-time help.
Like a nanny?
Like a nanny.
You know, that
is a great idea.
Is it?
I read as long as they
don't take your kid,
you should be good.
Very funny, Sean.
- What?
- I gotta get back to work.
Hey,
let's hang out, man.
I got work to catch up on.
Yeah, of course.
It's good to have you back.
It was a great wedding.
Best day of my life.
Anyway, I was just
checking in on you.
We got that
consultation in an hour,
so I don't know if,
are you up for it, or?
I'm fine, just buzz
me when you're ready.
Here you go.
Thank you, Sarah.
Can I have the check, please?
Miss Smith?
Dr. Matthews.
How are you?
Clearly, I'm fine.
Would you like to sit?
Going somewhere?
You've got to be
kidding me, right?
What, you been too
busy vacationing?
Drinking Mai Tais on the beach
with your beautiful wife?
I lost my baby that night.
So I hope the date was worth it.
I wanna try and explain.
Please.
Explain to me how
your perfect life got
in the way of that night.
Exactly.
I'm sorry.
Truly, I am sorry.
Can we just get out of here.
If you give me a chance, I
would really like to explain.
Please?
It was an amniotic
embolism, it's very rare.
Dr. Matthews...
I can't even imagine all of that
within minutes, that's horrible.
Hello.
Sage, this is Katharyn.
I'm his mother.
I hope you're not here to
interview dressed like that.
Interview?
Oh, she's an old patient.
Ran into each other, I
thought we'd have lunch.
Ah.
Your son is a great doctor,
I'm sure you're very proud.
Yes, I am.
Oh.
Well, looks like you get to
meet the star of the show.
So,
you were his patient.
Yeah.
Cancer?
Here's my little nugget.
Sage, this is Jessee.
Oh, my, she's
adorable, hi, may I?
Of course.
Ah,
she's so cute!
Yeah, don't let that
pretty face fool you.
She can be a handful.
Oh, could you be
mad at this face?
'Cause it's easy, right?
Oh, I wouldn't be mad,
not one bit, no, not me, no.
Hi, hi.
Sage, you have nanny
experience, right?
Oh, sure, I used to work
with the Dunhills, actually.
Well, I am looking
to hire a nanny.
Luke.
It would start immediately
as a full-time,
live-in position.
Are you serious?
Are you interested?
I am so interested, yes.
I know the Dunhills,
I'll call them.
And please tell
them I said hi.
I started going
back to work part-time
and then in about a week
or so I'll be full-time.
Dr. Matthews, I mean, Luke,
I can't thank you enough.
Well, you could start
today, if you'd like.
- Are you serious?
- Mm-hm.
That is awesome.
I need to go grab some
things, yes, I do.
Thank you.
That worked out well.
What?
I already know her, she
has experience, and...
And a shaved head.
And tattoos.
And look at the way she dresses,
she looks like one of those
kids you used to hang out with.
Well, I like her.
Well, I just don't
think it's right.
You having a young girl like
that living in the house.
Hey.
I will show you your room.
- Right this way.
- Okay.
Hey, have
you seen my keys?
Those ones over there?
Well, since my work is done,
for a while, at least,
I am off to Sedona
with the ladies.
Would you like me to
help you with your luggage?
No thanks, dear,
I'm quite capable.
What you could do, however,
is clean that baby's crib.
It's becoming ghastly.
I'll see you next time.
Okay, I'm gonna be
gone most the day.
I'll have my cell on me.
The diapers are in the nursery,
the extra bottle's
in the kitchen, the...
Yeah, I got it,
go, you're late.
We have a big day ahead of us.
- All right.
- Don't we, little lady?
Thank you.
Your
call has been forwarded
to an automated voice
messaging system.
At the tone, please record
your message.
Hey, man.
It's me again.
Um...
Yeah, just, just
checking in on you.
Just thinking about that time
we all went camping and,
you got that big ol'
mosquito bite on your face
and it swelled up.
Jess and I convinced you you
had West Nile.
Yeah, that was pretty funny...
Hey, you.
No phones on the mats.
Think your fingers have
had enough exercise.
Anyway, give me a call back.
I hope you're well, man.
- Hey.
Whoa,
hot...
Babe.
What's up, doc?
Wanna grab some lunch?
I would if I could.
Got all these new patients.
Thought you'd say that.
Tuna on wheat, turkey on rye.
Tuna.
All right.
Whew.
Sage, huh?
Seems like things are
going pretty good.
Can't be all bad
havin' a hot nanny
running around the house.
She's been helpful.
Really?
That's it, Luke?
That's all you're gonna give me?
Come on, man, she's looking
after Jessee all the time,
she's living at your house.
I bet she's cooking
for ya now, huh?
Is she cooking for ya?
She's cooking for ya, isn't she?
Is there anything else
I can help you with, Sean?
Little busy.
Lighten up, man, come on,
I'm just messing around.
You used to like
to laugh, remember?
Yeah, and you used
to be good at your job.
What's that supposed to mean?
Nothing, man,
don't worry about it.
Is this about Jessica?
You know as well as I do
that we did everything
that we could.
Did you, though?
Did you?
I know you got a lot
going on in your head.
So I'm not gonna react
the way I probably should.
Enjoy the sandwich.
Yes, I ordered the
test just before I left.
I know.
Okay.
Just make sure it happens.
All right, talk
to you then, bye.
Hey, so dinner
is in the fridge
and Jessee is fed,
bathed, and pooped.
Great.
Oh, so, I actually
just put her down
if you wanna pop in
and say goodnight.
Nah, I don't wanna wake her.
I've been taking her to
this baby group in the park
and they would
love it if you were
to pop by and say
hi to everyone.
'Bout what?
The baby group.
Yeah, hangin' out with mommy
groups really isn't my thing.
Did they need money?
No, they just thought it would
be nice to meet the father.
Oh, maybe if I get more
time, I'll let you know.
Good girl, such a hungry
little monkey.
Good morning, Luke, would
you like some breakfast?
Nope, I'm all right.
So, I was hoping
that you would be able
to put her down tonight, I
think she misses her daddy.
I'll do my best.
- Okay, here.
- Thanks.
Oh, I'm sorry.
My bad.
Here we're dancing.
I'll try to be
home early tonight.
Sounds good.
Kisses.
Good girl.
There you are.
Uh, hey, um...
Your mother, she's
been calling the office
10 times an hour, and
every time she calls,
she calls the nurses The Help.
She's a peach.
Thank you.
Luke, you know I love
you, but do me a favor.
Would you please talk to Sean?
Everybody in the office
can feel the tension.
Yeah, I'll get to it.
That's not a request.
Hello?
Hey.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Is that?
This is James.
It's just so unfair.
I would have been
such a good mum.
Why was he taken from me?
Hey, hey, you didn't
do anything wrong.
We can't predict our future.
We just try our damnedest to
make sure it's a good one.
People like you do
not deserve to suffer.
People like us.
I am so sorry.
So embarrassing.
Come with me, I wanna
show you something.
I ask myself the same
questions all the time.
What if I would've
seen the signs?
If I could have saved her.
What if?
That's what I
live with everyday.
What if?
You guys, again, great
job, hospital's happy.
Hey, just keep it up,
talk to you later.
- You have a nice one...
- Take care.
Thank you.
Hey, Sean,
wait up, man.
So I am just in a bit of
a hurry to be a bad doctor.
Look, stop for a second.
I'm sorry, what I
said was uncalled for.
You don't deserve that.
That really sucked, man.
I loved Jessica too, I mean...
I know, I know.
You guys are my...
You were my family.
Now the only time I ever
hear anything about you
is through Sage's Facebook.
How do you think that feels?
I can't explain to you
how hard it's been for me.
Can you just give me one...
I don't wanna do
this here either, okay?
You wanna talk, let's go have
a few beers and get real.
Right now?
Never stopped us before.
Will you clear my schedule?
So Sage has a Facebook.
Are you gonna
start lurking now?
Uck.
Now what?
My little princess.
Oh, look at you!
Look how much you've
grown, so big!
- Oh, sweetheart...
- Hi, Mrs. Matthews.
Sage.
We just got back
from the park.
Yep, she smells like she just
got back from the dog park.
You need to change her diaper
as soon as she poops, dear.
I was going to change
it before her nap.
Well, why don't I just
change it for you now?
I can change her
diaper, Mrs. Matthews.
I hope you didn't take her
to that park on Griffith Street.
It's filled with homeless.
I read in the paper
that they found
more than 12 homeless
people living there.
Filthy, just filthy.
And you know what they do?
I don't know what they do.
They leave trash everywhere.
Clothing, tents.
Needles, it's disgusting.
Wow, that really is something.
I just think it would
be highly irresponsible
for you to take
her to that park.
So, a surprise visit, huh?
Mm-hm, I'm redecorating my
master bedroom and I will take
any excuse to visit my princess.
What time is dinner?
Oh, well, Luke doesn't
get back till later
and I was going to make
myself a salad and...
Well, Sage, dear,
that won't work.
Okay.
You have a guest.
You need to go to
the grocery store
and get something to prepare.
I just got back from the
grocery store earlier...
Well, good, that means it
must not be very far away.
Okay, well, I'll just
give Jessee her bottle
and then be on my way.
It's almost four o'clock,
I can manage the bottle.
It's just if...
I can handle it.
Well, just be sure to
put her down afterwards,
otherwise she'll
be up all night.
You have a
nice night, ladies.
You're the worst.
It's good to hear
you laugh again.
It's good to talk
about her again.
How you doing?
Better, I think.
Everything's been, I don't know,
just blurry for so long.
I wanted to be
there for you, man.
I shouldn't have
pushed you away.
It was kinda selfish.
I just didn't know
how to talk to you.
I saw your texts and your calls
and I see you in the office.
It just reminded me of Jessica.
We've both been there, Luke.
In that room where
it goes wrong.
But when it's somebody you know,
I really miss her too, man.
And I really miss
having you around.
I'm sorry.
You're a good doctor.
I had it all planned out.
A good girl, a good
job, a good life.
And when it was yanked
away from me, I just,
I didn't feel worthy to
ever have that again.
Like it was my fault.
And now?
Hey, sometimes second chances
come in really weird ways.
Jessee's definitely
my second chance.
I bet having Sage
around to help is a bit
of a breath of fresh air too.
Yeah, more than you know.
She's so good with Jessee.
She cooks a mean steak,
and most importantly,
she doesn't put up with
Katharyn's attitude.
What?
What, what's that?
Nothing.
Shut up and drink your beer.
This fish is interesting.
It's mahi mahi.
Hm, it's interesting.
What time did you say
Luke was coming home?
I didn't.
Well, you do the dishes,
I'm going to get some dessert
for my sweet princess.
Well, actually we don't like
to feed her a lot of sweets.
We.
We don't like to give
her a lot of sweets.
I think you should let
me be the Grandmother.
I just think...
No, dear, it's not
your place to think.
I've seen the way you
behave with this child.
- Excuse me?
- It's highly unprofessional.
You walk around like you
belong in this family.
Mrs. Matthews...
I know you lost your child.
I talked to the Dunhills.
They said they had to let you
go because you were depressed
and unfit for the job.
No.
I'll take care of her.
I'm reminded everyday
of what I lost.
Well, that baby is not yours.
And you are not going
to replace her mother.
- You...
- No!
Pack your bags, you're done.
What?
Hey, let's do this again, huh?
Absolutely.
Less beers next time.
All right, get home safe.
Why are you here?
I came to see
my granddaughter.
I called but you didn't answer.
Are you drunk?
I'm fine.
Where's Jessee?
It's late, I put her to bed.
And I sent Sage away.
I'm sorry, you did what?
I sent her away.
I got tired of her finagling
her way into this family.
- Jessee is not her...
- Mom!
You need to stop.
Luke, I did it for
you and for the baby.
She is not a part
of this family.
You didn't do for our family.
Like everything else,
you did it for yourself.
Oh, Luke.
You wanna know why
I pushed you away?
I mean, ya gotta
be curious, right?
You smothered me my entire life.
Well, it must have worked
because look how
good you turned out.
Oh my God, you are
so arrogant sometimes.
I turned out the way I
did because of Jessica.
School, my business,
because of Jessica, not you.
Well, Sage isn't Jessica.
She's not your family
to control anymore.
Where
are you going?
To find Sage.
Luke.
Thanks for answering, I just
wanted someone to talk to.
Well, it's perfect timing.
We just got into town
for the show tomorrow.
You're coming, right?
Sage, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I wasn't there
when you lost the baby.
It was our baby.
Yeah, yeah, our baby.
I'm sorry.
It's fine.
No, it's not fine.
I was confused, you know?
I shoulda done a lot
better, Sage, and I'm sorry.
And then to hear what
that woman said to you...
One for you, miss,
one for you, sir.
Thank you.
Oh, Allen, I don't
drink anymore, not since...
Come on, you're with me, babe.
Make sure nothing
happens to you.
Can't be scared of a drink.
I was just alone for a
really long time after I was...
Listen, you don't have
to explain that to me.
And after every show,
I would wanna hear from you.
I would get out my phone,
I would look at it,
I would look at your number
and I would just stare at it
and I'd wanna hear from you.
And I just wouldn't do it.
Guess life just got in the
way, you know what I mean?
I mean I think it's
hard for him, it must be.
I can only imagine
what it's like
with his mother growing up, I
mean, it must have been hell.
Your mother never
liked me much.
Allen.
I just miss feeling you.
Come on, let's have
some fun tonight.
Sage, hey, it's me.
I don't know what
my mom said to you
but please, call me back.
Sir, do you know
where you wanna go?
Not yet.
Oh!
I have a confession.
Go ahead, what?
What is it?
I'm drunk.
I'm drunk, I am...
Oh, no, your
secret's safe with me.
Shh.
Just give yourself 10 Hail
Marys, it'll be all right.
Hail Mary?
- Hail Mary.
- Hail Mary,
Hail Mary.
Sorry, guys, it's that
time, I'm closing up.
Aw, come on, Tommy.
We need mas tequila por favor.
Not tonight, bud.
Come on, senor, give us
some more tequila, please?
- No, miss...
- Come on, buddy.
You need a cab?
Hey, she's fine, man.
I'm a kitten.
Allen?
What's wrong with him?
Maybe I should get going.
No, no, come on, we're
just reconnecting, it's fun.
It is fun, but...
I'm only here
for one more night.
Let's hang out.
Let me just make
one call, one call.
- Okay.
Okay, one call.
Sage.
Hey, sorry for
calling so late.
It's no problem, where you at?
Hey, Sage,
we gotta go, Tommy's
kickin' us out.
Ma'am, Tommy's.
- Luke, I need to go...
- I'm going.
I'll call you later.
I'll be right there.
Are you ready?
Actually, I, I can't.
Come on, you can come over
and you can tell me
about your horrible boss.
He's not horrible.
Eh, whatever, it'll
be like old times.
Actually, Tommy,
I will get that cab.
Hold on, one minute you're
all over me over there and,
suddenly you're not gonna...
Hey, pal, I think
she's fine on her own.
Hey, why don't you
mind your business, man?
- I'm calling the cops.
- Hey...
Yeah, whatever, you call 'em.
Allen, you need to let go.
Yeah, you know, this is why
I left you in the first place.
You know that?
'Cause you can never get a grip
on what's right in front of you.
No.
I'm right in front
of you, baby, I'm here,
- I'm here tonight.
- Let go, let go!
Come on, please, come.
Hey, hey, hey, hey,
hey, get off her.
Luke?
Luke.
What, is this the new me?
Blonde-haired,
blue-eyed, preppy-ass me?
Hey, you know what?
You can have that little
Aussie girl, you know what?
'Cause I don't
have time for this.
Face for this,
I don't have time for this.
I don't have time for
this!
Are you okay?
I'm really sorry about that.
It's all right.
Katharyn, she didn't
have the right.
It's okay, I
think she was right.
I got too comfortable.
Too comfortable?
When I lost my
baby I was drifting.
And then you and Jessee came
along and it was like a family.
But it wasn't my family,
it wasn't meant for me.
- Sage...
- Listen,
I love Jessee, I love her
with my whole heart but,
I think I have to go.
I think that's
a horrible idea.
What?
I don't accept your
resignation, ma'am.
Well, I don't think
that's how this works.
Okay, why don't
you sleep on it?
I'll take off tomorrow
and watch Jessee.
If you wake up in the morning,
you feel the same way,
I won't stop you.
Sleep on it.
Huh.
Good morning, Sage.
Hi.
I didn't know how
you liked your coffee.
Black is fine, thanks.
How did you sleep?
Where's Luke and Jessee?
He took her out.
I was hoping to tell him that
today would be my last day.
Yeah, he told me this morning
that that's what
you were thinking.
Well, there it is.
Why don't you sit.
I'll stand.
Sit, please, dear, it's
just coffee, it doesn't bite.
Did you know that I hated
Jessica in the beginning?
It's true.
Luke was a wild child
when he met her.
He was hanging out with
riffraff and hellraisers,
and then he met this girl.
She was nice, she was
beautiful, she was educated.
She gave him a reason to
get serious about school,
get his degree.
I'm not following.
I hated it.
For the first time in his
life there was someone
who wasn't me that
made him happy.
It was her that he
wanted to please.
Well...
From the time Luke's dad
died, for a long time after,
it was just the two of us.
I held onto him really tightly.
And then to see this
woman take my place, I...
It broke my heart.
Is this going somewhere?
The way I've treated you
has not been very polite.
And I realized last night
that the reason I've
treated you that way
is because you remind me of her.
You have become important
to the two people
that I care most
about in my life and,
I was just worried that there
wouldn't be room for me.
I don't know what to say.
Luke told me about
the man you were with.
I wish I'd been there.
I would have let
him know how we deal
with things like
that on the ranch.
Luke and Jessee love you
and I lied about the Dunhills.
Shocking.
They were really
sorry to lose you,
and they told that you'd
become a part of the family
and that you used to take
the boys to ride horses.
Now, why didn't you put
that on your resume?
I don't know.
Well, horses and I go
together like steak and sauce.
Let me make it up to you.
When's the last time you
had a girls' day out?
Never.
Go get dressed, I'm
taking you with me.
Today you're mine.
Okay.
I'm ready
to go, Mrs. Matthews.
I'll be right there.
Looking more and
more like her everyday.
She woulda spoiled you rotten.
She was so excited when she
found out we were having a girl.
I was pretty scared,
to be honest.
Can I tell you something?
I'm scared I can't
live up to that.
It's been pretty hard on your
dad not having your mom here.
I haven't been home much.
When I am home, I've
been ignoring you.
I'm sorry.
But I'm gonna get better.
It's gonna be better.
Promise.
Boop.
All right,
mm-hm
get ready for the...
Mashed peas and squash.
Oh, God, oh, no.
Let's get you something
better to eat, baby girl.
Whoa.
I mean, wow.
Thanks, I think.
Your mum took me out.
And now I'm gonna take Jessee
and get you cleaned up.
Come here, my sweetheart, whew!
You're staring.
Sorry.
I just, you look different.
I'll take that
as a compliment.
It is.
Your mum and I
had a nice talk.
We've found some common ground.
Like what?
We both love that little girl.
Does this mean that...
Yeah, I'm gonna stay.
Okay, good.
And I'm gonna try to
be home more often.
Yeah, good.
Good.
It'll make us both really happy.
Where are the diapers?
Oh, I can show you.
All right, how 'bout...
Oh, no, not that one,
she won't eat the carrots.
You need the banana
and split pea.
All right, I can't wait
to feed this baby a steak.
Steak.
So, I was thinking...
Of giving me a raise.
Close.
How 'bout a night off?
Huh, details, sir.
I have this banquet
I go to every year
for the OB-GYNs
and I thought maybe
if you wanted to go,
we could go together.
Well, I don't have anything
that nice to wear and,
I mean, isn't that kind of...
Boring?
Lame, square?
Nailed it.
Why don't we come
up with a codeword
in case we get too bored?
Mm-hm.
All right, well,
I will pick you up
at your bedroom door at 8 p.m.
Okay, so I have all the
necessary information right here.
If you need anything,
please call me.
You don't need
to worry about us.
We're gonna catch up
on the Kardashians.
Perfect.
You know, you two
better get going.
You're gonna miss
out on the open bar.
I'm ready for my closeup.
I think that's what they say.
You look incredible.
Where'd you get the dress?
I had some help.
You're welcome.
Nice to see
you, how are you?
Great, wonderful,
having a good time?
I feel out of place.
Is it because you're the
youngest one here by 15 years?
I'll give you the lay
of the land, come on.
All right, that there
is Dr. Hamilton.
He gets handsy after a
few drinks, so be careful.
Okay, this guy here,
this is Dr. Pearson.
The young lady he's
with is his fifth wife.
He met her while vacationing
in the Bahamas with
his fourth wife.
Wow, quite the spread of
colleagues you have here.
Mm-hm.
That guy there in the cool suit,
Two shots.
- Shots, go!
- That is my business partner
doing shots.
That'll put hair
on your chest.
That was so strong.
- Nice.
- I hope not.
The codeword for
tonight is disco dust.
Disco dust?
Shh.
Luke Matthews, glad to see
you came out of your cave.
Dr. Price, I knew you
wouldn't miss an open bar.
Ah, it's the only good
thing about these things.
You remember my wife.
Yes, of course,
Emily, nice to see you.
This is Sage.
Good day.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
We just wanted to
stop and say hi.
I'm glad you did,
see you guys around.
Didn't
his wife just die?
And he's already
with someone else?
Mrs. Price, can you
speak up a little bit?
We couldn't quite hear ya.
Ooh, disco dust, disco dust.
Nah, don't worry about her.
She likes to borrow pills
from her husband's office.
- Oh.
- Mm-hm.
I need a drink.
You and me both.
Hi, I'm Sage.
I'm Kelli, with an I.
Oh, hi, Kelli with an I.
So how long have you
and Sean been together?
Who?
Oh, Sean, we met a couple
months ago at the gym.
Oh, at the gym.
I tried going there once
and decided to take a nap.
So, what about you and
that other hot doctor?
Oh, us?
No, nothing, I'm just
his daughter's nanny.
Oh, that's boring.
Wanna do shots?
Uh, maybe, yeah.
You know they're free, right?
You don't even have to tip.
It's the best, I can get
like three, four, five,
how many do you want?
Yeah, let's, okay.
I like you, Sage.
Thanks, Kelli with an I.
So what's up
with you and Kelli?
Mm-mm, don't judge until you
see her work the pull-up bar.
No, come on, the
real question is
what's going on with you two?
Not a thing.
Come on, Matthews.
This coy little game
you're playing is cute
but you can't fool me.
I see the way you look at her.
I mean, she looks good.
Smells good.
But she's my
employee, that's it.
You're making me sober.
I think you have
a drinking problem.
Oh, there you are.
I was try to escape
Kelli with an I.
Yeah, she's somethin'.
Yep.
Come on.
Uh, where?
I can't dance, I have
cinder blocks for feet.
You will be great.
Well, I feel like
the unpopular girl
at high school dancing
with the quarterback.
That's silly, I
played baseball.
Really?
Yeah, my whole life, actually.
Mom wanted a sports star.
How 'bout you?
Oh, no sports for me,
I was too punk for that.
I was all about loud
music and horses.
Horses?
That doesn't sound very punk.
Oh, but barrel racing
is.
It's like the music,
controlled chaos.
Hm, must be a lot of space
to ride around in Australia.
You have no idea,
it is so beautiful.
Hey.
Hi.
Just havin' a party, people.
Hey, we're thinking about
getting out of here.
You guys interested?
Yeah, there is this really
rad club down the street.
Yeah?
Is the club called disco dust?
Yes.
I don't get it.
Uh,
we should get inside,
check on Jessee.
Well, Michelle's with Jessee
and I'm sure she's
asleep by now.
We need to, we should
just get inside, you know?
Did I do something?
What is it?
I keep seeing her.
Who?
Jessica.
If it would have been up to me,
we would have lived in
that apartment forever.
This whole house was
just her brainchild.
Being in the desert
made her feel
like we lived in the Old West.
She sounds really great.
She was.
When I first met her, I was
always looking for the
next beer run party.
She got me focused,
pushed me to be a doctor.
And I just assumed you
loved the female anatomy.
Sounds kinda cheesy but,
I became an OB because
I just loved the idea
of being there when
a family starts.
Seeing that look
on a father's face
when he first sees his child.
Or the relief a mother
has when you tell her
that she has a very
happy, healthy baby.
Nothing quite like it.
Well, Dr. Matthews,
you do have a soft
side under there.
Yeah, somewhere under there.
How 'bout you?
All I know about you is
that you are an Aussie
and you used to ride horses.
Every weekend
when I was a kid,
my dad taught me to barrel race
and I loved it so much
that I started competing.
Like a real cowgirl.
Yes, like a real cowgirl.
Hm.
The summer I sold my
horses was really rough.
My mum moved back
here to the states
and my dad stayed in Adelaide
and he had to sell the
horses just to get by,
and that was that.
I buried myself in music,
and my horses just
became a faded memory.
So the cowgirl has a past.
Yeah.
You don't have to
answer this but, Allen?
Yeah.
Girls like bad guys, I guess.
Mm-hm.
Mm-hm, I met him
back home at a show
when his band was doing
smaller opening acts,
and at first, I was just
another girl to him.
Then he made me feel special.
Dedicated songs to me onstage,
winked at me during solos.
I loved it.
Then I followed him to the
states when he got signed.
And then he changed, real quick.
Our late nights became
his late nights.
He stopped sleeping on the
bus and disappeared a lot.
Then I got pregnant.
Yeah, and he adopted
the rockstar lifestyle.
Yeah, things became
too real, he said.
Needed to work on
touring and his work.
He said he'd send me
money and I'd be set.
Until the other night,
the last I saw him
or heard from him was
when the bus pulled out
and he headed east.
Why are men so horrible?
Let's face it, we're jerks.
Well, present company
excluded, obviously.
I left voicemails,
and emails and texts.
And I'm about three months along
and he tells me I
shouldn't call him anymore.
I'm upsetting his artistic flow.
Such a load.
You never wanted to show up
to one of his concerts
and call him out?
What's the point?
I make a scene, it
makes me look crazy
and I'm still left alone.
I just wanna start over,
clean slate, you know?
Let's get you inside.
- Look who's here!
- Hi!
Hey, guys.
Hi, good to see you again.
Nice to see you.
Look at you, hi!
How you doing?
- Good.
- Ooh, oh, yeah.
- Oh my goodness!
- Hi.
♪ Happy Birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy Birthday dear Jessee ♪
So I was thinking about
what you were saying
and now wanted to
see if it was true.
Sage, this is Texas,
Texas, this is Sage.
Whoa, he is beautiful.
He's yours all day.
A patient of mine owns
the place and he said...
You have no idea
what this means to me.
Let's see what you got.
Hi.
Mom?
- Oh, God, hey!
- I'll get Jessee.
Hey, you okay?
Call 911!
Hey.
How's she doing?
She's been in and out.
You look tired, you
should go home and rest.
No, I need to be here.
No, you should rest.
If she wakes up and
you look like this,
I'm not gonna hear
the end of it.
All right.
Fine, I will go home and shower.
Okay.
You good?
Yeah, I got it.
Oh.
You have a nice nap?
Could you ring for a nurse
and get us some dinner?
God, what time is it?
It's time for dinner.
Katharyn, do you
know where you are?
In the hospital.
Do you know why?
Yeah, I...
Jessee?
Jessee's okay.
Let me call Luke.
No.
Gimme a minute.
Is my purse here?
The first time I met
Luke's grandmother,
I was scared out of my wits.
She was a formidable woman
and she carried
herself so strong.
Luke's father and his
family were ranch owners
and I was the girl from the
other side of the tracks,
and I started dating their
son when we were both 19.
Got engaged when we were 20 and,
married when we were 21.
Do you know why
pearls are so special?
Why they're different
from other gems?
No.
Well, they come from
the sea, not the earth.
They don't have to
be cut or polished.
They're born.
And when they're born, they
come out strong and beautiful.
That's what my
mother-in-law told me
that night before I got married.
When she gave me this ring.
It's like you, Sage.
You are strong, and
beautiful, and unique,
and I want you to have it.
I can't accept this.
I'm not the one you
wanna give this to.
Yes, you are.
You are, dear.
It's just...
You don't know me.
Sage.
Hey, you, where you off to?
Hi, I have to go,
Luke, okay, your mum...
Hey, what'd she say now?
This isn't how
it's supposed to go.
How what was?
This was meant to
be a job, just a job.
What are you talking about?
I love you.
I love you too.
No, no, Luke,
I am in love with you.
Hey.
Luke,
say it.
I am so in love with you.
Hey.
Well...
There's
some scary one.
Do you wanna meet
your little brother?
Okay, come on.
Hello, Baby Blake.
Aww!
I'm glad you hired her, too.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org