[man]
All of us have wondered...
what is love?
[music starts]
[man]
Love is...
commitment.
Sharing your life.
All of it.
Your fears and dreams.
But...
the more you share
the more you love?
Or the longer the relationship
How do you rate
a good relationship?
By moments?
Which ones?
The happy ones?
Or perhaps by enduring
the sad ones?
[music continues]
I HOPE YOU NEVER STOP LOVING ME
Hi.
[music continues]
Hello.
Where did you get wine?
Over there.
Would you have a glass
with me... or seven?
OK...
I'm Sebastián.
Valeria.
[Sebastián] Why is it different
to fall in love
than to love somebody?
[music continues]
To fall in love is simple.
It's about emotions...
first times...
The first date.
The first touch.
And the first kiss.
[cell phone rings]
[Sebastián]
What if we put it all together?
The real and the virtual?
THREE YEARS AGO
YOU STARTED DATING SEBASTIAÁN
[Sebastián] If we put together
the laughter...
the kisses...
All the pictures we took.
The ones we shared
and those that are private.
And what about
the late-night conversations?
The messages,
the comments, the posts...
If we put together
all we shared...
The movies, the songs...
I LOVE YOU, PANDA
More moments...
equals a better relationship?
The more information
we create...
the more we love each other?
Perhaps.
But in the real
or the virtual world...
An action, a word...
one click...
can delete everything.
[music continues]
I got it when I met Valeria.
I had to go back to my mom's
after going all in
and losing everything.
And yes, there were hard times,
but we faced them together.
And we would move forward
just the same.
[cell phone rings]
NEW MESSAGE
IT'LL BE OK, PANDA.
WE'LL GO THROUGH IT TOGETHER
NOW AND ALWAYS... I LOVE YOU
NEW MESSAGE
THANKS FOR YOUR SUPPORT.
I'D BE LOST WITHOUT YOU.
I LOVE YOU, PANDA.
I love you, Panda.
[music continues]
[music ends]
VALERIA
INCOMING CALL
[woman]
The call will be charged...
[honking]
Sebastián!
Damn it!
[Valeria]
Sebastián!
I'm coming!
I'm ready, honey!
-Just a minute!
-Hurry up!
[honking]
-What is it?
-Just hurry up!
[music]
[cell phone rings]
-Hello?
-Will you keep ignoring me?
Oh, I'm sorry, sir.
Wrong number.
-Thanks.
-Panda!
You knew I had to work.
I was up all night!
Will you forgive me
or we're going in like this?
You promised we'd be on time.
We didn't even make it
to the service.
I'm a maid of honor.
Well, that may be not so bad.
Standing up and sitting back
down 50 times is absurd.
I mean...
Really?
Hello. Your name, please?
Valeria Laisequilla... plus one.
God!
Will you forgive me already?
We missed the service, so what?
What do you mean?
You know Ale is one
of my best friends
and I missed her walking
down the aisle.
Yeah, Ale, Dani, Majo and Sofi
all are your best friends
and all want to get married.
What's with that?
But that's not the point.
The point is: you should forgive
me so we can enjoy the wedding.
It's not my fault
that you don't have friends.
You'll pay for this.
Wasn't the release in a month?
Yes, but we had to work on...
Valeria Laisequilla plus one.
-Table seven.
-Thank you.
Plus one.
[exhales]
It's not convenient to invest in
cryptocurrency, it's obsolete.
Now multi-sided platform
companies are in.
So, what are you doing now,
Sebas?
[Sebastián]
I am...
going after my dreams now.
I finally became...
the caretaker
of a whole building.
Is that part time while you go
after your dreams or...?
Full time.
In fact, I started as
a janitor and now...
I'm in charge.
He's obviously joking, Erick.
He works at a record label.
He's in charge
of the digital transition.
Oh, I see!
Another of your projects like...
that of the online music app...
TuRocolApp, with double "p."
It was very similar
to Spotify, right?
The wedding is awesome, right?
Ale and I would always
dream of a wedding like this.
-Besides, Roy is a great guy.
-[woman] I know, right?
Ale must be really nervous.
Why nervous?
I mean, if they always dreamed
of this wedding
and Troy is a great guy...
-Roy.
-Roy is a great guy.
Yes, but this will be
her first time.
The first time she gets married?
No, honey.
Ale is a virgin.
[Sebastián laughs]
[Sebastián]
In a school play?
No, I mean it.
God... I get it.
Nothing at all?
She saved herself
for this special time.
She "saved herself."
So, not even...
Hey, Sebas is a bit
out of line, isn't he?
Your husband is charming!
-We're not married.
-We're just dating.
[Sebastián]
So, hold on...
Back on that...
What if they don't like it?
Right? It's like...
buying a very expensive car
without test-driving it.
-That's for idiots.
-I was a virgin, too...
and I'm no idiot.
No, that's not it, girl.
Sebastián didn't mean that.
-Right?
-No, not at all.
You are...
totally different.
-You are doing really well.
-Yes.
I need to go to the toilet.
[man coughs]
Are you OK, man?
-Do you need water?
-No, I'm fine.
-Who are you?
-I'm...
Valeria's plus one.
Huh?
Valeria, the bride's friend.
Twenty-seven.
Since Ale has so many friends,
I resolved to number them.
Nice.
And who are you?
I am the groom.
Whose?
At the wedding.
Damn, you're right!
Congratulations.
-Do you want some?
-No, I'm fine.
-Just a hit.
-No, really...
-Come on, just a hit.
-OK.
[exhales]
I don't know what I'm doing.
I know, dude.
You're getting married.
When I saw her
walking down the aisle,
I wanted to run away.
Why did you get married then?
Ale is two months pregnant.
What! Isn't she a...?
Rodrigo!
What are you doing here?
I've been looking for you.
I can't stand these heels!
-Nothing.
-Hi, how are you?
-Congratulations!
-Thanks! Come with me,
the Garcías are here.
What did I tell you?
-We must always be together.
-Yes.
How are you enjoying
the party, handsome?
I'm good.
Guys, I mean, this is my moment!
Attending weddings is weird.
It's like... going to the past.
Not everybody is afraid
of commitment.
I know, but it's unnecessary.
What?
Are you never getting married?
Like this?
A wedding party, a service,
200 guests
and a drunk bride, no.
Not even with the love
of your life?
Look at that, honey.
It's embarrassing.
You fell for it,
you really did...
It's unnecessary, old-fashioned.
I'm feeling sick, shall we go?
[Ale]
One... two... three!
Honey...
wake up, sleeping beauty.
-We're here.
-Where are you going?
Well, I'm going up...
to your place.
No?
I thought we could...
Why would I go to my place
with a guy
who doesn't want to commit?
I'm not fifteen.
No.
Get an Uber, Sebastián.
-Bye.
-Panda, wait.
Panda, hold on!
Hold on!
You know
I wasn't talking about us.
I mean...
Ale and her fancy wedding,
well...
I felt overwhelmed, but...
I love you.
You're my soulmate.
[music]
-Hold on! Hold on!
-What?
What about your roomie?
He went on vacation
with his boyfriend.
-OK.
-Uhu.
How drunk are you?
-I won't forgive you so easily.
-OK.
What's with your dress?
-Hold on.
-What?
Now what?
I love you, idiot.
And I love you.
-Sebastián!
-I can't unzip your dress!
Let me see.
How many fucking layers
are there?
-Tear it off! Ow!
-Are you OK?
[music]
[alarm]
Working on Sunday is a drag.
-Hey!
-[groan]
What's going on?
I don't want to go to work.
I'm mad at you.
But I can't quite remember why.
-You're not mad.
-I am.
Everything is OK.
I love you, little Panda.
[music]
[little boy screams]
-So they can continue.
-Precisely.
Thank you.
I'll see you in a minute.
Cheers.
NEW MESSAGE
PANDA, I DON'T FEEL VERY WELL.
I'M SORRY,
I CAN'T SEE YOU LATER,
BUT YOU'LL DO AMAZING.
I LOVE YOU.
-Sebas!
-Alonso.
How are you?
I'm fine, bro.
Hey, don't...
-Alonso...
-Your skin is so soft.
-Come on...
-You remind me of Valeria.
Don't start man, I mean it.
-By the way, where is she?
-She couldn't make it.
That is a real woman.
I mean it.
Don't start, man.
Do you know what I miss
the most about her?
-No and I don't care.
-To make love to her.
Son of a bitch!
You know? I've been
with over a thousand women
and I've never felt
the connection I had...
Sebastián?
-Hi, Mike.
-Mike.
I was talking with Alonso.
There's something wrong
with the platform.
Give me your mobile.
What do you need it for?
Take it.
What is it?
Let's see.
-Show me.
-That's it.
Is that all?
Huh?
The problem was your phone.
When you downloaded the app,
did you allow data sharing?
No way, that makes
me very nervous.
What if someone accesses
my phone and hacks it!
Nobody wants to, Mike.
That is necessary so the app
can use your mobile
Internet connection.
So, in that case,
I owe you an apology, don't I?
I'm sorry, OK?
Can you imagine
what could have happened
if you hadn't invested
all your money
in your application
and Spotify hadn't gotten
ahead of you?
TuRocolApp, with double "p."
Exactly, huh?
You would be one of those
young billionaires now.
[laughs]
Come on, truth is,
at first I doubted hiring you.
Mostly, because
of your massive failure.
But now I see...
it was the best decision.
By the way, do you remember
you said something
about hiring a "training"?
A trainee.
That's it, a "trainer."
Hey, Pam!
She is my daughter.
And I want her to be useful.
Sure, she must be the youngest
and she might call you...
daddy, right?
Yes, why?
Hey, daddy.
Pamela, this is Sebastián.
The guy I told you about.
Hi, I'm Sebastián.
How are you?
I'm Pamela.
Pamela is taking a gap year
and I want her to learn
a bit of the business.
I'll be all yours these months.
Excuse me?
-No, I didn't mean...
-I get it.
I get it.
I'll leave you to two
to break the ice.
Bye, princess.
See you, my visionary man.
Number one!
Take care of her.
-I will, Mike.
-OK.
-Stop it.
-I love you, I can't help it!
I don't know why he thinks
that looks good.
Well, your father belongs
to a generation
of rockers that...
is dying.
It's OK.
-The music is great.
-Yes, in fact...
-we brought the band to...
-Oh, I love this song.
-Do you want to dance?
-In a minute, yes.
[music]
NEW MESSAGE
Who is texting you this late?
Huh?
Sorry, no.
Weren't you on pills?
Yes, but I forgot to take it
on the wedding day
and the next day,
I was hungover and I did, too.
And the day after, I took three.
But...
it was useless.
Useless.
What if it's a phantom
pregnancy?
They are real. They are.
It's a fact.
We'll sort it out.
Don't worry.
Everything will be OK.
You...
want to have it, right?
Yes.
[sighs]
Well, it's not like
I planned it,
I'm scared to death...
but I think it's different
to get pregnant
at 15 than at 28.
Look, I also know...
this isn't the best timing
for us...
but I do want to have it.
What about your career?
Which one?
Being a restaurant hostess?
Being a photographer!
It's not a terminal illness,
it's a baby!
[music]
[clears throat]
We're having a kid.
Like mature adults.
Are we?
Sometimes.
Two green juices.
No prickly pear for me.
-Sure, and for you?
-The same, but without sugar.
-All right.
-Hi, Mom.
-How far along is she?
-How do you know?
[laughs]
Don't be silly, I'm your mother.
How far along?
One month and a few days.
Oh! Oh, how exciting!
I'm finally going to be
a grandmother.
I don't know what to do.
I'm really scared.
Well, you'll do what is right.
I didn't raise a jerk.
Hi, how are you?
Hi, Juan.
The usual, please.
Right away, ma'am.
I...
I'm happy!
Smile!
[baby crying]
[sighs]
Honestly, I'm scared to death.
But I do want to have it.
Well, it's not a big deal.
It's like having a Tamagotchi.
I mean, you say your boyfriend
is doing well, right?
Yeah.
Valeria, the truth is,
we're nearly adultescents.
Besides, remember they say
a child is born under
a lucky star.
-Yes, you're right in that.
-Yes.
Look, just relax
and let it flow.
Everything will be alright.
Thanks.
Panda!
-It's really late!
-It is!
-Give me a minute!
-Hurry up!
-I'll be right back!
-I'll wait here.
Hi, the bar is about to close.
Can I offer you a drink?
No, thanks.
I'm just waiting for Valeria.
-Sebastián.
-Yes.
Damn it, man!
Do you remember me?
Long time no see, man!
Alberto!
From high school!
The Sevilla, man!
-Alberto...
-Can I sit down?
You already did.
Damn! You still have
that black humor.
So, what have you been up to?
Are you still
in that posh rock band?
I'm not posh
and I quit the band.
Denial.
Honestly, the songs were
too corny for me.
But you always defended
your style, that was cool.
Yes, actually, we did.
And what about you?
Do you still jump
anything that moves?
Hey, not so loud,
people will think I'm a stalker
and I'll get hash-tagged
and everything.
Look, I know...
I know I was a mess
in high school,
but I've changed.
I'm really glad for you,
Alberto.
It was nice to see you.
Since I met Jesús
and I let him into my life...
the truth is, it changed.
I became a more
enlightened being.
OK...
You want to meet Jesús,
don't you?
No, I'm fine.
He always wants to meet people.
Certainly.
-I really don't...
-Jesús!
I'm more of an atheist...
[Sebastián laughs]
Jesús, this is Sebastián,
my high school best friend.
Sebastián, this is Jesús.
-No way, is this Jesús?
-Yes.
-Sebas!
-What's up, Chuy?
-Hi.
-We were never best friends.
-He's just joking.
-You know my Betito.
Are you... a couple?
-Yes, since...
-Last month?
The inventory night
when you got here.
-Of course.
-Stop it, Beto!
I'm glad you assumed it.
Assumed what?
That you're gay.
-Who is?
-You.
I'm not gay, man.
-What?
-[Jesús] I'll explain it, OK?
I'm gay.
He isn't.
And it's OK,
I don't need a label.
No, hold on. You don't have
to explain yourself.
-Beto, honey...
-It's very clear.
Yes, we have, because there are
many close-minded people
like him and we have
to explain them.
-That's impossible, man.
-I mean...
So, you're saying
that because I'm gay,
I can't have a heterosexual
boyfriend?
I mean, apples to apples
and oranges to oranges.
None should mix, right?
You know what?
I didn't know you were
like this.
You're... a super Nazi.
You're a couple, right?
-Yes.
-Yes, that's what we said.
And you fuck.
Hold on, I won't answer that.
It's a very tacky question.
Of course we fuck, man!
OK?
I'm a man, I need to fuck.
Exactly, you're a man,
but it turns out you're gay.
I'm not gay, man!
I don't like they put inside...
Beto, hold on!
You may not like anything
inside you, but...
you like touching another man.
Beto, it's OK.
I'll explain to him.
I'll ask you something, OK?
Do you jack off?
Yes, what does that
have to do with...?
[Jesús]
You're gay. Period.
You like to touch another man.
-He's gay, don't get mad.
-Yes, he is.
-But it's me...
-It's the same, you are.
-Honey...
-I'm glad you two met.
He's Jesús' boyfriend.
I've told you about him.
Van, they went
to high school together.
Can you believe it?
It's like destiny.
-Really? How crazy!
-Yes.
Destiny.
-See you.
-Bye, Chuy.
-Bye, Sebas.
-Bye, Alberto.
-Nice to see you.
-Bye!
-Take care.
I'm really glad Jesús is finally
with someone well-balanced
who takes care of him
and loves him.
Yes, very well-balanced.
-We're really late, hurry up.
-Let's go.
"I promised him," she told me.
But she doesn't want
to have children.
Or to choose any sperm
or that nobody gets inside her
for 9 months.
Can you hear me, darling?
I don't want love
to be marriage,
children and Instagram pictures.
I just want it to be...
the unpredictable silence
in the sofa.
Forever.
[applause]
Thank you.
[Valeria] You snored
all the play, Sebastián!
"Play"?
That is a joke to theatre!
-I loved it.
-Yeah, right,
because she's your super
conceptual and artsy friend.
I won't move in three hours.
Hey! I invited her
to your birthday party.
-Behave!
-Alright,
but she'll have to blink.
It freaks me out she doesn't.
[guitar music]
What is it?
Do I have a booger?
No, you don't.
So?
Vale...
-Why are you acting so weird?
-No, I'm not.
I was thinking...
on this subject...
I mean,
in this situation that...
I think the best for both
would be...
I mean, what we should...
Well, yes...
Well... We should get married.
-What?
-We should get married.
Are you proposing to me?
Yes.
Sort of.
-"Sort of"? How romantic!
-No, no. I am.
I'm asking you to marry me.
Valeria Laisequilla,
would you...
be my wife?
I swear I'll get you a real one
when I have money.
You know
I don't care about that.
Is that a yes?
Are you asking me...
because of the baby or...
because you love me?
-Because of our kid, obviously.
-Sebastián!
Because I love you.
What do you say?
Hmm...
Then...
-Yes.
-[Sebastián] Yes?
[guitar music continues]
I love you.
What?
Are you happy?
You are?
I love you.
I love you, too.
[guitar music ends]
I think we can make
the graphic straight
and the letters closer.
That's it.
I sent you a Facebook
friend request.
You did?
-Let's see.
-Yes.
You accepted it.
Well, I sometimes
don't pay attention...
to Facebook.
-All these numbers...
-Do you have like... many fans?
Fans? Just my mom.
That's cute.
There's something
that doesn't...
What?
Has anyone told you
you look like Christian Grey?
Who?
The sexy millionaire
from Fifty shades.
-Me?
-Yes.
-No, I don't think so.
-I mean it.
Look, come here.
Okay, your hair is a bit short,
but if you do it this way...
That's it, you look like him.
[message ping]
You're... you're getting emails.
You've got...
emails.
I'll talk to my friend,
Father Paulino,
to get you married
as soon as possible.
We don't want a church wedding.
Sebastián is...
Well, he doesn't believe
in those things.
Then...
What are you going to do?
We're having a civil wedding,
for the time being.
You're not getting married,
then.
-It's the same for us, Dad.
-For you...
but in God's eyes, that child
will be floating
in Purgatory forever...
No, he won't be
floating anywhere!
I came to give you the news,
but I don't expect you there.
Save yourself the embarrassment.
Let's go.
[clears his throat]
Mr. Andrés.
ABOUT PAMELA
DOB: 08/25/98
RELATIONSHIP STATUS: SINGLE
FAVORITE MUSIC:
ANYTHING I CAN DANCE TO
Ninety-eight?
What was I...?
Damn, she's younger
than Super Nintendo.
That's embarrassing, Sebastián.
-Sebastián.
-Mike!
How are you doing
with the app changes?
It's going well,
I was just working on them.
That's great.
And how has Pamelita been doing?
Well, very well.
She had a very hard time
after the divorce.
Yes, well...
She was unstable.
You know how that is, right?
But if you notice she's sad,
please, let me know.
I see she's very well, Mike.
Do you have the changes there?
No, well, yes.
But they aren't ready yet.
I'll get them to your office
as soon as finish.
-No, let's see them now.
-Let me finish, Mike.
I want to do...
Let me...
Nothing worth doing
can be done overnight.
Let's see.
Mike, I can explain.
-For fuck's sake!
-Mike...
-No...
I'm more fucked up
by the minute.
-No, don't say that.
-I can't see a thing
without my glasses!
Where are they?
I'll come back in a minute,
they're at my desk.
You're an asshole,
you're an asshole.
[bell rings]
Coming!
Hi.
How can I help you?
You're Valeria, right?
I'm Carolina.
It's your pleasure to meet me,
because I'm here
to help you plan
your dream wedding!
[high pitch scream]
I know, I hope you don't mind
I've lots of ideas,
but I know we must hurry up
if you don't want your...
how embarrassing, belly to show.
I'm sorry, who are you?
What are you doing here?
You know what I think?
We would get over with it faster
if you weren't making
this type of stupid questions.
Why don't you tell me
your... ideas?
You may not have many
or they may be bad,
so I can tell you mine,
which are amazing.
Then, together, that is
me and not so much you,
we'll find a style, OK?
A style that is...
exactly what you don't have.
-What is that?
-Who is this?
Is that thing the groom?
No, that's Jesús, my roomie.
You took a load off me.
For a sec, I thought, this
poor girl doesn't have style
or good taste
and she's pregnant.
Excuse me?
No, I mean, I'm perfect for
this desperate and sad cases.
-Like yours, so...
-[Jesús] Fucking crazy.
You must know what are these.
-They're catalogues.
-Carolina, right?
Yes.
What are you doing here?
OK.
I'm Carolina, right?
I'm a wedding planner.
That is, I plan weddings,
in case you didn't know.
I'm here to plan
your dream wedding.
-Would you like that?
-Yes, I get that.
Who hired you?
[Jesús laughs]
Your dad didn't tell you,
did he?
[Valeria] How dare you
hire her, Dad?
It's my wedding!
It's not the money,
don't you get it?
I won't have a church wedding!
And I won't go to hell,
because it doesn't exist!
Moreover, you hired
a bipolar Art Attack girl.
I don't care!
Stay out of my life!
-I was leaving, don't worry.
-I'm so sorry.
My dad drives me crazy.
It's OK.
I know very well
how it works. Don't worry.
I do.
It's just that...
since I broke up
with my boyfriend...
I try to move forward
one way or another...
and nothing works.
But it's OK.
Congratulations,
I hope your wedding is amazing.
Real pretty, real cute
and real nice...
and that your relationship
works better than mine.
Carolina, hold on.
[music]
I felt sorry for her.
She's really depressed,
she just broke up
with her boyfriend.
She's not bad, she's...
kind of bipolar.
Great, now we have
a depressive and psycho planner.
We wanted a small wedding,
didn't we?
You want a small wedding.
I always wanted
something bigger,
but I made up my mind for us.
Let it go.
Bigger.
The shrimp one is delicious.
Yes, shrimp is really good.
Full of cholesterol,
bad for babies...
OK, fine.
[moans of enjoyment]
This is my favorite.
-No, I don't think so.
-Why not?
I'm just saying,
it's full of salt
and it causes swelling.
You're very swollen,
maybe you want a blowfish look.
Enough.
Write this down.
And the Serrano ham one, too.
If I get swollen,
it's my problem.
And if you don't fit
in the dress, too.
I'll write that down.
What...
What I don't get is...
how can you submit a newborn
to that savageness.
That is called circumcision.
And what is cut is the prepuce.
Nobody likes a man
with the skin hanging...
-Who wants dessert?
-I'll go with you.
-Sir?
-No.
-Thank you.
-And you, Mom?
Yes.
[Sebastián]
A big success, right?
Their eyes will get
their eyes out.
[Valeria]
I don't know where to start.
All of them look delicious.
Let's see... chocolate.
It's Nutella's,
it's really good.
Don't you dare.
I swear I wasn't going
to say anything.
Hey, do you know
what we have skipped?
Your bachelorette party!
I need you to make a list
with all your guests,
but more importantly,
that you start
to choose the toys.
-No, Carolina.
-Why not?
Not here, there's people around.
Besides, I've never liked
those parties.
Honestly, I think I'll pass.
No, no, no.
What are you talking about?
Moreover, my friends are prudes.
I don't think...
Val, this is your last day
of fun.
It's madness,
it's the day you surrender,
let all your desires out
and give up to marriage.
Maybe.
Maybe they'll have a lot of fun.
Obviously!
Just leave it all to me.
I'll arrange it, and remember
one thing Valeria.
My wedding service is integral.
Hey.
Who is Pamela Asencio
and why does she like
all your posts?
She's Mike's daughter.
She's working at the office.
I see.
Do you like her?
No way!
No! Besides, she's almost
a minor. She's a little girl.
-Well, she likes you.
-I don't think so.
-It's your imagination.
-Sebastián.
Why would she like
everything you post, then?
I don't know, that's the way
kids connect nowadays.
What can I say? I don't get
it either. Things are like that.
By the way, Carolina is planning
a bachelorette party
with all my friends.
Have you thought about yours?
No, those are old-fashioned...
boring, unnecessary,
expensive...
Stop it. It's up to you.
Hey...
Mike's birthday is on Friday.
Shall we go?
-Sorry.
-Will I go alone again?
-Come on.
-No, I can't.
My bachelorette party is on
Friday and you can't be there.
There will be only girls
and Jesús.
Obviously.
You can't get...
-Mike!
-You made it, Sebas!
It's nice to see you!
-I wouldn't miss your birthday.
-Thanks, son.
Don't.
This is Sebastián, darling.
Hi, nice to meet you.
Hi.
Have a drink with me, would you?
Sure.
Cheers.
-Put that cigar down, darling.
-Oh, come on!
He will be OK.
-Who?
-The baby.
I'm two months.
-Pregnant?
-Yes.
Well, we have to greet
The Trujillos that just arrived.
-Go, go.
-Not The Trujillos.
-Enjoy the party.
-Congratulations.
-No, I don't want to.
-Yes, of course you do.
-Help me, Santiago, please!
-Come on.
Enjoy the party, Sebastián!
Santiago?
What's wrong? It's Sebastián.
Carolina, don't! It's ross!
Look how cute!
It has eyes!
Really? Nobody uses this.
This is just like Eric's, girl.
Hey, the toys are great and all,
but when is stripper time?
[music]
No, no.
Stay away, asshole.
-I said stay away!
-Look who's here.
I'm sorry, I thought...
-Hello.
-Hi.
How are you?
This is like a funeral.
It is.
Would you go with me to smoke?
This is a garden,
I think you can do it here.
I know, but my Dad doesn't like
that I smoke.
Come with me.
I think I'll wait here.
Dude!
You've got to see
my father's guitar collection.
Now?
Relax the sacrum.
I feel how my iliac crests
expand lightly.
I let it reach my anus.
-No, Pamela.
-Hey, hold on.
No way!
Wow!
I told you.
I see a spear through me
from the perineum
to the crown.
-And for a moment...
-Valeria, are you OK?
I forget about my history.
Yes, I feel a little low.
Why don't you go and grab
a bite, then you throw up.
-I always do it.
-Hey!
If she doesn't,
she won't fit in the dress.
I feel better now.
-Why are they on the floor?
-I don't know, he likes it.
-He's crazy.
-A little bit.
[music]
[Sebastián] No, no, no.
Don't.
-No.
-Where are you going?
-Somebody could come in.
-Nobody will.
-Your father will.
-It's locked, OK?
-Hey, relax.
-Don't.
No, I'm not relaxed at all.
I'm not, I mean...
-You don't like me?
-No, that's not it.
I'm getting married.
This could be
your bachelor party, then.
Yes, but it isn't.
Have you ever had it underwater?
What?
This isn't OK.
Your dad...
Valeria...
[Carolina] Val...
Val are you OK?
I feel terrible.
What do you mean?
Do you want to throw up?
[music]
-What's wrong?
-She's not well.
We'd better take her
to a hospital.
Sebas...
is everything OK?
Hi.
What's wrong?
I called you
a thousand times, Sebastián.
My battery died.
What happened, honey?
You should have been with me.
Please, tell me what happened.
[sad music starts]
[sad music continues]
[sad music ends]
PAMELA ASENCIO
POSTED ON YOUR WALL.
SEBAS, I HAD A BLAST ON FRIDAY.
THANKS, HANDSOME.
Fucking bitch.
Fucking mother fucker!
COMMENT, SHARE, DELETE POST
Delete, delete.
POST DELETED
Fucking bitch.
"A little girl,"
said that asshole.
No fucking way.
[Pamela]
Sebas!
Are you leaving?
[Sebastián]
Yes.
Pam.
Why did you post that
on my wall?
Oh...
Well, I...
I didn't know it was wrong.
You...
get that what happened
between us...
No, what happened between us?
I don't remember anything.
Exactly.
Thanks.
Bye, Pam.
Bye!
Shit!
Hey!
You're still up.
What is it?
You were with her, weren't you?
What?
With who?
Don't act stupid. With Pamela,
that night at the party.
Of course not!
Well, I mean,
she was there, but...
all the office was there.
Besides, she's Mike's daughter.
She had to be there.
Wasn't she a little girl?
She is.
Well, I saw her pictures
on Facebook
and she looks quite grown.
Well, yes, but...
She's a little girl to me.
Did you fuck her?
-Come on, Val.
-Sebastián!
I didn't.
I didn't have sex with her.
Of course not.
I didn't.
I'm sorry.
I don't know what's going on,
I feel I'm going crazy.
No.
You aren't going crazy.
It was a shitty week.
Just that.
Panda?
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday, dear Panda
My voice is awful.
-Hi.
-Congratulations.
Are you OK?
I had to get it off my chest.
I wasn't expecting this.
Hey, Carolina found a garden
for the wedding.
It's amazing and really cheap.
We can pay in installments,
but the first
must be done today.
I...
Well, I was thinking that
since there's no rush anymore...
I don't know, we could...
-Postpone it.
-Call it off.
What?
No, no.
I meant postpone it.
You don't want to marry me.
No, not at all.
I meant to postpone it.
Because now, we have more time.
Wow!
You would only marry me
because I was pregnant.
Honey, I'm just saying
that we could take things
more slowly.
It was the only thing
I asked you, Sebastián.
Panda, would you listen to me?
I do want to marry you,
now, we have time to plan
a better wedding.
-Go.
-That's all.
-Honey...
-Could you leave me alone?
-Are you serious, Panda?
-Get out, Sebastián!
Well...
Breathe.
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday
Dear Sebastián
Happy birthday to you
-Hurray!
-Bravo!
NEW MESSAGE
I'LL GIVE YOU YOUR GIFT LATER,
SEBI
Blow the candles!
Come on!
Come on, son!
CHAT-FRIENDS FOREVER
THE WEDDING AND THE BIRTHDAY
PARTY ARE CANCELED
IS EVERYTHING ALRIGHT?
NO, IT'S ALL WRONG.
SEBASTIAÁN'S AN ASSHOLE
I ASKED HIM TO DO IT FOR US,
NOT THE BABY, AND HE LIED TO ME
I DON'T WANT TO SEE HIM AGAIN
THAT'S TERRIBLE. YOU DESERVE
BETTER. IT'LL BE ALRIGHT
HE'S AN ASSHOLE, I TOLD YOU SO
I'LL CALL YOU LATER
VAL, TO HELL WITH HIM
COME TO PALAZUELA'S PARTY
AND HAVE SOME FUN
THANK YOU ALL, BUT I DON'T FEEL
LIKE DOING ANYTHING
[music]
Come on, stop it.
THIS USER HAS BLOCKED YOU
[music]
Sebastián.
I don't know if you've noticed,
but Valeria hasn't come
in two weeks.
So, no matter how much you wait,
she won't show up.
Where's everyone else?
We are short on staff.
And Jesús?
Don't even mention him.
We're not together anymore
and he doesn't work here.
What happened?
He's very gay and, honestly,
I'm more heterosexual,
more of an alpha male, dude.
Right.
What went wrong?
He made the biggest
mistake of his life.
Picture this, he told me...
that he accepted me
for who I was.
I mean, I could deal with...
Well, that he was a bum bandit,
a Peter Puffer,
-a pole smoker, a queer...
-I get it, man.
But that he wants
to convince me that I'm gay...
No fucking way!
Don't you care
what you feel for him?
Yes, that fucker is dead to me.
And you know what?
I can accept anything,
Sebastián, except liars.
They sing in your ear
in this beautiful place.
I'm not sure
this is a good idea.
No, no, no.
Don't give me that.
-When did you last go out?
-Let's come back another day.
No!
Please, don't do this to me.
Why are you doing
all this for me, Caro?
Didn't I tell you?
My integral service
also includes psychological
and moral assistance
to unfortunate friends like you.
As long as the unfortunate
soul is you and only you.
Well then.
-Shall we go?
-Yes.
OK, go.
Shot! Shot! Shot!
Come on.
One, two...
[music]
Cheers!
It's a kind of cute, admit it.
Isn't it?
Thanks for bringing me here.
Sorry? Did you say "thanks"?
Can you say it louder?
Say it loud...
What?
Why did you kick me?
Val?
Alonso, what's up?
What are you doing here?
I'm giving a gig in this hotel.
And you?
She's celebrating she's single.
-We both are.
-No, no.
-Really?
-We're just partying.
Well, if you're single,
come meet my band.
Are they single?
-Yes.
-Really?
Very single.
I think I'm going to say hi.
It's rude not to greet people.
-Bye.
-No.
-Martín.
-You go, girl.
I was just thinking
of you yesterday.
And what were you thinking of?
Of all the times
you cheated on me?
Hi.
Hey.
Why are you still here?
It's midnight.
Yes...
but we haven't talked
in about a month.
We talk every day, Pam.
Yes, but about boring stuff.
I don't know, about work.
Can't we talk about...
me, perhaps?
OK.
The same happened to me.
She stood me up two weeks
before the wedding.
All was set.
That's terrible.
But it worked for me.
Because I turned
all that pain...
and I turned it into
creative energy.
-God, Alonso!
-I turned into the alchemist.
-OK.
-It's my second album's name.
Wow!
How would you like to go
to talk to a more private place?
No.
I won't leave my friend
on her own.
Well... she isn't exactly
We have a problem, Sebastián.
No...
Which?
I think I'm...
You're what, Pam?
You're...?
I think I'm...
in love with you, OK?
-Is that all?
-What?
Isn't that enough?
-I need you...
-No! What are you doing?
No, no, stop it.
-Listen to me.
-Please, stop.
-I need you to make love to me.
-No.
-I can't!
-Sebas, just a little!
Don't tear off my shirt!
-Pam, please!
-Hush.
What?
What is it?
-What?
-Stop it, Pam.
-I love Valeria.
And I love you.
-I'm being serious.
-I'm, too, OK?
-Pam, get off me.
-What? Come on.
-Please, get off.
-What are you doing?
-Please, get off me.
-Come on.
-No, get off me.
-Come on!
Pam.
You're really a jerk!
I am, get dressed.
You know you want it.
-Please, get dressed.
-You don't like me? Is that it?
No, that...
That isn't...
I can't.
I don't want to.
They gave me a very cool suite
because of the gig.
Don't you want to see it?
No, Alonso.
We'd better go back.
No, stop.
I can't do this.
I swear I can't.
Are you rejecting me?
Yes.
I am rejecting you.
What do I do now?
That's big.
I'd never been rejected.
How awkward.
Pam...
I'm sorry.
But... there's always
a first time.
-No, I mean it.
-It's OK.
You don't know
who you're messing with.
Yes, I know.
No, you don't.
Alonso, stop.
Stop, I...
-I'm going to Hell.
-No...
NEW MESSAGE
I'M SORRY, SEBI.
LET'S BE FRIENDS
Fuck!
What the fuck!
What's wrong with you?
You're a murderer!
[Sebastián]
Fucking psycho!
Pamela!
NEW MESSAGE
I'D RATHER NOT
Fucking psycho bitch!
I'm going to tell your dad!
You're not going to tell
anything to anybody, fucker.
Otherwise, I'll say you raped me
at my dad's party.
Who would they believe?
What?
I told you not to mess with me.
Fucking psycho!
Valeria, Valeria.
Honey, pick up, pick up.
SEBASTIAÁN
INCOMING CALL
Help!
-Smile, dude!
-Wait, we're going to stumble.
Holy crap!
You do look handsome!
Don't worry, man,
with all that morphine,
you won't feel a thing.
You're a good friend,
Alberto.
-Thank you.
-You should thank the nurses.
You owe me a big one.
Yes, I owe you a big one.
But you're indeed
a very good friend, man.
We were best friends
in high school
until you tried to rape me.
Come on, don't be a pussy!
You can't cut it.
So?
Shall I take you home?
No, take me to Valeria's.
I don't think it's wise.
Take me to Valeria's,
goddamn it!
Fine.
Friend's number one rule.
You don't yell
at your best friend.
I'm sorry.
Write something cool.
Best friends, rescue, Alberto.
And tag yourself.
[Sebastián]
No, not the puppy face.
Bye, gorgeous.
I'll call you.
[Valeria]
Sebastián?
What are you doing here?
What happened?
I'm OK.
I wanted to talk with you.
-Look, I...
-Val.
Please, listen to me.
I screw up.
We're going through this
because of me.
But I need you to know
you're the love of my life.
It's not that I didn't want
to marry you...
I'm terrified...
I might not to be the man
you deserve.
I'll probably lose
you over this...
but I need
to tell you something.
I made many mistakes.
Many that I can't make right.
But lying to you was the worst.
What are you talking about?
[sad music]
At Mike's party...
I was with Pamela.
Did you...?
-You're an asshole.
-Yes.
I am.
You just got down
from Alonso's car.
Will you tell me
nothing happened?
It's not your fucking business.
We're not together anymore.
[music starts]
[music continues]
Fucking idiot!
[music ends]
I was thinking that
since we won't work together
and you're single now,
we could try to...
Pamela, I really hope
you've enjoyed it,
because I don't want to see you
again in my fucking life.
SEBASTIAÁN
INCOMING CALL
[sad music]
EMPTY TRASH?
NEW MESSAGE
MOMENTS
VALERIA, PLEASE FORGIVE ME
I CAN'T LIVE WITHOUT YOU
[sad music]
Really, Sebastián?
Will you go on?
What else can I do?
I lost the love of my life.
Yes, sure.
It's perfectly OK
not to have a job, right?
Man, listen.
Why don't you download
one of those Apps
to shake the sheets?
Did you say, "shake the sheets"?
It was too much, right?
I'm sorry, I visited
my mom yesterday.
I'm not interested.
Well, you should be,
because after
the stupid act you pulled,
I doubt you have another chance.
I know, trust me.
But I only love her.
I love Valeria, my Valeria.
-So, stop whining and find her!
-Where?
She won't answer my calls
or answer my messages.
I may know
where she'll be tomorrow.
What?
Jesús posted on Facebook
they'd go to a concert.
Didn't he block you on Facebook?
Yes, but I created
a fake profile
with one of his fairy
friends' picture.
What?
I miss him a lot, man.
-Damn, you're a genius!
-What?
Where are you going?
No way, miss.
We're going
to this concert together.
I'm not in the mood, Chucho.
There are two options, and we
didn't want to tell you, but...
Either you let him go or...
-You call him.
-What?
No way!
God, Valeria!
Why are you so hard on him?
He wasn't the only one who...
-Right?
-I'm sorry for that.
I hate you.
[music]
Well, before we go on,
I've a surprise for you.
A very dear friend
asked me a favor.
He has a very important message
for the girl he loves.
Thanks a lot, Rodrigo.
Valeria, I know you're here
and we can't undo our mistakes.
But I think we can...
begin again... always.
Hold me
I don't want to see you
Disappear
Forgive me
I didn't mean to hurt you
That time
We crashed
And burned unknowingly
Against the break of day
And in a thousand pieces
On your skin I stayed
We uncovered ourselves
Until we vanished
Lost in the moment
I gave in
And when we forgot it...
-Hold on, they'll see you.
-I don't care, faggot.
We were born again
Panda...
Would you marry me?
["Caderas blancas" playing]
["Caderas blancas" continues]
Yes, I do.
She said yes!
[Valeria]
So, what is love?
I don't know the precise words
to answer that.
[Sebastián] Love is incredible,
but it's not perfect, right?
It's wonderful,
but oftentimes it's not easy.
[Valeria]
Love is everything.
It's indeed sharing
and commitment.
[Sebastián] But it's also
to recognize we aren't perfect
and we make mistakes.
[Valeria] To give yourself
completely and unconditionally.
To take a leap of faith
despite the fear.
[Sebastián] Love is
to face the world, together.
To forgive and begin again.
[Valeria]
For better...
or for worse.
["Caderas blancas" continues]
["Caderas blancas" ends]
[music starts]
[music continues]
[music ends]