Hold it! Hold it!
Hey, hey, hey.
Easy, easy.
FBI, all right.
Stop!
FBI!
I'm sorry, sir,
the plane has
left already.
You can't
go through!
We have one
passenger that
just went through.
I'm sorry, sir!
You can't
go through.
go through!
FBI!
We need security!
Security right away!
We have 3 people
who just went
through.
Come on.
Eat and run.
Whoa!
Hold it!
FBI. We're taking
your truck.
Freeze!
Come out of the car!
Price?
Special agent turgenson.
Does this asshole look like
Vincent moretti to you idiots?
Were you with him
all the way?
Yeah...
Except for
the men's room.
Where is he?
I'm not fucking around!
He's a key witness against
the barinas drug cartel.
You got him to turn
and hung him out
to dry.
We're giving him
protection.
Ha. And a stand-up
job at that.
Too bad
the hit last week
almost got
him killed.
So the system ain't perfect.
Mine is.
Find yourself
another dude.
No fucking way!
We've spent 2 years
on this guy.
Unh!
No wonder we kicked
your ass out.
Arrest him.
Powell?
Release him. Now.
This is an
FBI operation,
not NSA
I'm changing that.
Let him go.
I'm gonna
catch up with you.
I swear.
You ok?
Yeah. Be a lot
better if I knew
why I'm hiding
a witness
that could put
the hurt on barinas.
You are not doing
anything, price,
we are.
It's a work-for-hire,
like always.
Need-to-know basis.
That's bullshit.
Moretti was
one of our plants.
We have larger fish to fry
with the cartel.
Only those idiots
at the bureau,
they always miss
the big picture.
From now on, price,
remember this:
We don't ask about
the private clients
you run through our system,
don't ask about ours.
Tastes great, guys.
Everything ok?
Yeah? Good.
Welcome to the breezes.
Thank you.
Um...
Take care of them.
This way, please.
Ladies, gents...
Have a pleasant evening.
Thank you.
I can't believe it.
We're broke, and he's
giving away $50 cigars.
$38,000 loss this month
for the breezes.
$176,000 for the year.
And now this:
It's an I.R.S. Garnishment
for back taxes.
It's been...
Difficult.
Difficult?
It's disastrous.
Every penny we're making
gets swallowed up
by this...Eatery.
Kev, you know we can't
promote the restaurant.
It could expose US.
I just want some relief
for Christ's sakes.
You know the deal
with the NSA...
They get 2 freebies
a year from US,
and we get
unlimited access
to the network.
Yeah, and that's great,
except all we've done
this year are the freebies.
Forget it.
I need a drink.
Sorry, we're closed.
Even for
your best friend.
Sonny!
Hey.
Look at you.
Undercover
suits you well, I see.
Where have you been?
Seattle.
Seattle's got rain
and the icarus group.
I know the bureau
doesn't give a damn
about rain.
I heard you got
Paul elkert
to turn state's evidence
against the syndicate.
Nice work.
Thank you very much.
So how's biz?
Not bad. We're
winning awards,
but I got a feeling
that's not why
you're here.
Turgenson.
He's pissed
about moretti.
I knew the judge.
I intercepted it for you.
I thought i'd
give you a heads-up.
Well...
Too bad he can't
take a joke.
Hey, look, man.
You pulled
his pants down
in front of a lot
of people.
He wants payback.
Be careful,
all right?
All right.
Thanks.
Hey, come on.
Let me fix you something.
No, I'd love to,
but I got
a grand jury
waiting for me.
Justice
never sleeps, man.
Hey.
Hey, Sonny.
Anything interesting?
Yeah, sure,
if you call looking
at window washers
all day interesting.
What about
the periphery?
We got 2 guys
out back.
It's all clear.
All right.
Here we go.
I'm going inside.
Yeah, sure.
Sonny here yet?
Yeah,
he's inside, sir.
Good.
How about getting US
inside, too?
Or haven't
you guys heard,
"the cleaner"
is on our case.
I've heard,
and I'm not worried.
Yeah, yeah.
- Of course not.
- A bullet to his head
couldn't do
too much damage.
Shut up.
Hi.
All here.
We've been detaining
them separately for
the last 5 days.
Good. We don't want them
comparing testimonies.
They friendly?
They gonna finger
yoesky?
They like the deals
and the protection
we're offering.
That's why there are
no lawyers here.
Good.
Let's do it.
We're gonna start
with paolo bucci,
then Renee Brooks,
end with elkert.
Got it?
You know anything
about a warrant
I'm supposed to get
on your buddy price?
I have no idea.
I'm going for a smoke.
Take bucci
and escort him to
the grand jury room.
I gotta go.
Look, genius,
unless you want me
to ruin your
snappy shoes,
I suggest
you let me out.
What? You wanna
hold the toilet
paper for me?
Uptight pricks.
Please place
your left hand on the Bible
and raise your right hand.
Do you solemnly swear
that the testimony
you shall give
this court and jury
today
in this matter on trial
will be the truth,
the whole truth,
and nothing but the truth,
so help you god?
I do.
Please be seated.
Mr. Bucci, let's begin
with the description
of your duties
with the icarus group.
Come on!
Don't just
stand there!
Do something!
Outside!
Get outside!
There's a sniper!
Who are you?
You can't just
kill me like this.
No, don't!
Don't!
Help! Help!
Here comes the cleaner!
Watch out! Watch out!
Shut up!
Shut the fuck up!
- What's going on?
Shut up!
Check in
the bathroom!
Check if
she's there!
Damn it!
God! Would somebody turn off
that fucking alarm?
Hey!
I got a court order
right here
authorizing his release.
We cannot guarantee
his safety if he's
not in our custody.
Are you kidding me?
He stays
in your custody,
he gets killed.
Let's go.
Son of a bitch.
Who the hell
did this?
It's got the cleaner
written all over it.
As in
the assassin?
No, as in Sara Lee,
you idiot.
So tell me, you saw nothing
but window washers all day,
jerkoff?
Yeah.
Well, I think
you missed something.
What are you
looking at?
Price, we need to talk.
Do you know who I am?
Yeah. Paul elkert.
Good.
Then you know
why I'm here.
Not really.
Did you read
the morning's paper?
Look...
I'm a restaurateur.
Come on, price.
You know the situation,
don't you?
It's all right there,
The gunman...
It's the cleaner.
Right.
I'm telling you.
I saw him.
You saw the cleaner?
Yeah.
It was dark.
He had a hood on.
But it was him
all right.
He walked right up to me,
put a gun to my head,
and then he frisked me.
What was he after?
I don't know.
You're right.
If he didn't
find it though,
you wouldn't
be alive now,
would you?
That's very perceptive
of you, price.
He probably missed it
because it was...
Taped under
that rug of yours.
Now I am impressed.
I'm not.
What is it?
The key to my
safety-deposit box.
The money you stole
from yoesky.
So, price, you gonna
help me or not?
Your case is too hot.
Icarus wants you bad,
the FBI even worse.
I'll pay you.
My understanding
is you're having
some financial
trouble.
I.r.s. Liens,
fed pressure.
I can make it
all go away.
$1 million.
$5 million.
5.
Plus, half the money
you stole
to a charity
of my choice.
You're out
of your mind.
Then you're out of luck.
Good-bye.
Shit.
Wait!
Price!
Ok.
It's gonna take me
some time.
48 hours.
I could be dead by then.
No, you'll be safe.
Unh!
Mr. Price...
Will you behave
if Ivan and nicholai
let you up?
Well, I'm not the one
breakin' arms here.
Do you know who I am?
Ed McMahon
and the prize patrol?
I got an idea.
Where's my money?
Behind door
number one, asshole.
Unh!
That's enough.
Can we talk?
I don't know where
elkert put the money.
I can't tell you
where he is.
We are going
to find him...
Then we'll be back.
Have a good evening,
Mr. Price.
This will
piss off the feebs
to no end.
I'll understand
if you don't want in.
Aw, screw 'em.
We need the moola
anyway,
but can I ask you
something first...
The D.C. home
for boys?
It's an orphanage.
Yeah, I know that.
It's a lot of money.
Hey, we get 5.
Ok, we're goin' deep
on this one.
Deep? Shit.
We're not even
supposed to know
where they
end up, anyway.
That's NSA
policy, right?
But we do.
They don't know that.
True, but this time,
we won't,
and neither will they.
I don't get it.
It's icarus
and the cleaner
we're dealing with,
so I'm making sure
elkert goes beyond
the vanishing point.
How?
We'll get to that.
Connie...
Get your
com lines open
to these providers.
Secure lines only.
On it.
Kevin, transportation.Yeah.
Minimum 5,000 access points
and reservations.
All modes. Everything
cancelable in 30 days.
Shit. Tall order.
Yep.
That's
why Charlie's
crunching
route permutations
on daedalus.
Patch me through.
Can we get started,
please?
All right. We'll be using
a mersenne prime algorithm.
That makes shadow tracking
that much more difficult.
Elkert will get
a handheld unit
with an encrypted
flash-memory card.
He'll have more than
150 links along the way.
We'll need
all our resources.
Call on the least-used providers
in the NSA system...
Providers who won't even know
what it's all about
but are looking
for a trigger code,
a break in the chain,
an infiltrator that needs
to be disposed of.
If there is a match,
he gives up a new envelope.
He'll get
birth certificates,
passports, subscriptions,
then on to the next link.
I've run
the provider list,
but there are 2
noted as "unknown."
That's our ace
in the hole...
Something I've been saving
for a rainy day.
Static drops...
Providers who
can't give up information
even if they wanted to.
If you remove
the human element,
there can be no betrayal.
He must enter
the correct code here...
Or he dies.
If he gets through
without mistakes,
his trail will forever
be erased.
He'll be a ghost.
I ought to install
a revolving door.
You boys
got reservations?
Shut up.
I told you I'd be back
to see you real soon.
Now we can do this
the easy way...
Or we can do this
the hard way.
This pillow talk, Sam?
If you think
you're gonna try...
Relax.
I'm not gonna interfere,
but I got an interest.
Really? What's that?
Let's just say price
tricked US, too.
Elkert's so deep,
we can't even
track him.
Now I wanna
talk to him.
Yeah? Well,
I want the skinny
on price and his people.
Hey, buddy.
Sonny.
I tried to warn you,
man.
Yeah, and now
you're here to offer
me a friendly deal.
Nah, nothin' like that.
Though, you did
put a whole new twist
on this icarus affair.
Elkert's still alive.
I might not be,
though.
Jason price.
FBI academy '81.
Top of his class.
Youngest special
protection agent
in division history.
8 commendations
including
a presidential citation,
but was suspended twice
for insubordination.
What do I look like,
an idiot?
I know all this shit.
Gimme the post-bureau stuff.
Icarus knows
I was a plant.
The cleaner's been
contracted to whack me.
Jesus, Sonny.
Do I have "stupid"
written on my forehead?
Look. Wiretap
on yoesky's phone.
Conversation took
place this morning
with the cleaner.
Find him, and while
you're at it,
there's another haircut
I want you to schedule.
The cleaner, filtered:
We already discussed
that.
His type is usually
not a Mark.
I'll double
the fee. Just do it.
We picked him up right after
the second suspension...
Put his skills to use
in east Germany.
With NSA funding,
he devised
the most sophisticated
protection system
in the world,
called "daedalus."
It was used for
hiding western agents
who had been exposed.
Never lost a runner...
But when the wall
came down,
the usefulness
of the program
came into question,
so price made a deal with
the NSA and went private.
Son of a bitch.
What about
his people?
That information
is beyond even
my clearance.
I don't know what the hell
you want me to do.
Yes, you do.
You're FBI, Sonny.
I'm not touching this.
You would give
a scumbag like elkert
a fighting chance.
You won't even help
your best friend?
How could you put me
in this position?
Because I don't have
a fucking choice!
You know how screwed up
the FBI is.
I mean, hell.
Your own kid Charlie
just hacked the system
last month,
and he e-mailed
the director a list
of protected witnesses
just to piss him off.
The fucking system
is a joke.
Please. I got
nowhere else to turn.
So you know where all
the guys are he stashed?
You wanna find elkert
or don't you?
Rival agencies
sharing
a private moment.
How touching.
What happened
to elkert, price?
to "I don't ask,
you don't ask?," frank?
That only
works one way.
Well, then, it's my way.
You have a good thing
going here, price.
I wouldn't spoil it.
You have
a lot more to lose.
Fuck you.
I designed daedalus,
so if you wanna
play hardball,
remember this...
The only losers
will be the marks
I ran under for you.
Is that a threat?
No.
I just think that...
On a need-to-know
basis,
there's some pretty
important people
who'd rather
not be known.
He's free to go.
What?
We had a deal.
We had an understanding.
I changed my mind.
Agency prerogative.
This is fuckin'
blackmail!
I'm goin'
to the director.
All right.
You do that.
I'd watch my next few steps
very carefully.
We will be.
Do what I told you?
Yeah.
Utilities on,
bank accounts open,
mail's running,
gym membership,
I even went
to the dentist.
Yeah, like
you're staying put.
Except I'm somewhere
else, right?
That's right.
But where
am I gonna be?
Here...
Rub off the gold seal.
Use your thumb so you
don't damage the chip,
then pop the card in.
Connecticut?
Just the first leg
of many.
How are you gonna
know if I make it?
I will. I will.
You see the car
in the parking lot?
Key's in the visor.
Will I ever
see you again?
No.
Remember sister Sarah
from the boys' home?
She gave me this thing
when I was 8 years old.
She said as long
as I wore it,
I'd always
be taken care of.
I want you to have it.
Thanks.
Good luck, Sonny.
Yeah. See ya.
Burned-out car
was found in
a ravine yesterday
by a couple
of hikers.
The coroner puts
the time of death
at 52 hours.
Jesus.
Are you sure?
Yeah. It threw US
at first
because there were
2 sets of I.D.S...
One for Carl sands
from Connecticut...
Then we found
Sonny's FBI badge
halfway up the hill.
It can't be.
We ran a dental check
on some teeth we found.
Care to comment
on these, golden boy?
Fuck you.
He was a friend.
He's a dead friend now.
You've got a lot
of explaining to do,
and this time, you won't
have the NSA around
to cover your ass.
Ok, ok. Come on, Jason.
Come on.
Have a nice day.
But we double-checked
everything.
What happened?
What went wrong?
Well, that's just it.
Nothing could have.
I've done this
too many times.
The only way the cleaner
could have gotten to Sonny
is if he was
already inside.
But how is that
possible?
I don't know...
But I'm gonna find out.
Yeah.
Kev,
we're reconstructing
Sonny's route.
I need
all transpo details
uploaded to Charlie
for processing.
I'm on it. I should
have the first leg
within the hour.
What a dump.
Let's go.
You sure this is it?
Kevin confirmed
the point with Charlie.
It's a provider.
Step back.
Wait here.
Ok, Jason.
I got it.
The next provider
is in Pittsburgh.
163 red maple street.
Good afternoon.
What'll it be?
Daedalus.
Well, I'll be.
I never thought
I'd hear that word.
So, um, what do I do?
Show me
your provider kit.
Yeah.
That's right.
Check him.
He's dead, Jason.
Let's go.
I know.
Let's get outta here.
Jason, there's a break
at the 5th point,
but you gotta hurry.
Thanks, Charlie.
What is it?
We've reconstructed
the 3rd and 4th link
of Sonny's path.
Those providers
are dead, too.
We gotta get
to the next one fast.
If you don't
get the rustproofing,
you're gonna be unhappy
about the whole thing.
Now, you trust me
on this. You get
the rustproofing,
it's all gonna
work out for you,
see it? All right.
Well, personally,
I think you're gonna
be very happy.
I'm lookin' for Jerry.
That'd be me.
Can I help y'all?
Yeah, let's chat
about daedalus.
I'm sorry.
I...I don't understand.
The hell you don't.
Unh!
Raaaaugh!
So, you're a big
talker, Jerry?
No, no.
Well, are ya?
Who'd you
talk to, Jerry?
No one!
Who?
It was a voice...
Fake voice...Fake voice.
What did they want?
I don't know.
You don't know? I don't know.
They want me
to use the flash card.
You know the rules.
Why'd you do it?
What did you
give him, Jerry?
Nothin'. I give him
nothin'. Nothin'.
I gave him the address
that came up.
I thought it was for TV.
Sorry.
Anyone else show up?
Later. This guy...
I...i gave him the stuff.
That's it. I swear.
I swear.
Unh!
Give me
your provider kit.
If I find out you lied,
I'll be back...
And it ain't
gonna be for TV.
Unh!
Yeah, Jason, it's me.
Go ahead, Charlie.
There's some
good news, and
there's some bad news.
First, the good.
Daedalus'
extrapolation couldn't
pinpoint a hole.
The codes received
were all in order.
No penetration.
Charlie, he knew
Sonny was going there,
but don't tell me
he couldn't have
cracked the system.
Anything is possible.
Sonny wasn't supposed
to be in Virginia.
The code should
have directed him
to south Dakota
where he'd link and...
Wait, wait.
South Dakota?
Yeah, Kevin's checking
all the transpo routes,
but so far,
there's no redirect
in the database
for Arlington.
That doesn't make sense.
Unless...
Unless what?
Sonny...
He figured it out.
I'll check
the back door.
Be careful.
Let go of me!
Who the hell are you?
If you'd get off of me,
I'd tell you, you jerk.
I thought you were
with the FBI or icarus.
Don't sweet-talk me.
What's your name?
Renee Brooks.
I was one
of Paul elkert's
associates at icarus.
The cleaner
tried to kill me
at the courthouse,
but I got the hell out.
How'd you manage that?
I was in the bathroom.
I heard gunshots,
so I climbed
through the window
as fast as I could.
Still doesn't explain
what you're doin' here.
Are you always
this sympathetic?
No wonder
you and elkert
got along so well.
How'd you know
about me and elkert?
He told me he was
coming to see you
and that
I should, too,
because I got this.
What is it?
It's a key to
a safety-deposit box
in the Caribbean
worth $100 million.
Do you expect
me to believe
that elkert would
hand you a key
to money he stole?
He trusted me.
I took care of his
finances at icarus.
Besides, the bank
requires 2 keys.
Why would
he hand one to you?
He didn't have a choice.
He keeps one with him.
The other one was
in his safe at icarus.
When the FBI raid
went down,
I grabbed
what was inside.
And now you're
gonna get it to him?
No doubt for a price.
10% is my standard
safekeeping fee.
When did you
last talk to him?
The day of the hit.
I was supposed
to come to you
after he was
safely hidden,
but you
weren't around.
And why should
I lead you to elkert?
For the money
he owes you.
What if I don't?
He'll contact
me anyway.
I'll just
have to wait.
You don't really buy
that phony story.
Of course not...
But there's a link
to elkert there.
We need to keep
her close
in case he does
contact her.
I don't see why.
The cleaner
is inside, going after
our biggest fish,
and that means the FBI
has a shot at him.
It also means all
our people are exposed.
I need to put
a stop to this
before someone else
gets hurt.
So?
I haven't decided yet.
Where's your car?
Got a rental.
She your girlfriend?
What's it to you?
Just wondering why
she doesn't like me.
Like's got nothin'
to do with it.
It's trust she's thin on.
I think it's you
who's lacking.
Maybe, but I want
the truth...
And I don't think
I'm getting it.
You ok?
That truthful enough
for you?
Tell me more about elkert...
What you did for him.
I set up shell companies
that billed icarus
for services in
out-of-the-way places,
like Africa
and the middle east.
Trouble spots.
Places no one would
go check.
It worked
for a long time,
then he got reckless.
Kept wanting more,
taking bigger risks.
Greed?
Control.
He was consolidating
power and assets
to challenge yoesky.
What happened?
Sonny.
He was playing
both sides
against each other,
setting icarus up
for the FBI.
When did elkert find out?
Not until it was
too late.
Sonny lured elkert
with a billion-dollar
weapons buy
involving 4 countries.
The feds were waiting.
Elkert was floored.
He trusted Sonny
like his own.
He made everyone
look bad.
So that's why yoesky
put the hit out.
And the cleaner?
What do you mean?
You were on the inside.
You must have heard stories.
Just a killer.
Expensive. Never misses.
No one knows who it is.
That's a stock answer.
I was hoping for an idea
of who I'm dealing with.
I couldn't tell you
who it is,
but I'll tell you this.
I think the cleaner's
looking for a way out.
What makes you say that?
Because it's
what happens
when you work
for the mob.
You do things you
don't really want to do
just so you can believe
you're actually getting
somewhere,
when in fact
you're only biding time
until you can no longer
do what they ask.
And then
you're eliminated.
Kind of sounds
like an excuse.
Maybe, but it happens
to everyone.
Elkert, Sonny, me.
It'll happen
to the cleaner.
Do you, um,
have a rest room?
Through there.
Thank you.
Hello?
Kev, listen.
I need you to call Charlie
on the secure line.
I want the two of you
to gather all statistical data
on Sonny's run.
Specifically?
Route corridors, phone calls,
bank charges,
credit card bills,
whatever.
I'm looking
for anything abnormal
that'll confirm my suspicion.
Which is?
If the cleaner
was on the inside,
how come he was
a step behind Sonny?
He isn't. He got him.
Not where he was
supposed to be.
That's what's not right
about this.
Something's fishy.
Ok, I'm on it.
Shh.
What is it?
There's someone outside.
Go up...Go upstairs. Go.
FBI. Everybody freeze.
Price, we know
you're in there!
We know she's with you.
Price, we got a warrant!
Exit plan.
Somebody break a window!
They're gone.
I think we're safe.
You don't really
need protection, do you?
That was some job
you did on that agent.
Where'd you learn
to fight like that?
When you work for icarus,
you'd better be ready.
Come in.
They're gonna start
coming down hard now.
Did Kevin talk
to Charlie?
They ran the matrix.
There's something.
What?
He said you should
see it for yourself.
Do you mind if
I leave her with you?
No way.
No way!
Now listen, both of you,
in case you
haven't noticed,
we got a big problem
here.
I need to go
and see Charlie,
and I can't take
either of you.
So, can we be adults
for 2 seconds here?
Thank you.
Just take her
to the safe house
and wait for me there.
So, what'd you
want me to see?
While cross-checking
through some
975 million calls
made during Sonny's run,
we came up
with a remarkable
coincidence.
The provider at every
one of Sonny's stops
received a call within
an hour of his arrival.
Well, how could that be?
It can't. I mean,
one of the providers
is fisherman
in bar harbor,
who hadn't had a call
on the secure line
for the last 2 years.
And that was
a wrong number.
All right.
Guess we gotta
bring elkert in.
I thought there was
no way to trace him.
Think I tell you everything?
Well, this is,
um, interesting.
It's safe.
That's all that matters.
So, how long
you and price
known each other?
Long enough.
For what?
To know when he's not
thinking clearly.
You always
warm up to everyone
this quickly, Connie?
It takes a lot more than
the damsel-in-distress routine
to sell me.
Well, lucky for me
it's him who's buying.
I'll take
the bedroom.
Thank you.
Good night.
Reverse the factor
by the 29th marsenne prime.
Match your beta code.
Sending these codes
could expose
the providers
and their locations.
You sure you want
to do this?
We got no choice.
Continue.
Well?
I wonder if
the runners ever knew
they were leaving
a DNA trail behind
by rubbing off
those gold patches.
Doesn't matter now.
Yeah.
So, you found the remote
that bombed her car
in her purse?
Man, that is fucked up.
Hey.
Sorry.
Well, it sounds to me
she's after all the money.
Yeah.
Well, then why
keep her around?
Well, I need her
at arm's length...
And, there's
another possibility.
What's that?
She's not who
she says she is.
Think we hit a static drop.
Let me do it.
The static drop coordinates?
A back door.
Next card's
not coming up.
He didn't use it.
He jumped track on his own.
That's what he planned
all along.
Yeah, well, then
he could be anywhere.
Back up
to the previous provider.
What did he give elkert?
Plane tickets.
Ok, match that provider
with all tickets
ever issued to him.
2 hits.
Phoenix and Boston.
I.d.s?
No.
But there are 2 high
probability addresses
for those areas.
But I can't tell
if they're providers
or final covers.
Ok, call Kevin. Tell him
I'll pick him up in an hour.
Ok.
Well, at least you two
didn't strangle each other.
Spare the chitchat.
Did you find him?
No, but there're
2 possibilities.
In other words,
he's lost.
He broke protocol,
jumped track.
But there's
still a chance
if we move.
What do we do?
We split up.
Kevin's already
arranged flights.
You and him
hit Phoenix...
We'll go to Boston.
We?
Come on, let's go.
How well did you
know Sonny?
Not real well.
And only for about 2 months.
I was the last one
brought into the circle
by elkert.
And he trusted you?
It's why he trusted me.
I had no allegiance
to anyone else.
How'd Sonny manage
to fit in?
It wasn't so hard.
He had more mob in him
than a lot of made men.
Sonny? No way.
He may have been FBI,
but he loved
the high-flying lifestyle
the syndicate afforded him.
Houses, boats...
Personal well-hidden assets
in countries the government
can't touch.
Nonsense.
I set it up for him.
Ok, I don't want
to hear anymore.
How long did you know Sonny?
Since we were kids.
We were orphans
in social services
together.
Grew up
in the same streets,
same foster homes.
Eventually joined
the FBI together.
So, if you happen
to run into the cleaner
during all this,
what will you do?
I'll ask him
to walk away,
leave my runners
alone.
And if he doesn't?
I'll kill him.
Or her.
Come on.
What?
Why?
We're being followed.By who?
Someone who
doesn't really know
what a bottle of ripple
can do to you.
Are you ok?
Yeah. Fine.
Price!
Gimme your hand.
Come on.
Come on!
Big baby.
Thanks.
Well, you know,
one back scrubs the other.
Speaking of which, I...
I think I'm gonna
take a shower.
Everything ok?
Yeah. Why?
Well, you're looking at me
like I have nothing on.
This is nice.
Who's this from?
Used to belong
to Sonny.
What is it?
I need you to wait here.
Why? Where are you going?
If I'm right,
to meet Sonny's killer.
Hello?
Charlie, it's me.
The Boston address
is a static drop.
Anything from Connie?
She's still in the air.
Ok, call me when she lands.
But I think hers
is a dead end.
What makes you say that?
Faith.
Aah! Unh...
Jason, it's me.
Sonny?
What the hell?!
Get up!
Let me explain.
Shut up, man.
Shut up!
I knew I was being tracked.
Just couldn't figure out how.
What the hell's going on?
I faked my own death.
With the dental work.
I scattered some teeth
behind.
What the hell
is wrong with you?!
I helped you.
I know, man.
I fucked up.
No shit.
Why'd you do it?
It's fuckin' turgenson.
He's after the money.
He knew about some perks
I took from icarus.
He told me he'd nail me
if I didn't do it.
Do what?
Penetrate your system.
Why?
If you were convinced
that the cleaner
whacked me,
you'd think the cleaner
was inside
and getting close.
You'd have no choice
but to go back
to elkert. Save him.
And then I would
fuckin' follow you,
and I would deliver him
to turgenson.
You killed those providers?
No, I didn't do that!
That was turgenson.
He killed 'em
after each pickup.
I had no idea, I swear.
I knew something stank
about your death.
Fuck, man,
the pressure is huge.
My sources
are telling me
that the cleaner's
close.
Your sources?
Who are they?
I mean,
who are you, really?
It's me, man.
Who's the cleaner?I don't know.
Yes, you do!
Fuck,
it's the cleaner.
He doesn't give
a rat's ass about you.
Those are yoesky's thugs.
Come on.
Get your gun!
Make sure you leave
no trace of him.
Get down. Move!
Let's go.
Jesus. Ok, what now?
Jump.
Jump?!
You bastard!Jump.
Room 56.
When'd she leave?
About an hour ago.
She make any calls?
Seattle.
You have reached the mailbox
of Renee Brooks.
Please leave a message
after the tone.
So, what was it?
It's how elkert
or somebody contacted her.
Who?
All right, where do we
go from here?
You go with me.
I'm gonna have
a little talk with elkert.
After all
that's gone down,
Why are you dragging
Sonny along?
He's my prime suspect.
The way to find
elkert is through
a safety-deposit box.
It has to be registered
in his name at a bank.
Jeez, we don't
even know which one.
I'm not exactly
a specialist
in bank systems.
Well,
I know someone who is.
Time to recall
another runner, kid.
And that's
where we are.
I need to put
your knowledge of
bank systems to use.
What are we looking for?
A
safe-deposit box...
And its owner,
Paul elkert.
What bank?
That we don't know.
Caribbean somewhere.
Shit.
That many?
Cayman Islands alone
have 1,034.
10,000 banks.
That's 10 million accounts.
All with passwords.
Renee
hid assets with you
in the Caribbean.
So?
I'll bet she used
the same bank
for elkert.
For control.
What was it?
Aruba.
Banco financiero di Aruba.
It's a hit...
But no personal info.
Just an e-mail.
Can we use it?
Isp's out of Canada.
Could use the a.C. Program
I once wrote.
E-mail the account
and attach trojan virus,
hack their billing database,
but it might
easily get traced.
You might
not be the only one.
NSA, FBI, you name it.
Anyone might
get this info.
Don't worry.
Anything happens,
I'll take care
of you.
Something
on your mind?
Just wondering
what's gonna happen.
My guess would be
someone's gonna die.
All right,
what do we do?
We go in.
What kind of fuckin'
plan is that?
It's the only one
I got.
Let's go.
Fuck!
Get down!
Ok, I'll take
the back.
Look
for a way in.
Don't betray me
again, Sonny.
Elkert, it's price!
What do you want?
I'm here to help you.
Your life's in danger.
You never should
have come here!
Stop shooting!
It's me, Renee!
Renee! What are
you doing here?!
She's gonna
kill you, elkert!
Shut up, Sonny.
God damn it,
who else you got here?!
How about the cleaner,
elkert?
The cleaner?!
What the fuck
you talkin' about?!
Take your pick,
either one.
Fuck you!
Elkert!
Kill 'em.
Kill 'em all!
Sonny?
I'm so sorry.
Unh.
Elkert?
Stay away from me,
price.
Take it easy.
I'm here to help you.
Bullshit.
You led them all
straight to me.
You called Renee.
Why the fuck
would I call that bitch?
She had
your second key.
I don't need a second key.
That safety-deposit box
is in my name.
You only need a second key
if you're not me.
Hold on.
The cleaner's been
after this key for...
Cleaner doesn't exist,
price.
You said...
I just mentioned him
so you'd help me.
Yoesky invented the cleaner
to scare people
shitless. That's all.
Well, how about
the courthouse hit?
Sonny set that up
for me.
I made Sonny
a rich man.
He owed me big-time.
Yeah, Sonny.
Think about it, price.
Who else
but a government agency
would know the exact time,
location, and the layout
of a secret grand jury hearing?
Stop shooting.
I can get you out.
I'm the last chance
you got.
I don't need
your help, price.
Fuck you
if you're gonna
get any of my money.
You?
But I trusted you.
You expect me
to believe
she shot elkert
to save you?
That's right.
Horseshit!
I'm gonna tear
your story apart.
Like you did
to my providers?
You murderer.
I don't know
what the hell
you're talking about.
They were innocent.
Nobody's innocent,
price.
Drop it,
turgenson, drop it!
Place him under arrest.
Can't arrest me,
I'm FBI!
You're wanted
on 5 counts of murder
in the first degree.
Get him outta here.
I warned you
this case could go bad.
Why did the NSA
want elkert dead?
You picked up on that.
Not so hard, considering
your panicked reaction
when I ran him under.
Elkert was too hot.
We have certain
jurisdictional rights,
but we couldn't
seize him from the FBI
without raising
a red flag.
So you had him come to me.
We thought
we'd track him...
Quietly, but
we weren't expecting
your static drops.
Very clever.
So, you were working
with icarus all along.
The mega arms deal
Sonny got involved with,
only the NSA
had the interest
and resources
to set that up.
So you were
using the syndicate
to illegally divert weapons
to some dirty little war
somewhere, right?
That's what
elkert had on you.
you didn't want
the FBI to know.
You don't
have to worry
about that now.
Icarus
has pulled out.
Your actions
have torpedoed
important
national operations
and objectives.
Bullshit.
Was she your cleaner?
Does it matter?
No.
I guess this is one time
when there's no
need-to-know on my part.
Well, you...
Take care of yourself,
price.
Thank you.
And I've arranged
with the NSA
for a 5-million wire transfer
to each of your accounts.
Whoa.
Powell agreed to that?
If I shut daedalus down
forever.
I did explain
the potential downside
of having
a motley crew like
you guys running it.
Thanks.
Look after yourself,
will ya?
Hey.
Who's gonna
mother me now?
I'll send you
monthly e-mails.
Yeah, yeah.
So, what do we do
to get you under?
Nothing.
This one's
my own doing.
The ultimate
vanishing act?
Yeah.
I'll miss you guys.
How can you just
disappear on US
like this?
It's the only way
I can leave it
all behind, Connie.
I guess things never did
settle right for US?
Everything ok?
You?
Fine.
Free as a bird.
So where are we
going?
If I told you...
We wouldn't be safe.