Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Good morning.
It was.
How people can take that corner
that fast is beyond me.
It's maddening
What you've done with your
grandmother's flowers...
She'd be so pleased.
Actually, these are for you.
Well, now that I'm here...
How was your date last night?
It was good. I guess.
When you meet the one, there'll
be no 'I guess' about it.
Did you hear about the Meyers?
No. What happened?
They're moving to a senior
residence.
Oh, I don't know. Maybe it's for
the best.
I mean, that house is really big
for the two of them.
I'm helping her back this
afternoon.
Well...
I'd better be on my way, let you
get back to your gardening.
Almost done. Then off to work.
Oh. Are we still on for our
power walk this afternoon?
Wouldn't miss our time together.
Here you go. Extra hot and extra
sweet.
So finish telling me about your
date with Ken.
Ron. Kenny was last week.
Where'd you guys go?
The Waterfront Supper Club.
Fancy.
It was.
I don't know. I feel like I'm
sort of stuck or something.
Last night,
Chris and I ate leftover mac and
cheese in front of the TV.
I'd love to be your kind of
stuck.
I mean it's not like I don't
appreciate it. But...
nice dinners aren't really
cutting it anymore.
Or maybe it's the company. I
don't know.
Do you think I should be more
social?
You go out every night. How much
more social can you get?
I don't know how to explain it
when I don't even get it myself.
Well, our church is having a
concert in a few weeks.
You could come with. Meet some
new people.
Yeah, I'm not really a church
person.
Think about it.
It's just a concert,
not a lifelong commitment.
Let me guess.
Ron?
Hey.
They're beautiful.
Can you get away for a sec?
Yeah, sure.
Grab us a table?
All right.
Jason, I presume?!
You must be the pastor. Nice to
meet you in person.
Saw you coming in, so I made you
a little welcome gift.
This is my signature latte.
I appreciate Sun City Church
taking Home Base Ministries
under their wing.
We're very happy to have you
here.
I see you've met Pastor Matthew.
Thank you so much for helping us
with the build.
Lord knows the need is great.
You want to join me on a coffee
run?
Coffee? I just gave him coffee.
No. You gave him bargain brand
mud.
Whatever. For the record...
The reason Chris wants to get
coffee
is cuz he has a thing for
one of the baristas.
We call that thing a marriage
license.
I wouldn't drink that.
So, what's going on with you and
Rachel?
She's a major reason for my
moving up here.
I figured as much.
I don't have a lot of time,
so...
Well, hey, my CEO is hosting
this fundraiser.
Would you please be my plus one?
Definitely.
Wait. When is it? Cuz I'll need
to get my hair done.
Three weeks from Saturday at the
Freemont Hotel.
Yes. I've actually always wanted
to...
I got to get going.
I'll call you.
Okay. Bye.
Bye.
Excuse me.
Who's that guy with your man?
His old college buddy, and the
new director at Home Base.
How you doing?
Good.
Here she is. My beautiful wife.
Shelby. Nice to meet you.
You too.
Look, sorry I missed your
wedding.
Hi! I'm Victoria, her favorite
co-worker.
Hey.
How are you enjoying your first
day so far?
So far, so good.
So, you see anything you like?
Hmm.
Oh, peanut butter mocha looks
great.
Ready for your first project?
Babe. Let Jason get settled in
first.
I'm just asking.
It's fine.
Yeah, Chris has done a great
job at getting the word out.
So we'll see how many show up
for the volunteer orientation.
People have been picking up the
info cards.
Oh yeah?
Even though social media
would've been the way to go.
Everything helps.
Hot and sweet.
We should go.
Bye.
Glad to finally meet you.
Nice meeting you.
Remember Ron? He literally just
brought you flowers.
What's up with this Jason guy?
I'm guessing you're not his
type.
Is he alive? Single? Then I can
be his type.
Hey. Can you watch the kids?
3:30 on Monday.
Oh, sorry. I'm getting my hair
done.
You can do that anytime.
Well if I wait too long, people
will know it's fake.
Oh, people know.
Okay, you're not helping your
case.
Come on, sis. Please?
I guess my hair can wait.
You can't be late.
Fine. I won't be late.
So where are you going anyway?
Oh, just an appointment.
Are we keeping you from
something?
Kind of.
Another date to get ready for?
Actually, it's a volunteer
thing.
Volunteer? You?
I can be a... volunteer person.
Oh, I get it. There's a guy. Is
your target a volunteer too?
You make me sound like I'm a
sniper.
No, Jason, he organizes
the volunteers.
Oh, a guy with a purpose. I'm
impressed.
So what's the name of this
volunteer thing?
Do you even own any tools?
Why would I need tools?
Jason's organization builds
houses.
That's what you're volunteering
to do.
What? No, no, I can't build a
house.
You do this, and you're gonna
have to swing a hammer.
And you might chip a nail.
I think this is a Christian
organization.
Most likely he's a Christian if
he works for them,
which means he's probably not
gonna date someone who isn't.
No. It won't be a problem.
I'll just pretend. Fake it till
you make it.
Vic, you can't fake faith.
Sure I can.
I mean, do you remember when I
cheered for Seattle
at Nate's football party?
I didn't know a thing about
football, but no one knew that.
You brag about the weirdest
things.
He's gonna figure it out
eventually.
Yeah, but by then he'll be
totally into me.
Hey, Wyatt.
Hey.
Everything's ready to go.
Thanks, man.
You wanna wait a few?
This is probably about all we
can expect. Let's get started.
If I could have everyone have a
seat please.
Hey, everyone. Thanks for coming
out.
I appreciate your interest
in volunteering.
My name is Jason Holman, and I'm
a... Uh...
The director of the new branch.
Uh, how many of you are familiar
with what Home Blonde does...
Base? Home Base.
Uh, we're a nonprofit
organization
dedicated to helping families in
our local community.
None of what we do is possible
without legs. Haha, and arms.
Gotta swing those hammers.
Anyway, what I meant was...
We can't do it without you all.
Our volunteers.
Thanks.
Your talk was great.
Uh, okay. Thanks.
Glad you were able to join us.
So, how do you like your new
job?
Yeah, so far, so good.
I've lived here my whole life.
So if you ever need anyone to
show you around,
I'd be more than happy to. I'll
make myself available anytime.
Are you free this Saturday?
I am.
If you want to write down your
number...
Yeah.
You know, I...
Are we about done here?
We all good?
Oh, umm yeah. All, all good.
See you Saturday.
Right.
I thought I'd come to the
rescue.
She might be a handful.
You think?
Decent turnout.
Half the people who sign up
actually show.
Well, we know at least one
person who'll be there.
Yeah. We'll see.
Hey, morning.
Hey. Megan, right?
Yeah. Hey, I'm impressed with
the turnout.
We ought to have the frame up in
no time.
I like your optimism.
I've done a lot of volunteer
building projects.
Hey, if you need any help with
the newbies, just let me know.
Thanks.
Hey, I know you left Cali to
start over,
but don't be so focused on the
work.
Be more open from moving on from
Rachel.
I don't get involved with people
who volunteer for me.
You know this.
Unless there's a wow factor.
A what? No, that's...
Like when you see someone from
across the room and
suddenly nothing else even
matters.
That's ridicul...
You were saying?
Come on. We need to get started.
You know, I don't know her that
well.
But by the way Shelby talks,
I'd say she's more into hunting
guys than building homes.
Doesn't mean she can't
volunteer.
Dude, I'm just saying be
careful.
Because she's clearly
into you.
Look, there's nothing I'd like
more than to meet someone.
But volunteer or not, this girl
is way out of my league.
If what you say is true,
I don't need that kind of
complication in my life.
Complication, nine o'clock.
Peanut butter mocha.
Thanks. Were you planning on
working today
or just bringing the coffee?
Oh, yes. Working, absolutely.
I brought my own tools and
everything.
Yeah, no. Umm, hang on, please.
Use this one.
You sure you're gonna be up for
this?
Of course.
Okay, great. Well, grab a hat.
Get your boots on.
We're about to get started.
Hey, Megan! Can you please help
out our new volunteer?
Hey, you need some help?
Uh, hi. I'm Megan.
Victoria. And yes, I would love
some help.
Where did you get yours? These
are so... so dirty.
Exactly why I bought my own.
Umm, here. This one's not too
bad.
Hey, did you bring your vest?
No. I've never built a house
before.
Oh, first time for everything.
Do you want some grapes?
Yeah, maybe later. After I wash
my hands.
By the way, where does
one do that?
Bathroom's over there.
Okay. I'll be right back.
I'm just gonna throw some things
in my car.
Oh, no, no, no. Toss it in here.
Especially the jacket. You don't
want to get it dirty.
It's too cute.
Is this yours?
It is.
Hey, Wyatt.
Hi.
Hey.
Right. Do you think you could
find an extra vest for Victoria?
Yeah, sure.
Thank you for not making me look
like a complete idiot.
No worries. I totally get it.
So, if Jason doesn't have you
stationed anywhere,
you can just stick with me.
Trust me. I think he'd like
that.
So, where do you go to church?
Umm...
Thank you.
Thanks, Wyatt.
So, how do you know Wyatt?
Oh, I've known him for like
forever.
We go to the same church.
He's cute.
Oh my gosh, your earrings are
adorable.
Uh, but they might get caught on
something,
so they'll have to go.
Umm, please tell me you brought
boots.
No.
Lucky for you, my brother left
those in the car.
Hey, everybody. Gather around.
I always like to start a build
with a quick prayer.
Father, we are grateful for
everyone here today.
We ask your blessing upon this
build
and upon this home and
Yelena's family. Amen.
Amen.
So, have you swung a hammer
before?
Nope.
Hung a picture?
No.
Took wood shop class?
Well, let's start with something
a little more simple
like a window frame.
So we're just gonna take one of
these.
Take this. Line it up.
Okay. So now you're gonna take a
nail and hammer it right here.
Yeah, that's good.
Okay.
You're gonna hammer it down.
Oh. My hammer. Okay.
Oops. Sorry.
I see why there's a need for a
hard hat and boots now.
Here. Maybe try holder the
hammer a little tighter.
Okay.
We're not trying to send anyone
to the ER on the first day.
All it takes is a little
practice.
Okay.
You gonna take that?
No. Just a guy. He can wait.
So, do you have a boyfriend?
Nope.
Is there anyone you have your
eye on?
How'd you know?
Girl, it's so obvious.
It doesn't even matter. We're
just friends.
There's one thing I do know.
It's that guys are not that
complicated.
He's had his eye on you all
morning.
If you teach me how to build a
house,
I'll teach you how to win
the guy.
Okay, look.
Start with this.
What are you...
Go ahead.
Me?
Yes. Go ahead. Go.
Go on.
Okay.
Try it like a little bit more
side to side.
Get the wind blowing in there.
You know what I mean?
Okay. Then, you look at him like
you're hanging onto every last
word.
Then, you finish with the
fluttering of the lashes.
I'm serious.
Oh, also. This will grab his
attention.
You carry this around with you
everywhere?
Always got to be prepared. Here.
Arms.
Rub them together. Good.
Oh. It's actually nice.
Mm-hmm. Okay, so go on. Chat him
up.
About what?
I dunno. Ask him for a nail or
something.
All it takes is a little
practice. Go.
Hey.
Hey, Megan.
Uh, hey, I was wondering... Are
you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Perfume... Perfume.
What happened?
Apparently, he's allergic to the
perfume.
Oops.
I'm gonna check if he's okay.
That was totally my fault. Sorry
about that.
You doing okay?
Yeah. I'm pretty much one of
your top builders.
Well, great job over there.
That would be Megan's work.
Actually, I could use a little
assistance.
Maybe don't choke up on the
handle.
Give it a try.
Ah.
Uh, your hair... it's a hazard.
You should put it up.
Three, two, one.
Mom!
Hey! Hey.
Look what we made for you.
Oh, honey. I love it.
I smell dinner. Thanks for
getting it in the oven.
Of course.
Are you staying?
Unless of course you have a date
with the volunteer hottie.
No. No date yet.
Building a house is hard.
Ya think? Have you met the
family yet?
What family?
Who you're building the house
for.
Oh. No, they weren't there.
Weird, right? I mean you'd think
they'd be helping?
Careful not to judge, sis. Oh,
we're only four tonight.
Oh, Mike's not gonna be home for
dinner?
No.
So, did he buy your whole faith
act?
I haven't even gotten that far
yet.
It's like this guy's immune
or something.
I love you. But you can be so
vain.
Whatever.
I mean it's not my fault this
guy's not like the others.
That's what I've been trying to
tell you.
Well, your'e right.
I mean I don't even understand
what these Christian
people are saying half the time.
It's like they speak a
different....
Wait.
What?
Duh. If I want to play on his
field,
I have to play by his rules.
You've completely lost me.
I've gotta go. Bye. Love you.
Hey, Wyatt.
Umm, I was just wondering. I was
just wondering... Umm.
Can I help you with something?
No. Yes. Yeah. Umm.
Do you have a nail gun and some
nails?
Umm, I mean, well I just, umm.
Do you have something in your
eye?
What was that about?
Yeah, don't ask me.
Hi, I'm John Marcus. And welcome
back to our show.
Framing your house is an
ambitious yet exciting project.
And since the frame is the
skeleton
or the backbone of your
house,
supporting the entire
structure, you will need to use
the proper tools and materials.
The tools you will have to have
on hand are saw horses,
hand saws, power saws, chalk
lines, hammers, and nail guns.
Hey, ladies. Natty here, from
Fantastic Wear.
Tired of those frumpy drab work
clothes,
tired of looking like just
another...
I went shopping.
I can see that.
We got a lot done this morning.
Come on. I'll show you.
Praise God!
So, how's it going with you know
who?
Total fail.
I'm sorry, Megan. Jesus loves
you.
Well, yeah.
Wyatt will have more for you
shortly.
I'll go get it.
Okay.
So, I see you got the roof
sheeted.
Uh-huh. I feel like we should
knock on wood or something.
Oh. Be my guest.
So, are we almost ready for
insulation and drywall then?
Almost.
Well, what can I do while I wait
for Megan?
Uh, you could flatten those
boxes if you want.
I like to keep the work site
tidy.
Amen to that.
I was wondering, do you guys do
your own heating, plumbing,
and electrical yourselves? Or do
you hire an outside contractor?
We'll bring in professionals for
that.
A lot of them donate their time.
It's amazing that you guys can
actually build a house
in such a short amount of time.
I don't know how you guys do it.
My go to scripture is Matthew
nineteen twenty-six.
Especially during a build.
Mine too. My fave.
Are you hurt?
I'm okay.
Oh, I can get those.
They're
coming.
You sure you're okay?
Mm-hmm.
Okay. I'm gonna go greet them.
Victoria, what happened?
Sheesh. I left you for one
minute.
I know.
Hey, guys. Come on. Do you want
to check out your new home?
Hi.
Everybody! Can I get your
attention for a minute?
Check it out.
So they're gonna be here now?
I heard she's required
two hundred and fifty hours of
sweat equity.
Umm, well, Elena's going to be
doing office work
instead of building. She can't
exactly afford childcare.
Everyone, I'd like you to meet
the homeowners.
This is Elena, Jordan, and
Kelsey.
I am so grateful. As a single
mom working two jobs, it's...
It's been a rough couple of
years.
All of this... You wonderful
people building our home...
There are no words to express
our thanks.
It's been a process. But I have
learned to give everything,
all of my circumstances, over to
God.
So thank you all for being here
on our behalf.
Thank you. Thanks.
Hey.
I'm Victoria.
Elena.
I'm just imagining what it's
going to look like
when it's all done.
Your girls are adorable.
They're my everything.
I'm just happy
I'm going to be able to give
them a home after...
Their father... He... He left.
Been there. My parents divorced
when I was five.
My mom raised me and my sister.
You know, I always remind
myself...
That God, he will never give me
more than I can handle.
I mean, He provided you. Right?
What do you mean?
I asked God to provide a home
for us.
And here you are. A total
stranger.
Sacrificing your time to help
someone you don't even know.
I met the family today. Elena.
She has two little girls.
Reminds me so much of us.
Yeah, mom being alone? Taking
two jobs?
Totally. And like Elena, I mean
mom did her best.
And I loved being with Grandma.
Yeah, we had each other.
Always.
Hey, so there's something that
I...
I can't believe I didn't see
this till now.
See what?
That's what Home Base Ministries
is about. People like Elena.
I've just been getting in the
way.
Vic...
I've been awful.
Don't be so hard on yourself.
So you don't think I've been
awful?
Oh, no. You've been fairly
awful.
But you realize it now.
That's the important thing.
Now, use this new perspective
and go build a house.
I will.
I hear those kids who should be
sleeping.
I gotta run, okay? Love you.
Love you, too.
Matthew something.
Hey, Zingle.
What can I help you with?
Matthew nineteen twenty-six.
Jesus looked at them, and said,
"with man, this is impossible.
But with God, all things are
possible."
Oh, man.
I was literally in the room like
five seconds before.
All that matters is you're okay.
I could've died.
Well, you didn't.
Yeah.
Well, thank you for letting me
stay here.
Sorry to move in on you and
Mike.
That's what family is for.
I'm gonna go brush my teeth.
It's okay. Daddy's gonna come
home again.
He met someone.
Why didn't you tell me?
I feel ashamed,
like I didn't fight hard enough
for my marriage.
It is not your fault.
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
I have to find a way to support
us.
You know,
God is never gonna give you more
than you can handle.
Okay?
Who are you?
Look, I'm gonna be here for you.
Just like you've always been
here for me.
Your adornment must not be
merely external
braiding the hair, and wearing
gold jewelry,
or putting on dresses.
But let it be the hidden person
of the heart,
with the imperishable quality of
a gentle and quiet spirit,
which is precious in the sight
of God.
Hey.
Haven't seen you in about a
week.
You sure you're all right
from that fall?
I mean, if you're injured...
I'm okay. Promise. Not even
sore.
Was it because of the flying
nails?
Actually, my sister is going
through a rough time.
And some crazy driver hit my
house instead of his breaks.
So kind of a mess.
Oh. I'm so sorry.
How's Elena's house coming
along?
Yeah, it was going great, you
know
until we got news that they're
getting kicked out
of the place they're staying at
like a week early, so...
Oh wow. Are you guys gonna
finish the house or...
Not with our current number of
volunteers, no.
Hey, I didn't mean to make you
feel bad.
I knew what you meant.
Yeah.
It's a good time for Matthew
nineteen twenty-six.
For sure. Well, yeah I really
just wanted to come by and make
sure you're okay.
Thanks.
Thank you.
I don't think we're gonna
finish.
I'll go check, see how they're
doing at the back of the house.
Well this is a surprise.
A nice one, I hope.
Of course. I just thought you
weren't coming back.
You need to finish this house.
And you're here to help with
that?
Hey. If you're not nice, I'll
send your new crew home.
New crew?
Wait. What's happening?
You needed more volunteers.
He is cute. Brownie?
No, thanks.
It's looking pretty good.
One more thing. We're gonna need
a truck.
You were amazing today.
Elena gets her house now because
of you.
Hardly.
I get that people are generous.
But you made it happen.
The Meyers needed to downsize,
and Elena needed new furniture.
It felt good, though, to help
today.
So, you want to see my totaled
house?
Yeah.
Here we are. Home sweet home.
Nice, huh?
Wow.
Yeah.
I was actually on the couch
behind the wall,
and I got up to get my notebook
in the other room.
You were protected.
What do you mean?
God knew that guy was going to
drive into your house.
Okay, could have been a
coincidence.
I don't believe in coincidence.
What I do believe is that he was
watching over you.
I have ingredients for a mocha.
Do you want to come inside or a
coffee?
Yeah.
Okay.
I like old houses.
Good opportunity to make
improvements.
Have you always lived here?
No. It belonged to my grandma.
She kind-of raised us.
My mom was single, worked a lot,
so...
What's your family situation
like?
Parents are still married. I
have a brother.
They all live in California.
Oh, so why'd you move here?
Mostly this job. They needed a
director. I was available.
Mostly? Hmm.
Why were you available?
Come on.
Really?
Okay. I was in a relationship.
The plot thickens.
But my leaving was a good thing.
For both of us.
Oh, so that's all you're gonna
tell me?
Yep.
You're kind of mysterious
sometimes.
You're kind of a flirt
Moi?
Yeah.
Her name's Rachel.
We were engaged.
It wasn't long before we
realized
we wanted different things.
Like what?
I found faith. And she found a
reason to dump me.
So that was a deal breaker?
I probably should get going.
Oh. Okay.
You know, I'm sort of new to
this whole faith thing.
Yeah, I know.
Oh.
When I was offered the job,
I'd only been going to church
for a couple of months.
Oh, wow.
What's that for?
I don't know. I'm just trying to
figure you out.
Yeah, I'm still trying to figure
me out.
Believe me, I was trying to
belong,
act like everyone around me.
Total fake. I mean, who does
that?
Yeah. Who does that?
I finally settled into my own
relationship with God.
And it turns out I don't have to
pretend with Him.
Well, I gotta go watch Joy's
kids. So I'll see you around.
Hey.
Shelby keeps talking about some
concert. It's on Saturday.
Would you possibly want to go
with me?
Are you possibly asking me out
on a date?
Depends on your answer.
Yeah. I'd love to.
So I'm cute, huh?
Okay.
I can't believe I forgot about
my thing with him on Saturday.
Just go to the concert with
Jason.
No, I can't blow off my date
with Ron.
It's never bothered you before
to cancel for a better offer.
What's going on?
I don't know.
I feel like I don't even know
who I am anymore.
Or maybe you're finally starting
to find out.
If there's a chance with Jason,
don't mess it up.
Don't be afraid of a real
relationship.
You're not yourself today. Is
everything okay?
Hi, Shelby.
Hi. Your usual?
Nah, just coffee today.
Hey. Victoria?
Hey.
Umm, do you want to grab a
table?
Actually, I can't stay. I just
came to say hi.
Hey, Victoria.
Hi, Ron. You can grab coffee at
the other end with Shelby.
I'm not here for coffee.
Is he the reason you're avoiding
my phone calls?
Look, I'm just hear to touch
base about...
Saturday's very important
to me.
I know.
I assume you'll be ready?
These are for you. Replace the
others.
Thank you.
I'll see you Saturday?
Jason! Hey!
I forgot, okay? It was an honest
mistake.
I was just so excited that you
asked me...
I should've listed to Chris.
Chris? What did Chris say?
You really want to know? He
warned me off of you.
That's not fair. Look, I wanted
to go out with you.
I've been trying to get you to
ask me out.
Oh, so that's it? You got what
you wanted.
I guess you won, huh?
It's not like that.
I double booked myself, and I
never do that.
Do you hear yourself right now?
I'm not into being strung along.
Can you just wait a second?
Fine. Tell me why you
volunteered.
I volunteered because I wanted
to get to know you.
And I wanted you to like me.
So... I pretended to be a
Christian.
Were you pretending to care when
I opened up about Rachel?
Of course not.
Do me a favor. Just stay away.
What's up, bro?
You were right about Victoria.
Oh, man. I'm sorry.
Hey. You gonna tell me what's
going on?
About what?
You've been avoiding Jason like
he's the plague.
Look, we need to talk.
Obviously.
I haven't been completely honest
with you about who I am.
I'm not really a Christian.
Wait, then why would you tell me
you were?
I dunno. It's complicated. But
mostly,
when I got to know you guys, I
wanted you to like me.
Victoria, if you want people to
like you,
you let them get to know the
real you.
I'm not trying to start
anything. I just...
I can't believe I listened to
you.
You had me trick Wyatt into
liking me,
but that's not who I am.
And now he thinks I'm just some
kind of weirdo.
And you know what, Christian or
not,
I still would have been your
friend.
Hey, there.
Rachel.
How did you know where...
I called your mom.
And I texted Chris a few times,
but he's, well, Chris.
I don't think he likes me very
much.
So this is what you've been
working on, huh?
The whole flight up, I was
rehearsing what I was gonna say.
Now that I look at you, I
just...
I've missed you.
Look, Rach...
Jason, tell me you don't miss me
too.
Of course I do.
But we've been down this road.
We're different people.
So we don't believe exactly the
same things. So what?
My faith is the most important
part of who I am.
It is who I am.
I can go along with it.
I don't want you to just go
along.
I'm willing to do whatever it
takes. I just want you back.
That's not how faith works.
You're not being fair.
Sorry, Rach.
Look. This is my room number.
I'll be there until tomorrow.
Please come.
Jason. What are you still doing
here?
You and Shelby...
How do you guys make it work?
It's just like you said. Work.
We're both a couple of screw
ups.
But each morning, we wake up and
we make a choice.
To love each other. Prefer one
another.
It's not always easy. But it's
real.
Rachel came back.
She's waiting for me to make a
choice.
She's ready to make it work.
What do you think?
I dunno what to think. Not
anymore.
I'll see ya.
You look so pretty.
Thank you.
You sure about this?
It's just easier to stick with
what I know.
Then try to have fun. You
deserve it.
Yeah. I don't.
And tomorrow you have the house
reveal,
so that should cheer you up.
You've worked hard. I'm proud of
you.
I can't show my face there. I...
I'll see you later tonight.
Bye.
I thought you were getting your
hair done for tonight.
Oh, umm, well I've just been
kind of busy with the whole...
Whatever. Let's just go.
Hey, Jonah! Don't forget golf
this time. It's next Thursday.
I didn't know you liked golf.
I hate it. But I need to stay on
his radar.
You shouldn't have to pretend to
like golf.
That's my boss. I can't wait for
him to meet you.
Ron, my man.
I hear you landed the Ginsburg
account for us.
That is nice work.
Well Ginsburg is a Harvard man.
Just like me.
That is well played.
This is my girlfriend, Victoria.
Hello,
Hi.
You two enjoy yourselves.
There is great shrimp at the
buffet. Save me two.
Girlfriend?
Just roll with it for tonight,
okay? Please?
Fine.
Harvard? I didn't know you went
there.
I didn't.
Hmm.
It's business. You tell people
what they want to hear.
There you are. Come on. I want
to show you off to David...
Ron... This is not what I want
anymore.
Excuse me?
I'm not your arm candy.
Why are you being so difficult?
I need to people in my life who
are honest
and expect the same from me.
I don't understand.
I'm just realizing this all now.
Come on!
Continue on for five miles.
I know we're just getting to
know each other,
but please let this be the right
thing to do.
You guys are awesome!
Your destination is on the left.
Oh, thank you.
No umbrella. Just great.
If only I had those ugly boots
now.
Ugh, you're not gonna make this
easy, are you?
Thank you! Good night!
Hey, hey, everybody! Weren't
they amazing?
We come to my favorite time of
this evening,
especially after that
performance.
And I don't want to miss an
opportunity
to celebrate with anyone who's
accepted Jesus tonight.
So, who's brave enough to come
on up here
and share about it? Share their
testimony.
Yeah, come on up, young lady.
What are you doing?
What's a testimony?
Your story. But...
Yeah, I see you. Come on up.
Come on.
No.
You've made it this far. We'd
love to hear your testimony.
Come on. Don't be shy now.
Umm, hi, everyone.
Oh, whoa.
Sorry. Umm, I'm a bit of a mess.
I was not planning on coming
here tonight,
hence the awkward gown.
But I want to be here with my
friends.
The ones who think I'm shallow.
And I agree with them.
I've only known superficial
relationships.
I mean they're safer. They don't
cost me anything.
And I can protect myself from
being hurt.
A few weeks ago, I met a guy. A
really great guy.
And, me being me,
I went after him pretending to
be someone I'm not.
In order to get him to notice
me, I volunteered
with this Christian organization
that he works with.
And it was wrong. I mean this is
his ministry, his passion.
And I treated it like it was a
game.
Nothing is worth hurting the
ones that you love...
that you care about.
But while I was pretending to
know what I was doing,
I actually started serving.
Putting other people ahead of
myself.
And that was a first. Trust me.
But it felt good.
And, I don't know, the best part
about all of this is that...
While I was pretending to be
like him, a Christian...
I was actually learning how to
be one.
When I took the focus off myself
and I stopped being so
selfish...
I opened up to wanting to know
God and who He thinks I am.
And then suddenly this whole
Christian thing,
it just it made sense. And it
got real.
So, I'm here tonight to share my
story.
I don't want to be the old me.
I want to be someone that
pleases God
and considers others, while
finding out who I truly am.
So to all my friends...
I'm so sorry. And I hope you'll
forgive me.
Wow. What a great start.
Wow. This is, this is amazing.
Let's, let's form a line.
Who would like to go next?
All right, come on up.
Well hello, everyone. I was
really moved...
I forgive you!
Hey, Jason's here. He must've
heard you.
He's not interested. Trust me.
He'll come around. I mean look
at you.
You're... You're stunning.
But seriously, I need to thank
you.
For what?
You gave me confidence.
Earlier, when I was upset, Wyatt
was really concerned.
And he and I talked a long time.
And I told him how I felt.
And?
And he said he felt the same.
I knew it!
Hey, I totally owe you one.
Oh yeah? Well you can
start by teaching me the Bible.
That book is ginormous.
You can join my Bible study.
That's a thing? I'd love to.
Hey, you gonna come back in? You
can sit with us.
Oh, umm, I don't think I can
face anyone else today.
That's okay. Call me.
Okay. Bye.
Hey. Have you seen Victoria?
Yeah, she literally left a
second ago.
Okay.
Jason!
Are you okay?
I'm sorry.
I should've listened to you the
other day.
No, trust me. I would't have
wanted to date me either.
I heard what you said in there.
So...
Oh, thank you. Oh that's
beautiful.
So, do you guys like it?
I love it.
Did you really build this house?
I wouldn't exactly say I built
it.
But there's definitely a
crooked nail
or two I can take credit for.
But your aunt did do all the
decorating. I'm so proud of you.
They're coming!
Let's go.
This way.
Hey, everyone! Gather around.
Come on.
Jason is great in so many ways.
I know. But we're taking it
slow.
Oh, guess what? I joined a Bible
study.
What have you done with my
sister?
I'm happy things are working out
for you.
They will for you too.
Actually, I got the job.
What? That's amazing!
Yeah.
Hey, everybody!
I'd like to say a blessing over
the new house.
God, thank You for everyone
here.
We give this home to You
and pray blessing over it and
Elena's family.
In your name, amen.
Amen.
Welcome to your new home.
Now let's go eat some cake!
Nice work.
I couldn't have done it without
you.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org