It's not you chose Ibiza.
What, it's not.
You chose to Ibiza.
Ms. ahead.
- Doctor, but she squeaks.
- But you Pariente, barely heard.
A creaking will disappear with time,
only you need to walk a lot.
Come on, let your moves ...
And please, creaking weakening.
- When do I get a new prosthesis?
- for 6 to 8 months. A maximum of 12.
This product manual from Karlsruhe.
The prosthesis for a lifetime, German quality!
- Goodbye, Doctor.
- Goodbye, Mrs. Pariente, good luck.
And please be careful on the steps!
Eight weeks waiting for a prosthesis?
It's a scandal!
I do not agree with you.
As this goes on, I order a prosthesis
from Germany, I have contacts in Karlsruhe ...
It certainly lasted much longer,
Mr. Damien.
Maybe so, but the quality
would be better.
Such a prosthesis would be much more expensive.
It zszedłbym the margin, Ms. Tang.
Carole, are you here?
I wanted to surprise you.
I have a meeting in the area,
drop you?
With pleasure!
I hear nothing, Ms. Tang.
It's raining cats and dogs!
But here's the trash, darling!
I know, honey. I do not have the time
or inclination to clean.
Well, let them lies.
- Kiss?
- Sure, but look at the way!
It's from high school.
Or maybe better call me back for a moment?
Phone stares you three points.
It's probably the director, this bastard ...
Excuse me?
Good day. Your son just
kicked a younger colleague.
What?
- How he is kicked?
- He kicked him with full force!
- He does not behave like this!
- Oh, that is my fault too?
I'm not talking,
it's the school's fault ...
Be careful, you will enter into it!
Okay, I'm going after him.
It was close...
This Menace?
It is aggressive?
No, not at all.
But since divorce is uneasy.
Well ... View the father of 24-year-old bartender ...
- has the right to shake a baby.
- Of course, otherwise it will pass!
Your children will see us together,
happy,
you will see that you will feel better.
As further will be so bimbać,
it does not pass the exam.
Well, they are amendments.
I need to stop worrying.
Do not give up!
And do not let him continue in defeat.
It's bad for him, for you ...
And even bad for ...
Be careful, right!
- You were almost dostawczaka!
- Excuse me! Yes I know...
Dostawczak, a little hair!
About almost dostawczaka.
I know, I'm sorry. Listened with attention ...
- Blow me here ...
- Here?
- Yes Yes. A short walk will not hurt me.
- OKAY. Wait, now I turn ... I've been.
Yet I do not feel confident
in the car.
I realized.
Thank you sweetie.
Or maybe we will go together on the weekend
for my parents to Crotoy?
Finally, we would all know.
Where?
Do Crotoy.
- Crotoy? Where it is?
- Bay Sommijska, sound familiar?
They like, it will be great.
But once your parents?
Philip, teenagers ...
Do not worry, parents
love young people.
And they are very receptive.
- I'll talk to them.
- Bye Baby,
- Get out.
- Have a good day!
Oh, and almost threw up.
How to turn it off?
Mom!
Mom, chill,
You could cause an accident.
Julien, do not say today that tone,
with his grace.
Be nice to Philip and his parents
are good people.
And you know the kind of old?
I do not know yet, but I know
that they like each other.
You have to know that I care,
that everything went well.
- Can I turn the muse?
- No.
For the moment we arrive.
But wiocha ...
I forgot to warn you,
father Philip is deaf.
It is better to speak to him loudly.
- Good morning everyone!
- Good morning sir!
Why are you tearing up?
You do not have to scream so. Meet
Philip, he is not deaf!
- There is a lot older than my dad!
- No. Massacre.
Pleased to meet you, kids!
Come,
Come inside ...
Drizzling a little bit, but then go!
I would not call this drizzle.
The weather at the dog ... We have bad luck!
But the nonsense, I wanted to finally
dust off the board!
NESKA? As he wants, then he zaparzymy!
Board, not instant, Dad!
I did chamomile!
Mom, help.
Some weed ...
Just a joke.
Once we get out
of this shithole?
9 and a double score for the word,
together 18. Bravo.
Carole, and where you work?
I ran a restaurant with her ex-husband.
Ah, the cook!
You are right, they say,
that through the stomach to the heart!
I think by the liver.
He left me for a chick from the bar.
- I'm sorry ...
- But that's old news!
Let's focus on the game, OK?
Your turn, dear.
- Mom, when are we going?
- Julien, hang up the phone
Come and help me, because I totally
have no idea!
Julien is good at Scrabble?
Such letters have.
- and not super.
- Serious?
Maybe I'll win this round!
We here, please: FELATIO.
Felatio?
So.
- But it is in the dictionary, right?
- Maybe vulgar words in the dictionary.
But like anything, with two "l".
- You want to check?
- There's no need to! It is true,
There should be two "l" ...
not clearing up.
Threads of the weather today.
And we have emergency options
in case of rain?
Of course,
we have everything in place!
Oh, great ...
Firing in the fireplace,
the kids will enjoy.
- They come home!
- Why to Lyon?
Lyon are the same!
Forgive me for this disaster.
The holiday will be better!
It's not your fault! And Julien fail his
high school diploma and go nowhere.
And I believe that it passes.
We spend a beautiful vacation together!
Honey, I've tried everything.
OK, I am going.
This arrangement Empire with him!
How to pass the final exams, will be able to choose
where we're going.
We have done so once,
the young got a red bar ...
and we drove to Bulgaria!
Trust him! Maybe it will be the
best vacation?
- Mom!
- He is going!
Philip, quick!
Father rug burns!
Pled?
After all, I forbid you to give
him this rug!
Blank cottage with smoke!
Quick, water!
- And?
- I passed, Mom.
Well done, darling! I told you.
I'm so proud.
Me too! But the jaram!
You want to know what the left?
- I passed!
- Ingeniously.
- Ibiza, dude! But the tarry!
- Ibiza? You have chosen Ibiza?
- So nice?
- Ideal! Cool!
- I am very pleased Julus!
- Me too.
Come on, have a drink champagne!
- Have fun on vacation, Sophie.
- I wish you the same, Doctor.
Already going?
There will drink after rozchodniaczku?
I have no time! At 5 we are
flying out to Thailand.
And yet I'm not even packed.
And as Ibiza,
you have not changed your mind?
There's no way I'm going there!
Carole will understand ...
I am on the island of junkies and eternal events?
I jump into techno and take ecstasy?
Thank you!
Listen, 3 or 4 years ago
we were there with Pauline.
We were delighted.
Something łyknęliśmy, it's true ...
but then we popped up in the morning the night.
Nothing else did!
After returning I slept for a week!
Holidays by osteopath, huh?
Envy!
You're right, this is not for you.
You're too ...
- Too what?
- too so ...
Well, no crazy ...
- It's where you go?
- To Crotoy.
Holidays by podologa,
envy!
Bye, see you.
Dupe.
Hat?
Piżamka?
And sometimes even hail in northern France
and in the Bay of Somme,
temperatures there will be
definitely the lowest.
19 degrees in the shade
Come with us, it will be great!
I'll miss you!
Such temperature
is not recorded since 1952.
Sit back, uparciuszek because you
do not want to change places!
I beg your pardon, I bought a ticket
at the last minute ...
government have a place for you.
As you can see, this family trip.
- Would you like to, you're not my father!
- Julien, shut up!
I paid 12 euros for this place
and I'll sit here, okay ?!
I understand,
- 12 euros is not przelewki.
- You're kidding me?
You want to get out?
- Can I help you gentlemen?
Relax, it's finally a breeze.
And I do not like aggression.
I'll sit in the back, it's only
two hours flight.
In any case, I thank you sincerely.
Good day.
- Good morning.
- Romeo, nice.
Dear passengers,
find your pilot, Enrique Jimenez.
Zone of turbulence ahead
- Bebidas?
- Nada, only fly in one piece.
Honey, are you afraid?
Relanium want?
- Do not comforted me!
- Excuse me.
- We perish!
- Mom, calm down! You're scaring people!
Honey, it's only air hole!
Spectacular, but nothing to worry about,
It is a matter of difference in temperature,
pure physics.
Go play Scrabble with my parents
and do not talk to me anymore!
He says that because recently
we played with my parents.
I do not care, shut up!
Ladies and gentlemen,
the zone of turbulence is behind us.
Sweetheart?
However, I want to Relanium.
Welcome to Ibiza
welcome to the party!
It is said here that it is not you
going to Ibiza,
This Ibiza chooses you.
I could warn you,
on the plane I am not myself.
I'm so glad, however, that
you are here with us ...
I love you.
I love you too.
You and your phobias.
You know, that such problems can be
worked in the simulator ...
You no more have to
shake with fear.
- This ship will sail.
- Yes, and seasickness?
You do not have seasickness?
- I have.
- Exactly...
How well do you get out of the sun!
Watch out, it sub-Saharan climate.
The sun is dangerous here.
Dangerous, kids!
Honey what are you doing?
I'm looking for sunglasses,
as soon as you catch up.
Or better police?
I do not believe, Carole!
This is madness.
A type of just
offering me coke!
- Not bad for a start!
- But did you all?
Do not forget that Edith fled
Goa with yoga instructor
smoke turns from morning to night.
It is for me a little touchy subject.
No ... They are not interested!
It even children!
- Irritable about, darling.
- Charles? Fiat 500?
Thus, the Fiat 500's us!
Seriously, wynajęłaś Fiat 500?
But down! There will put up!
Julien will be well,
we can do it!
Honey, I have a card
American Express ...
we can raise the standard.
- I speak French.
- It's praises!
Council could raise the standard car?
- I picked up a Hummer.
- What?
Hummer, yes, but grazing!
- Julien! This is not a car for us!
- Why?
What's so special?
It's some bigger combo?
Ah. Indeed, such
a little bigger combo.
What we have here ...
This is probably the reversing camera.
- Do you want to enter the address in the GPS?
- Sure thing.
I'm not bother you?!
Of course not!
Here we have the memory of the driver's seat.
What is he doing!
What's happening?
What are you doing?
Mom, do something! Crush my legs!
I can not unlock! Help me!
It's all under control.
- Stop it!
- I do not know how!
I have a steering wheel in your stomach!
- Stop!
- I can not!
- It's okay.
- Well, can we go?
Wait a minute, wait a Bringing your.
And now, most importantly,
without it there we go - music!
In the end, good music on leave
is a matter of the first importance.
Look now ...
A little too loud,
too loud. And what a good muse?
but shit
iPod z 1850!
Go, sheep!
But grandpa is dispersed
12 km / h!
Kids leave these phones,
we're on vacation!
- Wow! David Guetta game in Ushuaia!
- Guetta! It is the only one whose associate!
Ibiza is not only the clubs!
We'll go north.
There is more wildly,
authentically.
Especially such a place,
El Rayo Verde.
- You do not want to know, what is it?
- What? And, yeah, sure I do.
Thus, El Rayo Verde,
or "green beam"
It is visible for a fraction
of a second during sunset
- on the horizon ...
- Just send an SMS father that arrived!
Someone here at all listening?
- No!
- Oh, yes, dear.
- Do not go too fast.
- I prefer to avoid fines.
- A piece of the hotel.
- And we are.
Typical Spanish architecture
from the time of General Franco.
Only concrete, concrete and concrete ...
Knock Knock!
Mom, this hollow is a joke!
What do I do!
In the pictures it looked different.
I want to have your room!
No you do not!
We are in Ibiza, right on the sea!
Some anywhere
do not go on vacation!
There is no need to be nervous,
there is still one room! Look!
- And no, it's just storeroom.
- And well, we have a storeroom on the broom.
And anyway, if someone lives here?
What's the neighborhood died?
- Stop it, please!
- Indeed, very quiet here!
For me it's OK, but Julien Manon
may get bored.
Bored?
See for this ...
Here you are!
TECHNO HAPPY HOUR!
Every day from 18:00 to 20:00!
What? Every day we hear this ?!
- It's like, the area is better?
- Thanks mum!
Ogłuchniemy, but whatever.
- Do you like this kind of music?
- I love!
Well, I've only dream about,
to lie down.
Is the daily Le Monde?
A Figaro?
No? It talked himself.
Soon will die from the heat.
What I'll do about it,
it's your brother wanted to come here!
But I did not want Shrek.
- Shrek?
- You heard snoring? Massacre!
- At the age of 6000 years so everyone has.
- That's enough!
I also do not get enough sleep,
and I have a good humor,
I'm on vacation with children,
with Philip, the sun is shining!
Mom, it is embarrassing.
Not what your daddy!
He was so cool that you left
for some busty idiot!
Mom, please ... This is our father,
you should not say that in front of us.
Yes! This father and left him!
And Philip is my guy enough.
What's the skwaszone mines?
I bought a couple of newspapers in Spanish.
It's fun, but I'm busy.
I also go to take care of you, bye!
- Did I say something wrong?
- You know what they are young.
Well, let's go to the beach,
I want to take a bath!
- I wypiłbym cup of coffee on the terrace!
- It's go get a cup of coffee ...
- join me later.
- Well.
What a woman ...
Listen?
Get lost, caballero!
Carole, it's crazy!
- Again, they wanted to sell me a coke!
- Can you look koksiarza.
What on koksiarza?
Okay, time for a delicious cup of coffee and a newspaper.
And as your brother and this chick,
on which he insisted?
In life you will not find her.
But he is trying to surprise, as he finds out
what you're there.
Nothing godmother.
He insisted on this old man
with a 40-pound iPod.
We have a new collection!
Now, 5 years warranty, amigo.
Perhaps the iPhone? Samsung? Pendant? Apap?
I do not need anything.
Anyway, I have no cash.
No cash, no interlopers!
Wonderful water!
- I think I burned.
- You think through these glasses.
- Nice look! It's Tom Ford?
- No.
This Ray-Banosy. Ray-Bans for a tenner.
Besides, you can not see the difference.
With children baby ... I think
we have to calm, nothing by force.
- They said something about me?
- No, I'm just saying.
And if you do not accept me?
It is just impossible.
Thank you, it's beautiful what you say.
What is?
What are you laughing at?
Honey, you dropped the glass
and look ridiculous.
Damn, I just bought it!
- Ray-Banosom spoil the quality.
- But I did not pay much?
No, but still ...
- How much?
- tenner.
- How so, the glass has the right to go out ...
- Well, breathes in the mud ...
What is he doing with this phone?
- What did you show?
- I'm not going with you to talk about it.
Give it a hoax in peace, dear!
There are holidays, deserved!
- Use, kid ...
- No one bajerowałem!
Just looking for someone,
you happy? It odczepcie.
And I'm not your kid.
I guess I'm not
a master of communication.
Did you know that he came here
to find someone?
No, nothing tells me.
Tara, mamo.
What Tara? Who is this?
Typiara, for which he flew
from the beginning of the year.
He moved here
and stopped talking.
That's why Ibiza?
Why did not you tell me before?
You had to ask!
I am a hopeless mother.
Honey, do not worry,
we will find this Sarah ...
Tara! Not Sarah!
That's it, we will help him find
this whole Tara!
What a name, the first time I've heard ...
- All OK?
- drive me insane.
What are you, the parents.
- This center?
- Guess.
Not bad!
That's where this is Tara?
Do not pour the collar.
- Behold! This error is not she?
- She's not drinking.
It is impossible to withstand these your events!
Super atmosphere. She does not have a cell phone?
- You do not have to help me.
- But I want to Julien. We'll find her.
You say that it is a tiny, tiny ...
Here she is!
Very funny.
Julien! We look, but we can
also make fun!
Here it probably was not.
- Does not matter.
- Wait!
Do not give up.
Or maybe this one?
Come on ...
Wait.
- What's the oddity on wheels?
- It's hoverboard!
Break his nose, it will not be
so confident ...
Hey, Frankie!
- What pacan doing this?
- kisses mom?
You here? Welcome to Ibiza!
Give me a number, a bit of a hurry now.
Sure ... 0620214632.
- 46 32
- Honey, what are you doing?
We're talking, Grandpa, you can not see?
No no! This is my partner
and my children.
Wow, you're the posters everywhere!
It's me, but I do not like posters.
Carole said the same thing at the airport.
They are terribly obscene!
And you did not go well.
- And what do you do for living?
- I'm Podiatry.
Podo-what? Anyway, the
poster that you did not take.
You know, honey, I know Frankie
from the times of Lille,
old times.
He ran his own club, Privilege.
Memories come back!
- It was my first club.
- Mom, go to Ushuaia?
Yes of course.
Provided that dance
again on the table.
Oh no! Are you crazy?
It's not for me!
Do not you told me never think about this?
- I wonder why?
- Stop.
It's nice talking to you, but please
go back to the skateboard.
- hoverboard!
- Want to try?
- No, because I'm gonna fire.
- It did not look easy!
- It's simple, why do not you try?
- No, it's probably not a good idea!
What are you afraid of, darling?
If he gives you advice!
Well skied.
I can do it, I was pretty good skier.
- But it's not the same ...
- Not the same, and yet!
Nothing hard!
- Mom, long?
- I do not know.
Do not wait! I'll
control, and you go.
That we fall.
No, we stay here!
Family sticks together.
- And accidents happen ...
- It certainly his doing.
These guys are always jealous
of people like me.
- If you say so.
- He had it in his face!
What's your ticket?
237.
We will spend eternity here.
- What are they?
- Medusa.
- Sure burns.
- Ah, that must hurt!
- This is good ...
- Yeah ... Good ...
Very good....
Batman staring at me.
I feel trapped ...
And Jimi Hendrix is ​​...
I think not only I tore off today ...
- And to what?
- What does he want?
It's getting dangerous, we go from here.
Junkies everywhere ...
- All OK?
- Yes Yes...
Mom, I'm going to the club to look for Tara.
To the club? It is already eighteenth!
At this time of opening.
No way! You saw today what I?
I'm not going to go back to the emergency room.
Mom! I'm smart enough,
so as not doing drugs ...
Sweetheart...
I met him a little longer,
it sensible boy.
It is love, give him a chance to
find this girl.
And if it's the only one?
Worth looking for love life.
For example, I failed!
What are you talking about? I'm not the
woman of your life?
Oh yes ... That's not what I meant!
I mean...
the first half of my life.
This does not mean, after all,
that the second half is not successful.
Honey, do not torment me now,
I'm all battered.
- All right, let it be 22:00.
- Thanks mum!
You do not want to go too?
Oh, no, honey! I dream already
about to lie down!
Oh no! I do not go to sleep at 18:00,
I'm not a baby!
Zmówiliście we all ?!
OK, but do not you go outside the complex!
Thanks.
We trust you, Manon.
Come on, baby.
- gate valve, gate!
- Shut up!
Moron...
I have!
- I'm going to take a shower, you wait?
- All my life, if need be.
And tell ...
Not that I was jealous, but ...
There was something between you
and the typkiem of skateboards?
No! How did you come to that?
He said that you were together
very close ...
Yes, but as pals.
Phew ... That's good, because it would be me
with this strange.
Frankly, it looks
to the limited.
The genius of this might not be, but it is nice.
- Do not genius? Rather mediocrity!
- He's nice...
- Entry 50 euros.
- I do not have enough. But I know Frankie!
- Yeah, everybody knows him. Get lost already.
- It's my mom's ex.
This ex everyone.
Come on!
Mama?
- Mom, do you hear?
- Wait a minute ...
Mother?
Wait!
Where are you?
In Ushuaia, they do not want to let me in!
You call your ex?
This is not my ex!
- Julien, come back soon!
- No!
Tara is definitely here!
You promised to help me!
- Okay, I'll come there.
- Thank you, Mom.
But wieśniackie name.
Seriously? And I think
that Jordan is sweet.
And it's cool, so why
would I not do it?
Mom?
You are going out? I'm going with you.
No! Go back to your room and do not make noise.
Filip asleep.
- And when she wakes up?
- Tell him not to worry.
So you do not remember,
how ubrałaś ...
Yes! No! Calm him somehow simply.
I'm going.
- All OK?
- Yeah, great ... And you?
- Fine. What are you doing?
- A total of nothing ...
- And you?
- Nothing ...
Cool.
But stick with you!
Thanks ... I love how you're
so horny!
Throw away those two guys,
they do smoke there!
Damn, not a moment of peace!
- Frankie, I'm in front of the club.
- What? Here?
Yes, it is by a son,
I will explain everything to you ...
Wait, I'll give you to the VIP area,
only keeper I call ...
Louder, I can not hear!
- What are you wearing?
- On red.
I throw myself in the eye.
Julien!
- All OK?
- Wow, what a suit!
- I exaggerated?
- No, Mum! Grade!
Did you call the former?
Yes, but come on now,
it's just a buddy, bring us ...
- You're tense, something happened?
- It fastens in the VIP area.
I'll go help them ...
Oh no! You do not leave me here alone!
It was supposed to be our night!
Mom, what are you doing ?!
We had to look Tara!
I never find!
In this crowd?
- Sure, get it. I can handle it!
- Julien? Julien!
I can not! Mr. Słodziak woman!
All OK?
- You do not get a panic attack?
- No, I just like them fly.
- Well, because I have no more Relanium.
- Very funny!
Where podziałaś Słodziak?
- Well, where's your VIP Member?
- Enough!
Cocaine! Yes!
Hello, police ?!
Carole?
I do not want you to push
itself you have to want it ...
Want?
- And it hurts a lot?
- At the beginning, and then you do not ...
Hello, here voicemail Carole ...
- Manon, all right?
- Yes.
- Do you know where Mom went?
- She went to the Julien Ushaia.
Co?!
Do... Frankiego?!
Oh no, I reassure you ...
Do not tell my mother that it was me!
By you?
She ran to the dealer ?!
Yes, I think we need to go after them.
No way! You have 13 years
and will not go anywhere from here!
- What a pitcher ...
- What are you talking about, Manon?
I'm going to sleep! Now, you hear?
We would also gladly slept!
It is difficult, here is Ibiza,
there is not sleeping!
Eat to the sanatorium,
as loud for you!
How's our acrobat?
- Is he all right?
- Nothing serious, now asleep.
In this age, it's probably standard.
Do not you think?
No, I'm very happy with him.
I came here after his son.
- Your son is playing great now.
- Not true, looking for his ex.
Not only does he.
Everyone is looking for former today!
Come on, no way!
Carole, I still have someone.
But today really
bad chick with you!
- I do not want to listen to this.
- Carole?
This is my wife!
You good in red ...
- You're still here?
- Oh, no, have you seen my son?
And what I'm after him? Do not move from here,
bring a drink! Not a step!
- Who it was?
- one such friend ...
What are you doing here?
Chrapałeś! Julien could not
go home.
What? I can not hear, you can turn down?
Unbearable!
You not downloaded plugs at the entrance?
- No.
- Damn ...
- Frankie, dump him?
- Wrong.
It is better to give him a lesson.
I say immediately that I abhor aggression,
I will not defend, no art ...
- There will be no aggression, racuszku.
- Who's he talking about?
Will you show us what you can afford.
Let's see what you release muse.
- Certainly not the rąbankę!
- What's your nickname?
- First stage?
- Dr. F. F Filip.
- Here we go with coke!
- What type of ...
- Dr. F? What it again for tomfoolery?
- Trust me, honey ...
I made several symposia
chiropody,
everyone always enjoyed.
We are with you, słodziaku!
And now drink.
Come on, to the bottom!
It tastes flour ...
Sweetheart! Before you one
of the most important moments in life!
See you, sweetie!
- Honey, do not!
- Let him have some fun.
Have a drink, you need to chill.
- Come on, come on ...
- Strong, what is there?
Vodka!
- And a little bit of ecstasy.
- Drugs ?!
Hey, is anybody here?
CAN YOU FEEL IT?
Forgive me that I turned off the music,
but this one says
that we can not have fun.
Well, come.
Come.
I thought so ... if
you let it sit down behind the console.
Why not...
His name is Dr. F, F Filip!
CAN YOU FILIP!
Do you want to say something?
- Good night friends!
- Ok, Dobra.
Here you change the disc, here's a playlist ...
There's no need to!
I own playlist,
music lives in me,
music is me!
And only good music!
Where can I put this?
Your ass.
- Listen?
- Come on, give it!
And now a jiffy ...
Two minutes....
I snip!
You're doing fine, podologu!
All in all, a nice guy with you,
seriously!
Take łapsko because przetrącę them to you!
Anyway, caught!
- Fire!
- Shut the fuck up!
Come on, nerwusku.
Manon?
Well, now you've got a 18?
Promising!
Come on, it's important that they let me!
- Where are they?
- Over there!
Come on, Phil!
Honey, I fly!
Latam!
Look!
It's Mom!
But how is it possible that you fly ?!
I fly in the air, see!
I'll go too soon!
Carole, I fly!
- The triumph of Dr. F.
- It clearly.
Dr. F. nerwuskowi gave a lesson,
thinned his minka!
Philip, you will not be led!
Well ... Come on!
Filip!
- Get in!
- He got what he deserved!
Triumf Doktora F!
Stop it already!
Really you can do it lead?
- Better me than Dr. F.
- Dr. F, F Filip!
Julien...
Disable this muse, what a lame!
Kiss?
A Tara?
I think it will forgive myself ...
Through it was a hospital, ecstasy ...
- probably time to stop spoil our holiday ...
- What are you, I'm playing great.
I wonder if stoned Shrek also snoring ...
Can you Filip!
It's not good.
Come on, get outta here.
Slowly slowly...
- What clumsy.
- But he has moves!
My egg!
Honey, do not go it alone!
I'm sorry about yesterday ...
My mother was not herself.
- Philip also was not Philip.
- No...
But everything is under control,
- now we feel great!
- So great.
Hello? Hello!
- This SMS!
- But with me Stupid!
But Stupid! Excuse me...
- Something's wrong?
- Frankie invites us to the yacht.
Children might have wanted to swim.
Wait a minute,
as you want to have started doing drugs,
I know a few guys here with the goods,
- we do not need to push the sea.
- Cool, and so we do not go anywhere!
- I think you dream!
- milutko, I will fix you cruise ...
Honey, let the young to live their own way,
do not force.
- No problem, but I want the yacht.
- Approx! Let's go, darling!
There is parking.
Let's go na drugi parking, darling!
Have fun!
How do we hold out
all day with Frank?
After all, not bad ...
I made him upset yesterday.
So now I want to accept the
friendly invitation to the boat.
Sure thing!
- You know, I'm not jealous.
- Neither I!
Envy compound poisons.
And although this pacan Gilles betrayed me,
I'm not going to change.
- Also better watch yourself.
- I do not see the world outside of you!
But stop talking now about the former,
is unbearable.
- We are!
- Relax, do not shout, he sees us.
- Not to Spin!
- humming in my head ...
Just chill!
- But yesterday was fun!
- What a night!
I invite you!
- All OK?
- Yes.
All OK?
We feel great now ...
Hello nice ladies ...
- Phil.
- Tess.
Lubmila.
Something beautiful! Where are you from?
- I am from Colombia.
- And I'm from Puerto Rico.
But the story of the first time I meet
a real Latina.
- It clutch for the button!
- Well, it's full speed ahead!
A catch! Because the first time.
Well, goose! The direction of Formentera!
How to say "sea wolf"
after portorykańsku?
Sailor, my love!
You hold up, Grandpa?
So...
But I overlaid a kidney ...
- Do you want to turn back?
- Wrong.
Maybe I'll make you a massage?
My hands work wonders ...
- No need, I will deal with it!
- Do not react so nervous ...
It has smooth hands, wanted to help.
And now I'm really hurt the kidneys.
Hold on!
Cool, Frank!
Here we throw anchor?
A big chunk from the shore, right?
Sit and wait, soon will be the boat.
Well, the boat. If you
'd still swam.
No problem!
In any case, a nice trip!
- You are the man for his age.
- Thanks for kind words.
Seriously, I wish my mom
was such as you.
I did not even have wrinkles.
You see? There is no wrinkles ...
They say that time is celebrated
with me leniently than others.
I do not know.
- He has the eye as laughs.
- Okay, just ...
So after a 40-ce poker face is,
how you want to look good?
Okay, then we off.
- What is it, honey? Boczysz up?
- I have wrinkles, how to laugh?
What? I have no idea.
I did not notice.
But you turned on the young ass!
Oh no!
Why bother with the old,
as you have fresh meat here.
Who do you take me for?
I'm not your ex.
I realized!
He was a true seaman!
Ah yes! How does not fit,
I am buy a ticket and come back home!
Come back! You definitely have a direct
connection Ibiza Crotu!
- CROTOY not CROTU!
- Now, calm down.
It's just a little tiff ...
And I've got a cure!
For Madame pink wine,
for you and 25 kg of lobster with my
buddy Pascalou, what do you know?
You'll see that it will help!
And yet calm.
Come on ...
Like anything, you did not see
me with his wife.
Because it happens that sometimes
a little jealous ...
Hey Pascalou, Catouche,
brought to you guests!
Did you bring guests so?
And I'll just press down!
- Padding you fuck, you know?
- But for what?
- For what?! You know what!
- For what?!
Throughout the week there did you come
to visit me!
Not eggs, not too ...
I brought you a visitor.
- Good morning!
- Good morning.
Catouche? You do not say hello?
Hey, Frankie.
- And what of this?
- How's your lobster?
Homary?
Joseph!
- Show lobsters!
- Did you see? Magnifico!
And I advise you to eat clean,
if you want to get out of inches!
Before us a real treat, what a day!
You can not take it anymore, huh?
You have to keep a distance.
For me it does not work anymore.
This is my everyday life ... of
what, Frankie, since when?
You do not count.
Brunette, blonde,
small ass, big tits ...
Even they do not even notice!
But if I wanted to, przeleciałbym
everything that moves here.
- Undoubtedly.
- But is not love.
If you love a woman,
is it respect, Philip.
- Of course ...
- Catouche!
- How long are we together?
- 15 years, baby.
15 wiosenek, no jumping to the side,
without a cloud in our sky!
And so it should be at home!
This is. And you, Frankie?
When they finally get married?
Do you want to be alone like this ...
Just...
Unfortunately, I have not found
your Catouche ...
- I'd rather not find ...
- What's she so undermined?
You better give us another bottle,
because sober you can not hear this.
It was a real treat,
immediately unless they burst!
Philip likes to eat!
As soon as you throw in two lobsters.
Giuseppe 2 lobsters for Philip!
- Oh no, no ...
- Philip, are on the house.
No longer fit, anything!
And Mrs. nothing is not, Diet?
I need a drink before I show up
with the dupskiem on the dance floor!
But gull, huh?
- Hi.
- It's not you I saw yesterday?
- Yesterday? Yes ... That was me.
- OK, to cool.
- No, cool.
- Do not you ask my name?
- Sure ... What's your name?
Justine.
- Approx. Julien.
- I did not ask you about the name.
I'm kidding.
Justine Julien, that's so sweet!
Champagne for my friends!
- You are now one of them, Philip.
- I feel honored.
I recognize this girl,
I recognize her!
Impossible!
And this where? You can not leave
just like lobsters?
These are not the cheap stuff!
Your buddy is an ordinary boor!
- He is not one ...
- What do you mean?
Catouche what you gotten into?
- What did you do?
- Wait wait....
I know why so stroszy me.
The point is that I brought this guy ...
This type of hunter.
Hunters? Are you crazy?
It does not look like this ...
I learned that he tried
to grope club Catouche ...
And so now I look like,
it must be true!
Cholera!
Well...
You stop getting angry?
Go have fun with their whores!
Come on, they have 20 years!
You know, I prefer real women!
Stop bother me ...
Tell me you love me!
No more ...
You can not say it!
Immediately everything outspoken Pascalou!
I have these lies fed up!
The young lady Tara?
Tara?
Sorry, do not be afraid.
I am, let's say ... stepfather ...
Julien Lemerche, you went with him
to school in Lille.
I remember ... It is clear to Ibiza?
Yes! I wanted to speak to you,
but apparently did not have a cell phone?
- Parents are antyfalowcami!
- Oh, yes, great ...
A stationary?
We are, but rarely someone answers it.
It was me I would have enrolled,
Julien will gladly call.
Sure, 0034 ...
Wait a minute, however, the case acts,
as promised ...
0034 ... Wait a minute, I erased ...
But clumsy of me, already, 0034 ...
Hey, buddy!
You wanted to fuck my wife?
- shake the fuck you!
- He's crazy!
You shake the fuck up!
Help! Help!
It's a maniac!
What's happening?!
Pascalou, what are you doing?
- Stop it! Let him go!
- It is true that you groped?
- Who told you that?
- Who told me?
Frankie!
All that I told you, I told
only that something was on top of things ...
It's not him...
It's a thick Belgian,
wanted to catch me in the toilet ....
Thick Belgian?
How to find him now ?!
Already I'll show him!
Where is that son of a bitch ?!
- I'll handle it tonight!
- Calm down.
I'm calm.
Thank you, Frankie. Well,
that although I can count on you!
Move up.
Maniac!
- But I got ...
- We go back, I've had enough!
Do not take you back?
Oh no! I'd rather have more
will not see you!
Stay with a buddy and his wife,
unless you have to comfort her.
Definitely!
He got me.
- What we do?
- I'm looking at you right Insta.
- I'm here with you, what to look for me?
- But you know, later on.
Ah yes?
On the what?
There you are! @ Justine25, right?
Wow, how many you have followersów ...
- Okay, I go out, right here melt.
- Wait, I turn aircon.
- Leave.
It's perfect!
Plus it is that Tara found.
And minus the one that I think I have
Guillain-Barre syndrome ...
What is this?
I have no feeling,
slap me numb ...
It's probably acute ...
Although, though ...
again, for sure ...
It is not bad,
I feel a slight tingling sensation,
I'm saved ...
- That's better, you smile.
- What you do make me laugh.
Anyway ...
to me they do not interfere.
Co?
Your wrinkles,
you laughing ... When the left eye
and the right too.
- That's less ridiculous.
- But it looks lovely.
I think the time has come,
we say to you ...
Philip has won a number of Tara.
Stationary. There is no cell, because her
parents are antyfalowcami.
- What, no reaction?
- What, me hanging.
- Julien! Do not talk to Philip!
- Easy, Carole ...
How quietly? As many have done,
to find her,
and he so thank you for that?
What do you have to Philip? It is too old,
is an idiot, is embarrassing?
- And something else?
- Carole, after all, so they did not say.
They said!
And if not, it definitely thought!
Enough lies, now we are talking
ourselves but the truth ...
Do you want the truth? Tara I do not care,
I met a great girl here!
Except that the pig someone already has ...
- Julien!
- Give me a break!
If we say anything now,
I also met a super guy and ...
- That punk from the pool?
- It's not punk, it's a hipster!
Manon, come on! What did you do with him?
Mom, but certainly not to piss off?
It was even nice.
Although still a little hurt ...
Manon, you have 13 years, what are you talking about?
About my tattoo ...
Aaah! That's wonderful, darling!
As well, that did it myself!
- We're going after Julien?
- Sure, Julien!
Tattoo is a great thing ...
Outstanding ...
- Even though you have not seen it ...
- That's okay, it is beautiful ...
It is certainly nice,
you have great taste!
Cholera!
He could not have gone far!
- He's not answering ...
- Why do not you call?
- That's unlike him.
Relax, think ...
We are the fortress of Charles V in
the sixteenth century ...
We are now somewhere.
I do not understand you. The point is
that it was built on the set of wheels!
So if you go this way,
and that way I ...
- Take longer forgive!
- I have to let go ?!
Charles V prided himself on this project.
Thanks to him the city was
impregnable!
Nobody wants to listen to me ...
Julien?
Julien!
Look, I know I'm not your father,
or even your bro.
- What?
- Come on, bro, buddy ...
But I'll tell you something.
Something personal
about me and my life.
It never went to women.
His first wife left me,
I hated her for it.
But now I think she was right.
If she was with me satisfied,
it would not do that ...
And now I'm shaking breeches,
your mom will do the same.
Do not leave you, what have you!
It is totally zabujana you ...
Thanks, but ...
it's not so simple!
My parents, scrabble,
dentures and all the rest ...
It's complicated.
And I'm not ready for you advice,
but today on Formentera
I met Tara, a beautiful girl!
And when I said that you are looking for her,
in her eyes she lit a spark.
You passed the high school diploma, you came here
to meet her.
We have her number ...
Perhaps now a shame to forgive?
A winning number was not easy!
He beat me one asshole ...
He attacked me for no reason.
I barely escaped with his life,
the poor man, because frankly ...
I do not abhor aggression,
it would have wiped him to a pulp!
Here, you call.
It's the number that begins with 34,
I'll wait.
I'll have to look,
because I certainly worried.
Why not add a gas?
We left the city.
Finally someone said it out loud,
it's not unbearable.
I do not know what it was,
from the beginning do not want to accelerate.
This speed limiter to 50 km / h.
Try now!
We have it! Thanks Julien!
But you can kick-start
this chaise ...
Not bad.
And beware!
Carefully, carefully!
Who wants to know the remarkable history of
the church of the holy Gertrude?
- No one!
- Too bad ...
Good day.
- Good morning ....
- Julien.
It's your parents?
Yes, but they are on their way.
- And yes, of course.
- Ideal,
and what's your name?
- Julien. Welcome to us!
- We will not disturb?
Not at all!
It's always nice to be with people ....
Philip, I am pleased.
- Julien.
- Carole and Manon's sister Ju ...
Adorable little girl!
The skin removed from my dad!
- I'm not her father ...
- Really! Those same eyes!
Come on, we'll have something ...
Come on, nothing to it arrives.
Welcome to our humble abode.
Sorry for the mess...
I introduce to you, Michel,
just floats.
Pysiu! We have visitors.
I'm coming.
- That's how you got your name?
- Philip.
- I told you.
- It's hard to overlook.
There is something else that hard to overlook.
Truth...
I'm sorry, I swim every 2.5 hours.
Caring for the heart above all.
I am a cardiologist,
so I know what I'm talking about.
- I am pleased, Michel.
- Philip.
We kind of a marching ...
- I'm Podiatry.
- Well, you had to learn.
Sure you had with
a good laugh at the university.
We used to say that the feet
are stinking specialization.
- actually funny.
- Justin
- Tara is waiting in the gazebo. Go to her.
- Go on, Justin.
- Beyond the trees and straight.
- Thank you.
And is Maella.
- Do not say hello, darling?
- Good morning, Maëlle ...
- Beautiful, huh?
Lovely.
- So it is with young people like to be ...
- I just have time.
How do you manage to be
so green garden?
- Watering must cost a fortune?
- Not a penny!
The biggest challenge for humanity
today is the treatment of waste.
- And with us is the whole recycling.
- Yes!
- It's great.
- We are 100% Organic!
- We go to?
- With pleasure.
- Tara?
- I'm here.
You take a shower in his clothes?
No...
I like to feel on the skin cold flax ...
You also want to be refreshing?
Sure, why not.
Come then.
You take a shower in his clothes?
Yes, I feel on the skin
wet cotton.
I wonder if your phone too.
Oh shit ...
Choose an area for nawiezienia
and fertilizer is directed there.
- Oh, I see.
- Please! The reservoir is filled.
He is filled?
All waste, water, gray
water, black ... like a ship,
We grind it and make this
100% natural fertilizer ....
- I circle closes.
- There are four of us, it goes fast ...
- Ah yes?
- Come to taste.
- With pleasure ...
- What do you mean "all waste"?
What do you think?
- It's disgusting.
- I prefer there not to eat anything.
You watch Walking Dead?
Typical American series,
which draws from the 15th of the season ...
- I pulled out of the second.
- It was a metaphor.
If I say that you hit
the ball in the fence, it does not mean
that there is a ball and a fence.
- Fertilization all the vegetables.
- That's fertilizer ...
Natural fertilizer.
You will not find these in France,
a round as a baby's bottom!
- And how it smells!
- How a baby's bottom ...
Maybe even you would have to scroll through it!
It's meant to be funny?
No, we often walk alone ...
We have a great central square in Lille bio.
Yes, Wazemmes ...
has always been boycotting it.
Pseudo ciapatych of bio ...
Yes! I had two days
of diarrhea after those strawberries!
Ryneczek Wazemmes!
Honey, what happened?
- They are well szurnięci ...
- Oh yes!
Do you have any tattoos?
I just did myself, it is great.
Mom probably will not be thrilled.
- You want to see?
- No need, I've got it somewhere.
Listen, baby, you can give me
joint from the table?
And recently I was at a concert
Nekfeu with Zenit was mega!
This annoys me terribly lad,
I can not look at him ...
And there is something you like?
In addition to its own Japa?
What?! How can you say that?
Everything I say is shit.
But maybe you're the shit?
You're crazy! Go cure yourself!
What am I doing here anyway? And yet
I spoiled by you phone!
- Okay, get outta here!
- You and your family is sick!
All in all, it's gone I feel like.
- Are you kidding me?
- Calm down, baby, what's up?
Manon, what are you doing here?
- Did you give her a joint?
- I did not give, you fool ...
- Manon gave you smoke?
- Yes.
- But it gets dark ...
- And what, you hit me?
No, but I'll do it ...
What are you doing?!
Who do you have?
Dad! He twisted my neck! Dad!
- What did you do to my daughter?
- joint gave my sister!
Oh no! Now, please, come on!
And what is it?
Julien, violence is never
anything not do the trick!
Sure, just do not scrap a lick.
Stupid, smelly podolog!
Mug, small fiutku!
A blond man what he wants?
What's she doing? Not that!
Well done, darling! Bravo!
My irrigation system!
Who wants the prickly pear fig?
You know where you can shove
these their prickly pears ?!
Nobody wants!
Spoiled the whole system!
PYSIO?
- What was that?
- Gównotrysk!
100% bio!
They are everywhere!
Immediately grabbed them!
War! Shocker!
They are everywhere, everywhere!
Dupki!
Idiots!
Auto open, keys inside!
Fast!
- Wait!
- Mom, come on ...
- Come on, Mom!
- wash up, assholes!
Let them grabbed!
We came out of this with dry feet!
But their załatwiłaś, Mom!
Championship!
Well done, darling, bravo!
Well, that you were with us!
Because you wymiękłeś again!
- crazy?
- Come on, we ourselves speak the truth!
Dad gave to him in the throat
and it would be the case ...
Manon, silence!
Sure.
Thank you and good night!
Sweetheart!
Philip, do not take it personally,
did not want to say so.
Give me a break.
I'm sorry, Philip ...
do not think so!
I know very well what you're thinking!
From the beginning! End of it.
I'm an old, stupid, weird ...
I can never become part of
your family! And that's it!
- so cool!
- Thanks for support...
See for yourself! Do you see the sign?
El Rayo Verde, told us about it,
there really ...
It turns out, however, that I am not
such a fool finite ...
Come on, let's go.
- Come on, Philip!
- Go alone, I'll stay here.
No way, he told
us about this place!
- Come on, please ...
- Do not be mad anymore!
Come! Without your story
will not be the same.
If you ask, I'll go.
You'll see a real,
wild, untamed Ibiza,
the islanders come here just ...
Julien, you will make beautiful pictures!
Indeed, wild Ibiza.
Maybe even too much, huh?
It's not good.
- That's what we like, darling.
- Come on lemonade.
Manon, do not look up!
Did you see? All the goals!
It's hard not to notice!
And I believed in the fairy tale
of the green radius of the sun ...
Oh no! I missed!
- Damn!
- Oh no!
We missed!
I have not seen anything!
Eternal gapa ...
In any case, thank you
for the holidays, Julien ...
I played great,
it's your merit!
Thank you too...
It's not over yet,
we still have tomorrow.
That, about which we have a plane?
I have saved it somewhere ...
It makes no sense, no?
Saturday, 0:10 hour.
That means Sunday 0:10?
... not tomorrow, Saturday,
ten minutes after midnight.
- In front of us the whole day to relax.
- Honey, wait a minute.
Sunday 0:10 time
is the beginning of Sunday.
Not Saturday ...
If you want, fly on Sunday.
But we have tickets ...
Saturday at 0:10 for an hour!
Mom, it's Friday night ...
So at 0:10 on Saturday will be soon!
Philip is right!
But me an idiot!
No idiot!
Wait ...
With a little organization we can do it.
We will not, we will not ...
Wait, I stumble over a dress!
Fast!
Okay, kids! Fasten your seat belts!
I zaiwaniał!
Zaiwaniał?
And the music!
Take care!
- How do you counter?
- Less than 100 ...
On contact!
- But it's me!
- This is too much!
A right image ?!
- Philip!
- Mom, let's go!
- Unbelievable.
- Madness.
- Sorry for punctuality.
- It's disrespectful!
Sorry ...
I'm sorry, you're right.
What is your number?
I'm sorry, unless you sat
in my place.
- early check ...
- Get out of here!
Cholera!
Sorry, I usually
abhor aggression, but ...
the place of my wife,
and she has to sit close to me.
- Sit down, honey!
- Julien?
Besides I paid the place for it.
I do not reply to messages.
Broke my phone ...
Anyway, you were probably busy with it here.
This is my brother!
See you on arrival ...
- It was Julien?
- Yes.
Well, they did not listen to me ...
It's gorgeous.
Welcome aboard flight Ibizair
to Lille.
Flight time is 2 hours 40 minutes.
The temperature in Lille is 17 ° C.
Before us the zone of turbulence
over the Auvergne.
What is he saying? You know Spanish!
- What he said?
- Excellent weather conditions!
Mom, OK? You do not stress?
No, great weather,
and I took 3 tablets Relanium.
Three?
That's what a family photo?
- Make it fast, because as soon as I fall asleep.
- Smile please...
OK, Mom sleeps, I'll show you
my tattoo.
- You want to?
- Of course.
"Fuck me I'm Manon" ?! Serious?!
What was that?
- You going?
- Yes, yes, sweetheart ...
now we're going ...