(electric sizzling)
(ominous music)
(creature huffs and growls)
(creature breathes loudly)
- I'm so bored.
(creature huffs)
All right.
I'm gonna make some popcorn.
(creature huffs)
(ominous music)
(creature growls
softly and sniffs)
(creature grunts)
(crashing)
(suspenseful music)
(creature growls)
There's something in the house.
Yes, there's something
in the house.
There's something in the house.
Oh my gosh, please hurry!
(creature huffs and pants)
(creature pants)
(suspenseful music)
- Kayla!
Get in the house!
It's not in there,
it's out here!
(crickets chirping)
(soft breathing)
(creature grunts softly)
(creature pants)
(creature growls)
(creature growls loudly)
- [Man] Holy shit!
(creature roars)
(creature growls softly)
(creature sniffs)
(creature growls)
(creature growls loudly)
(dramatic, energetic rock music)
(indistinct chattering)
- [Woman] Your boyfriend's here.
- Um, hey, will you tell him
I'll be there in a minute?
I've gotta drop this
coffee off at table seven
and then check in
on the kitchen.
- I sure will, in a sec.
(man grunts softly)
- Oh, crap.
- Is everything all
right here, sir?
- Uh, actually no.
My bacon wasn't crispy,
my eggs were running
all over the place,
and my toast is burned.
- Well, your eggs
were scrambled.
But it seems like you
ate a lot of it already.
- Well, I struggled
with most of it,
and I'm not satisfied at all.
- How about I go get the kitchen
to make you another plate?
How's that sound?
- No, no!
No, my stomach's upset now.
- Hey Nick, Marilynn
is busy over there.
But she'll be here in a minute.
Can I get you anything?
- Coffee.
- Extra cream, right?
- Yeah.
- Okay, got it.
There we go.
- Joan.
- Yeah?
- Why's Lisa here today?
Shouldn't she be at school?
- Oh, she wasn't feeling well.
And you know, on
such a short notice,
there's no way she
could get a sitter.
- I'm sorry, sir.
Like I said, I'd be happy
to get you another plate.
- [Customer] I said I
wanted crispy bacon!
- Hi, Nick.
- Lisa, how you doing?
- I'm good.
- Ah, you're good?
I heard you were sick today.
- Oh, that's what I
meant. (coughs weakly)
I'm not feeling so well.
- Well, I hope you feel
a little bit better.
Wouldn't want you
getting behind in school.
- Can you keep a secret?
- Of course.
- Well, I'm not really sick.
I just didn't wanna
go to school today.
- Why didn't you wanna
go to school today?
- Well, I told Marty Schulz
that I wanted to
marry him someday.
And he told all of his friends
and they all laughed at me.
- Lisa, you're in sixth grade.
I think you're a
little too young
to be worrying about marriage.
- Oh silly, I meant in
high school or someday.
- Well, I think
Marty'd be a lucky man
to marry you at any age.
- You really think so?
- I'm sure of it.
- Now, when will you
come to your senses?
- Come into my senses?
- When are you
gonna marry my mom?
- I'd be better off if you
were better at your job.
Oh, what's this?
You called the Army in?
What can I do for you, captain?
- Is that any way
to talk to a lady?
- Well, you know, I mean,
there'd be no problem here
if they got my order right.
- John, I get it.
After they closed the mine,
times have been
tough for everybody.
But you can't be treating
people like this.
- That's easy for you to say.
You got a job.
- Tell you what.
- What's this for?
- If you don't want
it, I'll take it back.
- No, that's okay.
I'm just asking what it's for.
- Just like to help you out.
Got a job opening, State Park.
- A state job?
That's a great job, man.
That's better than shoveling
shit at Jacob's farm.
- All right, the
pay's not that great.
It's my old position.
But at least it'd be a start.
- Well, that's okay,
man, I need a job.
- [Nick] Could you come in
for an interview Monday at 11?
- Absolutely.
My wife would be really happy.
- One more thing.
You've got to quit drinking.
Can you do that?
- Yeah, I can do that.
- Can I have that?
- You just asked me
to quit drinking.
Now you want my flask
and you drink my alcohol?
- I want your flask
so you don't drink it.
- Oh.
- All right.
I'll see you Monday
at 11 o'clock.
Make sure she gets a
good tip, all right?
And don't forget, no drinking.
You can do that?
- Right, yeah, I can do that.
- [Nick] All right,
see you Monday.
- Starting tomorrow.
- [Joan] Hi, Tom.
- Hey, Joan, can I get
a cup of coffee, please?
- Sure, I'll bring
it right over.
(Tom sighs)
- Oh, hello, Tom.
- Hey John, how you doing?
- I'm doing all right.
- How about a little ride home?
- I'd like that.
- I'm ready when you are.
- All right.
- Joan, I'm gonna have to
cancel that coffee, okay?
Thank you.
- Howdy, babe.
I know you are so busy.
I'm sorry to stop in.
But tonight, I got
something special planned.
- Yeah?
- [Nick] Six o'clock.
- Okay.
- I'm picking you up.
Put something nice on.
I'll see you then.
- Okay.
- Right, I love you.
- Love you.
- [Tom] How you doing there?
- Fine, thanks.
- Where you headed?
- I was gonna go up
in the hills to camp.
- Oh yeah.
Well, there are plenty
of places to pick from.
Looks like you got
perfect weather, too.
- Sure is.
- Well, you go and have
yourself a good time now,
and be safe, okay?
- All right, thank you.
(gentle guitar music)
- I wanna live a metaphor life.
You know, like I
read in that book.
People say, "He lived
a life worth living."
That's what I'm going for.
And right there.
Morning sun, man.
This is where we get
the National
Geographic-level finish, man.
- Heck, yeah.
I was here last week and
there were turkeys everywhere.
- That's what I'm talking about.
See, we don't have to
sell a documentary series.
I don't need to be a star.
We're the documentary, the
turkeys are right there.
- I wanna be a
filmmaker and stuff.
- Exactly.
So we go slow, right?
Stealth, whatnot.
And then you utilize your
cinematographic expertise.
- Like cinematic art.
- I'm talking Smithsonian
Channel, brother.
This ain't no Honey Boo Boo.
(gentle guitar music)
(huffs)
(engine starts)
(car rumbles softly)
- Goddammit!
John Hicks.
Oh hi, Honey, how you doing?
Yeah.
Look, you never mind about
that land and my brother, okay?
My daddy said, "Do not
sell the land to anybody."
I don't,
(stutters)
Honey, I,
listen, (stutters)
wait a minute.
I was down at Tammy's.
Tammy's, the restaurant
down on Canal Street.
Yes.
Listen, the Ranger
came over to me
and he told me that I
have a job interview
at 10 o'clock on Monday.
Yes.
I am not drunk.
Honey, (stutters) look.
(stutters and huffs)
Honey, look, honey.
Whoa, Honey, (vocalizes
hissing and grumbling)
yeah, (stutters) breaking up.
Yeah, oh, (stutters).
(soft guitar music)
Why'd she got to piss me off?
(mutters to himself)
(twig crackles)
Hey, who is that?
(eerie guitar music)
(door squeals)
- Hi.
- Are we still on for tonight?
- Of course.
- What time am I picking you up?
- 7:30.
- Nice.
That's a real nice
color on you, too.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
- So you're gonna
pick me up at my home?
- Yeah, 'course.
- Okay.
- Now, you gotta drive over
to the diner by yourself.
(woman huffs)
- All right, so 7:30, okay?
- Yeah, I'll pick
you up at your house.
- [woman] Okay.
- All right, Sweetheart.
- Bye.
(gentle guitar music)
(gunshot bangs)
- [Man] Woo-hoo, heck yeah!
It's a damn clean shot.
- [Nick] You boys
enjoying yourselves?
- [Both] Uh.
- Yeah, guess you
could say that.
- You guys do know
that shooting a deer
outside of the season is
against the law, right?
- Well, yeah, but,
we didn't shoot this deer.
This deer was dead
when we come upon it.
Ain't that right, Ernest?
- That's right,
Jeb, it was dead.
We just walked right up on it.
- [Jeb] Yep.
- All right, so you're
expecting me to believe
that you guys were just
walking through the forest
on this trail, with guns,
and you came across a dead deer?
- Yup, yes sir.
That's quite a story.
Well, you don't mind if I
check your guns, then, do you?
- [Jeb] Wait, don't you
need a warrant to do that?
- Oh yeah, don't
you need a warrant?
- A warrant?
No, no, we're all good.
Don't worry about it.
All right, this gun is clean.
Mind if I check this gun?
(gun clicks)
Yeah, we got a problem, guys.
(both grunt and stutter)
(shot blasts)
Get back here.
(Jeb chuckles)
Why?
Why would you run?
- Scared, I guess.
- That gun was fine.
I don't think I need to ask,
but who's the owner of this gun?
- That'd be mine, sir.
- Now, wasn't that
easier than lying?
- Oh man, you're not gonna
give us a ticket, are you?
- Don't you think
you deserve one?
- Well, yeah, but,
couldn't you give us a break?
- Yeah, come on,
give us a break.
- Did you give
this deer a break?
- Yeah, right through the neck,
can't you see that? (chuckles)
- Shut up, Ernest.
- All right, guys.
You're catching me
in a very good mood,
'cause I'm gonna be
proposing to my lady tonight.
- Oh!
Hey, well, congratulations.
- Good luck, man.
- Yeah, yeah.
I'm sure she's gonna say yes.
You're a good looking
man, don't you think?
- What, you getting
queer on me or something?
- No man, I'm just saying.
- Whatever.
- Anyway.
I'm gonna let you guys off
with just a warning
this one time.
But I want you guys
to take this deer
down to my truck.
(Ernest huffs)
I'll take the guns, you grab--
- You serious?
- Are you serious?
- Do I look serious?
Let's go.
- (stutters) Could
we gut it first?
- Does it look like we
have time to gut it?
Let's go!
- Shot it through the neck.
What were you thinking?
(both grunt and groan)
(soft breathing)
- Hey, who is that?
Hey, who is that?
You don't understand
who you're messing with!
Hey, who keeps doing that?
Cut that out!
You know I'm gonna find you.
(creature grunts softly)
Hey, come out here!
Who's out there?
Oh, the heck with it.
(mutters to himself)
You ain't supposed to be here.
This is private land.
(shot booms, creature roars)
(low, tense music)
(creature grunts)
Hey, you come out
from behind that tree.
(creature huffs and grunts)
(shot booms)
(creature grunts)
(creature roars)
(John screams)
(blood squelches)
(creature grunts and whines)
(roars sadly)
- [Paula] Wow.
First class service.
- I'm not quite sure
I understand what
you mean by that.
- Car, silly.
- Oh.
Well, my real car
is in the shop,
so it's gonna have to do.
- That's okay.
This is awesome.
Can you turn the lights on?
- Uh, for you I can.
Boom.
- Whoop, whoop!
- There you go.
- That's awesome.
- Pretty cool, huh?
You like that?
- I like it.
- Guess where I'm taking you.
- [Paula] Where?
- Just, we're going
to this place,
they serve nothing but
caviar and champagne.
- That's it?
I have to work
after, I can't drink.
- Okay, well, actually I'm
taking you to the diner.
I was messing with you.
- [Paula] Ooh, wow.
(both chuckle)
- Is that okay?
- That's okay.
- It's all right? All right.
- Let's do it.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
- All right, let's do it.
- Okay, let's go.
(creature growls softly)
(both creatures growl
and grunt softly)
(larger creature
roars and grunts)
(roars)
(creature breathes softly)
(sniffs)
(breathes softly)
(tense, suspenseful music)
(tent rustles softly)
- Shit.
(creatures growls softly)
(tense music intensifies)
(creature breathes softly)
(creature growls loudly)
(creature roars)
(cracking and squelching)
(creature roars and huffs)
(roars)
- So, uh, Paula, I had
a really nice time.
- I had a really
awesome time, Tom.
- Really?
- Um-hm.
- Is it something
you'd like to do again?
- Of course.
- Okay.
Well, we definitely should then.
- We should.
Oh wow, I gotta be at
work in 15 minutes.
- Okay.
- All right.
(car door slams)
- See you tomorrow.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Okay.
(sighs)
- Ma'am?
Uh, you okay?
- Did you see it?
- Uh, see what, ma'am?
- A big, hairy
creature or something.
It just jumped up
in front of me.
I swerved to miss it
and hit this tree.
- Are you sure about that?
- Yes, it was,
it just jumped out
so fast that I, uh,
didn't have time to react.
- Uh, well, it was most likely
a deer, don't you think?
- Sonny, I know what
a deer looks like,
and this was no deer.
It was ungodly big, huge.
- Uh-huh.
Ma'am, could you tell
me your name, please?
- Oh yeah.
My name is Lois Stevens.
I live up the road from here.
- I'm gonna need
to see your license
and your proof of
insurance, please.
I'm gonna call you an ambulance
and probably most
likely a tow truck.
If you could give me that
paperwork, I'd appreciate it.
- You sit tight, okay?
I'll be right back.
Just sit there.
Don't move too much 'cause
you might be injured, okay?
I'm not allowed to
touch you or move you.
- Thank you.
- I'll be back couple
of minutes, sit tight.
Dispatch, it's 239.
I got a single car accident,
license plate Frank, Nora,
Edward, five, one, nine, seven.
I'm out on Route 28, about two
and a half miles south of 33.
Looks like I'm gonna
need an ambulance
and most likely a tow truck.
Copy that?
- [Paula Through Speaker]
Okay, 239, we're on it.
- Okay, copy that.
Miss Stevens, hi.
I'm gonna try and open the door,
just give you a little
bit more room, okay?
Looks like it's a little
jammed, so hang on.
- Okay.
(Tom grunts softly)
(door thuds, Lois gasps)
- [Tom] You okay?
- Uh, yeah.
- The ambulance is
on its way, okay?
I'm not really allows to
touch you or move you.
But why don't we just
get back to, you know,
what you were talking about,
you telling me
about what you saw?
- Uh, well, at first sight
I thought it was a person.
But it was way too big for that.
No way it was a man.
- [Tom] Too big, huh?
- It was huge and furry,
with long arms and very tall.
It took maybe two or three
steps to cross the road.
- Uh-hm.
- Well, you do
believe me, don't you?
- Oh yeah, no, of course I do.
- [Lois] Oh.
- Ambulance is
gonna be here soon.
- Okay.
(Lois sighs)
(dog barking)
- Bear, quiet down.
- Hey, why is Bear
barking, Tommy?
- I don't know, Mom.
What is it, Bear?
Something out there, buddy?
(dog barking)
- Tommy, I got
another bag for you!
- [Tommy] Okay, Mom,
I'll be right there!
(dog barking)
Who's there?
Man!
What is that smell?
(creature growls)
(creature roars, Tommy screams)
- Tommy!
Tommy, what is it?
(pants) What?
Tommy, where are you?
Tommy, please come out.
Oh my God, what was that?
Oh my God! (pants)
- 911, may I help you?
- Yes, it's my son.
He's been kidnapped.
- Okay, ma'am, calm down
and tell me where you are.
- I live at 1314
School Rod Road.
Please send someone, hurry!
- Okay, tell me what happened.
- Oh, he was taking
out the garbage
and I asked him to come
and get another bag,
and he said okay and
the next thing I know,
he's screaming for me.
He's screaming my name, "Mom!"
I go running out of the
house and I'm looking
and I don't see him anywhere.
I heard him calling for
me, started coming out,
and all of a sudden
I see someone running
really, really fast
through the woods.
- Was it your son going
through the woods?
- No, no, there's no way!
It was going way too fast
and he's only 12 years old.
Please, please send
someone, hurry!
Hurry, come and
help me get my son.
- Okay, Mrs. Jones.
I have a deputy nearby.
- Okay, okay, send
him down please.
Thank you, thank you so much.
Please hurry!
- [Paula Through
Speaker] 239 dispatch.
- Yeah, dispatch, it's 239.
- [Paula Through Speaker]
We have a missing child
over at 1314 School Rod Road.
Is it possible for
you to check this out
as soon as possible?
- Well, I'm finishing up here
in about five, 10 minutes.
So I can get there real
quick if you need me to.
- [Paula Through Speaker]
All right, thank you.
- Copy that.
- Ambulance is coming,
but here's my card.
Wanna give it to you.
If you have any questions,
you need anything,
you just give me a call, okay?
- Okay, all right.
- [Tom] Ambulance
be here any second.
You just hang tight, all right?
- Thank you, officer.
(tense music)
(brake squeals, creature growls)
- (pants) Help me, help me!
Oh my God, it's my son.
- What's the matter, ma'am?
- He's missing!
My son is missing!
- Okay, okay, calm
down, calm down.
Step away from the
vehicle, please,
so I can help you.
- [Mrs. Jones] Please,
please help me.
- Talk to me, slow
down, calm down.
Calm down, tell
me what happened.
- He was taking out the trash.
He was taking out the trash,
and then he was
already out there,
so I asked him, please just
take another bag for me.
- All right, ma'am, show
me where this happened.
- It was right over there.
- Do you see it, can
you see the barrel?
- Yeah, I can see it.
- He was right there.
And then they was running
really fast right through there.
It was something, I
know it was my son.
(gasps)
- Okay.
Was there anything that you
noticed that was unusual?
- Just the dog.
Our dog was barking
hysterically.
And it wasn't like him at all.
It was just odd.
- Uh-uh, how so?
- Well, like it was trying
to protect him or something.
It was just really different.
- Okay, okay.
- I don't know.
- Okay, ma'am,
I'm gonna need you
to just calm down, okay?
I'm gonna go up there, I'm
gonna check it out, all right?
- Okay.
- So stay right here.
Just, just please be careful.
Be careful!
(suspenseful music)
(tense music)
(sniffs)
Oh my God, damn!
Shit. (huffs)
All right, ma'am.
I did not see
anything out there.
- Okay.
- Okay?
But if something did happen,
they probably went
in that direction.
- [Mrs. Jones] So
what are you saying?
Are you saying
somebody kidnapped him?
- No, no, no, no.
Don't jump to conclusions, okay?
I'm gonna go over to my radio,
I'm gonna call in
search and rescue team.
They're gonna come down--
- Thank you.
- And they're gonna
look for your son,
see if they can find him, okay?
This is what I want
you to do right now.
No, stop, stop, don't talk.
Don't jump to conclusions, okay?
We don't know anything
that happened, all right?
Okay, so this is what
I need you to do.
I'm gonna give you my card.
- Okay.
- Okay?
You have any
questions, you call me.
But I need you to go in there,
sit down, and wait until
search and rescue comes,
'cause I'm gonna go, I'm
gonna call 'em in right now.
- Thank you so much.
- Okay?
Calm down, it'll be fine.
We'll find your son,
everything's gonna be fine.
- [Mrs. Jones] I
just want him home.
- Of course you do.
I do, too, ma'am.
Go in there and
sit down, darlin'.
- Thank you so much.
- I'm gonna call
it in right now.
- [Mrs. Jones] Okay. (sobs)
(creature huffs
and grunts softly)
- [Tom] Hey Paul, will
you check this out for me?
- [Paul] What you got?
- [Tom] I found it about an
hour ago at a crime scene.
Mrs. Jones' boy.
- This is ripe.
Well, it's not canine.
There's pieces of hide here.
(mumbles)
- Can you just give me a second?
I gotta talk to dispatch.
- [Paul] Yeah,
I'll be right here.
- [Tom] Okay.
(gentle guitar music)
(men chatter softly)
- Camera right there.
- Okay.
- [Younger Man] Man, this is it.
- Don't get any
better than that.
- Hey, check, it's
a turkey call.
Turkey call, no turkey call?
Yeah? Meh, I'll give
it to you later.
(mutters to himself)
Lookin'.
We need a flashlight.
- What the hell?
Brian, Brian, you
gotta see this.
- [Brian] Hold on, man.
I gotta find my, my
other flashlight--
- No, no, you gotta see this.
- What?
- [Man] Look!
- Oh shit.
(creature huffs)
That's like a big-ass
bear or something.
- That ain't no freaking bear.
It's got arms!
It's a Sasquatch.
- Goddammit, man!
I'm on meds and I drink!
Not funny, I don't believe you!
He's,
it's moving,
it's moving this way.
Uh.
No, no.
It's running this way.
- Oh shit, man!
(creature grunts)
(both yammer)
(creature growls)
- Man, this is gonna be
historical damn footage!
- Come on, let's--
- Okay, okay, okay.
(Brian babbles)
Damn, no signal.
Damn Obamaphone!
- Who the hell are you calling?
- I'm gonna call Bobby.
He knows the park ranger.
- Run, we gotta
get to the truck!
(creature growls)
- This way!
- This way.
- Faster, faster!
- I am, I am.
- My back is killing me, man!
(creature roars)
I got a signal, I got a signal.
(mutters to himself)
(phone rings)
- Hello?
- Hey Bob, how you doin'?
- Hey, Brian.
Uh, how are you?
- I'm doing fine, Bob.
Hey, I just need the number
for that park ranger guy
that you know.
- Ranger Nick.
Why are you gonna bother him?
- Well, don't worry
about it, Bob.
I just, me and Duane were
out filming some turkeys
and we seen ourselves
a straight up Bigfoot.
- A Bigfoot?
Yeah, okay.
- Yeah, we got the
shit on video, okay?
So ha ha, Bob.
- Yeah, oh yeah, I see Bigfoots
out in my back
yard all the time,
like seven feet tall
some of them are.
- Oh yeah, you ever seen
a nine-foot, jackass?
- (sighs) Yeah, okay, um.
So here's his number,
it's 555-7634.
Don't tell him I
gave you this number.
- We'll try, Bob.
Thanks.
- He tried to call
bullshit on you, didn't he?
- Yeah.
He was laughing until I
told him how big it was.
Son of a bitch.
(Duane giggles)
- So what do you got, Paul?
- Well, I can see what it's not.
It's not bear, it's not boar.
And it's not really a primate.
Whatever it is, it
gashed itself pretty good
because there's
traces of blood here.
- Look.
I gotta tell you something,
but you gotta promise to
keep it private, okay?
A few hours ago, I
was investigating
an accident, right?
A woman had wrecked her car.
And get this.
She told me the reason
why she wrecked was
because a big, hairy creature
jumped in front of her car.
- And?
- I didn't think much of it.
I thought she was kind of nuts.
So I got in my car,
I was going over
and checking another
scene, you know,
the missing Jones boy,
and, uh,
I saw it too.
Gotta understand something.
This thing was huge.
Okay, it was enormous.
It were covered in hair,
too, like wool or something,
it jumped right out
in front of my car.
And it took off at
tremendous speed.
- And you found this
sample in that area?
- Yeah!
Listen, Paul, I know what
I saw, okay, I know it.
I know it sounds totally
crazy, like, (stutters)
I can't even believe it myself.
But I think we may have
a Bigfoot on our hands.
Or something like it.
- We might.
You know, I have an
old friend of mine,
was very experienced in
incidences like this.
He knows what that smell means.
- Okay, great, could
you call him even now?
- He lives about
100 miles from here.
He'll be here in an hour
when I call him with
this information.
We just have to keep
it on the down low.
- No doubt.
- I'll get right on it.
- Okay, thanks, buddy.
(phone rings)
- Ranger Nick Thomas.
- Hey, hi, my name
is Brian Johnson.
I'm a friend of Bob Wilkes.
- (laughs) How is
old Bob nowadays?
- Oh, he's doing fine, sir.
Hey, listen, the reason
why I'm calling is,
me and my partner, we see a
really, really weird thing
up on the, in the Hawking
Hills area this morning.
- Okay.
What exactly did you see?
- Well, I'm just gonna give
it to you straight, ranger.
We seen a Bigfoot.
- A Bigfoot?
- It might sound a little crazy.
But the fact is,
we got it on video.
Me and my partner Duane have it.
- All right, first things first.
Where exactly did you see this?
It's only about a mile
up on Happy Hollow Road.
- Okay.
You know, I'm actually not
that far from that spot.
How about you meet me
at the intersection
of 56 and Happy Hollow Road
in, say, 15, 20 minutes?
- You've got it, man.
- All right, I
will see you there.
- Boom!
(both yell over each other)
Very dangerous, very dangerous.
Drive, drive without passing.
Please, go.
- Hey, thanks for
meeting me, guys.
Ranger Nick Thomas.
- How ya doing, man?
- Duane.
- So, uh, area's right up there.
Are you ready to go?
- Yeah, let's do it.
(gun safeties click)
Who, uh,
we're not gonna
need those, are we?
- When you see the size of
this thing, you'll understand.
- Okay, well, why don't
you show me the footage
and then I'll understand.
- Well, we kinda
figured it'd be best
to take you to the actual place.
That way you can get
an idea how big it is.
- All right, fair enough.
Let's go.
All right, so which
one of these trails
are we gonna be taking here?
- Well, we ain't going that way,
'cause that's where
the Bigfoot went.
We'll go up this way.
- Sure, boss, come on.
- [Duane] After you.
- You guys ever hunted
in this area before?
- Yeah, I have.
- Who owns this land?
- Old man Turner.
He's my dad's friend.
(creature huffs)
(sniffs)
(huffs and grunts)
This is it.
- This is where you saw it?
- Yep, this is it.
Tell him, Duane.
- Well, we were
setting up right here,
and he was right down there.
- Can I see the footage now?
- Well, sure.
- Go ahead.
- All right.
That's the trigger right there?
- Right there.
- Oh my God.
That thing is huge!
- Thank you.
- [Duane] No, it's
monstrous huge.
- Let's go down to that tree.
- All right, I guess
I'm not scared.
- I mean, look at this.
Its arms are lower
than its knees.
This thing is not human.
- It's all right there, bro.
- All right, I'm
looking at this tree.
If we're at standing, this
thing's almost nine feet tall.
- So who do we call?
CNN? Ghostbusters?
- Let's take it easy here, man.
This is huge.
- Life is different
from hereon out, bro.
It's like alien contact.
- So it started
walking this way.
- [Duane] It's a good thing we
got out of here when we did.
- It was definitely
heading in your direction.
- So you had sightings like
this reported before, huh?
- Yeah, all the time.
But it's normally pretty hokey.
This is different.
We've got proof.
This is incredible.
- So much for turkey
hunting videos, huh?
- Francis Coppola says
film is a series of
brilliant accidents.
- Accidents, whatever,
brilliant or not,
you guys, this thing
does look aggressive.
I'm just, I'm glad
nobody got hurt.
(twig cracks)
- Holy shit, did you hear that?
- Hold on, you guys,
just hold on a sec.
Don't go shooting.
That brush is thick.
Just everybody relax.
- Oh, oh!
(shots crack)
Son of a bitch!
- [Duane] I hear that.
- Whoa, wait a minute.
Oh, you guys, look at this.
- [Brian] Wow.
- You know, that
is a foot print.
About 20 inches
long, 10 inches wide.
- I thought I had big feet.
- Yeah, the more
I think about it,
I'm convinced this
thing is dangerous.
We should get out of here.
I got a couple
calls I gotta make.
- [Brian] Heck, yeah.
- Brian, are you comfortable
with me holding on
to this footage
for a little bit?
- Tell you what, man.
I'm gonna keep the original,
I'll give you a copy.
- Okay, but seriously, you guys,
we gotta keep this on lockdown.
Don't be putting it on TMZ,
don't go on YouTube with it.
- No, man, I'm
calling Gloria Allred.
This shit's serious.
(Nick huffs)
- Yeah, this is my
retirement, man.
- Let's go, guys.
(knocking)
- There's no birthday
party for me here.
- Hey, I'm glad you could come.
- Hey, good to see you, man.
How you doing?
- Well.
This is very fresh,
like last night.
- (sniffs) Ho!
- Yeah.
- Where'd you get this?
- Tom found it.
Let me see if he's still here.
- Tired of sitting in my
chair, like, flipping buggers,
you know what I mean?
- [Duane] I'm hip with that.
- My future's bright!
- Boom!
- Yes!
(knocking)
- [Woman] Come to this
goddamn door, Duane!
Open it or I'll beat your ass!
- I don't have to take that.
(bangs on door)
- [Woman] Open this door!
- I'm busy.
- [Woman] I don't care if
you're walking on the damn moon!
I need my smokes and
my lady products.
- You ain't gonna believe
what's about to happen, Betty!
- [Betty] Shut the
fuck up, Brian!
- You better pack for L.A.
- [Betty] Duane,
I'm warning you.
- I hear you, Baby, I hear you.
- You'll see, Betty.
- [Betty] Shut up, crack head.
- Hey, I'm sober.
I might drink a beer
every now and then,
snort a little
Klonopin, but not like,
you know, (vocalizes buzzing).
- And here we go.
- Yes, yes! All right.
We got the original in--
- The place.
- The place, hell yeah,
full Shawshank, bitch.
Worst case scenario?
- We meet in the place.
Yes!
- Okay.
- Follow me.
- I'll follow you.
Listen, we'll get my truck
at the end of the driveway.
You got the camera.
- I got the.
- Before we go out, you look
right, I'm gonna look left.
I think we're safe.
- Let's do it.
- I see you, motherfuckers!
- [Brian] She's a
scary son of a bitch!
She scares me more than Bigfoot.
- [Duane] You ain't
married to her!
- [Brian] God, I love this shit.
I'm so in my fricking element.
- I hear ya.
- [Brian] Who needs drugs?
- Yeah.
- [Brian] Crack is whack.
- Holy shit, look out!
(both scream)
(creature roars)
(both yell)
(creature growls)
- [Brian] Grab your shotgun.
- Doggone, I got no shotgun.
- [Brian] It's behind
your seat, you fool.
Shoot that bitch!
- It, it's gone.
- [Brian] Shit, it's gone.
Thing's a hairy ghost, man.
- Why don't we,
we take the long way into town?
- [Brian] I heard that.
I'll turn this thing around.
- All right, I basically just
moved the reservation
back an hour.
No, everything, no,
everything's fine.
No, I appreciate you
being so flexible.
Um, you know what?
I gotta get going here.
No, tonight's gonna be awesome.
All right, I love you, too.
Bye.
- [Brian] Ooh, shit is
getting thick, ranger.
- Why, what happened?
Did somebody contact you?
- Somebody needs to call
the fucking Air Force, man!
- We saw the thing again.
And we think the
thing is chasing us.
- All right, calm down,
everybody just calm down.
Where's the video?
Do you have it?
- Go ahead, Duane.
Take the whole camera, man.
Analyze it all you want.
We got the original
copy sequestered.
So anybody starts any
shit about who owns what,
everybody can suck my ass.
- We'll see you in court.
- Um, this is a digital chip.
- So what?
It ain't the golden chalice,
brother, don't worry.
- Uh, my point is,
it doesn't matter
where you hid the original.
That's not how the
technology works.
- You know what, ranger?
This whole thing is frankly
fucking above you, dude.
We should have gone
straight to the damn FBI.
I mean, come on,
you wear shorts.
- I was in the Army
for five years.
I could kick your ass.
- Well, wrong on me, then.
I was a drug addict
and I could not serve.
- (sighs) One day, guys.
All I'm asking for is one day.
I just don't want
the whole county
going up in hysteria.
You know, after that, you can do
whatever you want
with the footage.
- Yeah, well, what
about the son of a bitch
that's chasing me right now?
- Us.
- You guys, I gotta get
some work done here.
- I must be speaking
in gibberish.
- The thing is out there, man.
- All right, we need to do
things one step at a time.
(Brian sighs)
Right now, the step
I need you to take
is to please leave.
- Yeah, right.
- Out.
(Brian mutters to himself)
- I'm Joe Hicks.
I'm here to pick
up the survey maps
for the Hicks estate.
- Are you John Hicks' brother?
- Yeah.
- Police department,
may I help you?
- Hello, officer.
Yeah, this is Ranger Nick Thomas
from Lake National Forest.
I, uh, I think we've
got a problem here.
- Okay, what might
your problem be, sir?
- Well, I got a call earlier
from a few turkey hunters,
and they've got
some video footage
of what they think
to be a Bigfoot.
- Really, a Bigfoot?
First off, Mr. Thomas, isn't
it, say, a little crazy?
- Well, consider
this a curtesy call
because I do believe that
this thing is aggressive
and it's in the area.
- Now, did you see this Bigfoot,
or did some cracked out
crack head tell you about it?
- Sir, I think you should
be taking this call
a little bit more seriously.
- Oh yeah, why is
that, Mr. Ranger?
You gonna call my Chief?
- Hey Paul, you
needed to see me?
- Oh, Tom, this is the friend
I was telling you about,
the expert in the field.
- Tom Benson.
- Hank Fletcher, good to see ya.
So you're the one
that saw this, huh?
- Yes, sir.
- Why don't you
tell me about it?
- Uh, well, (sighs)
I was investigating a woman
who drove off the road.
So I thought drunk driving.
But now, she drove off the road
because she saw a
giant hairy Bigfoot.
- Because we don't know
what this thing is,
what it's capable of
doing, or what it wants.
- Answer me this.
How do you know that it is
not someone in a costume?
- It's too damn big to
be a guy in a costume.
- It's just down here,
follow me, please.
I wanna thank you, first of all,
for coming in on
such short notice.
- No, it's my pleasure.
I'm excited about this.
- You instituted a (mumbles)?
- [Hank] Yeah.
- Yeah, so the first location
I wanna take you
to is real close.
- Good, sooner the better.
- Okay, enough is enough!
No more of this Bigfoot crap!
- Excuse me.
Sergeant.
Who're you talking to?
- It's only a park ranger
who claims, get this,
there's a Bigfoot on
the loose. (scoffs)
- Give me that phone, please.
Gimme that!
This is Detective
Benson, who is this?
Uh-huh.
Okay, hang on, slow
down, slow down.
Where are you?
Uh-huh.
I know exactly where that is.
Can you stay put for 15 minutes?
I'll be right there.
You're getting on my bad side.
- [Woman] Are we still
picking everyone else up?
- [Man] No, we're just
gonna meet them there.
- [Woman] You're gonna
love this place, Claudia.
There are so many
cute boys there.
- [Young woman] (chuckles)
Frankie, Steph said
you're hooking me up
with one of your
friends, though, right?
- [Woman] Wait, what, Steph?
- [Frankie] Yeah,
I hooked her up.
- [Claudia] Come on, Frankie,
you hook Susan up and not me?
I love you, too.
- [Frankie] Sorry, Claudia,
but there's gonna be
other guys there,
don't worry about it.
- [Claudia] Yeah,
you better hope so.
- What the hell is this?
- (sighs) What the?
- Looks like someone drug
it here or something.
- [Woman] Yeah, it does.
- Hey.
- Shit.
- Sorry.
- Was just looking at
what you're looking at.
- I don't know.
It's fine, I just don't
get why I'm so jumpy.
- What's up, guys?
- Just looking around.
We should help.
- Yeah, we need help
moving this tree.
- [Woman] Okay.
(twig snaps)
- You guys hear that?
- Yeah, I heard it.
- Damn, dude, you scared
the shit out of me.
- What are you all doing?
- We heard a noise and
we're checking it out.
- Oh man, let's just move
this tree and get out of here.
- [Man] What's up, guys?!
(girl squeals)
- Oh my God!
- You scared the shit out of me.
(girl laughs)
- Sorry, bro, just having fun.
- [Man In Blue
Shirt] Yeah, funny.
- It's good to see you, man.
- Yeah, you too.
You put this tree here?
- Yeah, had to get you to
stop somehow, didn't I?
- All right, can
we please move this
and just get out of here?
- [Man In Gray Shirt] All
right, you're the boss.
- [Woman] One, two, three, now.
- Thanks for meeting me, guys.
Ranger Nick Thomas.
- Tom Benson, this
is Hank Fletcher.
- It's nice to meet you.
What do you got?
- All right, well,
earlier today I got a call
from a couple turkey hunters
out in the Hawking Hills area.
Now they're doing
a documentary film,
and they came across what
they believe to be a Bigfoot.
So I went out, checked
everything out,
and saw the location
of the sighting.
And get this, they got a video.
- Where can we see this video?
- Got it right in the truck.
Let's go.
- God, look at the
size of that thing.
It's gotta be eight feet.
- Nine, and a beauty.
- Yeah, I was right
there at that tree.
We're looking at nine feet.
There's also a footprint
about 20 inches long.
- I say we go check out
the footprint right now.
- Nick, you tell anybody else?
- No, just called your office
and talked to Sergeant Moody.
- Oh God, what'd he say?
- (scoffs) More like
Sergeant Asshole.
Told me I was crazy, said the
guys are probably on drugs.
Very unprofessional.
- He's not exactly
Mr. Popularity.
The other day I was dealing
with a missing child case--
- Wait, wait.
You say there's a missing child?
- Yeah, what about it?
- This is just a
hunch, all right?
But just maybe this missing kid
and our Sasquatch are connected.
- How do you figure?
- [Hank] Humans and primates
share 96% of their DNA code.
It's the most of
any other mammal.
There been actual cases
where human children
have been raised by primates.
Most recently, the
feral child of Borneo
and the Nigerian chimp boy.
Maybe the Sasquatch
abducted this kid
to raise it as one of
their own for some reason.
I don't know, but
it's just a guess.
And I say we should
go check the area.
- Well, now, search and
rescue is still there,
searching for the kid.
- Great.
If it did take him,
maybe we'll find him.
- Let's take my truck, just
in case we got to off road.
- I'll get a couple of
walkies and a shotgun.
- All right, pilgrim.
- Hey.
(people muttering)
- I'm glad to see you
made it, little brother.
- Hey, how you doing?
- Another day in paradise.
- You still (mumbles)
like Rambo up here?
- Always running
your mouth, smartass.
But yeah, little
bit of Rambo here.
- [Woman] Wait, I don't think
that's the one I'm looking for.
- I mean--
- I'm hypnotizing you.
- I mean, you could
be tantalizing.
If that's--
- Ooh!
(man chuckles)
- Is it cool?
- Aren't there more
people than this?
- Yeah, but there's a concert
or something going on in town.
It's supposed to be
a pretty big thing.
But I mean, we got
enough people anyways.
We'll be fine.
Where's Steph?
- Uh, she forgot her cell
phone back in the car.
She'll be back in a second.
She's walking to the car.
Dude!
- What's up, brother?
Hey, so, which one's my date?
- [Man] Oh, you see brown
haired girl over there?
- You serious?
- Fuck yeah, man.
(both chuckle)
- Oh. So who's the blond girl?
- Oh, that's Steph's
friend Claudia.
(mumbles) I'm gonna
get them over.
Hey guys, you come here.
Check this out.
- Hello.
Hi, I'm Terry.
- Susan.
Nice to meet you, Terry.
- Likewise, Susan.
So you wanna go sit down?
- Sure.
(chuckles)
- Anything to see around here?
- The trail you
guys just came up
is the only one in and
out of the parking lot.
Every other trail will
take you to a dead end
or it twists and turns.
So I wouldn't go on a walk
by yourself or anything.
But yeah, that's basically
the main in and out trail.
- Seriously?
- Yeah.
I mean, it's nice out here.
Just not much to see.
You know?
- Stevens wrecked
right over there,
and I saw the Bigfoot
probably right about there.
- Little kid's sneaker.
- That could have
come from anybody.
- Could be.
How many little kids'
sneakers you know
have a long, thick
hair attached to it
that smells like shit?
- Probably not too many.
- [Nick] Not too many.
- Looks like he
went through here.
I'm gonna follow this trail up,
see what else I can find.
- Hank, it might be
a little dangerous.
(gun clicks)
- [Hank] I'll be fine.
- Hank!
Do yourself a favor.
Take that.
- Thanks.
Talk to you in a bit.
- You got it.
(grunts softly)
(creature grunts)
(creature grunts loudly)
(creature roars)
(creature huffs)
(creature growls)
(dramatic music)
- Oh, shit!
(creature roars)
(creature growls)
(creature huffs softly)
(suspenseful music)
- Holy shit!
Benson, this is Hank.
I'm about a mile
up the trail here,
and I just came
across a dead guy
hanging about 10
feet up in a tree
with a branch through his chest.
- [Tom Through Phone] Me
and Nick are on our way.
(creature grunts softly)
(creature grunts agitatedly)
(creature grunts sadly)
- Hank, what you got?
- Right there.
- God.
- Yeah, that's John.
- You know that guy?
- Yeah.
- I gotta go back to the car,
go call his wife.
- I'm gonna follow this trail,
see where this end goes.
- All right, I'll
just stay here.
(door clatters)
(raps sharply on door)
- Can I help you?
(Tommy sobs softly)
What happened?
- I was taken by a big creature
from my house last night,
and I just got away.
- Your name Tommy Jones?
- Yes, sir.
How did you know?
- You're all over
the news, sonny.
Come on in here.
Now, let's come on in here.
We gotta get ahold
of some folks.
I know they're
gonna be real happy
to know that you're okay.
I'll bet you're really hungry.
Sit down here and have a seat.
We'll get you something
to eat in a minute.
I gotta make a call.
Yes, ma'am, my
name is Dan Jones.
That boy that's been missing,
well, he just showed up at
church on Brewer Boulevard.
All right, thank you.
Okay, buddy, they're sending
somebody over here right now,
pick you up, take you home.
- Thanks, could I call my mom?
I'm sure she's awful
worried about me.
- You sure can.
Come on over here and
let's make that call.
(indistinct chattering)
(leaves rustling)
- Hey, whoa, whoa.
Did you guys hear that?
- Yeah, I heard something.
(rustling)
(girl speaks indistinctly)
- Hell with it, I'll
go see what it is.
Anybody wanna come with me?
How about you, sweetheart?
- [Man] Screw that shit.
- Wuss.
Frankie, come on.
(tense, suspenseful music)
(boy roars)
(laughs)
- Dude, that's some
fucking funny shit, right?
- No, you're a fucking asshole.
- Hey dude, that
was fucking funny,
shut the fuck up.
(boys talk over each other)
(boys laugh)
Where are you guys going?
- Oh, we're just gonna
take a little walk.
- All right.
- Watch out for the grass man!
- Yeah?
- [Man] Yeah, I'll do that.
- So do you wanna
go for a walk, too?
- Where?
- I don't know,
maybe somewhere a little
more private, I guess.
- Sure.
- You guys heading out?
- Yeah.
Beautiful night for a walk.
- [Susan] Steph, do you
and Frankie wanna come too?
- Yeah--
- I think we're actually
just gonna hang here.
All right, babe.
- Yeah, just go on,
have a nice walk.
- [Susan] See you guys later.
- Why did you do that?
That was so mean?
- What?
Give them some time to
get to know each other.
- Yeah, I'm sure that's why.
- Well, it is.
- Yeah, whatever, Frankie.
- Sure are a lot of
cars out here tonight.
- Yeah, this event
does well every year.
I used to come here
when I was a kid.
- They ever give
you any trouble?
- These kids? No.
They're all good kids.
- It's awfully quiet.
Little too quiet.
- Yeah.
Well, let's just hang out
here just a little bit longer.
See what happens.
- Wanna sit here and
talk a little more?
- Sure, why not?
- Do you mind if I kiss you?
- Sure.
(smooching and sighing)
You're a good kisser, Gary.
- You're not so bad
yourself, Susan.
(Susan mumbles softly)
(both chuckle softly)
Do you wanna do something else?
- I thought you'd never ask.
(both pant)
Wait, did you hear that?
- Hear what?
- What was that sound?
- It's probably just
animals or something.
- There's animals out here?
- Yeah, just nothing
that can hurt you.
- Okay, sounds like whatever
it is is gone anyway.
- Good.
Now, where were we?
- We were right about here?
(deep breathing)
Wait, what is that smell?
- Whoa, I don't know.
Oh!
(Susan gags and coughs)
- So, was it you?
- (chuckles) It was you.
(creature growls)
(screams)
(Susan gags and coughs)
- That sounded like Susan.
- Uh, Terry probably
jumped out and scared her.
Look, it's nothing
to worry about, babe.
- I don't know, that scream
sounded really weird.
(creature huffs)
- You hear that?
- I sure did.
- Yeah.
Come on, guys, let's go.
- Go!
(creature huffs softly)
- Ew, what is that smell?
- Oh!
I don't know what that smell is.
(creature huffs softly)
Liz?
Get ready to run.
- What is it?
- Just get ready.
(exiting rock music)
(creature growls)
(Liz screams)
(creature roars)
(creature huffs)
(creature grunts and growls)
Whoa, shit!
- [Liz] No, please no!
(creature roars)
- Police department!
- [Boy] Watch out, there's
a Bigfoot over there!
- [Girl] My God, what do I do?
(creature roars)
(shots blast)
(creature grunts)
(groans)
- Nick, are you okay?
- [Nick] Son of a
bitch! (mutters)
- You guys, you gotta get me
some duct tape or some sticks,
(Nick groans)
rags, something like that.
Go, quick, quick, quick, quick.
- Here.
- Now get me some
sticks, come on!
Don't stand there.
(tape rips)
- Here you go, sir.
- Here you go.
All right, Nick.
I'm gonna set your leg.
I'm not gonna lie to you.
It's gonna hurt
like a bitch, okay?
- Yeah.
- All right, here we go.
(Nick groans)
Sorry about that, buddy.
Hang on.
(Nick groans)
Here we go.
That's good.
That's done.
(creature huffs)
(creature roars)
- It's back, guys.
- All right,
everybody, stay calm.
Nick, I gotta call this in.
Where's the radio?
- I must have dropped
it when it threw me.
- Damn, Elwood.
- I don't hear any more.
- No, it's just toying with us.
- Hey, how many
kids are up here?
- Uh, 10, but four
are still missing.
- Can't worry about
that right now.
The creature's out here and
it's not going anywhere.
I haven't been up on
this hill for years.
Does anybody know if there's
another way off this hill?
- No, just the path
you all came up.
Terry knows other ways,
but we can't find him.
(exhales sharply)
- I guess we're just gonna
have to find a way
with that path.
(creature huffs)
- I do know one thing for sure.
Something really
pissed that thing off,
for it to go after
humans like this.
It's like it's on a vendetta.
- How long ago did
it attack you guys?
- Not a long time ago.
About an hour ago.
- Did you get a good
hit when you shot it?
- I definitely hit it once.
Might have missed
the other times.
- If it's wounded, we'll
definitely have a better chance
of getting out of here alive.
But you guys saw that
thing, it's huge.
- All right, guys, everybody
try and stay calm, okay?
The less frantic, the better.
Just stay cool.
We'll all get off
this hill alive.
- Sounds good to me.
- Nick, you okay to do this?
- Time to find out.
- Couple of you guys help
the ranger down the hill?
- Yeah, no problem.
Come on, Char.
(Nick grunts)
Sorry, sir.
- [Nick] No, that's all right.
Thanks for the help.
- [Boy] Let's do it.
(creature roars, kids scream)
(creature huffs)
(Nick groans)
- That's the way.
Yeah, right there.
You okay, man?
- No, I'm not okay, but hey,
Jimmy, do you have a cell phone?
- Yeah, yeah.
Here.
Hey, I'm gonna go check
on the rest of 'em,
make sure they're all right.
- Yeah, be careful.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, dispatch, this
is Ranger Nick Thomas.
I'm gonna need some emergency
service vehicles sent
up to the Buck Doll Hill
camp-out parking lot.
If we can get those on the fly.
- What is the state
of emergency, sir?
- My colleagues and I were
attacked by a Bigfoot.
- Did you say a Bigfoot?
Are you sure?
- I know.
Just please, we need
an ambulance here ASAP.
- Sir, they're on their way.
I told the authorities
to use caution.
Can I ask who your
colleagues are?
- Um, yeah, we've got
a Bigfoot researcher
and a detective.
- (sighs) Oh no, Tom.
- You know Detective Benson?
- Yes, I do.
Is he okay?
- As of right now.
I don't know.
Okay, please keep me
informed, Ranger Thomas.
- No problem.
(sighs)
(suspenseful music)
- What do you think
our next move is?
- I don't know, I'm thinking.
- [Dispatch] Unit 312 central,
we have a report of some
type of animal attack
near the old gym
on Buck Doll Hill
with multiple fatalities.
- We gotta get over there.
- You're darn tootin'.
- Shit.
- Yeah, hey Marilynn.
Babe, I'm sorry about tonight.
No, everything's fine.
No, you wouldn't
even believe it.
But yeah, I'm up by the
camp-out parking lot
up near Buck Doll Hill.
No, don't come up here, we've
got this all taken care of.
But I'm sorry about the.
No.
Hey, I gotta talk to you.
Let me give you a
call back later.
Bye.
(creature growls and huffs)
- Ranger!
Hey, we heard on the radio.
Are you okay?
- Dang, ranger,
your leg is jacked.
- It's fucking broke, man.
- They say we're going live mic.
All right, what the heck?
Going live in five, four, three,
(huffs) two.
Good evening.
Action News reporter Steve
Darnell reporting live
from what is rumored to
be a scene of horrors.
I'm in normally tranquil
Buckland, just off Highway 83.
If what sources are
reporting is true,
it is a scene of gargantuan
animal violence and murder.
- Holy moly.
Man, you're, (stutters)
you're drooling, man.
- Come on, you guys,
that's my girlfriend.
- Excuse me, sir.
Can you tell me
what's going on here?
- No, come on, man.
I'm dealing with this.
Hey, you wanna know
something about the Bigfoot,
talk to those guys.
Not me, them.
- Right, thank you so much.
- Sir, hi, can't seem
to grab a sheriff
or a law enforcement.
Can you tell me
what's going on here?
- Yeah, uh--
- Let me, let me talk to you.
Hi, yes, my name
is Brian Johnson
and this is my business
partner Duane McCoy.
First of all, I wanna offer
prayers and condolences
to the families of all those
who've lost their lives.
We have people up here who've
literally been torn to bits.
- Torn to bits.
By what, did they say?
- Uh, that would be by
Bigfoot, sir, the Bigfoot.
Possible even Bigfeet,
I kid you not.
- We got it on film,
secretly hidden away.
- Goddamn, Duane, you old turd.
- There you have it, folks.
I'm gonna try to get closer
to speak to one of
the first responders
or hopefully law enforcement
as we are live on scene.
- Actually, we were
first on scene, sir.
First to see the thing
and first to capture
the beast on film.
- Wait a minute.
Why are you talking
to these losers?
- Hey, get the fuck out of here.
- Go!
- Dumbass!
- Fellas, we can't do that.
No f-bombs, please,
we're live on air.
I am so sorry,
ladies and gentlemen.
- I wanna apologize
for my partner, sir.
He's very sensitive
and protective.
We're actually two
documentary filmmakers.
We have historical footage.
All inquiries call
T-U-R-K-E-Y-S-H-O-T, Turkeyshot.
The area code and phone number
goes directly to our office.
- And our website
is temporary down,
a little bit overloaded.
But it will be updated soon.
- All moneyed inquiries,
call Turkeyshot.
This footage will blow
your fucking mind!
- Okay, all right, thank you.
Thank you.
Officer!
- [Brian] Good job!
- Look, there's the
detective and Hank.
(Hank huffs and grunts softly)
(creature roars)
(second creature roars)
(both creatures roar)
(creature roars)
(creature howls)
(creatures howl and roar)
(up-tempo rock music)