[slow paced techno music]
- Dude, get out of the way!
- [Boy On Bike] Put
down your phone then!
[dog barking]
[dramatic music]
[cabinet door creaking]
[ominous music]
- Hey, call you back?
- [Male] Morning.
- [Woman] Good morning.
- Hey buddy.
- Hey.
- You get your homework done?
- Yes.
- Good.
You make it a great day.
- [Boy] All right.
- Oh.
[tires screeching]
[car crashing]
[ominous music]
[slow eerie music]
- Hey!
Good morning sir.
You're early.
- [Male] Yeah.
- I'm getting ready to make
some coffee, you want some?
- No thank you.
- I'll be in my office
if you need anything.
Moody this morning.
Sir.
- [Male] Yeah?
- We're having a service
Friday night at the church.
Thought it'd be a good idea--
- I know all about it.
I know all about it.
I'm one of the members.
- Care to join us?
[male exhales sharply]
- I don't know.
I'll think about it.
- [Woman] I'll just
leave this here,
just in case you
do decide to come.
[egg sizzling]
[solemn music]
- John!
John!
John.
Johnny?
John!
Johnny!
John?
John!
Johnny!
[door knocking]
- You think I didn't see
you hiding behind my door?
What's going on?
- I was just trying
to see if you
had a chance to
look at the flyer.
- I did.
And chances are I'm
not gonna make it.
- You sure?
- [Male] Yeah.
- But, I just--
[phone ringing]
You serious?
Yeah.
Are you, okay bye.
Johnny's missing.
- Johnny's missing?
Jake's Johnny?
- [Woman] Yeah, I'll go
ahead and call the watch team
so they could start looking--
- No, no, no, no, no.
- We'll just gather
all the information
and we'll deal with it if
the police need our help.
- [Woman] You wanna wait?
- Yeah.
- Why?
- Because it's
Father's Day weekend.
- Are you okay?
This is what we
do, it's our job.
We're the Community Ministry!
- Yeah, well
whatever that means,
why don't you just
pray about it.
[slow paced music]
[rushing winds]
- Enjoying your
morning wine again?
[door creaking]
Drunk.
[phone buzzing]
- Hello.
- Mom.
Johnny's missing.
- Did you call the police?
- Yes.
- Do you think he ran away?
- [Woman] I don't know.
- I probably shouldn't say this,
but I mean, I hope
he's all right,
but this is probably a sign.
- What is that supposed to mean?
- I told you and Jake
not to adopt a black boy.
They need to be
with their own kind.
You think he doesn't see that?
- I'm not doing this right now.
- Your husband died
and you're left
to raise him all alone.
- Race has nothing
to do with it!
Hateful people make it that way!
I called you to let you know
your grandson is missing!
Bye!
- Grandson.
You taught her,
she's just like you.
She never listens
to a word I say.
[door knocking]
- We came over as
soon as we heard.
You okay?
- Not at all.
- [Male] It's good
to see you Wendy.
- Good to see you too.
- I haven't been
here in a while.
- I talked to my mom,
and she just made things worse.
- Let's just focus on
John, 'cause your mom...
- [Male] Yeah, is it okay
if I searched the place?
Look for forced entry?
- Yes.
- Are there any leads
on where he might be?
- I have no idea.
I'm not even sure
he left on his own.
- Have you talked to the
school or any of his friends?
- I called, he's not at school.
The principal talked
to the classmates
and nobody has seen him.
- Do you mind if
we pray for you?
- Okay, thanks.
No sign of forced entry.
I spoke with the police.
Because it hasn't
been 24 hours yet
there's nothing they
can do until then.
- 24 hours?
Somebody could have taken
him across country by then.
- Look, I have some of
my friends on the force
looking for John while
they're on patrol.
And I also called
the Help Center.
- You mean the community
group at that church?
- At least we have
someone looking with us.
- We just can't sit here
and hope that they find him.
- Let's just calm down.
We can think better-
- Calm down?
I lost my husband.
And now I'm ab out
to lost my son.
You have yours.
I waited until I was
married to have children.
Trying to be obedient.
Nobody does that anymore.
[slow paced music]
I thought the Lord
would honor it.
And instead he
took Jake from me.
A couple of years
before Jake passed,
we found out we
couldn't have children.
That's why we decided to adopt.
As soon as life
starts to act right,
Jake passes,
and now this.
I don't think I can
believe in God anymore.
God wouldn't give people
more than they can bare.
- And we know that
those who love God,
all things work for good
for those who are called
according to His purpose.
[birds chirping]
[ominous music]
- Yeah, there's this
super hot guy here.
He has so many
tattoos on his arm.
But he has that one
piercing on his nose.
Oh it's so hot.
My Mom hates when they
have nose piercings.
Hold on, my Mom's calling.
Yes Mom.
I'm on the way okay.
Yes.
I was on the phone.
Wait Mom, Mom, Mom.
Can I use the car later?
[door knocking]
- Judy!
Judy.
I just got a call.
- [Judy] Okay.
I get those every day.
- Did you tell some people
to go look for Johnny?
- [Judy] I'm busy.
- I asked you to wait Judy.
What if we have an
emergency we can't fulfill?
It's Father's Day weekend
and we're short of help.
- I'm not gonna sit around
and wait for another emergency
when we have one right now.
- [Male] What if he's not lost?
Huh?
What if he's at a friends
house or something?
- Exactly.
You don't know where he is.
That's why we
prepare for the worst
and expect the best.
- [Male] Judy come on.
- What is wrong with you?
This isn't you.
I figured after what
happened to Lily
you would be the first person
to wanna find
somebody else's child.
You were born and
raised in a church.
Do you believe this
is what God wants?
- [Male] I don't
even believe in God.
- I said "Do you believe this is
"what God wants from you?"
- Are you listening to me?
I said "I don't even
believe in God!"
- How?
You work at a church.
- So what?
'Cause I work at a
church doesn't mean
I have to believe in God.
I need a paycheck!
- [Judy] What?
- When I was coming up,
I didn't have
choice of religion,
it was given to me.
And as a kid, I couldn't
ask any questions.
- You were just being curious.
- No, no, no.
You try telling that
to my Aunt Nessa.
You question anything
in the Bible,
she find the biggest,
thickest Bible she could
and she hit you it right
in the back of your head.
And I didn't realize
until I got older
that she was afraid.
Look, I never believed in God,
I never embraced any of it.
I mean I took communion,
I got baptized.
I went to confession.
I was just faking it.
I don't believe Jesus died
on the cross for my sins.
Especially no one
as crazy as I was.
But
after Lily died,
I just stopped
believing all together.
I didn't think He was real.
Why would He do that?
- Because He loves you.
- If He loved her why
did He let her die?
Why did He let my baby die?
I mean it wasn't her fault.
I didn't take care of my health.
And if he loved her
why did He do that?
She didn't deserve it.
I was driving
and I passed out
and I was wrong
and she had to pay for it.
It's not love.
That's why I don't
believe in God no more.
I don't believe it.
[solemn music]
Oh my God, this is crazy.
When did you know
you were a Christian?
I asked you a question.
It's a simple answer.
When did you know
you were a Christian?
- [Judy] When Jesus died
on the cross for my sins.
- No, no, no, no, no.
I'm not asking you when
you knew you were saved,
I'm asking you to tell me,
when did you know that
you were a Christian?
The moment.
The second, hour, the minute
that you knew what
you believe now.
When did you know
you were a Christian?
[somber music]
- [Woman] Lord, can
you hear me though?
A long time ago I stopped
believing Your reports.
Through Your son Christ
all things were possible,
and that I simply believe.
I believed every word You said.
After all, You're the same God
that raised Lazarus
from the dead.
He that wants some more,
so I got a question,
why did you save him
and not my daughter.
This is not divine order.
I wasn't supposed to bury her,
she's supposed to bury me now.
What in the world
do you want from me?
What do you mean that the
faith of a mustard seed?
It was your mountain
that fell down on me.
Left to die and the
rumble can't see
to get from under my humbles.
You never believed in me
til you see miraculous
signs and wonders.
I wonder, I wonder
was all that you could
claim even real.
When she touched the hem of
your garment was she healed?
What miracles did
you perform for Paul?
How did five loaves and
two fish feed all of y'all?
That water into wine,
they had to be lying.
Babies birthed by old
women and virgins,
Jonah in the whale,
Daniel in the den,
okay then, really.
See up until now I
never questioned you.
But the prayers of the
righteous did you even hear?
I begged to switch places.
She was just a baby.
Jesus was supposed to take
the will in an instant
my lifeline was killed.
Awake me from this dream,
this can't be real.
Devil on duty,
lie, destroy, kill.
Mission accomplished
I'm all out of options,
I can't face the odds.
The Lord said, "Let
go, and let God."
- Do you ever feel like
if you prayed hard enough,
certain things wouldn't happen?
- I never thought
about it like that,
but I know what you mean.
God's not punishing you
for not praying enough.
- It feels like it.
Or either He just isn't there.
- What?
- I just feel like
prayer doesn't work.
If it did, why are all these
things happening to me?
- Remember when was asked
why the blind man was blind?
He said "So that God
may get the glory."
Let God get the glory on this.
- So what do we do now?
- Why don't we go inside
and see if there might
be a clue as to where
he might have went?
Yeah, come on.
- [Wendy] No, no, no.
No, no, that's not
his room anymore.
It's this way, come on.
This way.
Why is this missing?
- [Woman] What is it?
- [Wendy] John's knife.
- You okay?
- Jake bought John this knife
as a souvenir from the
Father and Son retreat.
John never took it
out of the case.
- [Friend] What do
you think it means?
- Hopefully it means
he left on his own
and he's coming back.
[slow paced music]
[birds chirping]
- [Male] Come on
John, you can do this.
- [John] Hey!
- Hey.
- [John] Look what
I made at school.
- Wow, that came out great.
- [John] Yeah, I got an A on it.
- I bet you did.
Can I hang on to this?
- [John] Yeah.
- I'll put it up here.
That way, when I roll in a call,
I can think of you.
[ominous music]
- I appreciate your help,
but can you exactly explain
how the program works?
- Okay, so say
your bill is $1,000
and our budget for
that day is 700,
you have to come up
with the other 300
and show us proof
that you can pay it
before we can give
you the other 700.
- Well exactly how fast do
I have to get the money?
- Just as soon as you can.
It's based upon needs,
but I'm sure we can
work something out.
- I understand.
I'll try to come
up with the money.
Thank you, thank you.
- Sorry.
We'll get it figured out.
[door slamming]
- Look,
I just miss her a little.
I miss her so much.
I don't know why God
took Lily from me.
I miss her so much.
- It was a miracle.
- What is a miracle?
- Earlier today you asked me,
"When was the moment,
the second that I
"knew I was a Christian?"
It was when I saw a miracle.
Jesus said in John 4:48,
"Unless I see miracles
in amazing things,
"they will not believe."
Some won't believe until
they see a miracle.
I believe we're so consumed
by the worlds ways that
it hinders our beliefs.
We can't see clearly.
My Mom had cancer.
- [Male] You don't
need to tell me that.
[slow paced music]
- She had cancer.
I prayed for my
Mama day and night.
She wasn't getting any better.
Nothing was helping her.
Then there was this lady,
Miss Grace.
She came to see Mama
and she prayed for her
in a way I had
never seen anybody
pray for somebody.
She was on her knees
praying for her.
A few days later
Mama was healed.
The doctors couldn't explain it.
A few days after
all that I got a
chance to spend some
time with Miss Grace.
I understood why God
answered her prayers
that she was praying for Mama,
she loved Jesus.
I promise you, try loving Him.
Just try.
And you'll see.
He's been loving
you for a long time.
A long time.
[male sniffling]
- Why don't we just pray?
- [Wendy] We need more
than prayer right now.
- The Bible says
pray for all things.
- It's gonna be
getting dark soon.
- You've seen those
trophies in his room?
You know what those mean?
That means he's a winner.
He's gonna be okay.
- But right now we're losing,
and I'm tired of losing.
- Let's do something.
Let's play a board game.
- My kid is either lost,
stolen, or kidnapped,
a board game is the
last thing on my mind.
- I'm just trying to help.
I'm trying to ease your mind.
You don't wanna pray.
- I'll pray whenever
God brings my son back.
Jake's shoes are missing.
No, I mean Jake's
shoes are missing.
Oh my goodness,
what if it was a robber?
Like a petty theft?
- No, no, no, no.
Don't jump to conclusions.
Jamal already checked the house
and there's no forced entry.
Just trust God, God's got this.
- Trust God?
Trust Him?
The one that let my husband die?
The one that let my
child get kidnapped?
I'll trust Him when
He brings my son back.
[birds chirping]
- [Jamal] What's up?
How ya doing buddy?
- Jamal, how are you?
- Not so good.
Not so good.
You know John is missing right?
- Sorry man, I heard.
No sign yet?
- Nothing, nothing.
Look, you got a couple hours,
you can hop in the car
and help me look for him?
- You know, I wish I
could, I really do.
- [Jamal] I really
need your help buddy.
- You know the kids are
gonna pull up any second.
They've been driving all day.
We're gonna hook up,
we're gonna head out.
We've been looking
forward to this trip.
- Father's Day weekend right?
Slim, I really need your help.
- I bet you if I
get on this phone,
make these few phone calls,
we'll get you some help.
- You still got
Wendy's number right?
- [Slim] I've got Wendy's,
I believe I have yours.
- Yeah, mine hasn't changed.
It hasn't changed.
- [Slim] I got it then.
- All right.
All right Slim, if
you hear anything,
please give me a call or
contact Wendy all right?
- [Slim] You got it.
- All right man.
- [Slim] I'll get
on that phone call.
- Thanks.
Happy Father's Day.
- [Slim] Thanks.
[slow paced music]
- Talk to me.
Just keep pushing.
All right.
All right yeah.
Hello?
Tell me something good.
No leads?
We gotta do something.
Wendy's about to
have a breakdown.
All right look, I'm gonna
check a little further out
and then I'm gonna
go back and check on,
yeah, I'm gonna check
on Wendy and Natasha.
All right.
All right, yeah.
[water running]
[pots clanking]
[machine beeping]
- Hello.
Hello.
Are you gonna pay
for your food ma'am
or stand there and
keep loitering?
'Cause we have
customers waiting.
- Looks like
there's nobody here.
- They're coming.
Hey.
For whatever it's worth, listen,
don't let bad habits hold
you back from missing life.
Sometimes you just need
to stop and look up.
Hey, you shorted me two cents!
How in the world she
know how to use a
smartphone and can't even count!
Dang gone millennials!
[woman exhales]
- Nothing?
All right, thanks.
And Happy Father's
Day to you too.
[people chattering]
They said they done
all they can do.
Let's just let the
police handle this.
- I'm going out there by myself.
- Wendy!
It's gonna get dark soon!
[slow paced music]
Everybody had big plans
for Father's Day weekend.
- I'm done.
I lost everything.
Back to what?
I've got to move
out in two weeks.
- [Natasha] Why?
- The house is in foreclosure.
I used up everything to keep it.
- Wendy, why didn't
you say something?
We could of helped you.
Wendy!
Wendy.
Talk to me.
- [Jamal] Baby.
How ya doing Wendy?
- I'm just tired.
Feeling depressed all the time.
- Everything will get better
as soon as everything
gets back to normal.
- Yeah.
- I'm gonna be honest with you,
maybe you should
put up a few things.
I mean, the pictures
that you have of Jake
can be pretty depressing.
You have a photo of
him as your screensaver
on your computer and phone.
You mentioned the
other day that you have
a photo of him on a
dashboard of your car.
You even planning a ceremony
for the day that he died.
Look, I'm not saying
forget about him,
I just think it's
important that we celebrate
the joy of Jakes life.
Immersing yourself in his death
is only gonna make
you more depressed.
You probably don't
even realize it.
- And I agree.
You need surround
yourself with things
that bring you laughter,
joy, and inspiration.
You need to celebrate
his good memories.
And remember, you have
a life to live too.
- Our intake in our
lives is crucial.
Look, people say
we are what we eat.
We're also what we hear and see.
And we gotta be careful
what we allow in our lives.
- Do you mind if
we prayed for you?
- [Jamal] Lord God, the
creator of the earth,
the heavens--
- Dear God, please
bring my son back.
[birds chirping]
[heart beating]
- Okay, take your book bag!
- You stole my drink!
- I was thirsty.
Why are you at my house?
- Your house?
Wait, you live out here?
- [Girl] Yes, why are you here?
- I gotta do something.
[solemn music]
My Dad died here.
I just need to cross the street.
- [Girl] Why?
- I don't know.
I just got to.
What?
- I need to make it
across the street also.
- Why?
- It's a part of
someones destiny.
- Why do you keep staring at me?
- I think we should cross
the street together.
- [John] I don't need you
to cross the street with me.
- I know.
- You can just do
it by yourself.
- No I can't do that.
- Why?
You scared?
- No, I have nothing to
be scared of anymore.
We are brought here for closure.
[eerie music]
♪ Amazing
♪ Grace
♪ How
♪ Sweet
♪ The
♪ Sound
♪ That saved
♪ A wretch
♪ Like me
♪ I once
♪ Was lost
♪ But
♪ Now
♪ I'm found
♪ Was blind
♪ But now
♪ I see
[slow light music]
- I've avoided coming in here.
Because every time I do,
I can't stop crying.
The last time I was in here
was when Jake died.
John would run up the
steps every morning
to watch Jake's car go by.
He would look through
these binoculars,
to watch Jake go to work.
The last time he looked
through the binoculars,
was when the wreck happened.
- [Jamal] Oh my goodness.
- Johnny!
John!
He's at the road!
- We've been
looking 10 miles out
and he's out here
the whole time?
[somber music]
- Lily?
Oh my God.
[male sobbing]
[tires screeching]
- We've been looking
for you all day.
Why didn't you tell
me you were leaving?
- Where is she?
- Who?
- The girl.
Never mind.
[somber music]
[door knocking]
- Finally.
Come on in Gloria,
the door's open.
Where's Wendy?
- Home.
- Does she know you're here?
- No ma'am.
- You ain't got
tired of running yet?
I'm not scared of you.
- I hope not.
I'm your grandson.
Look, I just wanted
to say thank you.
- For what?
- For raising a son that
was willing to adopt me
and love me.
He knew people would
say mean things.
- You're welcome.
- Can I pray for you?
- I definitely don't
want you to pray for me.
It can wait until
church on Sunday.
[slow paced music]
What are you doing?
- [John] Serving.
- I'm sorry I never forgave you
for what you did to me.
- I'll call you back.
- Good morning.
- Hey.
- Hello.
- [Jake] What's up buddy?
Oh hey, you're gonna need these.
Have fun.
What?
Look, I am trying
to move past this.
- I guess that's easy for you.
- Look, we cannot be doing
this in front of Johnny.
- I'm not gonna pretend
like you didn't cheat on me.
I just pray that my
anger towards you
had nothing to do
with the wreck.
- I am sorry!
- [Wendy] That you got caught
or that you hurt me?
- Whatever.
Look, we...
- Don't touch me.
Take your lunch.
Why am I even talking to you?
You're not here.
This is just a
shell in the ground.
I just need to let go
and let God.
[light instrumental music]