[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Hello. He offered what?
You've got to be kidding me.
Just a second.
Hey. I'll tell you what
you can tell him.
Tell him to go
screw himself.
Yeah. Yeah.
Mr. Burrows,
our heat's out again.
-Call the management office.
-I have...
for the past two weeks.
Yeah, I'm back.
It's not a fixer-upper.
It's historic.
All right. Just a second.
I've got a little
problem here. Hold on.
Okay, I'm back.
Why can't you just get me
a damn offer on this building?
Okay.
I'm putting in some lights,
you know, like you said,
make it look
less creepy at night.
Yeah. Okay, bye.
[GRUNTS]
Damn it.
Now I gotta fix that, too.
[WOOD CREAKING]
[MACHINE WHIRRING]
[SCREAMS]
Help! Help! Help me!
Help!
Ahhh!
[GASPS]
MAN: Careful.
[ALL EXCLAIMING]
[FUNKY INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC PLAYING]
[GRUNTS]
[GLASS BREAKING]
Ah!
[MOANING IN PLEASURE]
Tessie. Tessie Swinton,
turn down
that devil music.
[KNOCKING AT DOOR]
Is she at it again?
Elsa Crothers,
I've told you
how many times.
When she goes loca,
crank you your own tunes.
'Cause that's what I do.
Thank you, but
the last thing I need
is advice from
a pervert like you.
Ooh, you hate me
because I'm beautiful?
In my day,
weirdos like you
were locked up.
Oh, and when was that?
The Spanish Inquisition?
You show some respect,
you freak!
[BLOWS KISS]
[GASPS]
-What do you want?
-Do you realize
how loud your music is?
-Leave me alone.
-Leave you alone?
Listen to me, Missy.
You'd better start packing
because I'm going to see to it
that you are out on the street.
You are rude.
You're inconsiderate.
Why can't you be like
your sister?
Just look at you.
[GASPS] Oh!
So, you're actually
identical twins?
Technically, yes.
But I don't think
you'd have any trouble
-telling us apart.
-I'd would've loved
to have had a twin.
Scam the teachers,
that whole bit.
Have you ever,
ever like, try to fool
your parents or anything?
Uh, you know,
I don't really remember.
They died when
I was really young.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Geez. I'm asking
too many questions.
No, it's okay.
Most guys just wanna
talk about themselves.
[EXHALES]
Can I see you again?
How's tomorrow night?
Okay.
But next time I get to ask
all the questions, okay?
Fair enough. Okay.
Good night.
What? Oh, come on.
We're going out. Whoo!
-Let's go, boys.
-[CHUCKLES]
Whoa! Hey, Sarah.
-Hey, guys.
-Hey.
You look fine tonight, baby.
Yeah, everybody looks fine
after a six pack.
-[ALL LAUGHING]
-Hey, Bryan. you coming?
I'll catch up.
Okay, let's go. [CHUCKLING]
So, uh, what's up,
Sarah? Huh?
Wanna come back to my place?
-Yeah, sure.
-Yeah.
Just give me a sec
while I get a lobotomy.
Hey, come on, Sarah.
We used to have
a lot of fun together.
That was one night.
Yeah. Actually,
if you remember correctly,
it was two.
You came back for seconds.
Hey, Bryan. You better
hurry up 'cause the bars
close in an hour.
-Come here.
-Get off me.
What? Suddenly you're
a fucking virgin now? Huh?
-Yeah, maybe.
-Come here.
Get off. Get off!
[GROANING IN PAIN]
Agh! You fucking bitch!
[GROANING]
Fuck!
Damn it.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Go away or I'll call the cops.
MAN: Okay, but then
you can forget about
borrowing my earrings.
Come in, Hector.
I thought you were Bryan.
So, so, so, so so!
Okay. Okay, okay, okay.
So...
Guess who was crowned
Miss Drag Strip tonight?
-You.
-No.
Some hoe needed
a lip wax,
but I was crowned
Miss Runner-Up.
That's great.
You know, you could pretend
to be a little bit more
excited for me.
Oh, sweetie. What's wrong?
Mrs. Crothers.
Apparently, she and Tess
got into it tonight
and she's threatening
eviction again.
Ah. That old bag
can't evict you.
Only the landlord can.
And you know, he's dead.
Temporary reprieve.
Somebody is gonna
buy this place.
Oh, this dump?
I seriously doubt it.
-[SIREN WAILING]
-So...
where is your
psycho-twin tonight?
Is she out,
sucking the blood
from a chicken's neck?
Shut up, Hector.
[CHUCKLES] Chiquita loca.
-Cut it out, Hector.
-Chiquita...
Tess?
[SIGHS] Dios mio.
She's hurt herself again.
I have to find her.
[SIGHS] I'll call the police.
No! If you call the police,
they'll commit her again.
Sarah, please stay calm, okay?
Every time she does this,
you make yourself all crazy,
and she walks in
like nothing's happened.
Hector, she's my sister.
Fine. I'm coming with you.
No. Just stay here
in case she comes back.
But, but...
I'm in here, fucker.
[CHUCKLES]
You're such a joke.
[GROANS]
WOMAN: That's not coming
in my house, Daddy.
MAN: Did I say it was?
WOMAN: Yes,
you have it on my truck.
MAN: I'm gonna take it
to my house, all right?
No, you're not.
You're going to
put it in storage
because it's going to end up
in my house. I'm not
putting that in my house.
Excuse me. Hi.
Uh, I was wondering,
do you know who manages
this building?
Actually, I do.
Hi, Amanda Winters.
-This is my father, Gus.
-How you doing?
My name is Bill Sheppard,
but my friends call me Shep.
Any vacancies?
No, not right now,
but there will be soon.
So, why don't you
leave me your number
and I can call you when
I have something available.
That would be great.
Um, I'm in a bit of a hurry,
so I would be willing
to pay a premium.
-Thank you.
-Thank you. Nice to meet you.
Uh-huh.
Dude, she is fine.
She is mine.
Like you'd have a chance.
Right? Who scored last night
when you went home alone?
'Cause I think,
I think it was me.
Dude, I saw
your score, okay?
Fifty pounds lighter
and she could
box middleweight.
Bring on the fatties!
Hey, let me help you
with that.
No, it's okay. I have it.
Come on. Thus is, uh,
this is heavy.
Yeah. And I might
break a nail?
Especially on a hand
as beautiful as this one.
You don't want to do that.
Take your hands
off my daughter.
I'm... I'm sorry.
I was just trying to help.
I'm, uh, I'm Reed Matthews.
Yeah, I know who you are.
You're in apartment 7.
-Sorry. Have we met?-No. I just bought the building.
And if you don't want
an eviction notice,
you'll stay the hell away
from my daughter.
-Daddy.
-What?
No. I know
these kind of guys.
Why are you two fools
still standing here?
See? Now, those are gonna bethe first tenants we get rid of.
We have other business
to deal with.
Like the old lady,
living in a two bedroom,
two bathroom for $300 a month?
Damn rent control.
No, don't worry.
You know the new laws.
Once we get rid of them,
we can charge whatever we want.
And I know
how to get rid of 'em.
-Yes, you do, honey.
-Yes, I do.
That's why I bought you this.
-You bought me?
-Yeah.
Ah! Daddy.
Yeah. Not only are you
a wonderful partner,
but you're a wonderful daughter.
Here you go.
Thank you, Daddy.
You better plant
some new grass.
I beg your pardon?
Well, look at these
bald patches.
You're not watering it enough.
[CHUCKLES] Ma'am,
I'm not the gardener.
-Well, who are you?
-The new owner.
[SCOFFS] You're kidding.
Well, I guess
if you live long enough,
you've seen everything.
I'm late for church,
but I want to talk to you
about some of these
tenants, and soon.
Who the hell was that?
Two bedroom, two bathroom
for $300 a month.
[GUS CHUCKLING]
Sarah. [CHUCKLES]
Oh, what happened?
Have you been out all night?
No, Mrs. Crothers.
Then I assume
you got my note?
Yes.
Can we talk about this
some other time?
I hate to make threats
because you're such a dear,
but something has to be done
about your sister.
-I'll talk to her.
-It's too late for that.
You can't expect me
to pick up everything and move.
I'm late for church.
I'll pray for you and Tessie.
Thank you.
Hector?
[PHONE RINGING]
Hola.
Hector, I thought you were
going to stay here
in case Tessie came back.
[SIGHS] Sweetie...
I stayed until 4:00 a.m.,
but this girl
needs her beauty sleep.
-[CLATTERING]
-Wait, I think I hear her.
-Fine, I'll be right over.
-Okay.
-Tess, you okay?
-What do you want?
I was up all night
looking for you.
HECTOR: Sarah?
-She's back.
-Ah, fabulous.
-I'm going back to bed.
-No, don't go.
Stay a minute, please.
You hurt yourself again,
didn't you?
I cut myself working.
It's no big deal.
Hector and I were
worried sick about you.
That freak was worried
about me?
Has he looked in the mirror?
Who you calling
a freak, bitch?
Shhh! You don't even
know him.
TESS: And I don't want to.
Sarah, I gotta go.
No, don't leave.
Look, baby, I am so sick
of her games, okay?
She is playing you.
She needs my help.
Sarah, you help everybody.
When are you gonna start
helping yourself?
I'll call you later.
[MACHINE WHIRRING]
What's a girl gotta do
to get some sleep around here?
[METAL CLANKING]
Hey! Who the hell are you?
[BREATHLESSLY] I live here.
-Who the hell are you?
-I am the new landlord.
-I thought a lady lived here.
-A lady does!
How did you get in?
I didn't know if anybody
was home, so I used
the master key.
Well, you see, my daughter's
moving in downstairs
and we noticed a leak,
and I thought it might be
coming from up here.
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't mean
to frighten you. My name's Gus.
-Are you through here?
-Oh, yeah.
You, uh, you have
a nice day, huh?
Oh, Missy. Uh,
do you have any idea
what's going on
in this building
under your very nose?
No. Well, I've only
lived here a few hours,
-so why don't you enlighten me?
-Oh, for starters,
that brown fellow upstairs,
I mean, he dresses up
like a harlot nearly
every weekend.
Wait. Does the brown fellow
have a name?
I don't know. Uh...
Julio or... Jesus.
Hector. It's Hector.
And something's got to be done
about the boys in number 7.
I mean, they are drunk
and disorderly every night.
And... and then
there's Tessie Swinton.
She's... She's...
I'm sorry.
I'm not a well woman.
I can't take
much more of this.
I'll look into it, okay?
Oh, thank you.
Oh, but I have to
remind you,
there are no pets allowed
in this building.
And I believe
you have two dogs?
I've had my babies for years.
Nobody's ever had
a problem with them.
Yeah, well now I do.
There's a no pets provision
in your lease.
So, I'm giving you
till the end of the month
to find a home for them.
You listen here, Missy.
You've got some nerve.
I mean, you people get
a few bucks
-in your pocket...
-That's enough.
-You think you can
just ride railroad
-That's enough.
over anybody?
You've really got some...
some nerve.
[GASPING]
Oh.
Don't sneak up on me like that.
Sorry about last night.
It's all starting again,
isn't it?
I'll be good, I promise.
Let's forget about last night.
Why don't we rent a movie?
You can pick it.
I can't. Ian's picking me up
in a few minutes.
You saw him last night.
I'm just going to dinner.
We'll only be gone
a couple hours.
He just wants to sleep
with you. That's all
any guy wants.
Stop it. We've only
been out one time.
So?
You used to screw a guy
in the first hour.
Well, I'm not as stupid
as I used to be.
Yes, you are.
Oh, God. Please, please,
don't go. Please.
I'll tell Ian you're sick.
Please. Just...
At least let me
come with you.
I can't.
Oh, right.
Right, I get it.
You don't want a freak like me
scaring off your new boyfriend.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
[LOUD THRASH MUSIC PLAYING]
I think Spam might be
the greatest thing
on this whole damn planet.
I mean... I can't think
of anything I'd rather eat.
[COUGHING]
Peeshka.
I'd rather eat Peeshka.
Peeshka?What the fuck
are you talking about?
Peeshkais the Russian word
for pussy.
[LAUGHING]
[LAUGHS AND CHOKES]
-Thanks for dinner.
-Yeah.
Um...
Can I come up?
I don't think tonight's
a good night. Tess is home.
Well, I'd like to meet
your sister.
Sure, just...
I have to handle
things delicately.
Tess can be...
Jealous?
-Don't flatter yourself.
-[BOTH LAUGHING]
You really look after Tessie,
don't you?
I'm the only family
she's got.
Oh. Must get
a bit lonely for you.
Um, look...
my father's an alcoholic.
And I know what it's like
to take care of
a needy relative.
Um, it's not like that.
Well, whatever it is,
it's a lot easier
if you let people help you.
Sorry. God.
-It's none of my business.
-It's okay.
-I really had fun tonight.
-Yeah, me too. Me too.
-I'll call you.
-You better.
Bye.
[LAUGHING] Peeshka.
I like Peeshka.
Peeshka, Peeshka, Peeshka.
Yeah. I remember
my first beer.
[BANGING ON DOOR]
Jimmy, see who the fuck
that is.
Oh, definitely not Peeshka.
Will you degenerates
please turn your music down?
What is it with you, huh?
You're constantly on my ass.
If I wanted to live with
a nagging old woman,
-I would've moved back home.
-Bryan, don't be such a prick.
Is this language
really necessary?
Just turn down the music.
It's almost 11:00.
Whatever.
[MUSIC STOPS]
Ah, dude, dude,
you are a peeshka.
You're welcome.
MAN ON TV: This thing has been nothing short of prairie fire.
[MAN ON TV
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Don't you worry,
my darlings.
If that colored girl thinks
she can make me
get rid of my babies,
she's got another thing coming.
[WHINING]
[GLASS BREAKING]
Oh, Sporty,
what have you done?
[CHUCKLES]
[GASPS] Oh, my!
[CHUCKLES] Oh, God.
[EXCLAIMS] Oh!
Oh, Elsa. Oh.
Elsa, get a hold of yourself.
Oh, God.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
Hello?
Hello. Hello?
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
-What do you want?
-[DOOR SQUEAKS]
[GASPING]
What are you doing here?
Oh!
Ahh!
Oh, my God.
-What happened?
-Oy, it is your lucky day.
Elsa Crothers
finally kicked it.
Heart attack. It's a shame.
You've obviously
never met that old bag.
AMANDA: I don't think
we've met.
I'm Amanda Winters,
the new landlord.
Oh, I'm Sarah.
This is Hector.
-Hi.
-Hey.
I'm having a party
Thursday night
for the tenants.
I'd love for you to come.
Like 8:00?
-Sure.
-Sarah, bring your sister.
-Okay?
-Yeah.
Excuse me.
She seems nice.
I love this jacket.
Can I borrow it?
I'm meeting a client.
Hmm. You mean,
some other lazy ass woman
who's too fat to get herself
over to the cosmetics counter?
-When are you gonna
get a real job?
-When are you?
You know, you should, like,
finish college or something.
You know, become
a doctor or a lawyer.
Get the hell out
of this building.
Who's going to
take care of Tess?
Tessie is your sister.
-She's not your daughter.
-I'm late. Bye.
[ENGINE STARTS]
You're late.
[SNIFFS]
Oh, papi.
-This shit is pure.
-Yeah, told you.
How much for
a couple of grams?
$250.
$250... But that's almost
twice as much as last time.
Cost of living, bro.
I don't even have
that much cash.
Wait. I'll pay you
next week.
What do I look like
to you, huh?
A fucking bank?
You already owe me $500.
I'm good for it, Bryan.
Look, you want
a piece of the rock, hmm?
It's $250 plus the five Bennies
you already owe me.
Bryan, please.
Bryan, don't leave.
Bryan!
-Tess.
-What are you doing here?
I came to help you.
By help, do you mean
more electro-shock?
Or enough drugs to make me
a drooling catatonic?
Nothing else was working.
Nothing ever works.
Thank God I was able
to find you. Come here.
Everything's gonna be
all right now.
-[GROANS]
-[TELEPHONE RINGING]
[SIGHS WEARILY] Hello.
Hello Dr. Sheppard,
it's Amanda Winters.
We met the other day?
-Did I wake you?
-No, no.
Well, as luck would have it,
I have a vacancy.
Two bedrooms, two bathrooms,
second floor, $1,250 a month.
Are you interested?
I'll take it.
Great. So come by tomorrow
to sign the lease.
Ah, yeah.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Hello, everyone.
First, I would like to
welcome Dr. Bill Sheppard.
He moved into the building
this week.
Hi, welcome.
Okay, let me put
all of your minds at ease.
I am not going
to raise the rent this year.
However, I do plan on
enforcing your current leases.
In other words, no pets,
no excessive noise,
no rooftop parties.
Okay, that's it.
So, have a drink and enjoy.
-Sweetheart.
-Yes?
Baby, why do you even
bother with these people?
Because you catch
more flies with honey.
-Hmm.
-Nut?
Dude, I'll be in her pants
by the end of the week.
It'll be a little crowded
'cause I'll already be there.
Yo, is there anybody
in this building
you haven't banged yet?
Her.
Oh, yeah. You should
definitely tap that.
Get even with Sarah
after dumping your ass.
She didn't dump me, dickwad.
Hello, Tessie.
It's been a while.
Do I know you?
Oh, yes.
Dr. Sheppard from Deerwood.
I don't know
a Dr. Sheppard.
I think you do.
So you guys think
that I really couldn't nail
Tessie Swinton
if I wanted to?
I got 100 bucks
says you can't.
Shit, I'd do it for $50.
Jimmy, you'd have to pay
your hand $50
just to touch your dick.
-Fuckers.
-Grow up.
Dude, she's hot for you.
Excuse me.
Now, watch and learn.
Hey, Tess.
Haven't seen you in awhile.
What'cha been up to?
If you're looking for Sarah,
she's on a date.
Um, actually,
I was looking for you.
I thought maybe
we could hang out sometime.
Really?
Just 'cause my sister
spread 'em for you
doesn't mean I will.
Just calm down, okay?
Don't get all crazy.
-Don't call me crazy.
-Geez, relax.
-I'm not crazy.
-Leave her alone.
No, you leave me alone.
You heard her, dude.
Back off.
-Come on, Tess.
Let's get out of here.
-Leave her alone.
-Hey!
-What part of "back off"
don't you understand? Huh?
Motherfucker.
This ain't a bar.
-Stay out of my way.
-You need to get
the hell out of here.
Now.
Move, freak!
Bitch!
Oh, Bryan.
I need your help.
Bryan, you have to help me.
No, I don't.
Bryan, please!
I'm freaking, Bryan.
Just give me a couple of days
to get the money together.
Motherfuckers!
Fucking...
[SNIFFS]
Yeah. What, Tess?
You don't want
a piece of this, huh?
You don't want this? Yeah.
I'm sorry. What'd you say?
What'd you say, Doc?
You stay away from me.
Are you talking to me? Huh?
Huh? You stay out of my way.
You stay out of my way.
What? You want
a piece of me? Huh?
Huh? You want a piece of me?
Huh? Argh!
Ah!
Argh!
[CHOKING]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
-[RAPID KNOCKING ON DOOR]
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Is Bryan here?
It's important.
He's in his room.
Mr. Bryan,
you have a visitor.
I think it's the chick
you banged last week.
[CHUCKLES]
Go ahead, fruit loop.
[KNOCKING AT DOOR] Bryan.
Bryan.
Bryan?
Dios mio! Dios mio!
What the hell happened?
Looks like an overdose.
But we'll know for sure
once we do the autopsy.
-Overdose?
-No! No way. No way.
We found this
in the bathroom.
See how it's got fresh blood
right there on the syringe?
Here's my card.
I will be in touch.
There's no way
he OD'd, all right?
Bryan could handle his shit.
Right. And I have a wife
and two kids.
You know what?
Listen, disco queen,
if I find out you had
anything to do with this,
I'm goin' right to the cops.
You're gonna be really
popular in prison.
Get your hands off me, man!
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
All right.
So, who's gonna
call his parents?
Yeah. His parents.
[DOOR OPENS AND SHUTS]
-SHEP: Oh!
-SARAH: Oh!
SARAH: Careful.
Do you need help?
Uh, no. I got it.
I broke a mirror
while unpacking.
-Seven years.
-I know.
Not what I need right now.
Hi. You must be Sarah.
-Have we met?
-No, but it's nice
to meet you now.
Tessie never mentioned you.
How do you know my sister?
I was an attending physician
at Deerwood.
My name's Shep.
I would really like to talk,
but unfortunately I have
to go to a funeral.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Hey, I heard about Bryan.
Is Tess going?
No. She hasn't been
to a funeral since
our parents died.
How's she been doing?
She's fine.
She's great, really.
Uh... Sarah, would you tell
Tessie that I'd like to talk
with her sometime?
You know. Just to make sure
that everything is all right.
Consider it
a professional follow-up.
I told you, she's fine.
I'm not so sure.
Well, I think I know my sister
better than you.
Sarah...
You're not going to prevent me
from talking to Tessie,
are you?
Doctor, she doesn't
need any more reminders
of that hell hole.
Leave her alone.
Excuse me.
Hi, Amanda.
Um...
Reed...
Oh, right. Hi. Hi.
-Uh... Wow, you look great.
-[CHUCKLING]
Look, I'm late for a meeting.
Is there something
I can do for you?
We lost the keys to
the basement storage space.
-Uh...
-We need to pack
up Bryan's things.
Oh, sure. I can get you a key.
You know, I'm really
sorry about Bryan.
I mean, first Mrs. Crothers
and then Bryan.
This building is cursed.
Yeah, the funeral's
this morning.
Oh, you know, I was wondering,
since Bryan is gone,
are you guys going to
stay in the apartment?
I hadn't really
thought about it.
You know, it could be weird,
so if you want to move,
I completely understand.
Thanks, Amanda.
But moving is not going
to make me forget about him.
And I think this building'll
be a lot better now that
you're running things.
You seem pretty cool.
You know,
maybe we could even
hang out sometime
and do something.
[CHUCKLES]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[PRIEST] Ashes to ashes.
Dust to dust.
The Lord bless him
and keep him,
the Lord give him space to shineand be gracious upon him.
Amen.
-SARAH: I'll see you back
at the building.
-Okay.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
Excuse me.
What are you doing here?
I'm sorry to bug you guys
at such a grave hour.
I need to talk with
you and Jimmy. Jimmy...
What's up?
I just got the
autopsy report back.
Based on the angle
and location of the injection,
there is just no way
that Bryan could have
overdosed himself.
[STAMMERING]
What are you trying to say?
I'm trying to say it looks
like maybe someone
murdered him.
[SCOFFS]
Do you have any idea
of who might've wanted
to do this to your friend?
I don't know. Do you?
I mean,
you're the detective, right?
-What, are you funny?
-Are you questioning us now?
Wh-what are you trying to do?
Do we have to do this here?
This is his funeral!
This case is now a homicide.
I'll be in touch
with the both of you.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
[KNOB CREAKING]
SHEP: Hello?
Is there anyone here?
Your door was open.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[DISTANT CHATTER]
What I don't understand is
that this Bryan bloke
is a complete arse,
but yet you go to
his funeral anyway?
He may be an "arse,"
but he's also been
my neighbor for
the last four years.
[SIGHS]
You're a mystery.
And that's why you like me.
[EXHALES DEEPLY]
So, uh...
are you going to invite me in?
I don't know.
I'm thinking about it.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
Is this typical post-funeral
behavior for you?
Are you complaining?
[DISTANT THUD]
Hold on.
Are you joking?
Tess, are you here?
We're alone.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
What have we got here?
Mmm-mmm.
Hmm...
[CHUCKLING] Relax.
Let's, let's leave some
things to the imagination.
-[DOOR OPENS]
-[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
[SWITCHES CLICKING]
JIMMY: Let's just get
this over with, all right?
-Yeah.
-It's going to be okay.
JIMMY: I can't believe
the cops think someone
killed him.
That's fucked up.
I mean,
who the hell would kill Bryan?
I haven't ruled out Hector.
Where the hell is our
storage room?
-It's like a maze down here.
-I think it's over here.
[BLOWING RASPBERRIES]
There's a reason why I don't
come down here.
Yeah, this place is
nice and creepy.
[LOCK CLICKING]
JIMMY: Oh, shit. What a mess!
Let's find Bryan's stuff
and get out of here.
Oh, there's Bryan's trunk.
-[CAN CLANGING]
-JIMMY: Fuck!
What the hell
is all this shit?
Paint thinner. Smooth move.
Shut the fuck up, dude.
[LIGHTS CLICK]
Okay. Great.
A fuse must've blown.
I'm going to find
the box or something.
Try not to destroy
anything else, all right?
Yeah, hurry up, man.
This paint thinner stinks.
[COUGHING]
Fuse box, shmooze box...
If I were Amanda's box...
[CHUCKLING]
[SCREAMS]
[OBJECTS CLATTERING]
People have some weird shit.
Reed, what the hell, man?
How long does it take
to find a fuse box?
This paint thinner stinks.
[GRUNTS]
Yo, Reed. What the fuck
you doing, man?
-[LIGHTER CLICKS]
-Hey.
Hey, this stuff
is flammable, man.
JIMMY: [SCREAMING]
What the fuck! Jesus!
Ah!
Yo, Jimmy. You're not
gonna believe what I
found down here.
JIMMY: Reed!
Jimmy!
Hey, Reed. Jimmy.
It's Detective Lewis.
I need to speak to you guys.
Are you there?
Open up.
[DOORKNOB CLICKING]
-[GROANS]
-Jimmy! Jimmy!
Just hold on, all right.
I'm going to go get help!
Who are you?
Did you do this?
-[GRUNTING]
-[EXTINGUISHER CLANGING]
REED: Help! Help me!
Help! Help!
Can anyone hear me?
I'm in the basement! Help me!
[REED SCREAMING]
[THUDS]
[LEWIS STRAINING]
Hm.
AMANDA: I think we're gonna
have another vacancy soon.
-[THUNDER RUMBLING]
-I don't know...
I guess I do my job well.
[LAUGHING]
-[KNOCK ON DOOR]
-Daddy, I gotta go.
Someone's at the door...
-Okay. Love you, bye.
-[PHONE BEEPS]
-Amanda Winters?
-Yes. Can I help you?
Detective Fred Lewis.
I'm investigating the death
of Bryan Davis.
Ugh. That was such a tragedy.
Yeah.
Especially if he was murdered.
Mind if I come in?
I guess that's a yes.
Where were you
the night that he died?
I was here.
I had a small party
for my tenants.
Do you recognize that?
Yes. I've been
looking for that.
Where did you find that?
It was in the bedroom
of the deceased.
What?
How do you think
your necklace ended up
in his bedroom that night?
I don't know.
Maybe he stole it.
You know, I had half
the building in this
apartment that night.
Anyone could've taken it.
Mind if I look around?
Yes, I do, actually. I'm busy.
Mmm.
Well, I can go get a warrant
and be back in two hours.
Fine, Lieutenant.
Look all you want.
Thank you.
[KEYPAD BEEPING]
[LINE RINGING]
Daddy, answer the phone.
[LEWIS LAUGHING]
Wow.
Amazing. Gotcha.
Ms. Winters, do you
mind explaining why
you have a vial
of heart medication
for Elsa Crothers?
[DOOR CLOSES]
Damn it!
SARAH: What happened
to dinner and a movie?
[IAN CHUCKLING]
Well, we're eating dinner,
and... here's the movie.
[LAUGHING] Wow. You really
know how to spoil a girl.
-Yeah.
-[THUNDER RUMBLING]
I really know...
how to spoil a girl.
-[BOTH LAUGHING]
-Cut it out.
What?
Don't you like it?
Yeah. Of course I do...
it's just... I think I'd like
what's underneath just
a little better.
Cut it out.
Sarah. Don't you think
this is getting a little old?
Are you complaining?
I don't know. Maybe.
Then get the hell
out of my bed.
Why won't you let me
get closer to you?
-Get out.
-Sarah, come on.
I said, get out!
This evening is over.
Fine! Fine!
Are you okay?
-I had a fight with Ian.
-Where is he?
Gone.
Good.
Oh, look at your scars.
They're your scars.
I wear them for you.
Just be glad
I don't cut my face.
[LAUGHING]
Why are you doing this to us?
I don't do this to us,
I do it for us.
What do you mean?
If I didn't cut myself,
I'd kill myself.
And therefore, dear sister,
I'd kill you.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[KNOCKING AT DOOR]
[SNIFFLING]
Is everything okay?
Everything's fine.
Then why are you crying?
Um...
I'm fine.
Well, I'm a professionallistener, if you'd like to talk.
Uh...
No, thanks. I just...
Ah...
-What's wrong?
-Go away.
Let me help you.
Actually...
Maybe I could use
someone to talk to.
Great.
I was just going to
make some tea.
I'll get you a cup.
Thank you.
Where's Tessie?
SARAH: In her room.
Why don't you ask her
to come and join us?
Because I want to
talk to you first.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Mmm.
I'd like you
to stay away from Tess.
Sarah, I know
you love your sister
and you want
what's best for her.
So do I.
And how do you
now what's best for
my sister, Doctor?
Well, we spent a lot of time
together at Deerwood.
We were making progress.
But then she left
before we could complete
the treatment regimen.
"Treatment regimen."
Now that's
an interesting euphemism.
Why is it so hot in here?
Doctor, that must be
the drug taking effect.
[GROANING]
What are you
talking about, Sarah?
I'm Tess.
You told Sarah
you wanted to talk
to me. So, here I am.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
But we only have
a few minutes before
the saxitoxin in your tea
takes full effect.
Saxitoxin?
[OBJECTS CLATTERING]
[TESSIE LAUGHING]
It's really quite
a remarkable drug.
Now, I'm sure
you're familiar with it.
It paralyzes the nervous system,
yet leaves you
completely conscious.
Why are you doing this?
I'm just returning the favor.
It's the least I can do
after all the experimental
drugs you pumped into me.
Tess, you need help.
[CHUCKLING] Actually,
I think you're the one
who needs help right now.
[STRAINING] So...
Why don't you tell me
what you're doing here?
I don't know what you mean.
I think you do.
I move halfway across
the country,
and yet somehow you end up
living across the hall.
When you escaped,
they fired me.
Oh.
So... you thought if you
found me and fixed me,
you'd get your job back.
[SLURRING] I want to help you.
[CLATTERING]
Really?
Or did you just want to play
some more of those
extracurricular games
we played while I was too
drugged to even know my name?
Where's Sarah?
Sarah's gone. I decide when
Sarah comes and when she goes.
Sarah.
Everybody always wants Sarah.
[KNOCKING AT DOOR]
IAN : Sarah, please let me in.
See what I mean?
[KNOCKING CONTINUES]
Don't move.
IAN: Sarah, it's Ian.
I'm sorry about tonight.
[KNOCKING CONTINUES]
Sarah they want,
Sarah they'll get.
-Hi. Can I come in?
-No. Tessie's sleeping.
Oh, listen...
I just want to say I'm sorry
I said what I did.
I just, um... I just, um...
I didn't want to, you know,
ruin things with you.
I feel like...
you're the most genuine girl
that I've ever met.
And I don't want
to ruin things.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I just...
I have a really nasty headache.
That's not exactly what
a bloke likes to hear
right about now.
I should lay down.
Well, okay. I could join you.
No, really. My head is pounding.I'm just going to go to bed.
Okay.
I'll call you tomorrow.
Sure.
Did you miss me?
You say you want to help me?
Look what your help has
done to me!
Can you see it?
I'm going to help you!
Sarah has the best taste.
If you like that
Martha Stewart sort of thing.
What am I going to
do with you, Dr. Sheppard?
I can't really have you
following me around
the country like
some lost puppy, can I?
TESSIE:
Mmm-hmm. You're right.
You're absolutely right.
I feel much better
about this.
And with that,
I think our time is up.
It has been really nice
talking to you.
But, um, I have
a lot of work to do, so.
Drowning is such
a peaceful death.
You really don't deserve it.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
-Sarah.
-Hi, Amanda.
-I need to talk to you.
-What is it?
Someone is setting me up.
They're making it seem
like I had something to do
with the deaths
in this building.
-[SCOFFS] That's ridiculous.
-Yeah.
Have you seen anyone
acting suspiciously?
Honestly, no.
What about your sister?
Do you think
she's behind this?
How dare you accuse Tess!
You've got a lot of nerve
accusing my sister...
I'm being accused,
and I didn't do it.
I hear the laughs.
I hear the whispers.
I see how people look at me.
You?
[SIGHS]
I mean Tess.
I'm sorry I'm so upset,
but people can be
really cruel to her.
So, if you'll excuse me,
I'm going to go to bed.
No, Sarah, wait a second.
I just want to ask you
a question.
Bitch. [SIGHS]
Oh, great! God!
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Shep? Open the door.
It's Amanda!
AMANDA: Shep!
Ugh! If he went out and
left the water running,
I will kill him.
You really shouldn't be
making those kinds of
threats, Ms. Winters.
Look, I've had enough
harassment for one day.
Well, too bad, because
I'm about ready to read
you your rights.
Listen, I'll tell you
everything I know,
if you can just
help me get into
this tenant's apartment
I think he's in trouble.
Police! Open up.
Open the door.
Stand back. Stand back.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[GASPS]
-Is he dead?
-He's barely got a pulse.
This water shorted
the wiring.
I can't see a damn thing.
I'll get a flashlight.
Hey, don't go
too far this time.
[GRUNTS]
I couldn't find a flashlight...
Oh, my God!
-Hi, Amanda.
-[GASPS]
Sarah! You did this?
Are you insane?
Well, I'm not Sarah. I'm Tess.
And, no, I'm not insane.
[LAUGHS ERRATICALLY]
Oh, Amanda, I really can't
thank you enough.
I couldn't have done
this without you.
Crothers was going to
have me evicted.
And then Bryan,
Bryan fucked Sarah
when I wasn't watching,
and he thought he could
just keep coming back
for seconds.
Oh, and I also got rid of
Reed and Jimmy,
so it would look like
you were clearing out
their apartment.
And then there's Shep,
but that's a really long story
and I just don't have time.
-Wait... Wait...
-HECTOR: Oye.
Hector! [SCREAMING]
I didn't know you were
having a party in here.
-Sarah?
-No, Hector, it's not Sarah,
it's Tess.
-Of course I'm Sarah.
-AMANDA: No...
-TESSIE: She's framing me.
-No.
-Are you sure?
-She killed everybody.
-She's lying!
-I walked in on her
latest killing spree.
-Don't listen to her, Hector.
-She's crazy.
Call the police,
call the police.
-I'm not crazy!
-Yes, you are, Sarah,
you're crazy.
-You're insane.
-Shut up!
-You're out of your
goddamned mind!
-Shut up.
Shut up!
Sarah, what's going on?
We have to catch her. Go! Go!
TESSIE: Where did she go?
[BOTH PANTING]
-Why is Amanda doing this?
-She's killing all the
rent-controlled tenants.
But Shep just moved in.
And that cop?
They figured it out.
She had to get rid of them.
Let's go!
Oh, my God!
Come on, let's go.
Help me!
AMANDA: Help! Help me!
Help!
Amanda?
Mandy.
[BANGING]
[SHRIEKING]
Come on!
AMANDA: Oh, my God!
[AMANDA BREATHING HEAVILY]
HECTOR: Oh, my God!
Sarah, what do we do?
We have to call the cops!
It's not Sarah! Listen to me.
It's Tess! It's not Sarah!
Please, listen, would Sarah
kill all of these people?
Sarah? Are you okay?
Sarah!
Have you ever actually
seen Sarah and Tess together?
-Of course I...
-No.
Oh, Hector. You stupid freak.
What have you done with Sarah?
She doesn't exist!
And soon, you won't either.
SHEP: Tess!
Put down the knife.
-How did you...
-Right drug, wrong dosage.
You bastard!
If you put down the knife,
I promise I won't hurt you.
Don't make promises
you can't keep.
-Where's Sarah?
-Sarah's gone.
No, she's not.
She's the one who protects you.
She'll know what to do.
Drop the knife.
[GUN COCKING]
[CLANGING]
Good.
[CRYING] Shep.
Come here.
[CRYING]
Oh, my God! You!
Sarah? Sarah!
TESSIE: Ian, Ian...
Sarah, what's wrong?
-Ian...
-What have they done to you?
Get out of the way.
I don't know who you are.
But we're getting
the fuck out of here.
Get out of the way.
Put the fucking gun down.
She's got a knife!
[GUN FIRING]
HECTOR: Sarah!
Sarah! Sarah! Look at me!
Somebody help! Somebody,
somebody, please help!
IAN: Please, somebody,
call an ambulance!
Somebody, help!
HECTOR: Amanda.
Hector.
-Hey.
-Hi.
You're the last person
I expected to see here.
Well, I had to come.
How are you?
I miss Sarah.
She was my best friend.
How about you?
Well, I'm selling
the building. Getting
out of real estate.
Um, you know,
see where I go.
I don't know.
You know, I never did
get a chance
to thank you for
saving my life.
Thank you.
Sarah?
Sarah!
I'm sorry. I just...
I'm sorry. Sorry, who are you?
I'm Beth.
I'm Tessie's sister.
It can't... You...
Tessie's sister doesn't exist.
Tessie's sister died
when Tess did.
Did you know her?
I thought I did.
We haven't talked in
about ten years.
She cut off all contact.
So she really
had a twin sister.
We were really close...
until my parents died,
and then she just...
lost it.
I just wish I'd known
how bad it had gotten.
Do you think I could
get your number?
I'd love to get to know
more about my sister.
Yeah, please. Um...
I'd love to know
more about her, too.
I'll call you soon, okay?
He seems nice.
Why? Because he's got
a stupid British accent?
Why are you so mean?
Well, somebody has gotta be.
We can't all go through
life like Girl Scouts.
Shut up. Shut up.