It's how
every message ended.
Previously, on
"MacGyver"...
But who they are
remains a mystery.
They call themselves Codex.
They've been around
a lot longer than we first thought.
There's nothing more dangerous
than people who do
the wrong things
for the right reasons.
Tell him...
...about File 47.
47...
would plunge the
world into chaos.
What do you say?
A little breakfast with your dear old aunt?
Why do you refuse to see
what is actually happening here?
- And what is that?
- You're compromised.
Auntie Gwen got to you.
I'm gonna try something,
but it means
risking everything,
everyone I love.
I'm sorry.
"We Didn't Start the Fire"
by Billy Joel playing...
Get out of my way!
We're not gonna make it.
♪ The world's been turning ♪
Ah, God. Nice try,
- jackass!
- Gwen, that was
- a Meals On Wheels.
- We're running out of time.
♪ We tried to fight it ♪
♪ Rock-and-roller ♪
♪ Cola wars,
I can't take it anymore ♪
There is a plan
in place.
Just take a deep breath.
- Okay, bossy.
- But if something happens to me,
There's something
you should know.
I'm gonna send File 47
to some friends in D.C.
Okay, that is a terrible plan.
It is a complex statistical
analysis of the climate crisis.
Indisputable scientific proof
that our planet is dying.
File 47 posits a plan
to wipe out
a considerable amount
of the population
- in order to get the planet back on track.
- A theoretical plan.
You don't think that's
a little dangerous,
to put that in the hands
of the government?
Seeing it in print
might scare them into action.
Politicians only care
about power.
And you want to give
'em even more power
to play God and decide
who lives and who dies.
We know
what kind of planet
the next generation is going
to inherit.
We have to do something.
Oh, no. No, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no. No, no,
no, no, no, no, no.
Oh, God. You know what,
I think you're right.
- We're not gonna make it to the hospital.
- Damn it, Ellie.
You never listen to me!
- Pull over!
- Okay, okay, okay.
It's okay.
We-we can do this.
We've got five PhDs between us.
Right. Well, I've got three,
you've got two.
Okay, I don't see
how that's important right now!
Oh-oh, God.
Hey there, little guy.
Hi.
All right.
- Ready to cut the cord?
- Can you wait
Just a minute? I just feel like
the second we do,
he's gonna... float away.
Aw, you...
You deserve the world.
And the world
deserves you.
Oh, look at us.
- So you don't have a name?
- We couldn't decide.
But I'll-I'll think
of something.
*MAcGYVER (2016)*
Season 04  Episode 13
Title: "Save + The + Dam + World"
Aired on: May 08, 2020
We have enough food
for a nice, long hibernation.
Generator's not great,
but, thanks to you,
we don't have
to worry about power.
What do you mean,
thanks to us?
You brought us Shiva.
Spoiler alert:
not just a weapon.
It's also known as a god
they call
the Destroyer.
It's also named
after a goddess
associated with reincarnation,
rebirth.
In order
to be born again,
first, we have to die.
Shiva here's
a...
renewable
power source.
Be right back.
Your aunt must be really great
at dinner parties.
She thinks she's
saving the world.
Exactly.
Do you really think
we can change her mind
about this plan? We don't
even know what the plan is.
Yeah, I have a gut feeling
about this. Just...
deep down somewhere,
there's some humanity left.
- Somewhere.
- Hey.
I get it.
You feel connected to her,
to your mom.
But I need you
to clear your head, Mac.
We need to do
everything we can
to figure out
what they're planning.
Yeah. You're absolutely right.
- Okay.
- Until then,
we need to look
like true believers.
Right.
That doesn't look good.
Your reputation as Artemis
precedes you, Ms. Davis.
You've got a lot
of fans around here.
Would you mind accompanying
me to our tech room?
Uh, like I said,
we're a package deal.
You and I have other
business to attend to.
We don't have a choice.
Right.
I'll s... I'll see you later.
- Okay.
You come with me.
And where are we off to?
To meet Leland.
What's a Leland?
He's the man who saved my life
when the CIA tried to kill me.
Uh, he paid 'em off,
had 'em declare me dead.
Who is he?
He is Codex.
The man behind the curtain?
Among others.
He's a genius.
Before Codex,
File 47 was just theory
and statistics
on paper.
Now it's a plan
to save the world.
He helped me
resurrect it.
He believes in me.
And now...
he has to believe in you.
And if he doesn't?
Roman,
isn't it about time
for your 4:00 feeding?
Let me guess. They drop a
live goat into your cage.
I'll take it from here.
- No, you won't.
- Leland wants you to get your team ready.
So, I will meet you in
an hour in the vehicle bay.
You'll be fine.
Chopin's "Nocturne
in E-flat minor" playing...
The years 1347 to 1351.
The Black Plague in Europe.
Over 100,000 million
people died.
And what happened
after that?
The Renaissance.
And?
Codex.
- Codex dates back to the 14th century?
- I know.
- It's hard to believe, huh?
- How is that
Even possible?
Well, a group of people
got together back then
with a singular purpose:
to protect the planet
from plague,
from famine,
and...
Excuse my French...
Dumbasses,
like the people
in power today.
A lot of amazing science
had just come out
of the Middle East,
but Westerners needed a...
bit of a push.
So we funded
a lot of the Enlightenment.
Things were really clipping
along for us.
And then,
of course,
things took a turn
for our dear Mother Earth.
The Industrial
Revolution.
Kid's good.
Everything went
all pear-shaped after that.
Plastics
were invented.
We were worried when
they started splitting the atom.
But we found
that chain reactions
do come in handy.
You remember
World War I?
'Course.
Franz Ferdinand.
Guess what.
He was Codex.
Is that a J.M.W. Turner?
Yes, it is.
Look at that sunset.
He was influenced by
the... 1814 eruption
of Mount Tambora.
Spewed gas and ash
up into the sky.
Volcanic particles
in the stratosphere
probably diffused the light.
Used to be
Mother Earth
could protect herself
with an eruption.
Cool the Earth back down
for the next couple
of years.
That's not the
case anymore.
Things have gotten out of hand.
There's just too damn many
of us.
Please,
tell me what I can do to help.
You got 20 people
on a lifeboat meant for ten.
You're sinking.
You're not gonna
make it to shore.
What do you do?
You throw the ten weakest out.
And the strong can row us
back to shore.
Very good, Angus.
Have a nice day.
You know...
...years ago,
a man that you know
answered that question
the exact same way.
Russ Taylor.
His mind and his resources
were a perfect fit for us.
But he refused our proposal.
Because he's weak.
Friends...
every single one of you
has made this day possible.
It's time to go to work.
- You okay?
- Hey. Yeah, fine.
Let's do it!
All right, for security reasons,
each team has a tablet
with instructions that will load
once you are on the road.
Everybody will be traveling
a different route
to attract
the least amount of attention.
I'll be directing the ops
from here in the bunker.
"What was is lost..."
"...but from death comes life!"
"...but from death
comes life!"
- Yeah!
Still think you
can change her mind?
Yeah, I think our
best bet right now
is just go along with this plan
and see if we can figure out
- a way to stop it.
- What plan, Mac?
We're flying blind.
Hey, thanks
for helping us out.
We can really use you
out there.
Sorry to...
keep you in the dark.
Don't suppose you could
let us know what we're in for?
This is how Leland does things,
but it's for our own good.
Right.
Come here.
Oh. I just wish
your mom was here.
All right,
let's do this.
Can you get in?
We need all the intel
- we can get.
- This thing is, like,
The Fort Knox of tablets.
Did Leland give you
any clues?
No, but I
did see something
in the vehicle bay.
Dosimeters.
The things
that measure radiation?
Yeah. So, the
question is,
what do they have, a...
- a dirty bomb, or...?
- Do they have
A nuke?
Any clues in the tech room?
No.
They just had me writing code.
There was something written
on the white board, though.
It's... it's weird...
It wasn't code,
it was like an equation,
with maybe six letters.
It didn't happen to have
an "f" over an "m," did it?
Yeah.
It did. Why?
It's an equation
for determining...
nuclear fission critical mass.
So they have a nuke.
That explains why they
wanted to hack NORAD.
Leland said something
about starting a chain reaction.
Maybe they're trying to start
World War III. If we can...
Well, well, well.
The fam's all here.
Get your gun out of my face!
We're trying to save everyone!
Oh, that's funny. So are we.
I've got a bad
feeling about this.
Okay, everybody needs
to calm down,
- and we'll be okay.
- You really want us to believe
You used Shiva to
infiltrate Codex?
Yes. So Mac could find out
what their master plan is.
Yeah, and we were making
a lot of progress
until you two showed up.
We do not have time for this.
- I'm not buying any of this.
- You gassed us, Mac.
I didn't have a choice!
You booted me out of the Phoenix!
Guys, I promise
we're on the same side here.
Yes, I seem to recall
You betraying
and lying to us
- as well, Riley.
- Betrayed you?
You guys dropped a freakin'
Hellfire missile on us.
- We tried to stop it.
- Oh, really? Now who's lying?
Codex has a nuke!
And every minute
that you keep
your guns trained on us,
it gets closer to going off,
and we get further away
from stopping it.
I've known Mac
longer than anyone.
He's telling the truth.
Desi, Taylor,
- take a breath.
- No, I'm bringing them in.
Mac, don't!
I am going to change this tire,
and we're gonna make
the rendezvous.
- We do not have time for this.
- Don't make me do this.
Taylor, stand down!
He's compromised, Matty.
Oh, really? I'm the one
who's compromised?
Hey, Matty, did Taylor
ever happen to mention to you
that Codex tried to recruit him?
What's he talking about, Russ?
Yeah, go ahead, tell 'em, Russ.
Tell them how Codex
approached you,
tried to bring you on board,
but you kept it a secret
because you didn't want
us to know
that you're the one
who's compromised.
Desi,
I want you
to put your weapon down
and put me on speaker.
Taylor, stand down!
I am not the one
who is compromised.
All right?
Three years ago, I was
approached by an organization
with considerable resources.
- Codex.
- Yes. I didn't know that at the time.
Spearhead Operations had a
contract with the U.S. military
to deliver the Hades prototype.
The bioweapon
we stopped in L.A.
The very same.
Codex offered me a large sum
to deliver it to them instead.
I, of course, refused.
So then they turned to Bishop.
Exactly.
Someone tried to eliminate
me, and they missed.
Instead, five of
my teammates...
my brothers in arms
for the last ten years,
were taken out by an IED,
which I later traced
back to Codex.
And I've been hunting
them ever since.
I'm sorry for your loss,
but does it justify this?
All of this...
Buying the Phoenix,
using us...
for your obsession, for revenge,
no matter the cost.
You're all the best
at what you do.
I needed you on my team.
Well, then why wouldn't
you trust me?
Because I can no longer
read you, Angus.
You fit no
discernible pattern.
For all appearances, you
crossed over to Codex.
Yeah. To stop you
from taking innocent lives.
To save you from yourself.
I just got a location
- For the rendezvous point.
- That could be
Where they're launching
the nuke from.
Okay,
here's what we're gonna do. Mac, Riley,
you're gonna keep your covers
and get
to that rendezvous point.
Taylor, Desi,
I want eyes on them,
and keep a low profile.
There's just
one little problem.
Thanks.
The last time
I changed a tire
was our camping trip
to Yosemite, remember?
Didn't leave our sleeping bags
for two days.
Hurry up.
Yeah, got it.
Good.
You know what?
I trusted you,
and you broke me down
and you got me to trust you
and let you in again and again,
and when things got tough,
you pushed me away.
Do you have any idea
what that did to me?
You're the last person
I wanted to hurt.
Tire's done.
Time to stop a nuke.
Everything okay?
No. No, definitely not.
Got it.
Coordinates say the
rendezvous should be right there.
We're in position.
We have eyes on Mac and Riley.
You're late.
Yeah, we got a flat.
What are our instructions?
Standing by.
Nothing received yet.
Copy that.
What is this place?
Just empty trucks.
No nuke.
What the hell is
a Codex team doing here?
I don't know, and
I don't like it.
This doesn't make sense.
They're all
at the rendezvous point.
- Where's the payload?
- Gwendolyn.
Everything's on schedule.
We're just getting eyes
- on the payload.
- It's not there.
What do you mean?
Folks, give us the room
a sec, please.
Sit down.
When I first found you...
right after the crash,
I thought to myself,
I've never seen another human
shine more brightly.
I could read a book
by you on a
moonless night.
It's easy to shine
when you have purpose.
Yeah, but I've
always been in awe
of you, Gwen.
I'm in awe of your
mind and your loyalty.
Even your anger.
Justifiable anger.
They took
your sister.
Still here.
Thanks to you.
Leland, what is happening?
You've brought me...
so much joy over the years.
I hate to have to
bring you pain.
Your nephew Angus.
You've had such
high hopes for him.
But he's still a Phoenix man.
So I've put us all in jeopardy.
We're often blinded by
the love of our children.
As I've been by
you many times.
But now comes the hard part.
What?
What is this?
Guys, you've got a helicopter
- approaching from the south.
- Can a helicopter
Transport a nuke?
Not this one.
That's a Cobra
attack helicopter.
It's a trap.
What?
Everybody needs to run now.
- What are you talking about?
- They're gonna blow up the warehouse.
Everybody needs to
get out of here now.
Let's move! Let's go!
Go, go, go! Code red!
- Riles, over here.
- Come on!
It's gonna be loud!
Why?
Scarlett, Mr. MacGyver,
and Ms. Davis compromised
our security.
More importantly,
they compromised you.
These human connections
are holding you back.
Taylor, tell me you see them.
No. This fire's too big.
There's no way of getting in.
Returning to base.
It's too hot! Drop it!
We've got them, Matty.
Only you could've
survived this.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Anyone else in there alive?
What have you done?
What Codex always does.
What was necessary.
These people were
your weakness.
I need your strength.
Need you to see
the big picture.
Now, I know it stings.
Even though he
betrayed you,
Angus is your family.
And Scarlett,
like a daughter.
Yeah, what am I gonna
tell her sister?
The truth.
Her sister died
for a greater good.
Is that what this is?
That's what it always is.
We're too close now for
these kind of mistakes.
Your nephew was dangerous.
And your attachment
to him even more so.
Hmm.
So, who's next?
The council and I
have complete trust
- in you.
- And yet you chose not to tell me
That you were gonna neutralize
- my entire team!
- To protect you.
To protect your mind.
To protect your
natural leadership.
You are valued
beyond measure
because you know
the hard truth.
Some are worth
more than others.
You really think
Gwen iced her entire team?
No, I don't.
Everything about that
attack just feels off.
No, Angus. That's the true
face of your Aunt Gwen.
I'm not giving up on her.
Guys, there's movement
at the Codex Ranch House.
Small convoy just pulled out.
Looks like a five-ton truck with
two jeeps acting as the escort.
They're moving something big.
Well,
that's got to be it. That's the nuke.
Closer!
Doing my best!
I'm inside.
Look for ID numbers.
I'll call up specs.
It wasn't me.
It was Leland's call.
He knew that you
would betray us.
He knew I would do
the right thing.
The ends will justify
what had to be done.
Who are you trying to convince?
Me? Or you?
Gwen,
it's not too late to
put a stop to this.
This couldn't be
what my mom wanted.
Nobody wants this, Angus.
It's what's necessary.
I can't believe that.
Sometimes you just have
to give people a chance.
We gave people a chance.
They failed.
- The world is dying.
- Then give me
a chance to do it the right way.
It doesn't take the whole world.
Sometimes you just need
that one person
that you can count on.
Who you trust.
And, together,
any problem can be solved.
I wish that were true.
You know it is.
I can see it.
This isn't who you are.
This isn't who
my mother hoped you'd become.
Not the place
I'd pick for a family reunion.
- I've got this, Roman.
- Got what, exactly?
Your supposed-to-be-dead nephew
hiding in the back of our truck?
No!
Angus!
- Mac!
- Take my hand.
I still believe in you.
No!
Mac!
Get a little help here?
It was a National Park Service logo
That said "Yellowstone" on it.
Why would they pretend
to be forest rangers?
Volcanoes.
Leland had
a Turner painting of one.
He was talking
about them a lot.
Yeah, but that guy just
sounds buckets of crazy.
Right. But what's
under Yellowstone
is a supervolcano.
Did-did you just say
"supervolcano"?
Yeah. I think they're gonna use
the nuke to somehow set it off.
You know,
I actually did you a favor
because Leland
would've had me kill you.
It's a bumpy road.
I need to concentrate.
Okay, so,
think of a volcanic eruption
like the, uh, popping
of a champagne bottle.
The cork blows out,
and then all of the gases
that are trapped inside,
they suddenly expand
and shoot out.
And Codex is popping
that cork
using a nuclear bomb?
Right. But now imagine
instead of liquid
shooting out,
it's the gases that have been
trapped inside of magma
for hundreds
of thousands of years,
expel ash and cover
the entire western hemisphere.
Summer would disappear
for possibly years.
Wait a second.
Just from one volcano?
Well, yes,
but not just any volcano.
A really, really big one.
The best I can tell, we've been
driving over this thing
for the past two hours.
Without sunlight,
the planet cools,
reversing the greenhouse effect,
which is good.
But it also destroys crops,
causing famine, disease.
It's basically a reset switch.
We need to find that nuke.
Matty, are you still tracking
that convoy?
We're trying.
We haven't spotted them yet.
Actually, I know how to find it.
You do?
Yeah. Before I fell
out of that truck,
I managed to jam my phone
under the loading ramp.
Tracing the signal now.
It's good to have you back, Mac.
Sorry about the, uh...
gun in your face thing.
Eh, what's a gun in the face
between friends?
One lookout.
Truck's empty.
They must have already moved
the bomb.
The Park Service
awarded a contract
to a construction company
to retrofit the dam.
It's been under
repair for a year.
And the president
of that company on paper?
Martin Bishop.
So Codex set up a dummy corp
to run the dam. But why?
I don't know,
but it has something to do with drilling.
Drilling. Wait,
what makes you say that?
Because at the same time
Codex took over the dam,
they started buying up
a bunch of local,
heavy-duty drilling equipment.
Riles, I need a USGS map
of Yellowstone.
Right.
Here you go.
Thanks.
I knew it. Okay, see there,
directly under the dam?
Mm-hmm.
- It's a side vent
to the volcano's
magma chamber.
It's a thousand feet
and some change down,
but it's right there.
They want to aim a nuke
at a river of lava?
No, I think they're gonna blow
a hole where the dam is.
What they want is this river.
Massive amounts of water
flood into the hole
that they drilled,
right into the magma chamber.
Pressure builds, and boom.
Water triggers the
eruption. Thanks.
Good news is, I got a look
at the bomb. It's a B61.
- And you can disarm it?
- No chance.
But what I can do is
build a shaped charge
to interrupt the
chain reaction.
You want to blow up
a nuclear bomb?
Yup. But, hopefully,
we just get
a good old-fashioned,
run-of-the-mill explosion,
no nuke going off,
no mushroom cloud.
If I can find the
right materials, and
if we can find the nuke,
it should work.
I think. Follow me.
Well, if
you're sure.
No sign of the
nuke on these feeds.
Right. We'll cover more
ground searching if we split up.
Riley, you stay here,
keep watch.
Okay.
Hey, guys, I, uh, found some
of Codex's drilling equipment.
And, uh...
...everything I need
to finish my build.
A nuclear explosion
is initiated
by a very precise
conventional explosion.
This pushes
the fusible material together
to start a chain reaction,
but if the material doesn't go
together in just the right way,
you might only get
a partial reaction
or even no nuclear explosion
at all.
So how is...
whatever you're building
supposed to work?
Like a shotgun.
I'm gonna aim it directly at the
nuke, and it should interrupt
the chain reaction.
The time-delay fuse will
give us enough time to clear
the building before it goes off.
Hey, guys,
uh, something's happening.
Codex is bugging out.
- I don't know why.
- I do.
They're getting out of the blast zone.
They armed the nuke.
How do you know that?
Because I'm looking
right at it.
Right, coming at you, Mac.
Auntie Gwen, I presume.
Taylor, wait. Wait.
Dying just
ain't your thing, huh?
You don't want to do this.
I don't want to shoot you...
but it's what has to be done.
That's what
you tell yourself, isn't it?
But I was wrong.
I saw the data, and
I lost hope that people
could change, that...
...that they could be better.
I know that Angus
showed you a better way.
He showed me, too.
He's my family.
I want to help him.
Killing me
doesn't stop this.
The only thing
that does that is helping Angus,
and you're not gonna
get to him in time.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
We have less than six minutes,
and it can't be disarmed.
I know.
That's not the plan.
Interrupt the
chain reaction.
Smart kid.
The time-delay fuse.
It must have broken
when he attacked me.
I'm gonna have
to set it off manually.
This is a one-way trip.
I need you guys to get
as far away from here as
possible, as fast as you can.
The time delay won't work.
I'm gonna set it off myself.
- Mac!
- Don't think!
Just run.
Angus. Go.
I can do this.
What? No, I...
There's
no time. Let me do this.
Please.
For Ellen.
You connect this to, uh...
I know. I got it.
"You deserve the world.
And the world deserves you."
Go.
Run. Now!
Well done.
We have a Nuclear
Emergency Support Team excavating
the Dixon Dam site.
Although Gwen managed to stop
a full-scale nuclear explosion,
we still need to sweep the area
for radiation.
Mac?
We're, uh...
We're sorry about your aunt.
Thanks.
So, what about Codex?
The bunker's empty.
Cleared out.
Looks like Leland took the rest
of Codex into hiding.
We destroyed
their infrastructure
and their plan.
Oh.
Uh, one more thing.
Oh, bloody...
- Ow!
- Oh, bloody,
- Wanking...
- Is that supposed to be swearing?
No, no, it's all right.
No, no.
Thank you.
Your badges.
Welcome back to the Phoenix.
Hilarious.
I'll get you new ones as soon
as possible. In the meantime,
I'm gonna be, uh, out of
action for a while, so, Mac,
you're going to have to
take over my duties, too.
There's a lot of work
to be done out there.
About that.
I think I know
just where to begin.
You ready for this?
Of course, yeah.
It'll be fine.
You're nervous.
I know you better
than you think.
Oh, yeah?
What am I thinking right now?
Third season of Rick
and Morty is the best,
you shouldn't have
had an espresso, and
you really want to fix that
broken light fixture over there.
It was Americano.
Ah.
Desi...
I... am...
Hey, let's not talk
about it, okay?
Yeah, right. Understood.
What I mean, egghead, is,
I don't want to talk
about it right now.
You can buy me a drink,
and we'll talk later.
You got it.
As long as I do
the drink ordering,
because your taste in
drinks is embarrassing.
It was one time.
I'd never seen a Bubblegum
Cosmotini Spritzer before.
- I just wanted to try it out.
- You had two.
Hey, we're ready for you.
Yeah, of course.
- Uh...
- Yes.
Thank you for joining us,
Mr. MacGyver.
We value your opinion.
Thank you very much.
But this is not
about opinions.
It's about science.
Our planet is in trouble.
"Knowing isn't enough.
"We must apply.
"Being willing isn't enough.
We must do."
Da Vinci said that.
And my mother.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Sync & corrections by srjanapala
Let's start with carbon pollution
due to fossil fuels.