Previously, on
"Magnum P.I"...
My one redeeming quality in
this life is that I've always
tried to be a father figure to you.
Man, I was surprised
when you called.
I didn't think you
were up for parole
for another 18 months.
You'd be surprised how far
a charming personality will take you.
How long? Couple of months.
Doc says it's stage IV cancer.
I'm gonna enjoy every
bit of life I got left with you.
My visa's expired.
- What are you gonna do about it?
- Well,
I haven immigration lawyer
who's working on it.
Well, you know, you can always
overstay your visa.
- You have 180 days.
- Yeah.
And 171 days ago,
that might have been an option.
- Everything okay?
- My immigration lawyer.
He filed an emergency appeal,
but it was denied.
And, 'cause I overstayed
so long,
there is a chance that
they'll deny me entirely.
Which means I'll be
moving back to London.
Magnum!
*MAGNUM P.I.*
Season 02 Episode 20
Title: "A Leopard on the Prowl"
Aired on: May 08, 2020
Easy. Easy.
Okay, s-steady, boys.
Steady.
No, no, no, Magnum,
you're doing it all wrong.
How can I be doing it wrong?
I-I haven't even done anything.
Dogs have a pack mentality,
Magnum, right?
In every pack,
there is an alpha.
The alpha has the first
and the last say;
you need to be commanding
and lose all the emotion
from your voice.
- Right?
- Okay.
Whatever you say, Master Yoda.
Sorry,
I-I don't get the reference.
Not a Star Trekfan.
Star Trek?
You got be kidding me.
Yes. Of course I'm kidding you.
That was a test,
which you failed
because you're still being
too emotional.
Now be... the... alpha.
Okay.
- Apollo.
- Magnum,
that is Zeus.
Surely, you can tell them apart.
Of course I can't.
What did I say
about being too emotional?
Okay, okay, okay.
Zeus... sit.
No, too late.Okay.
Ea-Easy, boys,
easy. Heel! They sense your indecisiveness.
Heel.
Okay, which is it, Magnum?
Is it sit or is it heel?
Do they even know
the difference?
Do you?
And don't roll your eyes,
Magnum.
How can you even see that
from over there?
I don't need to see it,
Magnum. I know you. Now focus.
I need to know that you
can look after the lads
whilst I'm in London.
Okay, you know what?
Listen to me, you two maniacs.
I've had enough of this crap,
all right?
I am tired
of you guys terrorizing me.
All right?
I'm the alpha.
I'm the alpha,
and you're gonna do
exactly as I say.
And right now,
I command the both of you...
to sit!
It worked.
Oh, my God.
Higgins!
♪ So on everything
you've got... ♪
Hold on.
You met a woman
in the cancer ward?
Not just a woman, Teddy.
An angel.
Look at you,
you old hound dog.
How did this happen?
I don't know. We were
just the only two patients
not distracted by our cellphones,
so we started talking,
and two hours later,
we're still at it, and ended up
grabbing a bite in the café downstairs.
Wow. That's amazing.
Yeah, we got plans
for next week.
We are going skydiving.
Ha! Ooh!
Hold on, hold on.
You realize
how dangerous that is?
Oh, how dangerous can it be?
What's the worst
that can happen,
man... my chute doesn't open?
I'm dying
of terminal cancer, boys.
I'm checking out either way.
Ice, that is not funny.
All right,
I'll-I'll be right back.
I got to hit the head.
You know, I know
the odds aren't great, but...
I'm glad he decided
to fight this thing.
Yeah.
What are you doing?
Just a little digging.
Ice has been acting weird
lately.
Plus, he's never had a cell.
A cell phone?
Now, that is
suspicious.
Don't mock me, all right?
I can tell something's up.
Ice never has had a cell phone,
even when most guys in prison
had burners.
Hmm.
- What is it?
- It's a text chain
with some number
I don't recognize.
Ice is meeting up
with somebody tonight.
Well, it's probably the woman
he was just talking about.
Nah, not the way
they're texting.
This is a guy.
Ice could be up to something.
He's probably just meeting up
with some dude
to hang out.
Kind of like
we're doing right now.
Yeah.
Ooh, yeah.
Everything good?
Yeah. You ready
for another Coops?
Yes, sir. I gotcha, buddy.
Well, this doesn't look
suspicious at all.
What the hell
you doing here? You know,
I could ask the same
of you, pal.
How'd you find me?
I made sure I wasn't followed.
I put Friend Finder on your
phone at the bar earlier.
Friend what? What-what
the hell is that?
It's an app. You can track your
friends' movements, you know,
in case they decide
to do something stupid.
Now it's your turn.
What's going on?
A score.
I'm hitting up a warehouse
over at Pearl City with a guy.
- You out of your mind?
- Look, it's an easy pinch, man.
I'll be in and
out in under 20.
Nobody gets hurt.
It's a no-brainer.
You just got out.
You want to go back in?
This is none of
your business, kid.
You're family...
that makes it my business.
Rick, I love you, man, I do,
but I'm doing this thing.
So you either turn me in,
or you get in that car,
you drive away...
Only two options here.
Okay.
Give me a hug first,
just in case.
All right.
Come on, man.
All cool.
All right. Be safe, okay?
Always.
Very smooth, kid.
Learned from the best.
Give 'em back.
Eh, you know I can't do that.
Knock it off, Rick.
I'm already late as is.
Why? Just tell me that. Why?
I got this friend,
he needs somebody
to hold his hand.
So why has it got to be you?
Guy had my back in prison.
Ice,
you're a 63-year-old man with lung cancer.
You haven't had a score since the '90s.
You're gonna get caught.
I know what I'm doing.
Ice, it's taken me long enough
to accept the fact
that you're sick.
All right? The only way I can cope
is by enjoying the time
that we still have left.
So hell no, you're not getting
these keys back.
Damn you, kid.
All right.
All right, what?
All right, you win.
You're a stubborn
son of a bitch, you know that?
I learned that from you, too.
Come on,
I'll give you a lift home.
It's gonna look bad,
me backing out like this.
Come on. You're Icepick.
You're a legend.
Your reputation
can take a hit.
Yeah.
I've been working
every angle I can think of
to keep Higgins in Hawaii,
but time's running out.
A few days from now,
she'll be on a plane to London.
She says she'll be back,
but who knows?
Could take a while
for this whole visa thing
to get sorted out.
A lot can happen
between now and then.
Maybe she'll change her mind,
decide London is
where she ought to be.
Maybe she'll meet someone.
One thing seems certain,
though:
it looks like
I'll be without a partner
for the foreseeable future.
On the plus side, I'm getting
two dogs that hate me.
Thomas Magnum.
Hey. It's Adam Noshimuri
with Five-O.
Tani Rey gave me your number.
Yeah. Thanks
for getting back to me.
Of course.
Tani fill you in?
She did.
And I reached out
to an immigration attorney
I know.
He's hooked up a few yakuza
with legit papers.
He says
there might be one option,
but it's a long shot
and very expensive.
Legal?
As far as I know.
He didn't get into details.
Look, I'll text you his contact
info so you can follow up.
Great. Yeah, much appreciated.
No problem.
Hope it works out.
Aloha.Aloha.
An expensive long shot.
Doesn't sound very encouraging,
but it's something.
Gonna need some help, though.
Good thing I know someone
with deep pockets.
Hey, Robin.
It's me.
Ice?
Ice, I know you're in there.
Come on.
We got to talk!
Ice, I'm coming in.
Ice?
Ice!
Oh, man.
Hey, kid.
You lied to me...
You went through
with it anyway.
Yeah, I should've listened
to you, man.
The whole thing went sideways.
Yeah, no kidding.
It's all over the news.
They're saying you guys
killed a security guard. Not me.
No, man, not me.
My-my... my partner.
- You know he was gonna do that?
- No, of course not!
Son of a bitch popped the guard,
then turned the gun on me
before splitting with the cash.
- I was lucky to get away.
- That looks bad.
- I got to get you to the hospital.
- No. No, no hospitals.
You're gonna bleed out.
Then let it bleed out.
I'm getting your ass
to the hospital,
you're gonna tell
the cops what you know.
Ricky, Ricky, forget it!
You were there.
You know who the killer is.
I'm not turning myself in.
I didn't kill nobody
and I didn't steal nothing.
Ice, you got to do something.
I am not gonna spend what time
I got left in a cage.
Besides, I tell Five-O everything I know,
you're gonna end up
there with me.
What happened?
Whose blood is that?
Icepick's.Is he okay?
He's alive.
Listen, I-I need your help.
You heard about that
warehouse that got hit
in Pearl City last night?
Yeah, I-I saw it on the news.
Icepick was there.
Well, you got to tell HPD.
I can't.
Rick, someone died last night.
I know you guys are family,
but this is... Magnum,
it's about more than that.
Look,
I knew it was going down.
I saw Icepick last night.
So you knew about it,
and you didn't do anything?
No, I got in his face,
I told him he couldn't do it.
I told him to turn around
and walk away.
Hell,
I thought he did. I gave him a ride home.
- And he still went through with it?
- Yeah.
You were with him last night,
you had advance knowledge of it.
Considering your relationship,
they're gonna think
you were involved.
That's why I'm here.
If I go to the cops,
we could both end up in prison.
But there's a killer on the loose.
Somebody's got to catch him.
And I'm sorry to put
you guy sin this position,
but I don't know
who else to turn to.
Look, Thomas, I need your help.
Sorry about the blood.
There's some pain medication
in the cabinet next to the fridge.
I didn't want
to come here.
Rick insisted on it.
It's just as well he did.
Tell us about your partner.
His name is Adrian Reese.
We were in Halawa together.
He was getting out,
he had a score lined up,
wanted to pick
my brain about it.
I figure, "I ain't going anywhere, so..."
So you gave him your take on it.
For a roll of commissary stamps
and a pack of smokes, yeah.
But then, I got out early, and
I figured,
"What the hell? I'll hit up Reese,
and maybe he wants
some company."
Where do we find this guy?
I wouldn't know.
Is there any information
you could give us?
Any detail that might help?
No.
Come on, there's got
to be something.
Ice, think.
There's a guy lying dead
in the morgue because of us.
What are you talking about,
"Because of us"?
I didn't see you there.
I should've stopped you. Come on, Rick.
You know you had
nothing to do with this.
No, I should've stayed with him,
made sure he didn't go back.
Instead, I trusted you.
Yeah, well, then you
didn’t learn what I taught you, kid.
- What's that?
- Never trust a crook.
Yo.
Yo, I got your message.
- You all right?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
All right, anything
you need, I got you.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
- Thanks, TC.
- I'm here for him.
If you didn't have
a hole in you,
the two of us
would be having words.
You're a good friend.
Like you should've been?
Look, my boy could go down
- because of what you did.
- All right, TC, just...
take a breath.
No, he's right.
I got myself into this.
I'm the one
who's got to make it right.
Where do you think you're going?
To find Reese.
Yeah, that's not happening.
Magnum's right.
You're in no fit state to go anywhere.
You need to stay here
till you get your strength back.
Let us do our job.
What's this about?
Our client thinks this guy Reese
might be the father
of her child,
so we need to find him and collect DNA.
Well, you need a
court order for that,
unless you plan to raid
his trash in search
of a half-eaten sandwich
or some used dental floss.
Right now, we're just focused
on, uh, tracking him down.
He's gone off grid.
I can let you look at the file,
but you can't take it with you.
Deal.
Here he is.
All right. Thanks.
Hey, listen, I just want to say
I'm sorry to see you go,
but I think you made
the right decision.
I appreciate that.
I hope this one doesn't give
you too much grief while I'm gone.
Heard that.
Let me know when
you get settled.
I'm thinking about taking my
son to Europe for summer vacation.
- Maybe we'll look you up.
- Oh, yeah,
you absolutely have to.
I'd love to show you around.
Okay. It looks like our guy
Reese has a bunch of aliases.
Okay, well,
that's a good place to start.
All right. Thanks, Gordon.
Owe you one.
Just one?
Cheerio.
Hey, when you're back
in London, you don't mind
if I ask you to do stuff
like this for me, right?
Hmm. If I said I would mind,
would it stop you?
Probably not.
And besides, I figure
it's the least you can do,
considering you're kind of
bailing on our partnership.
I'm sorry, but that is not my choice.
Is that why you've been
avoiding me this whole time?
- 'Cause you think l'm abandoning you?
- I'm not avoiding you.
You've been on the surf ski
three times a day
since I told you I was leaving.
- Well, I like to surf-ski.
- No one likes paddling that much, Magnum.
Okay, I take it back.
You're not bailing
on me. I just, um...
I'm disappointed
that you're leaving.
So am I.
Hey.
Anything yet?
We're working on it.
How's Mr. Hofstetler?
He's, uh...
he's sleeping.
What's going on?
Robin's coming to Hawaii.
I told him it wasn't necessary,
that we could
deal with the particulars
of my exit over the phone.
I-I don't think that's it.
What do you mean?
Well, I talked to a guy
from Five-O, and he said
he may know a lawyer
who can help out with this,
but it-it's
very expensive,
so I asked Robin
to look into it.
I wish you hadn't done that.
Why not?
Because Robin’s already done so much for me.
Yeah, you didn't ask
him to do anything. I did. And besides,
it's a long shot.
Uh, almost zero percent chance
that it's
gonna work.
What is it?
I don't know, but
Robin said that, um,
if it doesn't work, he still
wanted to say goodbye.
That's very thoughtful of him.
Yeah, well, that's Robin.
You know, I'd like
to throw you a party
before you go. Uh,
assuming I'm not in jail.
Thank you, Rick.Yeah.
Why don't you go home,
take a shower
and maybe check in on the bar?
Uh, no, I'm-I'm okay.
I'll stick around.
Rick, seriously,
go take care of yourself.
We've got this.
All right. Well, uh,
call me if you find Reese.
I feel bad for him.
Shouldering the weight of this problem.
He shouldn't blame himself.
I don't think it's that.
I-I just think he feels like...
Icepick betrayed him.
Well, he's not wrong.
I mean, if it were me,
I don't know
that I would protect him.
Yeah, I don't think
I would, either.
But it's complicated.
I mean, without Icepick,
Rick probably would've ended up
on a very different path.
Rick feels like he owes him.
Yeah.
Oh. I have something.
Reese used one of his aliases
to check
into the Honua Lani Inn.
Then let's head over there.
But, uh...
But, um, this is the
picture of the guy.
216.
Promise me you won't use
that fake badge when I'm gone.
This little piece of tin
opens a lot of doors, okay?
So that's a no?
It-it helps me do my job.
Asking me not to use it
is like asking Steph
Curry not to use his jump shot.
A jump shot... - Yeah, we have basketball
in England, Magnum.
The door's been busted open.
Mr. Hofstetler.
He ain't here.
We must've just
missed him.
You lied to us.
Yeah, well, I didn't
want you more involved
than you already are.
So you were just gonna execute
a man in cold blood?
He didn't hesitate to pull
the trigger on that guard.
Last night could've been a clean score,
but that wasn’t good enough for Reese.
No, no, he wanted
to have it all for himself,
and he didn't want
to leave any witnesses.
20 years ago,
I never would’ve trusted a guy like that.
Because I did...
you're all in a fix now.
Maybe you can
still do some good.
Tell us what you know about
Reese so we can find him.
Yeah, then what?
Then we turn him in.
Figure out some way to
keep you and Rick out of this.
Man, you don't get it.
I don't want
to put him back behind bars.
I want someone
to stick him in the ground.
It's the only way you stop a man like that.
He's evil.
Even if you are right,
that's not what Rick
wants us to do.
Hey, boss. Yeah?
- There was a guy in
here looking for you. - Who?
He didn't leave his name.
He's sitting in the booth over there.
All right, thanks.
Funny. I've been
looking for you.
Walk.
Walk. All right.
Where's the car?
Take it easy.
It's the Porsche.
Good. Let's go for a ride.
Okay. Where do you want to go?
You're gonna take me
to Icepick. Let's go.
If he moves off that sofa,
shoot him. You got it.
♪ Oh, girls
♪ They want to have fun.
Rick.
Okay. We're on our way.
We got to go.
Okay,
I know it doesn't look like it,
but I swear I got in
some pretty good shots.
- Yeah, sure, you did.
- I did, seriously.
- And I believe you.
- It doesn't sound like you do, Theodore.
Guys, please.
What did he want?
He wanted to finish what
he started with Ice.
Yeah, dude must've seen
coverage of the robbery,
heard that there was only
one dead body instead of two,
knew he messed up.
Yeah, well, if he's hunting Icepick,
it's only a matter of
time before he finds him.
I'm more concerned
about you at the moment.
I'm gonna be fine.
Maybe now you are.
But Reese knows that
you can link him to that heist.
He's gonna want you dead, too.
Ah, he's got the money. If he was smart,
he'd get off this rock
while he still can.
If he was gonna do that,
he would've done that yesterday.
Think he's more concerned
with tying up loose ends.
You sure?
It sounds risky.
I guess it's better than
looking over your shoulder
for the rest of your life.
We don't have a choice.
We have to bring
the fight to Reese.
We have to find him
and take him down
before he gets to Rick
and Icepick.
You guys got any leads?
None of Reese's other aliases
from HPD panned out,
but Icepick did mention
another name
he's been using.
Carl Brewer.
We're looking into it now.
All right, well, I'm
staying here with Orville
until this whole
thing's over.
I don't need a bodyguard.
- I'm staying.
- He's staying.
I don't know you too well,
but the way
you're looking at me,
feels like you might
want to use that thing.
Believe me, I'm tempted.
No one was supposed
to get killed.
Given your experience,
you had to know
that was still a possibility.
I've been on the inside
for a long time.
Being on the prowl...
That's... it's what I do.
I couldn't resist
one last score.
I really didn't want anyone
to get hurt.
Uh-huh.
What about Rick?
What about him?
He's like your son.
You're supposed to protect him.
I always have.
Best I could.
Until now.
You put him
and everyone I love in danger.
And for what? Money?
You only care
about yourself.
Should be ashamed.
I am.
Wasn't about the money, though.
Then why'd you do it?
I haven't got that long left.
I just wanted to
feel like... it used to.
I needed something
to make me feel alive again.
Really, really alive.
If only for
just one night.
Figure what have I got left
to lose?
You had Rick.
Wasn't that enough?
It should've been.
I guess I've been lying to
myself about being at peace.
Truth is...
...I'm not ready
to die just yet.
- Anything on Carl Brewer?
- Yeah.
Reese actually used that
alias to get a cellular data plan.
Oh, okay. Score one for Icepick.
- Mm-hmm.
- Ping the phone yet?
Why is it, everything that
comes out of your mouth is a query?
What? I'm driving.
You're laptop-ing.
Laptop-ing?
It's just not my thing.
Firstly, "laptop-ing" is not a word.
And secondly, you really ought
to make it your thing, Magnum,
if you're gonna continue
your business without me.
Well, maybe you can teach me
before you leave.
I have days, Magnum, not months.
And as to your query, I can't ping
Mr. Brewer's cell phone
because it's dead.
But according
to his cell phone records,
he did call one number
more frequently than most,
and that belongs to a...
Leon Yates.
Name sounds familiar.
Could you pull up the news
coverage from the robbery? Uh-huh.
Leon Yates
was the armed guard who
was killed during the heist.
Seems he wasn't such an
innocent victim after all.
No, he's more like
an inside man.
Which would explain
how Reese knew
that there was a safe
full of cash in the warehouse.
Yates have any family?
Says here he was survived
by a girlfriend...
Cynthia Lloyd in Kalihi.
Maybe she knows something.
Ms. Lloyd?
Yes?
- I'm Jan Hawks.
- This is Travis McCoy.
We're investigating
the warehouse robbery
on behalf of its insurance company.
We're very sorry
for your loss.
We heard your
boyfriend Leon
was a very dedicated
security guard.
Do you mind
if we ask you a few questions?
Do we have to do this now?
We understand
it's a difficult time for you.
Generally, in these circumstances,
it's better to move quickly.
We'll only take a minute.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
I, um...
I just don't know
how I can help.
For starters, you can tell us
if you recognize this man.
No. I've never
seen him before.Okay.
So, you, uh... you
live here alone, huh?
Just me.
This is, um,
you and Leon, huh?
Looks like
Wailua Falls.
Last Christmas.
Thank for your time.
We're very,
uh... very sorry for your loss. Jan.
We'll call you if we
have any more questions.
Our sincere condolences.
Can't let you leave just yet.
Lock the door.
Look... we mean no disrespect.
We're just working
for our clients.
Clients, right.
Friends of Rick.
Looked him up online.
Saw a press conference,
you guys got back from the sandbox
few years ago.
P.O.W. heroes.
Okay. You got me.
But this doesn't
look like a hostage situation.
On a hunch, I'd say these two
had something going on
behind Leon's back.
So, what, you use Leon,
stab him in the back,
and then steal his girl?
Not in that order, but yeah.
What do you want?
You're gonna call your buddy.
You're gonna bring him
and the old man down
here, and if you don't,
it's lights-out
for old Mary Poppins here.
Thomas, what's up?
Good news.
We got a lead on Reese.
Yes. I love you guys.
Seriously, Mai tais for life.
Or any other beverage
of your choosing.
What's wrong with Mai tais?
I'm just saying it's not your
best cocktail, that's all.
And you're just now telling me this?
Eh, Kammy said it, too.
Kammy said it? Rick, listen,
I think we have a way
to draw him out,
but we're gonna need
Icepick's help.
Do you think he's up for it?
Yeah,
of course. Anything to get this guy.
Okay, uh, great.
I'm gonna need you to be my QRF,
just like in the Korengal.
But, uh...
I'll shoot you the address
in a second.
- Yeah. Yeah, you got it.
- All right.
Thanks.
- That was weird.
- Right?
QRF?
We were his primary unit.
Yeah, and we didn't have
a QRF in the Korengal.
That's the whole reason the
Talis were able to grab us
when Hannah sold us out.
Thomas is sending us a message.
He and Higgins are in trouble.
Yeah.
So, what happens
when they get here?
- Kill all four of us?
- Or five.
She's a witness, too.
Wha-What?
Don't listen to 'em, babe.
They're just messing with your head.
Another workout of you,
last words you ever say.
Gordon. Save it.
Your pal Icepick is going
down for murder one,
and you helped
cover it up.
That makes you an accessory.
I get that.
You could face charges.
I know. We don't really have
time for that right now.
Yeah, he's right.
Let's just get our friends back
and worry about the rest later.
Stay on comms.
And these are to be
used only if necessary.
Sure you don't want
to give me the bigger gun?
Just follow me.
Reese is armed. He's got Thomas,
Higgins
and the homeowner
in the living room.
But there could be
other hostiles
in there I can't see.
Make the call.
♪ Oh, girls, they want to...
It's Rick.
Put it on speaker.
♪ Oh, girls...
Rick. What's going on?
We're on our way.
Should be there
in about ten minutes.
Okay. See you soon.
All right,
it's go time. You got two entry points,
- front and back.
- Copy that.
Front door.
- There's someone out there.
- Son of a bitch!
Gordon!
He hit my vest.
Go get him.
Don't move!
Terrific.
Magnum!
You okay?
Yeah.
How did you know
I wasn't gonna go flying
off the top of that thing?
I knew you'd do something.
How?
Because after two years,
Magnum, I think I know you.
Better late than never, I guess.
Mind if I have a moment?
You got a minute.
Hey.
Listen, I'm sorry
for everything, kid.
I know you are.
I was just, uh, scared
of wasting away.
Looking for one last thrill.
I should've gone skydiving.
Hey, look,
I don't want you
to feel bad for me.
I lived my life
the way I wanted to.
And most parts,
I'm... I'm proud of,
other parts not so much.
But the part that
had to do with you...
...I'm most proud of that.
'Cause you turned out
to be one hell of a man.
And always be grateful for them.
Family.
That's all we got... in the end.
I'll see you soon.
I love you.
♪ When you think
you're all alone... ♪
Expect to hear from the
prosecuting attorney.
♪ No matter what
you're going through ♪
♪ I will look after you...
We got you,
brother.
Higgins is leaving today.
I did everything I could
to keep her here.
I'm not sure if there was
anything else I could've done.
She drives me crazy,
but I got to admit,
I'm really gonna miss her.
♪ When you get knocked down
and you've had enough ♪
♪ I will look after you
♪ Oh... ♪
I trust that Magnum will look
after you as I have done.
Try not to be too hard
on him, all right?
I know it doesn't look like it
from the outside, but
he can be quite fragile.
That being said, do give him
a nick once in a while,
remind him who's boss.
I'm gonna miss you.
Juliet?
TC just landed.
Mr. Masters is here.
Okay.
Good boy. He's a good boy.
Yes.
♪ I will look after you
♪ Someday it will come to be.
Looks like Robin made it.
He's up at the house.
So, I guess this is it.
Actually... it's not.
Turns out I don't ha veto leave after all.
What do you mean?
Robin met with the attorney, and together
they resolved my visa status.
It's all taken care of.
So you're not going?
Uh, you want me to?
No.
Not at all. I'm just...
...surprised.
What did they do?
It turns out,
there's this obscure law in the book
that says if you own a
company that’s valued at $500,000
and you have at least five employees,
then you're entitled to a visa.
Yeah, but you don't have that.
No. No, I don't.
But, uh...
...thanks to Robin, I now do.
I still don't understand.
Robin's just signed over
full ownership of his estate to me.
You now own Robin's Nest?
Yes. And all of its contents.
And with employees like
Kumuas cultural curator and,
well, you as security consultant,
amongst the others,
I'll be allowed to retain my
legal resident status.
So, technically,
we now work for you?
Well, yes, I mean,
there's no "technically" about it,
actually, Magnum.
You and all the other employees
are now on my payroll.
Okay.
How is this gonna work?
That remains to be seen.
Anyway, best not keep Robin waiting.
You know,
I'm not sure l like this new setup.
Well, Magnum, you kind of
only have yourself to blame.
You were the one that put
this whole thing in motion.
I didn't know this
was gonna happen.
What about the Ferrari?
Oh, the Ferrari?
Yes, well, technically,
that's now mine.
You know, I think
I might rechristen it.
Higgins 2. What do you think?
I hate it.
Ah, reckon I will, then.
Captioned by Media Access Group at WGBH
Sync corrections by srjanapala