Perfection itself.
Not me, the music.
Well, that is the
mystery of Mozart.
But his life was less
than perfect, right?
No.
He said his peace.
He wrote his requiem.
He died at 34, was buriedin an unmarked grave.
That is not only a mystery.
That is a crime.
Take it again, please.
Good morning, Mr. Barudi.
Consider it done.
I'll see you on Wednesday.
I think I found my coat.
MAN : Can you clean it?
I don't know yet.
MAN : How about tonight?
Maybe.
MAN : Good luck.
Yeah.
WOMAN 1: He wanted what?
WOMAN 2: Music sent to him.
WOMAN 1: That's upstairs.
SALES CLERK: Can I help
you with something?
THEA: Yeah.
Hi.
I'm looking for Mozart K.488 with Brendel and St.
Martin-in-the-Fields.
For some reason, it's
been on order for weeks
and it just doesn't come in.
I do have Jean Bernard
Pommier with Perlman.
It's quite good.
Yeah.
Well, I think I
would really like
to try to find the Brendel one.
Sorry.
We don't have it.
- All right.
Well, thanks anyway.
MAN : Lost and found.
I've lost my coot.
MAN : Relax.
Take a steam bath tonight.
OK.
You look good, Alex.
This steam did wonders for you.
So whose toes did
I step on this time?
No one's toes,
simply rules, Alex.
Things went smoothly.
That's your complaint?
You're too much of a maverick.
That's my complaint.
Oh, Nahmi.
Listen, Alex.
Some people feel that yourcover has been compromised.
Some people are wrong.
I don't know about that.
It is safe, Nahmi.
Maybe.
I know where  is.
I know.
I've been given complete
discretion on this one.
I choose the team.
I'm available.
Oh, you better be, Alex.
Because Barudi is
just the beginning.
He's Masudi's executor.
Once he's out, you'll beable to get to Dr. Kesler.
You know he was once shortlistedfor the Nobel Prize in Physics?
Oh, yeah?
Oh, yeah.
He's a very noble guy.
He'll sell his soul
to the highest bidder.
And his soul will lead
us directly to Masudi.
ALEX :
My work brought
me to the town where you live.
My work is a series of surmises,assumptions, and risks.
I chose this work, because Inever loved anyone, except you.
Although all my life,I've been trying to love.
I can offer no explanation,
other than what
I'm about to tell you now.
For as long as I can remember,I've been searching for you.
I knew that you existed,
but I didn't know where.
You'll never have anopportunity to ask me questions.
But my voice will reach
you through my letters.
And I know that you read them.
I've devoted my life totough and disagreeable work,
because I needed to love.
Therefore, I loved
the country I served,
her mountains, her valleys,her dust and despair.
I acted as I did
through lack of choice.
I didn't know if I
would ever meet you.
THEA'S MOM: Thea.
ALEX : And now, nowthat we've met, it's too late.
What a baby.
ALEX : There'sbeen a mistake, in dates
and places and everything.
I'm quite sure that it
was me who was intended
to be tormented, not you.
Anyways, It's far, far too late.
Can you hear me?
I love you.
I've loved you all my life.
Don't be angry.
Don't take pity.
I never knew happiness,
until I found you.
Hi.
WOMAN 3: Sorry to be late.
He's really, really strange.
What do you mean?
Like weird strange?
Or like interesting strange?
No, no, no.
More like mysterious strange.
What do you mean?
Mysterious, as
in full of mystery.
I don't know.
Well, I don't think
it's mysterious at all.
Check out Jock Boy, 11 o'clock.
It's got to be him.
That guy?
I'm telling you.
That guy has been
gaga for you forever.
There's this girl.
She's in my class.
She knows him.
I think he's an economics major.
Huh.
For a numbers guy, hewrites pretty good poetry.
That guy writes poetry?
Excuse me.
Hi.
I'm G.R.
I'm Thea.
Yeah.
I know.
We need to talk.
Well, now?
I act--
No.
We could actually--
Go out some time?
Actually, how about tonight?
At 9:00.
I'll pick you up.
OK.
It's OK.
I know where you live.
You do.
Right.
OK.
I'll see you at 9 o'clock.
Bye.
It's a great place.
Yeah.
I know you like Spanishpoetry and that kind of thing.
So--
I suspect I'm not alone.
My father is from Cordoba.
I know.
I can't believe I'm
finally out with you.
I'm glad it-- itwasn't far, far too late.
What does G.R. stand for?
If I told you, I
don't think you'd
want to go out with me again.
I thought we were never
supposed to meet anyway.
Granville, Granville Rhodes.
My parents thought an unusualname might build character.
It certainly did.
Why economics if you havesuch a gift with words?
Excuse me?
Come on.
I know it's you.
What's me?
THEA: The letters, these
incredible letters.
What about them?
Excuse me.
I'll be right back.
Where's the ladies'
room, please?
Thank you.
G.R.: Would you come to themasquerade ball with me?
THEA: Yeah.
Sure.
So you really like
these letters, huh?
Yeah.
Well, thank you
for an amazing night.
Thank you.
It was great.
Yeah.
All right.
Good night.
Bye.
ALEX :
You're my greatest
loss, a loss that was recoveredonly when it was too late.
Believe me, if you and I
are what I think we are,
there's no need for
us to force the issue.
Today, I give you this bookof etchings of a Picasso.
Listen to the stories
that are there for you.
Listen close and
tell me, can you
hear the beating things inside?
Thea, I dreamed
about you last night.
Hi, baby.
Hi
How you doing?
Did I get any mail today?
No.
Just newspaper, regular stuff.
Why?
- Oh.
Nothing.
ALEX :
I had to do it.
Not to learn something aboutyou which I didn't already know.
Perhaps it was a childishwish to look into this room
and find that I was right.
You belong to a world
that I've lost long ago.
You're not my mistake, Thea.
In my work, I must nevermisjudge people's characters,
because if I were tomake a mistake even once,
I might have to pay
for it with my life.
If I had been wrong
about you, I should
have been dead a long time ago.
We can't meet.
And we can't be united.
I do not fear for myself, Thea.
I've learned that I'malso dangerous to be near.
I am a man with two hearts,and only one will survive
when all is said and done.
As the  said,
THEA :
Why are you so sad?
Please, don't be angry if Itell you that I can't accept
your lunatic explanation
that all your life
you have been waiting for me.
If you really have, then
you are truly insane.
But you're not insane.
I know it's not true.
In which case, what are you?
I've been reading yourletters for almost a year.
At times, I wish you'dnever started writing to me.
Now, I want you never to stop.
ALEX :
Are we cutting class today?
THEA: You scared me.
Sorry.
I'm just tired.
What's up?
Nothing.
I--
Ugh.
It's your secret mad letterwriter again, isn't it?
Are they still coming?
Yes.
Almost every day now.
You know, this guy
could be a weirdo.
No, he's not like that.
How do you know?
I just do.
MAN : Hello?
Mr. Barudi?
MAN : One moment, please.
MR. BARUDI : Hello?
Do we really go toschool with so many people?
I only recognize
half of these faces.
Dude, I don't play requests--
usually.
That fan is the perfect touch.
You would say
that, wouldn't you?
No, no.
I mean it.
ALEX: May I have this dance?
Do you mind?
No.
I-- I'll get us a drink.
WAITRESS: Hi.
Hello.
What beer do you have?
WAITRESS: Heineken.
- Perfect.
Great.
WAITRESS: All right.
, please.
That is a truly fine
piece of machinery.
Thank you.
I used to own one.
Really?
Mhm.
What do you drive now?
A Lamborghini, Countach.
But I still keep
my GX for the city.
I would give anything todrive a Lamborghini Countach.
You like cars, huh?
I love cars.
Well, your 308 is nothing tosniff it, once you get to know.
What do you mean?
With a few
tricks, your 308 can
give you as much performanceas you'd ever want.
How long have you had it?
G.R.: Actually, I just got it.
It was a graduation
gift from my dad.
Have you opened it up yet?
I'm sure could be openedup a little bit more.
ALEX: You're right.
There's a way to completelyopen her up quickly.
And it only works
on that Ferrari.
Really?
Really.
What do you do, G.R.?
Well, like I said, I'm
just about to graduate.
ALEX: What's your major?
G.R.: Economics.
ALEX: Sounds serious.
G.R.: Well, yeah.
It is.
I mean, I am.
How about you, George?
What do you do?
I'm a financial planner.
So you like-- like, youplan people's futures, right?
Yes.
You may say so.
G.R.: Cool, cool.
So a car like this
must get you plenty
of attention from the ladies.
Am I right?
Well, I--
I don't know.
You know?
I'm-- I'm seeing someone.
So I hadn't really noticed.
You're a lucky guy.
G.R.: Well, it is.
You know, she's amazing.
I hope to marry her some day.
Young man like you,
ready to settle down?
G.R.: Yeah.
She's incredible.
I-- you know, I don't
want to blow it.
Yeah, you might want toslow down here a little bit.
I'd, um-- I'd bring
it down a little bit.
Just-- just bring
it down a little.
I think I got it.
I got the hang of it.
You can bring it down
a little bit now.
Jesus.
I'm sorry, but I have toleave you by the next phone.
I'll find my way back.
Don't worry.
G.R.: Are you sure?
ALEX: Yeah.
I'll be fine.
It's all in there.
You can get the same out of her.
Yeah.
I'm going to.
All right.
G.R., do me a favor,
stay on the highway.
Sure.
Yeah.
Hey, thank you.
I hope to see you again,
have a drink sometime.
Yeehaw.
Come on.
Keep moving.
Let's go.
Move.
Come on.
Keep it moving, buddy.
Keep it moving.
Let's go.
No.
We shouldn't be
having this meeting.
I shouldn't have agreed.
We're losing time
and I have no time.
You have as much
time as we give you.
Things are right on course.
I want to meet Kesler now.
It's time to close in on Masudi.
Set it up.
We may be old friends, butI think you forget yourself.
I want to finish with it now.
That kind of talk
worries me, Alex.
We have to wait.
I've waited long enough.
An now, it's time.
This is what we do
for a living, we wait.
It's what our damn
business is about.
You don't go after them.You let them come to you.
It's different now.
Understand?
Will you set it up?
Please.
All right.
But we involve nobody else.
I'll back you up myself.
Thanks.
Darling, look
what just arrived.
Aren't they beautiful?
Thea?
I'm going to make
some lunch now.
And don't forget, you
promised you'd take
a walk with me this afternoon.
The fresh air is gonnado us both a lot of good.
ALEX : It was alla mistake, Thea, like my life.
I've no right to bother
you with words now.
And I certainly have
no rights to send
you any unnecessary reading.
I know that you have wordsthat you need to say.
So that's what I suggest.
Put your letters to mein an envelope marked Mr.
Franz Kafka, post
restante, and send
it to your local post office.
I'll be there to
collect your letters.
Post restante, please.
Great.
Thank you.
Is it you?
I know you're here.
Do you like watching
me, Mr. Kafka?
What for?
You're a coward.
You're dead.
You're nothing.
THEA :
Where are you now?
You can't remain silent forever.
You can't hide anymore.
I don't know if you had
a hand in G.R.'s death,
but I must leave, run awayfrom you, from your letters,
and from everything that'sso miserable between us.
I'm not as wonderful as
you make me out to be.
Look how you dominate me.
So many times I was amusingmyself with the thought
that you might be
around, very close.
Now, I'm doubting if
you really do exist.
Are you safe there
in the shadow?
It's OK.
Stay in hiding.
It's easier.
You're afraid
because of me, right?
Because you don't
want me to get hurt?
Well, I don't mind getting hurt.
I don't mind being touched.
Come on.
Step out.
I'm here.
Mr. Milan.
You took care for
the money, Mr. Milan.
We've opened aconfidential account at Swiss
Central Bank in your name.
I must have
absolute assurance.
There is the account number.
It could be a false account.
Call them now to
assure yourself.
The bank's number is 473-6409.
Please.
Phone, please.
Thank you.
Please.
Customer service, please.
Private accounts.
Yes.
My account number is 96610992.
I would like to know the
status of my account.
Yes.
Yes, Rudy Kesler.
Thank you.
I'm impressed.
And now, Dr.
Kesler, the goods.
The goods.
These are the last
photographs of him.
He has changed.
Where is he now?
Claridge Hotel, New York.
And now, Mr. Milan,
let's drink to progress.
You continue to lead the
good life and I as well.
May we all receive what
we so richly deserve.
Cheers.
Dr. Kesler.
Mr. Milan.
Please.
NAHMI: We're almost there, kid.
Hold on.
Hold on, Alex.
Hold on, kid.
We're almost there.
Who is it?
KIM: Thea, it's Kim.
Oh my god.
Hi.
How are you?
Wow.
You look great.
Oh.
I-- I wasn't expecting anybody.
Apparently not.
Oh, come in.
You want anything to drink?
We're getting drunk.
That's enough.
So have you even left theapartment since you got here?
I go to class.
That doesn't count.
Yes, it does.
You didn't get any moreof those letters, did you?
No.
Have you met
anybody nice here?
No.
I've been really busy.
KIM: No.
You've been keeping
yourself busy.
There's a difference.
I'm not against
going out with someone.
It just hasn't happened yet.
Thea, you have to
make something happen.
You know that.
Look, this is what
you're gonna do, OK?
You're gonna out.
You're gonna find a boy.
Then, you're gonna ask him ona date for this Friday night.
Well, Friday I have aguest lecture in the morning.
Then, I have to go to class.
Then, I have stacks
of work, because I
have a paper due on Monday.
I'm fine.
I-- I'm fine.
Good morning.
It is a beautiful,clear July day in Grenada.
The year, 1936 .
The phalangists occupy thecity, but the mood is mild.
It is on that day that FredericoGarcia Lorca, poet, playwright,
artist is executed
and his body is
thrown into an unmarked grave.
He was 38.
There are those who look
upon the death of Lorca
as a much greater symbol ofthe conflict of that region
in general, not the
political conflict,
but the deeper chasm
towards utter brutality
that lies in man.
The  wrote,
One body with littleblood, but with two hearts.
Is that to say that there isnot enough blood in the body
to keep two heart alive or
that two hearts can turn
thin veins into a
nurturing river?
We have to keep an eye on thoseopposing hearts, because--
Yes, come in.
Dr. Treanda?
NICOS: Sit down.
I'll be right with you.
My heart is in the East, butI am at the edge of the West.
Then, how could
I taste what I eat?
How can I enjoy it?
You're familiar with HaLevi?
Yes.
So you are here in responseto my plea for an assistant?
Sure.
I'd be delighted.
LECTURER: Wonderful.
I have the paper for theChicago lecture on Wednesday.
I checked all the references.
But I wasn't sure about the you wanted--
- For the opening.
- Yeah.
You marked a few.
So--
We're all done.
I don't think that I shouldkeep you waiting any longer.
No.
You shouldn't.
Hello?
ALEX : Thea, it's me.
I've been shot.
And the only reason I'm stillalive is because of you.
I wanted to talk to you.
I wanted to hear your voice.
This is as close
as we'll ever get.
Anything else is
just impossible.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I love you.
I want you to come
with me to New York.
I want you to meet
my mom, my friends.
I want you to know everything.
You're sure that's
what you want?
Yes.
You're sure?
Yeah.
Cause you shouldn't stay withme if you think I'm half a man.
You deserve better.
I want you.
I want to get on with
my life, our life.
Thank you.
TAXI DRIVER: Thank
you very much.
Thank you.
Scotch, please.
Hi, Mom.
Hi.
Hello.
You look wonderful.
This is Nicos.
Oh.
This is Mom.
How do you do, Nicos?
Very nice to meet.
Oh, it's good to meet you.
Well, I'm glad you
two found each other.
She really needs somebody.
Mom, should we show
Nicos to his room?
Oh, yes.
And I put some warm blankets outin the hall if you need them.
And there's some clean
towels in the bathroom.
And your mail's up on your desk.
All right.
Nicos, you're teachingSpanish literature, correct?
Yes.
ALEX : Thisis my last letter to you.
I know that we should meetand the hour is not far away.
You've never sinned
against me but once.
My terrible and
wonderful angel, it
is I alone who have broughtabout this abominable state
of affairs in which
we find ourselves.
I was hesitant, tried tohave it my way, a coward,
and miserable and
despicable coward,
someone who was privilegedto know of your existence
before he met you, should havebeen with you all the days
of his life, with you alone.
But I rested on the way.
I stopped off.
I left signs.
I left everything behind, Thea.
We're so close now.
No fear.
No regret.
Just freefall.
Look at it.
Look at me.
The letters have come to life.
I know.
Go.
I love you.