999 emergency
help me, I got lost while hiking
hello?
Hello? Can you hear me?
I can hear you, was it an accident?
I told you I got lost
do you know where you are?
Sai kung east
sai kung east
"465407"
is that it? "465307"?
Yes
sir, what do you see?
"233421"
sir, neither of those coordinates
are in sai kung
help
hello?
- My badge number is "238448"
- Hello?
You're a police officer?
I need to know your position
hello?
Hello? Can you hear me?
Sir? I can't hear you clearly
what do you see around you?
You came from sai kung east?
Can you hear me?
Hello?
Sir? Can you hear me?
Send someone here
hello?
Mom, I'm going to work
ying, don't leave yet
pay respect to your father
It's been seven years
since he's gone missing
I'm getting his death certificate later
Here, have some water
Remember to take your pills at 3pm
I'm going to work now
who are you?
Mom, I'm ching, your son
I don't know you
mom, I'm mak chi ching
what are you doing here?
I put you to bed last night, remember?
You're a stranger here, right?
Are you trying to steal from me?
- Help, thief!
- Mom...
Ying, I'm sorry for the noise
do you need help?
It's okay, don't worry about it
yes
sure, I'll send it to you by two o'clock
I'm ready
thank you
Morning ying - morning
new case, husband's been missing for a year
with a six year old daughter at home
thanks
Help her, missing a father
is a lot of trouble
ying
someone's here for you.
Thanks
suet wing, what's wrong?
Are you okay?
My mom has decided to marry that man
she's been neglecting me ever
since she was with him
keep going, I'm listening
it's like my dad has gone missing
I can't seem to reach him
but he's dead to me anyway
I'm always home alone...
Ying, ying
bye-bye
miss sit?
- Miss sit.
- Yes?
You should've told me
if you didn't wanna listen
suet wing
I get it, miss sit
thank you, I can handle by myself
you can reach me anytime
Hello? Nam?
Ying, there's news about wah
come to the police station
Nam
nam
A hiker found this two days ago
and brought it to us
here, you can keep his badge
the police
will no longer be involved in this case
it's been seven years since the incident
our protocol states
that we can't continue the investigation
his badge is best in your keeping
in my keeping?
I kept a lot of things too
but what's the point?
I thought you asked me to come up here
to let me know if there
were any developments
now that we've found his
badge, there's hope
but you're telling me
you're gonna stop investigating?
Ying, calm down
you know I want to find wah as well
where did you find his badge?
At wah's last known location
around the snake stone in sai kung
who found it?
A regular citizen
but something doesn't feel right to him
I want to meet him
alright
I want to know, where did
you find this badge?
I'm not obliged to say anything
but whatever I say,
can't be used in a court of law
hey, she's asking you a question
I've already answered you before, madam
you don't belive me, yet you've asked
your subordinate to question me
what do you want?
I'm not a cop
this is my father,
he's been missing for a long time
please tell me more
it's a place that doesn't exist on map
hey, what are you doing?
Don't you wanna know where I went?
Open the gate now!
What did you think I would do?
Alright
since neither of you believe me, leave now
I believe you
I want to know where you found this badge
please tell me, I beg you
many people have searched for him
for seven years
but we've found nothing
you were the only one who found something
so I want you to tell me more
as you said, it's been seven years
he'd be dead even if we found him
at least I'd have an answer
I won't give up until I find him
what if I told you
when I was there
I saw my wife who died five years ago?
Would you believe me?
Yes, I would
but what I say would sounds ridiculous
I don't want others to think I'm a lunatic
nam
It's an enchanted realm
it was a very foggy day
before I went into the enchanted realm,
I kept going on the same path
after god-knows how long, I finally left
but I couldn't locate myself on a map
and my compass doesn't work
I kept walking and walking
it must've been more than seven days
but it never got dark
I never got hungry or thirsty
I saw a lot of people walk by
hey
but they couldn't hear me at all
finally, I saw a beam of light
I walked towards it
And there she was, my late wife
as I was approaching
I came back out
I went back to the mountains a few times
but I couldn't get into the enchanted realm
how did you get in in the first place?
I have no idea
but I think it's a realm
that is fluid in nature
it doesn't have a fixed entrance or exit
and certain conditions need to be met
in order to get in
I'm still trying to figure it out
for the first few months
after my father went missing
I was at the mountains every day
but I never crossed into
the enchanted realm
I found his badge at the enchanted realm
if you couldn't get in,
you wouldn't be able to find him
so you're saying
that my father is in that realm?
Yes
enough
ying, let's go
this is absolute nonsense
let me ask you
are your dreams real?
Yes - why?
Because they feel real
but how can you quantify your feelings?
Do you have tangible evidence?
And the place you were in your dream
was it real?
A dream is a dream, what are you on about?
Ying, he's crazy
why are you still listening to him?
I guess it's time for this lunatic
to take his pills
both of you, leave
I beg you, please tell
me more about the realm
get out!
Let's go
ying, ying
it's been seven years
if he's really still alive,
he wouldn't be in the mountains
a badge doesn't mean much
can you be more rational about this?
He said he was up there for seven days
I've asked his family,
and they said he was gone for a few hours
he's a lying lunatic
the police weren't able to find anything
of his for the past seven years
but this so-called lunatic found something
that belonged to my dad
should I believe him, or you?
I want to find wah as well
but that doesn't mean
I'm gonna believe anything anyone says
I know you think this is ridiculous
but I choose to believe
at least there's a glimmer of hope
Slowly, be careful
don't worry, I can handle by myself
ching loves you,
that's why he hired a maid for you
why did you have to fire the maid?
That bastard kid
no, I've already submitted it
wait a second
sorry, Vincent
yes, it's at home, sorry
I'll submit it first thing tomorrow morning
ying ma, sorry for the trouble today
I'll hire a new maid as soon as possible
no worries, I was free today
I was just chatting with Mrs. mak
I'm fine now, why do I need a maid?
Mom...
You're not listening to me,
you're being unfilial
bastard kid
Sorry, I appreciate your help today
I'm off tomorrow, I can take care of her
thanks for letting me
store stuff at your place
don't mention it
alright, I should be heading back
- sure, I'll send you out.
- Okay
I'm off, Mrs. mak
- bye-bye.
- Bye-bye
"Unlocking the secrets of
an enchanted realm in sai kung"
"Retired cop goes missing for one week,"
"netizens claim that
he's lost in an enchanted realm"
"officer sit still missing
after seven days"
Mom
ying
I was at Mrs. mak's place all day,
I didn't have time to cook
let's eat out
what about the caretaker?
Mrs. mak fired her
she's getting more and more stubborn
it must be so difficult for ching
Mom - hmm?
Someone found dad's badge in the mountains
Isn't that some kind of hope?
But did they find him?
Ying, why do you insist on being like this?
That's my father
you lost your father, I
also lost my husband
we have to move on
mom...
I'm going out
No one would believe you, but I believe you
remember that
Auntie?
My mom's asleep,
if you wanna listen to music, turn it down
okay, I know
Ying
why are you dressed like that?
Aren't we going hiking?
There's an extra ticket
for a band show tonight
don't be angry
don't band shows start at night?
Shouldn't I have dinner with
whoever treated me to this show?
I'm your dad, you should be hiking with me
go on, don't come back too late
here's a compass and a map
and a cell phone,
in case you need to call for help
those concert venues are really sketchy
you should bring it with you,
in case you need to call for help
hello?
Hey
where are we having dinner?
You decide
honey
bye-bye
Why?
Why are you here?
Come play with me, big sister
what happened to you?
Ying
when will you properly meet a guy
and bring him home for dinner?
You're not young anymore
you should think about your future
some people went missing
in sai kung recently
is that so?
Those people got what they deserve
said there were ghosts,
and went there for an adventure
nobody would know if they slipped and fell
did you look through my notebook?
Ying, it's been seven years
when can you let it go?
I want to ask you as well
how can you forget everything about dad?
Why did you not leave behind anything
he used to own?
And you put his picture
up there like he's dead
didn't I go searching for him?
If he wanted to come back,
he'd be back already
but someone found his badge
so do we have to go up
to the mountains every day now?
It's not been seven days, it's seven years
nobody asked you to go
up and search for him
if you'd rather he be
dead, I won't stop you
but you can't stop me
Hello, suet wing?
Miss sit, I just wanted to apologize
you've always been good to me
suet wing, I didn't take it to heart
my parents neglected me,
my classmates didn't like me
do you remember what I told you?
There will be people
who like you or dislike you
we can't satisfy everybody
nobody likes me
everything I do is wrong
even my parents don't want me,
you know how much they hate me
they don't hate you
I called to thank you for listening to me
all this time
you're the only person who treats me well
good bye, miss sit
hello, suet wing? Where are you?
Hello?
I'm a social worker, I
want to go up to 17/f
sure, please register
I've called the police,
they're on their way
Suet wing
- Hello?
Is it dad?
Ying? Is that you?
Dad, where are you?
Far away
there's nobody occupying these apartments
where do you mean?
- Hello?
- Dad?
- Hello? Can you hear me?
Is anybody there?
Hello?
Is anybody here?
Dad
is anybody there?
Dad, is that you?
Help!
Dad
is anybody there?
Help!
Place your bets
Killing without mercy
place your bets
let's see!
Three four's, going for the kill
hey, don't!
Hey, don't!
Help
help
You're finally here?
This is not the place, follow me
We're here
What are you doing here?
You're not allowed in
sir, I'm a social worker
my client called me for help
you're so late,
we sent that girl to the hospital hours ago
hours ago?
I know her
oh right, I'll get back to work
ying, what are you doing here?
That's my client in there
she called me,
and I got here as soon as I could
don't worry, she's not in danger
but you don't look too well
I got lost just now
what are you talking about?
- Did you arrest that man?
- Are you okay?
There he was...
Ying!
Ying, are you okay?
Mom?
Yes, Vincent
didn't you know there was a meeting?
What? Meeting?
Isn't that tomorrow?
Two o'clock on the 4th
yes, sorry, I...
Sorry, I'll be there soon...
Mom! How many times
have I told you not to wander around
it's very dangerous
there you are
you've been gone a month,
you didn't even call
did you spend all your money,
and now you're asking me for some?
Mom, I made you breakfast this morning
come on, let's go home
do you have any shame?
Mom, let's talk about this at home, okay?
There's a lot of people here
what cannot be said out here?
Are you afraid of people finding out
about your bad deeds?
You little bastard,
everyone you know are imbeciles
you only ever ask me for money
you talk back at me when you're at home
you're the best at acting
acting like such a good boy out here
it angers me to have a son like you
other people have children too,
none are as bad as you
you nasty little bastard,
I regret having you
you never do what you promised
I hate people who are fake
Killing without mercy
ying, you're awake
that man killed people
- you were only dreaming.
- It's real
that man was killed children
in the housing estate
I saw a beam of light,
just like the one the other guy said he saw
I went to the enchanted realm,
I really went in there
stop your nonsense, okay?
The doctor said you had low blood sugar
if you carry on like
this, you'll faint again
also, my father called me
he really called me
come on, why don't you rest for a bit
Yes, Vincent
hello, when are you
submitting the proposal?
I'm working on it now
you are rushing?
You're always rushing whenever I call you
the client is flying off tomorrow morning
I need some time,
I'll send it to you when I'm done
what kind of attitude is this...
- Son.
- What is it?
I'm hungry
I'll make you something later
How many times have I told you
don't bother me while I'm working
why don't you ever listen to me?
Are you trying to kill me?
Is the whole world trying to kill me?
Trying to kill me?
I'm giving everything up
to take care of you every day
Mr. ho?
I'm not available,
just put down the money and go
I think I've been into the enchanted realm
what about your police friend?
She doesn't believe me
it was very foggy
I kept trying to find my way
then I saw a man, slaughtering children
That's the enchanted realm
what you just said proves that I'm right
the enchanted realm appears in places
where violence was prevalent
just like...
I saw a group of Japanese soldiers
burying some villagers
the enchanted realm is a place
where time and space interlace
people in the realm will witness
deeds of injustice from the past
that's why you saw that
man killing children
did you tell the cops?
I'm not actually crazy, okay?
Wait a second
how did you get out?
I saw a beam of light, just like you said
The space that the enchanted realm occupies
is the same as the real world
it's just that the fluidity is different
there can be an enchanted realm right here
this can still be a mountaineering shop
in the enchanted realm
we're just not in there at this moment
just like parallel universes in films
here's a simpler metaphor
fluidity
same place, but one is going faster
and the other is going slower
but there will be times when they overlap
like the hour-hand and the minute-hand
one goes faster, and the other goes slower
but they overlap at times
and when they overlap
the entrance to the
enchanted real will open
and because of the difference in fluidity
the two worlds experience time differently
so seven days in the enchanted realm
was just a few hours in our world
yes.
But it was the opposite for me
I was only there for a while
but when I got out,
it's already been a few hours
What symptoms did you experience
after you got out of the enchanted realm
I felt tired, so tired that I fainted
my friend sent me to the hospital
the doctor said that my blood sugar was low
what did you do in the enchanted realm?
After I saw the man kill the children
I kept on running
I get it now
the time you experience
in the enchanted realm
not only will it be compressed,
but it can also be extended
which explains the how
I was able to spend seven days in the realm
without any food or water, and no sleep
because I wasn't hungry, sleepy, or thirsty
I thought I was in there for seven days
but it has only been a
few hours for my body
that's why I didn't feel sleepy,
hungry, or thirsty
with the same logic,
I was running for a while in there
but I've been running for hours
in the real world?
Right, do you know why?
You had low blood sugar
from excessive exercise
also, when I was in there
I received a call from my dad
does that mean he's in there somewhere?
That's possible
but that could also be his spiritual waves
I've also received a call
from my dead wife when I was there
so, there's hope in finding him?
- Yes.
- How do I get back in?
Do you hear weird noises sometimes?
Or see strange unexplainable things?
Things that only you can see or hear
and nobody else can feel?
That's it
but once I left
I didn't see these things again
now you have the key
to enter the enchanted realm
what does that mean?
It's magnetic fields
it's radio waves
you're able to receive radio waves
that others can't
I'm gonna need your help
with getting back in there
why do you want to
get into the enchanted realm?
We are the same
we're both looking for answers
Mrs. mak
ying, there you are
your mother left a bag at my place
come get it for her
sure
your mother is a Saint
she's always here taking care of me
but she's forgetful
she was too busy listening to music
listening to music?
Have a look
June 3rd, 1980,
chan kin sang, a 55-year-old man
heavily in debt, with mental disorders
tied up his three daughters,
all under ten years old
and killed them
and commited suicide by
falling to his death
why are you telling me this?
That case happened
at lai ching estate, room 1224
that's the same room
you said you saw the killing
back then, the neighours said
that the man kept on saying
"killing without mercy"
before he committed suicide
so the case happened 30 years ago?
I also looked at the cctv footage
in the building that day
and found some abnormalities
I've also checked that wah's phone
did make a call from sai kung that day
So I was really in the enchanted realm?
I refuse to believe any of it
then how would you explain this?
You saw a case from 30 years ago
because it was a projection
from your subconscious
there must've been a signal jam in the cctv
so it was footage from another elebator
what about the phone call?
The radio waves in sai kung are unstable
there might be an error in the data
so if you don't believe any of this
why are you helping me?
Wah taught me everything at the academy,
he was my mentor
He called me on the day he went missing
but I was on a case, so I didn't answer
so I've always wanted to know the reason
behind his disappearance
what I can do
is to follow every lead on this case
nam, I know you don't believe me
but can you help me one last time?
I've already helped you many 'last times'
when did I ever refuse?
A women went missing in the mountains
early this morning
the police speculates
that she fell off a cliff
this was the sixth disappearance from
the mountains in the past two months
according to information found on the scene
the lady who disappeared
is between 50-60 years old
son, it's been a while
since you've gone on a hike with your dad
let's go on a family hike together, okay?
Oh, sure
when you're free, tell your dad
when we were young, we
never went to the mall
we would always go on hiking dates
we saw a snake one time
your dad was a big guy,
but he was so terrified
I had to hold him the whole time
he's absolutely useless
but when has your father ever been useful?
Vincent?
No problem, it's all done
I've been working on this report
for three months
we're gonna secure the funding
no problem,
there will never be anymore problems
We're almost at the sharp peak
it's close to where wah went missing
is anyone there?
Help me!
Did you hear that?
Is anyone there? “What is it?
It's dad
hey, ying
- help
- Ying, where are you going?
Don't run off
save me
- ying, stop, wait for me
- Is anybody there?
Help
ying, what's wrong?
It's dad
the sound came from here
did you hear it?
It's not here anymore
this is it, we're close
ying, you can't run off like that,
it's too dangerous
we can't lose each other
let's go back the way we came from
let's go
I can't do this, I want to go home
you wanted to reminisce the past
besides, the doctor said
you should go out more
did you forget that?
We didn't have to go so far
we're almost there, look
I'm really tired
It's beautiful, we haven't been here
admiring the view for a long time
then let's stay here for longer
we're so high up, it's so beautiful here
mom, I need to take a call,
there's no signal here
I'll be back real soon
Ching?
Ching, where are you?
You're a young child, I can't leave you
ching
mom, mom
I'm right here, it's okay
mom, it's okay, I'm right here
everything's fine, everything's fine
there were some eagles flying by
like they were looking for prey
Mom?
It's all your fault
brought me here to god
knows where, what now?
Mom, let's go back home
people are going to laugh at me
then let's wait until your pants dry, okay?
But I feel really uncomfortable like this
then you decide, are we going or not?
Don't talk to me like that
just leave if you want
but watch your tone
I'm sorry
you're sorry... that's
all you know how to say
you forget all about it when you wake up
that's enough, mom
do you think I'm annoying?
What did I teach you?
You need to be courteous and be considerate
I'm gonna get your dad to scold you tonight
dad has been dead for three years
you unfilial bastard,
cursing your father's death
I knew you were nasty all along,
yelling at me all the time
I wish I never gave birth to you
I constantly have to
care about your feelings
I'm already pushed to the brim at work
and you're like this at home
I'm exhausted
dad has been dead for three years
it's three years
don't mention him again
he's not coming back
wake up, can you hear me?
Mom?
Wait a second
I remember passing by this place
I've put a ribbon here with a marking
if we see this ribbon again
then it'll prove
that we're repeating the same path
where are we now?
Check your phone
- There's no signal.
- Me neither
- Hello?
- Hello, nam is that you?
We've been searching for
you for a long time
I'm sorry, I shouldn't have left you behind
nam
there's no sound
there was no signal at the housing estate,
but I got a call
I can tell you now that we've
already entered the enchanted realm
shut up! Nothing has changed
let's go
don't worry, I'll prove that I'm right
Right, we're repeating the same path
this is it, this is the enchanted realm
the housing estate was the same,
I kept going on the 17/f
according to my experience
something is about to happen
Ching?
Ying
ching, what are you doing here?
I was hiking with my mom
where's Mrs. mak?
I got a call from the office
I couldn't get a signal
so I went somewhere to get a better signal
but when I returned after the call,
she was gone
then I got lost
don't be afraid, we're also lost,
and we're looking for a way out
let's go together
- Go on, go on.
- Help
I thought you were the man
now you need someone to save you
police, let go of the man
help
let go of her
let go of the girl!
Otherwise I'll shoot
a few guys going after a girl, you cowards
I'm saying this one more
time, let go right now
otherwise I'll shoot
stop your nonsense, you're ruining the fun
Double homicide in 2011
the two victims were the model couple
male victim chan chi yuen,
was a champion athlete
female victim wong ching
yi, a gifted student
the three killers were their classmates
nam, are you okay?
I was investigating this case
when I was fresh out of the academy
wah was in charge of this case
because of jealousy
they used hiking as an excuse
to lure them into the mountains
He said he was forced to go up
to the mountain by three boys
the court couldn't convict him
due to lack of evidence
I was the one who let him walk free
aren't you a star athlete?
Come and save your girlfriend
- Everybody had enough fun?
- I'm done, let's go
The murder happened on June 5th
today is June 5th
I went into the enchanted
realm two days ago
that murder case happened on June 3th
it was the same day, I get it now
so the gate to the enchanted realm opens
on the same day the murder takes place
cool
what realm? What are you
guys talking about?
I need to get out of
here, how do I get out?
Get out? I don't know
what you're talking about
realm? What enchanted realm?
Tell me
a beam of light is the exit
of the enchanted realm
but whether we can find it is up to chance
let's go, let's find the exit
but I still haven't found my dad
we're dying here, let's go
can someone tell me what's going on?
Stop asking questions,
just stick together if you want to leave
let's go
come on
Ching
ching, are you okay?
I'm okay, let's keep going
We've finally left the forest
ying, come on
wanna leave?
Ching, you'll be sent to prison
if you get out of here
why don't you stay?
Mom, mom
just say the word
if you don't wanna take care of me
why did you have to push me off the cliff?
Turns out I've raised you
to become a murderer
did you know that unfilial children
will be punished?
Did you think you can get away with this?
You've left a lot of
evidence in the mountain
the police are gonna arrest you
enough, shut up
shut up
ching, what's wrong?
Calm down, let's talk about this
it's a hallucination,
I've entered the enchanted realm
none of this is real
No, don't hurt yourself
I understand
why so many strange things are happening
look
it doesn't hurt, there's no blood
it doesn't hurt at all
I must be dreaming
this would only happen in a dream
It doesn't hurt, there's no blood
then I know how we can get out
if we die in the dream,
we can get out of here
- come on, give it a try.
- You...
Give it a try, come on
come on, give it a try
I'm telling you to give it a shot
put the knife down
take the shot
shoot me
this is a dream
I'm not afraid, shoot me
there's no blood
I'm not bleeding, it doesn't hurt
I'm all right
did you hear that? This isn't real
this isn't real
Killing your mother is not enough
now you're killing another person
shut up
you won't be bored
even if you spend your life in prison
I'll come and find you every day
you were a burden when you were alive
you're just as annoying after you're dead
you deserved it,
I would've killed you ten times over
killing who?
They all witnessed you murder someone
you can't get away with this
who saw it? Who saw it?
This is a dream, I'm not afraid of you
I'll kill whoever witnessed it
drop the knife, otherwise I'll shoot
you all have to die
Ching
I've discovered something else
I've been stabbed here,
it doesn't hurt and I'm not bleeding
but I know that my body is bleeding
in the real world
and I've lost a lot of blood
Honey
honey
I've always wanted to ask you one thing
why did you have to jump?
You were my everything
but you only ever focused on yourself
was my existence important at all?
I'm sorry
Ying, we have to get out of here
let's go
Come on
That's the exit
come on
be careful
Aren't you here searching for your father?
Let's go, ying
you went through all this trouble
getting here, now you're going?
Is anybody there?
Help
dad
it's a hallucination
I really saw my dad
it's not real
the neighbour, and the murders aren't real
why don't we get out of here right now?
Let's go
I'm here for my dad,
now you're telling me to leave?
I don't care, you're coming with me
if you can't get out,
what's gonna happen to your mom?
Your father is dead
I don't care, I just need an answer
if you're so afraid, you go ahead
I'll leave when I find the answer
Don't be scared, it was a long
time ago, daddy is right there
- Dad.
- Stop right there
Did you think you can redeem yourself
by staying single?
It's too late
did you know how heartbroken
your mother was?
She lost her husband
and she had to live with a sinner
like you everyday
if you came up hiking with me that day
I could've gone home,
I wouldn't have been here for seven years
because of a decision you made,
I can never go back
and I can never see your mother
I'm sorry
don't tell me you're sorry
ask yourself of all your sins
you made your mother lose her husband
and you killed your brother
with your own hands
Ying, it's time for dinner
Honey
are you okay?
- don't move, don't move
- It hurts
let me see that
- I can't.
- It's gonna be okay
- it hurts, the baby...
- It's okay
because of you
I lost a son
because of you,
there is no one to carry the bloodline
your brother can never come into this world
all this happened because of you
you killed your brother 30 years ago
you killed me 7 years ago
are you still seeking redemption?
Yes, I want to seek redemption
as long as you're gone
you can't hurt anyone around you
and people around you don't need to suffer
as long as you die
you can stay here with us forever
you can compensate for everything
this place is better than the real world
here, you don't feel pain when you die
isn't it so tiresome being alive?
Just cut in there, and you'll be free
sister, don't be afraid, it won't hrt
Ying?
Mom, I killed my little brother
don't think this way
remember, no matter how
hard we try sometimes
we cannot control the outcome
if I wasn't carelessly playing around
you wouldn't end up like this
we cannot control
the outcome of a lot of things
but we can control how we deal with it
you're still young,
it's okay if you don't understand
you'll understand when you're older
Remember you refused to
eat when you were young
you said eating would make you grow
you're afraid of growing up
and we won't love you anymore
we were at the park, walking by the river
you saw your own reflection
in the river, and you said
there was another 'you' inside the river
and you wanted to save her
It's okay if you couldn't find me
as long as you can find yourself,
you understand?
Miss... are you okay?
Miss, are you okay? Miss
she fainted, call the police
Ying, you're finally awake
Have I been gone for long?
I told you not to wander around,
you're making me worry
mom, I'm sorry
I won't wander off again
I never found out
whether my dad was in the enchanted realm
but I'm gonna stop fixating on this
because I've found the answers
I was looking for
I've never been back on
the mountain ever since