You got off easy.
Of course.
Did you ever imagine
how it would be...
What do you want?
Just a simple favour.
Money?
Cold.
- Dope doesn't fly anymore.
I took big risks for you.
What am I to do with this picture?
I like this chick.
Is this your stake?
That's probably not my decision.
Think long and hard about it.
I want you to act
as a killer for her.
All you need is
a gun and imagination.
A bad movie.
That's the plan.
And what's the point?
Is it so hard to get?
You look like a killer
but you are no killer.
The gun's empty but
she doesn't know.
As soon as she'll realize it...
it will put an end to her fantasizing.
Why don't you leave her alone?
I don't want to lose her.
A FILM BY
Cinema Goetheplatz,
one moment please.
Number 14, Row D for two.
How may I help you?
I'd like to get to know you.
Not necessary. I already know you.
That's impossible.
In the theatre everything's possible.
I heard your voice a hundred times.
I know what you look like.
So you'll recognise me later
in the Ramona Bar.
We'll see.
Yes?
- Two for Cinema C.
Sold not a single ice cream.
One guy wanted
a 500 Marks bill changed.
No chance!
Why do you get riled up?
It's all just a show anyhow.
How many are in?
About eighty.
Please come into my office later.
Cinema Goetheplatz.
What kind of movie, is it the one
tomorrow at 10:30 P.M.?
10:30 P.M. tomorrow?
Horror.
- A horror movie.
That's not my cup of tea.
Is there sex in it?
Depends on you.
A man gets buried alive.
Ah, that one...
That jerk hung up.
Fuck.
I'm happy you're here.
Me too.
Would be nice if
you'd be here more often.
A rare occasion.
Know what we'll do?
We go to Acapulco
to break the bank.
And with the money we open up a bar.
And then you can invite all
the celebrities
you're searching for
on your nightly trips.
And in the bathroom you will meet...
Marilyn Monroe.
Ha ha, very funny.
Not Marilyn Monroe
but rather Porky Pig.
Better.
By the way,
it's nice and warm in bed.
Troubles?
- Not more than usual.
Wanna go out for a drink?
I've got to run.
Too bad there's no part
for me in your movie.
No can do.
I have something planned for later.
Life or business?
What do you think?
I've seen a wedding once
where the bride was in love
with another man.
At the last second...
Shortly before she said 'Yes'...
he ran into the church
and yelled her name
till they both ran off.
Before that, he locked the
wedding guests into the church.
I've seen enough.
And the whole class
is yelling 'Yes Miss!'.
Sit down, we need to talk.
- I thought we'd go to the movies.
Please, no back-talking.
Very well.
I once knew someone
who only could live by night
although he wasn't really alive.
He prowled the night
and drank the blood of humans
until they became like him.
At cockcrow he had to be at his home
because sunlight made him wither.
Or did he melt?
He turned to ash.
And I'm leaving.
What if we leave together?
Why now all of a sudden?
I'm taking a shower first.
What movie did you watch?
What do you mean?
Did you meet someone?
- No, or else I wouldn't have come.
Really? No one at all?
Don't ask these kind of questions.
You're still in bed?
What are you waiting for?
I don't know.
Let me drive.
We need to fill up gas.
Hello.
- Evenin'. Fill her up, please.
This is Annie.
Hi Annie. I'm Johnny. Have a seat.
I have to make a call.
The drinks are on me.
Do I have a reason?
Cheers Annie.
- Cheers.
I'm going home.
Cinema Goetheplatz.
- Has the movie already started?
It started 20 minutes ago.
Too bad. Thanks.
- You're welcome.
What's up?
- It's the seducing projectionist.
Get B.B. on the phone, please.
You're wanted on the phone.
Who is it?
- Three guesses.
Him? What does he want?
Bockmann speaking.
- Darling, how are you doing?
Unchanged since your last 97 calls.
Kiss my ass.
I won't be forming habits
because of you.
Jesus, who are you waiting for?
For Otto?
Definitely not for
a Frankenstein like you.
Have fun in your darkroom.
Do you have to break my heart?
Rather yours than mine.
Any more questions?
Hello? Who is this?
Cinema Goetheplatz.
Maybe it was the guy
I met yesterday.
But how would he know
I'm working here?
He was a freak, let me tell you.
First we went to a bar.
Champagne... He paid for it all.
Then he wanted to go to a hotel.
A hotel room!
Can you imagine?
I'm no hooker!
I asked him why he
won't take me to his place.
He said he can't go home.
His wife has a lover.
And in the meantime he
has to take a hike.
That's what I'm good for.
Forget it!
I asked why he isn't
getting a divorce.
Wanna know what he said?
He still has the hots for her.
You can count me out.
Then he tried to kiss me.
He started to grope me.
Nutcase! He only bit my neck,
he couldn't get any further.
There's something wrong
with a guy like that.
Did you ever have an experience
that feels just not quite right.
You meet someone and some detail
just does not fit.
What do you mean?
I'm not here!
Tell Miss Bockmann
to come to my office.
Not him again!
...talk to the American.
Maybe I'm coming.
See my feet in the mirror?
- Yes
Think they're pretty?
- Yes. Very.
And my ankles? Do you like them?
- Yes.
My knees?
I love your knees.
And my thighs?
Them, too.
...the guy is screwing you.
Every mornin', every evenin'!
As soon as I leave the door!
Have you rented the whole floor?
You gave me a scare.
I thought you'd come earlier.
Go right in.
I have to straighten out something.
Later!
Where are those beautiful legs
walking at this late hour?
Alone to bed if all goes smoothly.
Do you want anything?
Was Richard here?
- Richard...
He wasn't.
What about Maserati?
- He left a while ago.
The next one's paying.
What's going on?
Where do I know Richard from?
Have we met him before?
Ero-topa-thy.
Alright, I'm leaving.
Not necessary.
Hello, Annie.
Maybe someone else is coming too.
Did Johnny leave?
Don't know.
I don't understand men anymore.
I know a woman who waited
ten years for the man she loved.
She used to say:
"If he wants to see me one more
time he's got to come today".
Sure enough he came and
they wanted to leave...
But at the last moment
her boyfriend killed her.
Because he couldn't accept it.
What are you doing here?
- I could ask you the same.
You look like you've
expected someone else.
I expected no one else.
I just wanted a drink with Moni.
He shot her?
- No, he stabbed her with a knife.
What will you give me
if I give this back to you?
A night without me.
What do you think is up with her?
She's about to detach from you.
How many are in?
- Almost sold out.
Where's Miss Bockmann?
She felt sick and went out
to get some air.
Yeah?
- It's me. He just came in.
Fuck!
- I told him you went out for a sec.
Don't forget to switch off
the lights before you leave.
He's eavesdropping again.
"Don't forget to
switch off the lights"
Blah-blah.
It's going on all the time.
He wouldn't say one peep.
Even if we kept
all the lights on. Jackass
If I told a single word
about him grabbing my butt
he'd have a heart attack and
drop dead.
Idiot! I'm going to break my neck
because of his stinginess!
Can you explain this to me?
I'm assigned to kill you.
What am I supposed to do
with this thing?
I want you to do it for me.
Right now?
You've got twenty-four hours.
Is this why you were looking for me?
- Private issues don't matter.
Let me out.
You have a screw loose.
So that's your movie?
Good casting. Congratulations.
Out!
You're Miss Messerschmidt, right?
- No.
Of course, I know you!
"Keep me in mind!
Twelve hours left."
You only have one chance."
Someone asked for you.
- What did he look like?
A cute guy.
- Was he here?
Five minutes ago.
Who was it anyways?
Cinema Goetheplatz.
Got a cigarette?
The rear entrance is open.
- Fuck.
Is Marion there?
- She exploded.
This is the answering machine.
Currently I'm not home.
You have 30 seconds
to leave a message.
Please don't forget
to leave your name.
Speak now.
Asshole.
Take it easy!
There it is in black and white.
"Assassination at film opening:
'Love me or I kill Reagan.'
Was John W. Hinckley trying
to force the love
of movie star Jodie Foster
with his bloody deed?"
"A man takes revenge!
Repulsed by filth,
violence and godlessness
of the American city life
he strikes out on everything wicked.
He shoots down a robber and a pimp.
He tells a juvenile hooker, 'If you
don't love me I'll kill the president'
But this does not happen...
But this does not happen.
In a brutal slaughter
the avenger is gunned
down by the Police.
Showdown of the US movie
Taxi Driver".
The movie ends totally different.
Glad you came.
Can you show me how it works?
Can I have a coffee?
Your boyfriend is losing
to Richard in the back.
What do you mean 'boyfriend'?
Let's go.
You're out of the game.
We go to your place.
We go to my place.
I haven't been there for two months.
Is that all?
To the Mathaeser Movie Palace.
One ticket please.
- The movie started 30 minutes ago.
Doesn't matter.