[dramatic electronic music]
[tense music]
♪ Happy birthday
♪ To me
- One's for good luck.
Bad luck.
No luck.
[chuckling]
We'll see what you are, pal.
[tense music]
[engine zooming]
[clacking]
[tense music]
[engine zooming]
[uptempo electronic music]
[uptempo music]
[horns honking]
[tense ominous music]
[engine rumbling]
[tires squealing]
[tense music]
[uptempo music]
[tires squealing]
- What the fuck do you want?
[screaming]
[zapping]
[uptempo music]
[engine zooming]
[tires squealing]
- [Man] What the hell?
I mean, we ain't doin' nothin'.
Hey, pops.
[footsteps clacking]
[door bell dinging]
- [Dakota] Whoa, whoa, whoa.
I gotta do her on
my Harley, man.
- Ha.
You haven't done that?
- Well.
Friend of mind did once.
He was goin' 120 miles
an hour when he came.
- [Tom] He lost it.
- Well.
She did.
In a screaming, clawing mess.
- They die?
- In a bloody ecstasy.
- Oh.
Wait minute now, but how
do you know all of this
if you was--
- Hey, hey, hey, hey.
It was on the radio man.
Her ass was on the
gas tank and her cheek
was pressed up against the butt.
- Oh.
How do you tell when
an alcoholic is lying?
- How?
- His lips are moving.
[chuckling]
Missed you at the
meetin' a while back.
- What meeting?
- The Alcoholic Anonymous.
- Oh yeah, yeah that meeting.
- Full moon out there.
[register keys beeping]
Strange things can happen.
- Yeah well, that makes
for better night vision.
[chuckling]
- Hey uh, have you
seen her on TV?
Julie Paulson.
- The newslady?
Every day, six o'clock.
- Oh, happy birthday Dak.
[door thudding]
[door bell ringing]
- Yo, Harley.
- Hey.
Don't call me Harley.
I'm your watch commander
and if there's a beer
in this sack...
Oh.
Root beer.
[tense music]
- [Video Stalker] You've
betrayed the body God gave you.
Don't try telling
us you're sorry.
[whimpering]
It's too late to repent.
A little off the top?
- Haven't had one of
these in a long time.
Meet the new chief yet?
- Naw.
- You're gonna love him.
He screams when he talks to ya.
Got a PhD in efficiency.
Call him The Undertaker.
He's a friend of Mahoney's.
- So what?
- You got bad knees.
Your file's as
thick as your dick.
They pay ya three times
what they pay a rookie.
- I'm worth it.
- Aw, Dak.
You're an ex-detective
on a motorbike.
Shit sinks and this is bottom.
- Hey, screw you with
all respect, sir.
- You got one chance.
You got one chance only.
- Yeah, I know.
Low profile.
- It's a state of mind, Dak.
Say it again.
- Low pro
file.
- Happy birthday.
[tense music]
- [Video Stalker] You won't
be needin' these anymore.
[uptempo jazzy music]
[engine zooming]
♪ You bring me joy
♪ You make me smile
♪ Happiness [mumbling]
♪ I need your love
♪ I need your kindness
♪ You gave me hope
♪ So let it find us
[uptempo tense music]
[siren blipping]
- Hello base.
This is Officer Smith.
Makin' a stop on a black van.
May need backup.
[uptempo tense music]
[tense music]
[gunshot blasting]
[tires squealing]
[uptempo electronic music]
[uptempo tense music]
[engine zooming]
[gunshots blasting]
[helicopter blades whirring]
[uptempo tense music]
[gunshot blasting]
- This guy's got
heavy artillery.
[engine zooming]
[helicopter blades whirring]
- What the hell?
Holy shit!
This is Chopper One.
We got us a player, here.
I'm backin' off.
- All right, let's go for it.
- You crazy?
- Yeah.
[engine zooming]
[uptempo tense music]
[gunshot blasting]
Go in low.
Go in right behind him
and he won't see you.
Get down right behind him.
[engine zooming]
[gunshot blasting]
[uptempo tense music]
[engine zooming]
[blasting]
Oh, God, I hope you got that!
- No.
Just kidding.
[laughing]
[uptempo tense music]
[chattering on police radio]
- [Officer] What a mess.
This looks like Smith's bike,
but he ain't around.
- [Officer] Just go
check the nearest bar.
[uptempo tense music]
[engine zooming]
[tires squealing]
- Hey, hey!
Come back here!
[tires squealing]
[tense music]
[chattering]
[car doors thudding]
- Get out the way.
Make a little room here.
Make a little room.
[chattering]
Come on, get up, buddy.
You don't wanna miss
your breakfast, do ya?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, tell
it to your congressman.
- The top story
at this noon hour.
The reign of terror continues.
The body of Elizabeth
Richards, the 13th victim
of the Video Stalker
was found outside
our Channel Six news
building this morning.
Inside sources reveal that
she may have been shot
by a stray bullet
[tapping]
from the gun of police
officer Dakota Smith.
A video cassette was
found on Richards' body
containing footage
of intimate moments
of lovemaking, phone
conversations and diary entries.
The question on everybody's
mind at this time is
how does he do it?
How does he invade the lives
of his victims so completely
and what can we do
to protect ourselves?
- [News Anchorman]
Thank you, Julie.
And we'll be back
after these messages.
- We're here to pick up Officer
Smith's personal effects.
- For what?
- 'Cause he's a dead asshole.
[faint uptempo music]
Come on.
[knocking]
- [Dak] Yeah, it's open.
- Stinks in here.
- They're lookin' all over
the highway for your ass.
Mahoney bet his watch commander
he was shacked up
with a case of beer.
Root beer.
- Smells like you died in here.
- He and Mahoney
used to be partners.
- And Mahoney is now chief
detective and look at you.
- Fix you some coffee?
[chattering]
- Do you wash your
rubbers out, too?
- Naw, your mama told
me she was fixed.
- The van last night,
the Video Stalker.
- With number 13 inside.
- First solid contact we
get with this guy ever
and you don't call for back up,
you do get off a shot
and who do you hit?
- The girl.
Right in the forehead.
Damn, you're good.
- What are you sayin'?
What are you sayin'?
- Ballistics matched
the bullet to your gun.
[tense uptempo music]
What is this?
- Put that down.
- I'm turnin' this in.
Internal Affairs shoulda
had this weeks ago.
[groaning]
- Let him go.
[gun clicking]
[uptempo tense music]
- Take the shot.
[thudding]
[grunting]
Do you wanna play chicken?
Next time you draw down on me,
you better use that thing.
[clicking]
[uptempo tense music]
[door thudding]
[horn honking]
[traffic zooming]
Excuse me.
Aren't you the new transfer
they call Quick Draw McGraw?
- And you're Dirty Harry, right?
[chuckling]
- That's good, that's real good.
You know, just for the record,
if it was me, I'da
done the same thing.
- [Kristin] Yeah,
but it wasn't you.
- Oh, come on.
What's the big deal?
So you shot the scum.
People like that deserve
to be off the street.
[phone ringing]
- Low profile?
Lost a hundred bucks on you.
- Amnesia.
- Try this for your
amnesia breath.
- Nah, nah, nah, you got
it wrong this time, coach.
I'm on a root beer diet.
- Yeah?
Your ex-wife called.
She was lookin' for
insurance money.
I told her we haven't
got a body yet.
She said see that,
son of a bitch.
Never there when you need him.
- Why should I be?
- You know I wanted
you to know that I'm
behind you on this.
It wasn't my idea to
put ya out on patrol.
[phone ringing]
Internal Affairs decided
rather than suspend you
they'd put you on
probation on my turf
'til the incident's
been investigated.
- I understand.
- Yeah, well you know how it is.
They have to investigate
why the victim
had no gun on him
when you shot him.
- I didn't know.
He made a movement as though
he was reaching for one.
- Yeah, yeah, you're
dismissed, Officer.
- I was sure
he was dead.
- He was my partner, I know him.
- You don't know crap
except how to save
your own tail.
- You never let go, do ya?
You came in late, you blew
out your own kneecaps,
you blame everybody else.
- You let him take your piece.
- And if you'd
have taken a shot--
- [Teak] All right, all right.
- [Dak] Screw you.
- A drunk's response
to everything.
I want a report
on that van stop.
- You need my help on this one.
- Call 9-1-1.
[mumbling]
- What is it with you two?
- He's like a pit
bull with a hard on.
- Never mess with
a hard on, Mike.
- [Mike] We'll see.
Get me that report.
- Excuse me.
Could you help me make a copy?
- Of what?
- Your gun.
[laughing]
- So, I hear they call
ya Quick Draw McGraw.
So, what do you
say, Quick's Draw?
Let's you and me play
a game of whip out.
Bet I can whip mine out
faster than you can.
[thudding]
[grunting]
- Hey, wait a minute.
- Ho, ho, chill out, chill out.
Chill out.
- [Mike] Hold it, hold it,
hold it, that's enough.
- But he didn't do anything.
- All right, take it easy.
- Johnson grabbed her
ass, Bigelow offered
to whip out cock.
- No, he didn't.
- All right.
- [Detective] He
didn't do anything.
He didn't do a thing.
He didn't do anything.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Smith, Taylor, I
wanna talk to you guys
in my office right now.
- I guess a blow job's
out of the question.
[muffled yelling]
- [Detective] Bullshit!
Fuckin' bullshit.
[tense music]
- [Video Stalker] Is
Officer Dakota Smith around?
Thank you.
- [Dak] Dr. Harley?
[tense music]
- I been expectin' your body.
- Well, I'm sorry
to disappoint you.
- You all right?
- Maybe.
Sometimes I'm not
quite sure myself.
- Try meditation.
Extensive cirrhosis
of the liver.
[tense music]
- Damn.
- You saved her from
a horrible death.
He likes plastic
wrap on the face.
They suck it in their
mouths, their nostrils,
even their eye sockets,
and rigor mortis sets in.
[tense music]
- This liver, it's
from drinkin'?
- Mmm hmm.
[phone ringing]
Would you get that for me?
- Yeah, morgue.
- [Video Stalker]
Officer Smith, please.
- Okay, you got him.
- [Video Stalker] You
really piss me off.
- Come on, come on,
chill out, okay?
I sent the check.
It's in the mail, trust me.
- [Video Stalker] You don't
know who this is, do you?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I know who it is.
It's uh, my ex-wife's
lawyer, right?
- [Video Stalker]
We met last night.
You killed a
passenger in my van.
[tense music]
- What do you want from me?
- [Video Stalker] I'm
gonna teach you humility.
- Yeah, right.
How you gonna do that?
- Trust me.
[tense music]
- Sure.
- Dakota.
Dakota Smith.
- [Dak] Yo, what's up?
- They found your 12-pack.
- Oh.
Thanks, man.
- [Newt] All right.
- Hey look, [mumbling].
Come on man, I'm
sorry, all right?
- Sorry, sit down, Dak.
You know somethin', man?
I really loved your father.
And when you needed help,
you came to me.
But I'm tellin'
you right now, man,
you break one more of my rules
and you and your stuff
are on the street.
Deal?
- Okay, all right.
[tires screeching]
- What is that?
- These are tapes
from the video store.
- Hey, Newt, is that
you out there listenin'?
- No, sir.
- So tell me, have
you got a sponsor?
- No.
- Well, then.
How many sober days have
you strung together?
- 29.
- [Muscles] How many?
- 16.
- Come on, man.
How many?
- Nine.
- Right.
So uh,
how is your life?
- It's okay.
- Really?
And what have you got left?
Your Harley?
- Maybe.
- Tell you what.
How 'bout one meeting
a day for 90 days?
- A toothbrush?
I already brushed.
- Yeah, a few of them
video tapes I heard
been sold commercially
in Europe,
and a few of them are
right here on the streets.
- Professional?
- Naw.
Poor quality.
Copies of copies.
But I know some
guys that used to be
in the porno business.
I could holler at them about it.
- Well, that's good work, man.
Get on it, all right.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, Newt, Newt.
My man, I need some help here.
[laughing]
- Call 9-1-1.
I'm busy all right?
I'll holler at you.
Cool.
- [Julie] Is Officer
Smith up here?
- Yo.
- [Julie] Officer Dakota
Smith is a former detective.
What are you doing?
- Community service.
- It's a shitty job, but--
- You stopped the
stalker last night.
He's probably watching.
Is there anything
you'd like to say?
- Yeah, thanks for the call.
- The Video Stalker called you?
- Yeah, we have a
common interest.
- [Julie] Like what?
- He's sick.
He wants to die,
and I'm gonna help him.
[laughing]
- He's sick.
[tense music]
[knocking]
There's a little
surcharge on this job.
- What are you talkin' about?
Garibaldi paid for this.
It's goin' with us.
- Garibaldi doesn't have
anything to do with this.
This is a little
something between us.
- So, what are we talkin'?
- This skid row cop, Dak,
is on me like a pit bull.
He's almost as crazy as I am.
I don't mind playin'
cat and mouse with him,
but I think it's time
to change the rules.
- So, you want us to off him?
- That would be too easy.
I said I wanna change the
rules, not end the game.
- Well, I'm not too
much on games, so,
just tell us what you want.
- I want to make him suffer.
[uptempo tense music]
He has an overactive conscience,
so work over one of his
buddies and tell him
to tell his friend,
his good friend, Dak,
that he better get outta
this while he still can.
Start with this guy.
He owns a liquor store.
- You better know what
you're talkin' about.
[uptempo tense music]
- This could be fun.
- Be on the lookout for a
dark van, military weapons.
I know you already know
this, but we need to find out
where he gets his info.
He somehow knows
those little secrets
that people like to
keep private, so,
if you happen to spot it, don't
be a hero like Smith, here.
Call for backup.
Good news, bad news.
Good news, our new
officer, Kristin O'Connor.
Bad news, her partner
will be Dakota Smith.
- What?
- That's right.
You're gonna be riding
shotgun for O'Connor.
- It's O'Connor who's
gonna need a shotgun.
[officers laughing]
- All right, that's it.
Go out and do your jobs
and keep your radar
turned on for that van.
Dismissed.
- Come on, man.
What is this?
What are you talking about?
I'm a cycle cop, I work alone.
- Not anymore.
I'm puttin' you in a patrol car.
- [Dak] But I don't want
her, I don't need her.
- Dak, would you
cut it out with that
hurray for me and everybody
else is an idiot attitude?
You do need her.
I'm tellin' ya.
Take it from a friend.
She'll do you some good.
- Yeah, right.
[traffic zooming]
- Happy birthday, yesterday.
[Dak chuckling]
- Yeah, I've had a few.
- You're younger than you look.
It's probably the drinking.
[Dak chuckling]
- [Dak] What is this?
You're my partner, now
you're my psychiatrist, too?
I mean, how do
you know all this?
- I read your file.
I got it out of the computer.
It took half a box of
paper to print out.
- Oh yeah, you mean you know
how to do all these things?
You work computers
and all this stuff?
Yeah.
Well, look.
I need some
information on Mahoney
from the Task Force files.
You think you can help me?
- I'm on probation, I
have you as a partner.
How many strikes do I get?
[Dak chuckling]
- [Dak] Okay, all right.
[cart clattering]
[mumbling]
- [Kristin] Where we going?
- [Dak] Gonna watch a sex video.
You like sex, don't ya?
- With the right guy.
- So, I guess you're
kinda particular, right?
- [Kristin] Very.
- There's a VCR in here.
Ah, Jesus.
- [Kristin] What is it?
- It's a AA meeting.
- Are there any other newcomers
with less than 30 days?
[mumbling]
[clapping]
[cheering]
- My name is Dak.
- [Crowd] Hello, Dak.
[clapping]
[mumbling]
- I'm an alcoholic.
I almost had a
slip the other day,
but I have three
days of sobriety.
[crowd laughing]
- How do you feel?
- I'm thirsty.
[crowd laughing]
[clapping]
Thanks for your support.
I need it.
- Well, you got it, buddy.
[clapping]
- [Video Stalker] The
life and death of a slut.
The story of a woman
who loved to bang studs.
At what age does a slut
first become a slut?
Ah, look.
Look how scared she looks.
It's an act.
She wasn't scared when she was
screwing around on her husband.
She really enjoyed it.
I know that now.
[tense music]
Touching, isn't it?
- [Kristin] This guy's sick.
- [Dak] Yeah.
- [Video Stalker] Oh, how sweet.
She's so religious.
This must be her new husband.
Oh, no, wait a minute.
I've seen her husband
and that's not him.
This looks like
that guy from work.
She couldn't get enough
of this stud before.
- [Dak] How does
he know this stuff?
- [Video Stalker]
No wonder she said
her husband couldn't
fulfill her needs.
She said he really
just needed a friend.
They look friendly, don't they?
Oh, don't worry, Mr. Richards.
I'll look out for you.
Tell me where it hurts.
[horns honking]
- Can I help you?
- [Big Boy] That depends.
- On what?
- What I want isn't in here.
I need to send a message.
- Try Western Union.
- Real smartass, huh?
- Look, do you wanna
buy something or not?
[thudding]
[grunting]
- Now that I have
your attention,
I need to send a
message to your buddy,
the skid row cop.
[bell ringing]
- [Dispatcher On Radio]
All units respond.
- Is that an alarm?
- Sounds like it.
- [Dispatcher On Radio]
Lexington and State Street.
- That's Tom's
place, let's move.
- [Kristin] Right.
[tires squealing]
[uptempo tense music]
- [Thug] What the
fuck you do that for?
- He really pissed me off.
What about the cash?
- That's not what we came for.
We're outta here.
- I'm gettin' the cash, man.
[uptempo tense music]
[tires squealing]
- Let's go man, we're
fuckin' outta here.
[gunshots blasting]
- You check inside.
I'll go that way.
[uptempo tense music]
- Freeze, bitch.
[gunshots blasting]
[thudding]
[grunting]
[gunshots blasting]
[uptempo tense music]
Drop it, cop.
Go ahead, take the shot.
He ain't got the balls.
- Take the shot.
- Don't touch.
- Why not?
- Could get ya killed.
[gunshot blasting]
- You took the shot!
- You told me to take the shot.
- You took the goddamn shot.
Ugh, I got brains all over me.
[traffic zooming]
He's dead.
- Yeah, for what?
Few lousy bucks?
- Looks like they
wanted more than that.
They beat him up pretty badly.
Have you known him long?
- Three sober lifetimes.
[siren blaring]
[door bell ringing]
- Check out back.
Call this low profile?
- Hey.
We got a dead one over here.
- One got away.
- Have you been drinking?
Get the hell outta here.
Go file your report.
[knocking]
- [Dak] It's open.
- Hey, yo, another
cop to see you.
- [Kristin] Nice ass.
[Dak groaning]
- Oh, please.
You want a Twinkie?
It's in the refrigerator.
- Oh, maybe later.
I just wanted to say
thanks for last night.
- All right.
Want a root beer?
Goodbye, Newt.
[Newt chuckling]
- I got the deal on
the chief ravioli.
He's the porno king.
- What kinda friends
you got, man?
- Some ghetto soldiers that
got all the tight info.
- All right.
Stay on it, bro.
- [Newt] All right.
Yo diggity, I'm out.
[door thudding]
- [Kristin] Yours?
- No, it's my dad's.
- He was a detective for Metro?
- Yeah.
One night while he
had been drinking
and he was on stake
out, somebody sneaked up
behind him and slit his throat.
- Yeah, I heard about
that at the academy.
I'm sorry.
You know, Dak, with
all your drinking,
are you afraid you're gonna
turn out just like him?
[chuckling]
- Naw, naw, naw, no way.
I'm not gonna check out
of here until I have
a loving weekend with
you on my Harley.
- You must believe in miracles.
- Well, a man gotta
believe in somethin'.
- Tell you what.
You get a 90-day
chip, and we'll do it.
- Face to face?
- Belly to belly.
- 30 days.
- 90.
- 60?
- Done.
[uptempo music]
Here we go.
[engine rumbling]
- [Kristin]
Somebody's been here.
- [Dak] Yeah.
[tense music]
[door squeaking]
- Feels like he's here.
- Yeah.
Camera was probably there.
- And this is where
she was praying.
[phone ringing]
- [Video Stalker On Phone]
Hello, Detective Dak.
- Oh, it's him.
- [Video Stalker On Phone]
What are you looking for, Dak?
I'm like God.
I'm everywhere.
Do you believe in God, Dak?
Hello, Quick Draw.
I didn't recognize
you without your gun.
- [Kristin] Go blow yourself.
- [Video Stalker On
Phone] Well, that would be
delightful but for now,
please press play on the VCR.
[tense music]
The life and death of, oh,
must have forgot that part.
Maybe it's on the
closing credits.
Ah, before the fall.
Sweet, innocent.
If only her mom
could see her now.
She's had five different
lovers this year alone.
Actually, her mom's
probably a harlot, too.
She tells me things, like
how she uses these guys
to pay her bills.
She's betraying them.
I would never betray her.
Might kill her, though.
Oh, Dak, you're so clever.
Ouch!
What time you have, Dak?
- [Dak] 10 minutes after six.
- [Video Stalker On Phone] You
have four hours to find her.
- She alive?
- [Video Stalker On Phone] Yes.
Her name is Allison.
- Allison what?
- [Video Stalker On Phone]
You have three hours
and 58 minutes.
- Listen, this is
between me and you.
Why involve Allison?
- Allison is my friend.
I know what she thinks, what
she feels, what she does.
Every intimate detail.
Only you can save her.
- How do we find a girl
by the name of Allison
in four hours?
- I don't know, I don't know.
TV news?
Julie Paulson?
- That's a good idea.
[soft jazzy vocalizing music]
- All right, we'll go with it.
- We interrupt this
program to bring you
a special emergency bulletin.
Good evening, I'm Julie Paulson.
The Video Stalker
and the Skid Row Cop
have had further contact,
a kind of game in which a
young woman may soon be dead.
Channel Six has learned that
in a telephone conversation
with Officer Dakota
Smith, the stalker pledged
to strike again tonight.
The police have provided
us with photographs
of a man and a woman the
stalker may be targeting
as his next victims.
If you know the identity
of this woman or this man--
- Oh, get me to a phone!
I know that guy.
- [Julie On TV] At this
moment we know very little.
- Handsome devil.
- [Julie On TV] What
we do know however,
is that the name of the
woman in this photograph
may be Allison.
We also--
[soft jazzy vocalizing music]
♪ [mumbling]
♪ Come on around
♪ Put me down, lay me down
- [Man] Okay, people,
we're back two minutes.
Let's go now.
- Uh, could I talk
to you for a minute?
You son of a bitch.
You don't go through channels.
You don't go through procedure.
You just go on the air like
you're a one-man police force?
Who the fuck do
you think you are?
- I'm a cop, same as you, okay?
Now, you've had this
case for 18 months.
Now, we outta time, partner.
- What do you mean,
we're outta time?
- He's given us 'til 10 o'clock.
[beeping]
[soft jazzy vocalizing music]
♪ [mumbling]
♪ Like this and like that
♪ Tonight
[phone ringing]
- Hello?
I'm gonna put ya on
hold for a second.
The man's wife is on the phone.
He's a lawyer, and he's
supposed to be at the office.
- Well, is he there?
- No.
- Does she know who the girl is?
- It's his paralegal.
[soft jazzy vocalizing music]
♪ Set it off right
♪ Bring it on, bring it on
♪ Let's do it right
♪ [mumbling]
♪ Tonight
♪ I was lookin' kinda fly
♪ I was thinkin' you and I
♪ Could maybe hook
up and get together ♪
♪ I want to get to
know you better, yeah ♪
♪ Know this place
is kinda loud ♪
♪ Let's get away
from this crowd ♪
♪ Somewhere to be all alone
♪ And baby it's on
♪ Let's do it like
♪ [mumbling]
- Good evening,
I'm Julie Paulson.
If you know the
identity of this woman
or this man, call
Channel Six immediately.
- I'm on TV.
- [Man] Closed circuit?
- No, no, I'm serious, look.
- [Julie] What we do know
however, is that name
of the woman in this
photograph may be Allison.
We also know that
these two people
may be in very great danger.
- This girl, Allison,
is she with you?
- [Man] Yes.
- Look, you're in
danger, where are you?
- Paradise Motel
on Sycamore Street.
- [Julie] Channel
Six has learned--
- What kind of danger?
- This Video Stalker idiot.
Now, I'll tell you what.
You stay put.
I'll be right there.
- This is on TV.
This is all over TV.
Oh, God.
- Hello, hello?
Dammit.
[tense music]
- [Allison] What, what is it?
- [Man] A serial killer.
He's after you, us.
Come on.
- [Allison] Well, what do we do?
- I love the panic.
- [Man] I don't
know what's worse,
the Video Stalker or my wife!
- [Allison] Asshole!
You're such an asshole.
You always were an asshole.
[tense music]
[zapping]
[mumbling]
[tense music]
- [Dak] Oh Jesus.
Goddamn love sandwich.
What's the note say?
Sorry, Detective Dak.
I lied.
- This guy's sick.
- So, what time is it?
- It's 9:35.
- Jesus Christ.
- This is FBI Special
Agent Coleman.
He's been workin'
with Mahoney here
on the Video Stalker murders.
- There's been no
contact with this guy
in over a year and a half,
and now he's comin' out.
You really pissed him off when
you shot that Richards lady.
You destroyed his art.
His fun and games are
where he gets off.
- He wants to hurt you.
There'll probably
be more contact.
- Which is why
you're not suspended.
- Yeah, but if I was
still a detective...
- No, you're most
helpful where you are.
He's probably watching you.
He has money.
The latest in high-tech
equipment, military weapons.
He'll probably be
coming after you.
- Where does he get this money?
- His videos are being
distributed worldwide
by a crime syndicate
porn channel.
- Why haven't you
caught this guy?
- He's intelligent.
Plus, he has mob
resources behind him,
and he's been real lucky.
- Yeah, now that he's
operating out of emotion--
- He'll screw up
and we'll be there to get him.
[phone ringing]
- Well.
You pissed off
everybody but the pope.
We really don't know
how he feels about you,
but watch your backs.
- Well, I figure in a week,
I probably can find a way
to piss the pope off, too.
- Well, at this rate,
it won't take that long.
Catch up with you later,
gotta make a phone call.
- See ya in the car.
- Dakota.
- Dole.
- May I have a word with
you outside, please?
- No problem.
[tense music]
So, what's up?
- I'm keepin' a low
profile on this case.
You oughta try it sometimes.
- Not my style, brother.
[siren blipping]
Okay, so what's up?
- All right, then.
I'll come straight to the point.
We've got a bad cop somewhere
inside the department.
- So who is it?
- We don't know who.
Do you know a man named
Antonio Garibaldi?
- Yeah, he's a crime boss,
porno business, stuff like that.
- Yeah well, we have
word that the stalker's
snuff films are being
distributed by Garibaldi.
- Well, that's fine.
You FBI.
Why don't you pick him up?
- Well.
It's not just him we're after.
He has a silent partner
somewhere in your department.
- So what are you telling me?
There's somebody in
my department that's
protecting him?
- Protecting him, supplying
him, informing him.
He knows a hell of
a lot more about us
than we know about him.
- Jesus.
So what are you
laying this on me for?
- Well, unless that
flaming somersault
off the viaduct
was an amazing act,
I think you're a man
that can be trusted.
- Yeah well, they say
that about me sometimes.
- You find the bad seed
and we'll bury him for ya,
but in the meantime,
watch your back, Dakota.
There's someone
inside your department
that doesn't want the
stalker to get caught.
- Yeah, not for long.
Thanks.
[tense music]
[couple chattering]
[phone ringing]
- Yes.
- You're getting off
the track, my friend.
- [Video Stalker
On Phone] How so?
- Forget about
this skid row cop.
We'll take care of him.
You just get to work
on your next project.
- I am.
[tense music]
- [Man] So, you gonna ask me in?
- [Julie] I don't know.
[laughing]
- And he whisks her away.
[tense music]
- [Kristin] I don't
think is a good idea.
- [Dak] Well, if we see
anybody, we'll deal with it.
This stuff's too important.
We have to have it.
[tense music]
- Got it.
Gotta copy this.
[keys clacking]
[mumbling]
- No, there's one
more thing I want
from the computer in here.
Copy this, huh, and download
all the stalker files.
[tense music]
- Get the disc from
the other machine.
I'll finish here.
[tense music]
Fuck, come on.
[whistling]
I was hoping that you'd show up.
- Show up for what?
- Well, I just wanted
to personally apologize
for being on the wrong team.
They told me that you work late.
- Do you wanna kiss and make up?
You know what?
You have been a bad girl.
You know what else?
Talk is cheap.
- [Kristin] I walk
the way I talk it.
- Do you like music?
- [Kristin] Very much.
- Do you like to hum?
- I'm an excellent hummer.
- Ooh, baby.
I'll bet you are an
excellent hummer.
- Shit.
- Have you ever
played the flute?
- Once or twice.
- What about the trombone?
- I've always
admired the trombone.
- What about the slide trombone?
[tense music]
[smoke alarm blaring]
- Did you see his face
when the alarm went on?
- You were gonna do it.
I don't believe it.
You actually were gonna do it.
- Well, you said
whatever it takes.
- Wait, wait, wait.
The trombone.
Did you see the trombone?
- Whoo.
- A 12-digit number and
the words First Bahamian.
- It's a bank.
It's gotta be an
offshore account.
- What the hell would this
guy need a foreign bank for?
- I'll call a computer
buddy of mine.
Maybe we can access the account.
- [Dak] Yeah.
- Here you go, Mommy.
- Thank you, sweetheart.
- Well, thank you.
Wow, fresh lemonade.
It's really great.
You make it?
- Yes.
[smooching]
- You know, she's
the greatest thing
that ever happened to me.
Raising a child by
yourself is so expensive.
Sure glad my mom's
here to help out.
- Ah, so I see, that's
why you accepted
this demotion without
puttin' up a fight, right?
Ah.
- [Kristin] Mmm hmm.
- Okay.
It's good lemonade.
So, what do we got so far?
- Somebody, the serial killer,
he chooses beautiful girls,
early 20s, Catholic
and they're all
having affairs with married men.
- And they all go to the
same Catholic church?
- The task force has
people at every mass
and the FBI checked out all
the priests, nuns, janitors.
- Are you Catholic?
- When I was a kid.
- So tell me this, if you
wanted to choose a victim
at a church, how
would you do it?
- Well, I always
wanted to know what
my boyfriend said
in confessions.
[bell tolling]
- So, find anything?
- Nothing.
- Ah.
All right.
Give me a shot.
Back in five.
- Bless you, my child.
- Yeah.
- Bless me, Father,
for I have sinned.
- Yeah, right.
- It has been how long
since your last confession?
- Confession?
- [Priest] Just
tell God your sins.
- Well, uh.
I've enjoyed a little adultery.
Fellatio, uh,
receiving, not giving.
Is that a sin?
- Yes, go on.
- Oh well, I...
Lie a little,
cheat a little,
steal a little.
And I also drink too much.
But I eat right.
I exercise,
take vitamins.
- Any bad language?
- [Dak] Holy fuck.
- What in God's name?
- Well, I'm sorry
Father, but I'm a cop
and the Video Stalker has been
recording your confessions.
- [Man] We're on in five,
four,
three,
two.
- [Julie] Officer Smith,
why don't you tell us
about your discovery?
- Well, as we were
discussing earlier,
we found this tiny camera
and a transmitting device--
- [Video Stalker] Kris, they're
talking about the master.
- [Dak] Very popular
Catholic church.
- Can you imagine
having your confession,
your face, on video tape?
- Yeah well, if
he liked her looks
and if she confessed
to adultery,
then he'd begin to stalk her.
- And when he was ready,
having edited his movie,
he would abduct her and--
- [Dak] Well, as far as we
know, these tapes were being
bought and sold in Europe.
- [Video Stalker] Oh, Dak.
Can't you see she wants you?
Come on, man.
- Isn't that a bit unusual?
It doesn't fit the profile
for a serial killer
to be profiting from his crimes.
- [Dak] Well, certainly that's
more information than I,
I'd like to get
into at this time.
- [Julie] I understand.
Recapping our top story.
If you've been with us
throughout this broadcast--
- Take this out to her.
- On the air?
It's gonna scare
the shit out of her.
- Just do it.
Camera two, camera three,
tight on her face.
Yeah, a little tighter.
All right, rolling all cameras.
- To help us answer these,
and other questions,
earlier today I spoke with
clinical psychologist--
- Yes!
Oh.
[chuckling]
- We have received
what is apparently
from the Video Stalker.
It has its usual laser
printed label, logo.
[tense music]
This may be a joke.
We will check it out, of course.
It is another development
in the bizarre case
of the Video Stalker.
Where do we go from here?
Okay.
We'll be back shortly.
We're going for a break.
We'll be back with newstalk.
- [Man] We're clear.
Back in three minutes.
- Son of a bitch!
You bastard!
How could let them give
me this on the air?
[tense music]
- [Man] House lights.
- I'd like to dust
that for prints.
- Dak, I'm scared.
- Sweetie, you're
safe in here, okay?
Can't get to you.
Give me the tape, all right?
- Dak, I'm next.
- Julie, you're safe, okay?
Just give me the
tape, all right?
- No.
No, I wanna see what this
sick fuck's got on me!
[tense music]
- Check and see who
brought this damn thing in.
- I'm on it.
[uptempo tense music]
[knocking]
- Julie!
[blasting]
- Low life piece of shit.
Look, get me a
location on his van
and you get back to me
as soon as possible.
As soon as we're done
with this weight,
I want you to pick up
our Video Stalker friend
and fold up his
operation and ship
the whole pile down to Mexico.
- Got it.
[siren blaring]
[tense music]
[mumbling]
- Let's go, let's go, come on.
- [Man] What's goin' on?
- Dak, he's losin' it.
[knocking]
Dak, it's Muscles.
What's goin' on?
- Hey, workin' on the
12 steps, come on in.
[gunshots blasting]
- Hey, I don't wanna
get shot, Dak, okay?
How 'bout puttin' the gun away?
- Come on in, Muscles.
It's all clear, man.
[gunshots blasting]
[gun thwapping]
♪ Dakota Smith
["Dakota Smith-You're 12
Steps Away" by Jada Pointer
and the Pointer Family]
♪ Dakota Smith
♪ You know you can make it
♪ 'Cause you can, can
- [Kristin] Hi.
I'm on duty but I'll meet
ya back at the mission.
♪ One, two, three,
four, 12 steps away ♪
♪ Hey Dakota
♪ I know you can make it
♪ All you have to
do is be believed ♪
♪ Hey Dakota
♪ I know you can do it
♪ Just remember to
have faith in thee ♪
♪ Tryin' to be sober
♪ Ain't easy I know
♪ With each new day
♪ Another day to grow
♪ Dakota Smith
♪ Where you gonna run to
♪ Dakota
- They killed my fish, man.
- Varmints got everything.
Scavengers all over the place.
But I managed to do
this for you, bud.
- Thanks, thanks man.
- Tried my best, that's the
only thing I could manage
to hold back for you.
- My motorcycle.
Where's my motorcycle?
- IRS.
Ain't nothin' I
could do about that.
You know they're big guys.
♪ Hey Dakota
- Thanks, man.
♪ I believe in you
- Here, man.
I know, I know
this'll work for you.
Nothin' else.
Smoke one.
All right.
- Back at ya.
♪ Will surely smile on you
♪ Dakota Smith
Shit.
I mean, everything is
happening in my life.
I'm so close to rock bottom
I can almost feel it.
- If you don't
make some changes,
you're never gonna get
that loving weekend.
- Yeah, but I don't
even have a Harley.
- So, that's it?
You quit?
Mahoney walks.
The stalker wins.
You comin'?
[uptempo music]
Okay, I have a 12-digit number.
Now I need a code.
Three,
two two,
five four.
Shit.
- What about birthday,
wedding date?
- I've tried everything.
I have his file right here.
- Look, I'll tell you what.
I'm a little tired.
Let's do this again later, okay?
[keys clacking]
[melancholy music]
You know something?
I wanna change, but I can't
get out of my own way.
- Do you believe in miracles?
- Oh yeah.
I don't know.
- Well, you know how
to pray, don't you?
- Well,
I used to know how
to do that, but,
somewhere along
the way I forgot.
- Just close your eyes.
[chuckling]
- Okay, all right.
- Sweet.
- Catch ya later.
- Dak.
See ya tomorrow.
[melancholy music]
[uptempo tense music]
[chuckling]
I've got him.
- Damn.
My cigars.
- Would you still dress
that way if you knew
this was the last
day of your life?
[uptempo music]
Missed a spot.
Very clever, bitch.
Come to papa.
[buzzing]
- Party's over.
We're movin' you outta town.
- Fuck that.
The bitch has disappeared
off the screen.
Get her.
[uptempo tense music]
[gunshots blasting]
Damn, bitch.
[thudding]
- Oh, boy.
[cracking]
[thudding]
[zapping]
[uptempo tense music]
[engines zooming]
- Shit.
Son of a...
[tense music]
They've got Kris.
- I heard the APB.
- [Dak] Where is she?
- How would I know?
- [Dak] Wrong answer.
- You're dead, Smith.
- Screw you.
- You're crazy.
- Yeah?
[thudding]
[grunting]
Last time I'm gonna ask you.
Where is she?
- [Mike] I don't know.
I told ya, I don't know.
- Relax boys, put 'em away.
[tense music]
- Mahoney's on the take.
- [Mike] Fuck you.
- Fuck me?
Nah, fuck you!
[gunshot blasting]
[screaming]
- Jesus, Dak!
- Dak!
- How'd you like
that, Mike, huh?
That feel good?
- Oh!
- [Dak] I'm gonna take
out the other one.
- No!
Wait.
I'll tell ya, I'll tell ya.
- No, don't tell me.
Show me.
- Stay put boys.
Stay where you are.
[tense uptempo music]
- Turn left up here, turn left.
[tires squealing]
Oh, my knees are killing me.
My goddamn knee's killing me.
- Mine's been hurting
for five years.
- You came in late.
- [Dak] Bullshit.
- You sat in the car and
you drank a six-pack.
They didn't show up.
You drank another six-pack.
Then they showed
up but you didn't.
You came in late.
I didn't blow our
your knees, you did.
Oh, God.
[engine zooming]
- Keep going.
- But he's a fuckin' psycho.
He carved up his girlfriend.
He screwed every
guy in his company.
He's in the nut
house for 10 years.
Now he's out doin'
the same thing
except he's gettin' paid for it.
[engine zooming]
- Wait, you don't
really wanna do this.
I'm a bit claustrophobic.
[groaning]
Guys, guys, come on.
Is this really a good idea?
Sir, sir, sir, I really, really
need to go to the bathroom.
- Well, go then, baby.
- Thanks a lot.
[thudding]
[grunting]
- Get the rest of the
gear, we're outta here.
[speaking foreign language]
[tapping]
[engine zooming]
[uptempo tense music]
- He's losin' a lot of blood.
- Shut up, drive faster.
[uptempo tense music]
[gunshots blasting]
You get them.
I'll take the van.
[uptempo tense music]
[gunshots blasting]
[crashing]
- Don't shoot, it's me!
Glad you're here,
that wasn't any fun.
- Let's get the hell outta here.
[clattering]
Go help Teak.
[uptempo tense music]
[gunshots blasting]
- Teak, you okay?
- I'm all right,
just keep going.
Son of a bitch.
- Hey, Detective Dak.
You gettin' tired of this shit?
Come and get me, man.
You're just gonna
keep on comin', huh?
Come on.
I'm right here.
I'm all yours, baby.
[booming]
[gunshots blasting]
- We gotta stop Dak.
- [Detective]
Forget it, Mahoney.
This is where we get off.
Get in.
- [Mike] What are you doin'?
- [Detective] Get in!
[uptempo tense music]
[thudding]
[grunting]
[cracking]
[uptempo tense music]
[gunshots blasting]
[thudding]
[footsteps clacking]
[cracking]
[thudding]
[uptempo tense music]
[gunshots blasting]
[chuckling]
- I seem to be out of bullets!
It's not the way I planned it.
You ever think of
workin' together?
Can't prove nothin' on me.
Good behavior, I'll
be out in five years.
Got something for you.
[gunshots blasting]
[uptempo tense music]
I was just...
[gasping]
- Thanks.
Asshole.
- And for 60 days and nights
without alcohol, Dakota Smith.
- Well, all right.
[clapping]
[cheering]
- My name is Dakota Smith
and I'm an alcoholic.
[clapping]
[cheering]
This is the first
time in my life
I've ever had 60
days of sobriety.
- [Newt] That's right!
[clapping]
[cheering]
- One after another.
[clapping]
[cheering]
- You know something?
I like it.
I like me.
I like you,
and I think it's gonna last.
[clapping]
[cheering]
- [Newt] That's
right, big fella.
You make it happen.
- You know why?
- [All] Why?
- [Newt] Why is that?
- Hey.
'Cause I believe in miracles.
[clapping]
[cheering]
- [Kristin] What would it take
to make your miracle complete?
- Well, I don't see how
that's gonna be possible.
I don't have a Harley.
[engine rumbling]
[mid-tempo jazzy music]
[engine revving]
Teak, my man.
- You've got a few friends left.
Not many.
We bought it at the IRS auction.
- You're a life saver, my
man, you're a life saver.
What's up?
Where you get the
money for this?
- Money?
They wanted to give it away.
It's a piece of junk.
They said get rid of it.
Paint it, it's yours.
Get outta here.
- Come on, we outta here.
We're going far away
from this place.
- You got that right.
[chuckling]
[engine rumbling]
[funky jazzy music]
["Seduction" by L.J. Reynolds]
♪ I've noticed the mystery
♪ Deep in your eyes
♪ When you look at me
♪ So sensually
♪ Just like Cleopatra
♪ The Queen of the Nile
♪ I've become obsessed
♪ Within your smile
♪ In all you do I know
there's nothin' wrong ♪
♪ This spirit that you've
staring me is so strong ♪
♪ It's a seduction
♪ Seduction
♪ Of the gentle kind
♪ It's a seduction
♪ Seduction
♪ Of the body, soul and mind
♪ It's a seduction
♪ Seduction
♪ Of the gentle kind
♪ And I'm hungry for you
♪ I want you to be mine
["The Night Vision" by Rio
Appling feat. Code Blue]
♪ I can see you but
you can't see me ♪
♪ Call it night vision
♪ If you're lonely I
will set you free ♪
♪ Hocus pocus I
got you on video ♪
♪ You don't hear me though
♪ This is the night
vision intro ♪
♪ So own up before
you get broke up ♪
♪ I hate to have to
see you in the morgue ♪
♪ Gettin' sewed up
♪ [mumbling]
♪ In a bag from a plastic gag
♪ Cold as ice
♪ Not even a vice was able
to save the nurse's life ♪
♪ Another victim
of this insane ♪
♪ To the membrane
♪ Here I come again
♪ Strikin' like pain
♪ Able to creep
while you sleep ♪
♪ It's not trick
♪ Peek a boo, I see
you Miss Freak ♪
♪ Down on your
knees, oh please ♪
♪ I know you're feelin' me
♪ Physically, mentally,
I'm your worst enemy ♪
♪ Horny as my homie
♪ Without you I'll be lonely
♪ Put your head
on my shoulders ♪
♪ Pretend that I'm Dakota
♪ Sorta like must be inventin'
♪ You can't turn
back from the fact ♪
♪ That your trap don't
take in the night vision ♪
♪ I can see you but
you can't see me ♪
♪ Call it night vision
♪ If you're lonely I
will set you free ♪
♪ Even though I
seem so far away ♪
♪ Call it night vision
♪ You better get
down on your knees ♪