Henson, bring it in.
Incoming!
Uh, Red Six, Red Six,
this is Red One, over.
Red Six,
this is Red One.
Be advised, we are
in the Northwest corner
of the initial objective,
and we are taking
small-arms fire
from the Western side
of the initial objective.
Uh, small arms
and mortar fire.
How copy, over?
Well...
I think we found 'em.
What gives you
that idea?
They don't seem to be
a very big group.
If it's the same one.
Well, let's keep going.
I got to say, man --
It's pretty gutsy
what you did back there.
You would have done
the same thing, right?
No, man.
That was
above and beyond.
Jenkins thinks you have
a death wish.
Well... it was
the right thing to do.
You some kind
of Captain America, now?
And, Tango,
where are you guys at?
You hear that?
No, they went behind.
Don't -- do not --
Tango, you guys there?
Uh, Red Six,
this is Red One.
Roger, last transmission,
over.
Hey, Eli.
- Yeah?
Boss wants
to see you.
Wish me luck.
Okay.
I'll look into it
and get back to you.
Hey, Jerry.
Eli, hello.
Hi.
Look, I want to make this
as painless as possible.
Every month I sit down
and evaluate everybody
on the ranch.
It's something I do,
so don't take it personal.
Are we done?
First of all, I'm not gonna go
over every single reason
why I've come
to this decision.
I've given you
plenty of time
to make the changes
I've suggested,
and frankly, Eli, you're just
not suited for this job.
Figures.
There comes a time
when a father has to stop
bailing his son out,
and I believe that time is now.
I mean, I can't mold you
into something you're not.
And these men here, well,
it wouldn't be fair to them, would it
if it looks like
I'm just giving the job
to anybody walkin'
in off the prairie?
Really?
Hey, my responsibility is
this business, Eli.
I'm just looking out
for what's best for the ranch.
You're a grown man.
No.
You're doing
what's best for yourself.
Last I checked,
that's your name
on the gate out there.
Look, Dad, if you don't want
to help me, then don't.
I didn't come here expecting
some handout from you.
You have got
to be kidding me.
That's exactly
why you came to me
'cause you had
nowhere else to go!
I obviously came
to the wrong place,
so I'm sorry.
It won't happen again.
You know what, Eli?
I got news for you, buddy.
I'm not the enemy here.
You do a right fine job driving your own life into the ground.
That's -- That's not
how I raised you, son.
I mean,
I would've thought the service would've taught you somethin' --
discipline, honor,
responsibility.
Where's all that at?
Dad, why don't you just fire me
and get this over with?
I'm trying to get you
to listen to me, Eli!
I am listening.
Dad, I hear you loud
and clear.
I don't think you do.
If you were smart,
you would look at this
as an opportunity
for you to stand up
and be a man for once.
I pray you see it
as I do for once.
Yeah, when's
the last time you prayed
for anybody
but yourself?
All right,
go home, Eli.
You know, I worked really hard
to get where I'm at today.
I grabbed
that bull by the horns,
and I made something
of myself,
and I think it's high time
you did the same.
Mom...
please, you got
to help me.
No, I-I don't want you
to go against what he says,
it's just that I...
It's just
until I found another j--
W-Well, I-I don't know.
M-Mom, come on,
I need this.
Y-you got to help me,
please.
How can this be
for my own good?
So, you want to, uh, see
your grandchild begging
for change on the corner
of Main Street and --
No.
No, no, Mom.
Mom, I'm sorry.
D-Don't -- don't --
don't hang up.
Don't hang u--
Oh, boy.
No!
It's gonna be
all right.
Come on, son, there's someone
who wants to meet you.
Who?
Uh, you'll see.
I don't want
to meet anybody, Dad.
- I just want to go home.
- Trust me, Eli.
I thought
they killed you.
Oh, Kleiver?
Nah, he couldn't keep me down
for too long,
not even if he tried.
You know
what they say --
Cheaters never win
in the long run.
And next time
I get him in the ring,
I'm gonna get him good.
You're the best, Jeremy.
Is your dad gonna bring you
to the show next Saturday?
Can we, Dad?
Please?
How about we come
every week, Eli?
Yes!
Sounds like a pretty great dad
you got there, Eli.
Got to head back home
for the week.
Okay, we got to get
out of here, too, "Bubba."
You ready?
- Bye, Jeremy.
Bye, Eli.
Mr. Isaacson.
- Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
I told you he'd be okay,
didn't I, son?
Yeah.
You were right, Dad.
How'd you know?
Eli, when you do
what's right --
all the rules
and don't cheat in life --
you always
end up ahead.
- You're pretty smart, Dad.
- I try to be.
It's been quite a day.
Grandma, you told me
to be strong.
Paging Dr. Bender.
Paging Dr. Bender, please.
Where have you been?
I got here
as soon as I could.
Well, not soon enough.
She doesn't have much time, Eli.
Well, what
do you want me to say?
I'm sorry.
It's not us you need
to be saying you're sorry to.
Come on, Mom.
Don't use that tone with your mother.
I'm sorry.
She's been asking for you
for hours, Eli.
I think she's holding on
just to see you.
Didn't you get
any of our messages?
- Yeah, I saw them, but --
- Oh, so you got our messages,
so your phone's
working.
Yes.
- Have you been drinking?
- What?
You heard me.
Your grandmother's on her deathbed and all you can do is think
about being out there
indulging yourself?
- I was not indulging myself.
- You were drinking.
- I had one drink.
- Exactly, I knew it.
How does that make
you feel, Eli?
Your grandmother's last memory
of her grandson is him drunk.
What's your recruiter gonna
think about that?
I'm not drunk.
I was spending time
with my friends
at my sendoff party,
and some spilled her drink
on my jacket.
Y-You know, you always draw
these -- these ridiculous
and stupid conclusions
about me
like you -- like you think
you know me,
and you don't, Dad.
Okay, so I'm gonna go
spend time
with my dying grandmother
in the other room --
and is the only person
who shows any interest
in the real me.
I'm gonna be
in heaven soon.
- No.
- I can see it.
Please, Grandma,
I need you here.
We're never ready
to let anyone go.
No, please don't go,
not now.
Not now, please.
Someday, you're going to do
something great with your life.
You're going
to use your talents
to create something
so beautiful
and see how God was leading you
to your destination
the whole time.
Everything happens
for a reason, Eli.
You must be brave
and take courage.
I don't know how.
He will lead you
through the highway, Eli.
Everything is gonna be
all right...
even if I'm not here.
I'll always be proud
of you --
forever.
I love you,
my darling grandson.
You must persevere.
Eli.
Yeah.
You must have faith.
I-I'm trying.
I'm trying, Grandma.
Piece of junk!
Daddy's here.
No, no, no.
Go sit down. Please?
- You're home early.
- Yeah.
What happened?
Look, Ganeen, I don't want
to talk about it, all right?
I'm in a bad mood.
Our mortgage is due
in two weeks.
You pay half of it.
We count on you.
And do you know that we wouldn't
be in this mess
if you hadn't quit
your dancing job?
You know I couldn't keep
doing that job, Eli.
Ohh.
That's right. I'm sorry.
I forgot.
You've changed.
Eli.
Eli, we need
to talk about this.
What?
You know what, Ganeen,
at some point,
I just have to stop believing
that everything is my fault.
I mean, think about it --
Either everyone I know is
out to get me
for some reason,
or I have the worst luck
in the universe.
The universe isn't
out to get you.
My life isn't easy,
either.
And that's my fault,
too, right?
I shouldn't have
to have two jobs
because
you can't hold one.
If you're so unhappy,
why don't you just go?
Are we really back
at that, again?
Well...
guess I don't need
this, anymore.
The clothes don't make
the man, Eli.
It's not
about the stupid vest, Ganeen.
What, so, it's my fault
you lost your job?
You sound ridiculous.
Yeah, well...
That's me --
ridiculous.
Why are you still with me
if I'm such a loser?
How about this --
I'll go.
Is that better?
I'll get out of the way
of your happiness.
Is that useful enough
for you?
- If you walk out again --
- What? What are you going to do?
You going to find some little --
good little Christian
and play house?
I'm sure he'll be pleased
to find out
about your past life
as a stripper.
Aw, I'm sorry --
"exotic dancer," right?
Yeah, that's better.
You know why
we aren't happy, Ganeen?
It is impossible to be happy
with someone like you.
I'm sorry.
Eli, don't leave.
Where you going, Daddy?
* I could make
a million bucks *
Hey, Eli.
Howdy, John.
Kind of empty here
tonight, huh?
Eh, it's all right
with me.
Hey, look, I'm, uh --
I'm sorry about what happened.
What happened?
You gettin' fired
and all.
* ...but it's on my mind *
* Oh, on my mind *
* This feeling
I'm feeling right now *
* I like it so much *
Hey, can I get a -- get a shot
of whiskey, too, please?
Rough night?
Rough life.
How long you been coming
in here, Eli?
Um...
Well, about since you -- you
bought the place, I think.
Yeah.
It used to be a dump.
I didn't change a thing.
Really?
Yeah.
Oh...
So, I know it's none
of my business,
but what's going on
with you and Ganeen?
Things change, Tim.
I still remember the night
you two laid eyes on each other.
It was different.
"Different"?
She didn't come in here
too often,
but when she did,
every guy in here would trip
over themselves
to catch her eye.
Yeah.
I remember you sittin'
about right there.
And she --
she comes up to you.
Yeah.
Like a...
like a lost puppy.
Could've been.
I just know that, uh,
when you two were talkin',
there was
a connection there,
like you were
the only two people in the room.
I don't see that
too often --
as if it were, uh, meant
to happen.
Oh, Tim, you sound like you're
talking about God in a bar.
If you want
to call it that, sure.
Can't get away
from Him.
What?
Nothing.
* Yeah, and I might do it
again tomorrow *
* You got a Mercedes-Benz
and a uptown smile *
* Riding the real problem
ain't your style *
* Well, let me take you
on a knee *
* Yeah, I smell
that sweet perfume *
* And it always reminds me
of you *
* And a few summers ago *
* I can't see it in your walk *
Night, Eli.
* And in your voice
when you talk *
* He's gonna take *
* Take it too far *
* He's running out *
* You looking at me? *
* Hiding words *
* Not a frown... *
* And I know
And when Jesus said that
he's the light of the world,
...that means we are
the light of the world, too.
We shine in the darkness.
And when light shines
in the darkness,
nothing can hide from it.
Of course.
* You ain't gettin'
nowhere fast *
Loser.
What a bunch of... idiots.
I work harder than any of them.
Take some responsibility.
And for what, Dad?
Why, so you can fire me?
Thanks, "Pop."
Yeah, no matter
what you say, Dad...
I got a family.
You've been nothing
but a problem from day one.
See, Dad?
You see?
Maybe you shouldn't have been
born in our family.
Oh, no.
Come back, Daddy.
Oh, boy.
Hello?
Anyone?
Help.
Help!
Yeah, okay.
Now, wait, just --
I just went this way.
I just -- every --
What?
Hello!
Anyone!
Aah!
Don't be stupid, Eli.
It's just the wind.
Oh!
I told you
to take care of it, son.
Take some responsibility.
But, no, you've just been
one failure on top of another.
You've been nothing
but a problem from day one.
Maybe you shouldn't have been
born in our family.
Or maybe you shouldn't have
been born at all.
Yeah!
Whoo-hoo!
Drink up, man.
Live for today.
Live for tonight.
We shouldn't have to care
about anything else.
Just look around --
Life is one big party.
Who cares about Ganeen?
Who cares
about anything!
Yeah-ha!
Hey, Eli.
I'm so happy.
The weight...
it's been lifted.
You still don't see it,
do you?
No more striving.
No more doubt.
If only you opened
your eyes.
No.
Open your eyes.
Come on.
We are but a vapor.
Whoo! Ooh!
Aah!
Whew!
That's it?!
That's how it's supposed to end?
I'm going to die here alone,
and no one will ever know it!
Grandson, always remember
to put your trust in the Lord.
He'll never let you down.
I love you.
This isn't...
This doesn't make sense.
The fire should be...
Is somebody out there?
Hello!
We may get together
to study God's word,
but you know that
it's so much more than that.
I mean, we're here
to support you.
So tell us what's going on.
You know how Eli is.
Our last argument...
was really bad, and...
he left.
I think
that this is it.
Do you think
he's gonna leave you?
I don't...
I don't know.
I don't --
A part of me...
just wants
to show him the door
with his bags packed.
I'm hurting.
And yet...
"And yet" what, honey?
Maybe God's trying
to show me something.
I had a dream
last night.
And I don't remember much,
you know?
But when I woke up
suddenly...
I heard the words,
"Eli's time has come."
And I got
this terrible feeling.
And...
all I could do was pray.
So, that's
what I've been doing, but...
I think
that's why we're here.
We're reinforcements.
Come on, ladies.
Father...
we come to you
with heavy hearts
but hopeful hearts
because we know
that you love us.
And, Lord,
we want to lift up Ganeen,
and we lift up Eli.
You know him, and you know
what he's going through.
And we know
that the enemy would seek
to steal, kill,
and destroy him completely.
Father,
we ask you protect him,
that you'd reveal
yourself to him in a way
that speaks
to his deepest heart.
We ask this
in your mighty name.
Amen.
I know you're out there!
I'm armed!
Just don't come near me,
spirits of...
This is crazy.
Please, stop!
Why don't you help me
out of here?
Of course you won't.
Hello?
Show yourself!
I miss you too, Daddy.
Hannah?
Come on, Daddy!
Where are you, darling?
I have something
for you.
Over here, Daddy.
Hurry, Daddy.
It's just for you.
You're not Hannah.
Yes I am.
Come back, Daddy.
- Happy with yourself?
- What?
How do I know
if this is real?
It was you, wasn't it?
You're the one
who's doing all this.
No, Eli.
Then, who,
t-the Indian spirits?
I've appeased them.
How far off the path
you have gone.
You remember,
don't you?
It was
a long time ago.
Eli...
I knew that you were special
from the beginning --
set apart.
I don't believe in that stuff
anymore, okay?
It's for losers.
It's for people who --
who can't make it
on their own.
And your life is so much better without it?
You died.
When you left,
it left.
Eli,
are you listening?
Eli!
Eli Isaacson?
Yeah, I'm Eli.
Oh, well...
we have been looking
for you.
I-I crashed my truck,
and I'm -- I got lost.
Yeah, we know.
- P-People are looking for me?
- Oh, definitely.
Yeah, but I'm glad
we found you.
Your family's been getting
a little worried about you, son.
M-my family?
I-I-I --
Hey, listen, uh,
let me take a look at you.
Let me, uh, make sure
you're doing okay.
Hey, I-I just want
to get out of here, okay?
I understand.
Just hold tight.
It's all procedure.
- Fine, can, um --
- Well, look at me, son.
Let me see.
Well, you look fine.
Yeah, right, "fine."
So...
What you doing up here
by yourself anyway?
I just driving.
Just driving?
Listen, son, no one just drives
up here in these parts.
Yeah, well, this thing
with my girlfriend and...
Women --
Enough to drive you crazy.
Say no more.
I'll tell you though --
If your relationship is
causing you to drive up
so far away from home,
maybe it's ain't worth
the trouble, you know?
Really?
You got to look out
for yourself, son.
You know, don't get tricked,
you know,
into thinking
that you have, you know,
all these responsibilities
to other people.
You lose yourself
that way --
you know, your dreams.
It's like they say
on the airplanes
with the oxygen masks,
you know?
You got to put yours
on first.
I mean, if you don't take care
of yourself first...
there may be no "you"
to take care of.
My advice to you --
Look out for número uno.
Yeah.
Yeah, I guess
that makes sense.
You are darn right
it does.
Try telling that
to my girlfriend.
You know, you been up here
for days on end
because of her.
You know,
she drove you to this.
If she is
that much of a hassle,
you need
to cut her loose, man.
I'm sorry.
Where did you say your team was?
Hey, man, where are we?
Do you even know
how to get out of here?
Hold your horses, son.
I've got a map here.
I'll show you
where we are.
Okay.
Okay, so this is
where we find your truck, right?
And this is
where we are now.
Now, if you would have kept
walking around this direction,
you'd hit the highway.
See, now, really,
you ain't all that far from where you started.
You're just
a little turned around is all.
No, no, it's --
it was like a maze.
Yeah, it'll happen out here.
You got to be careful.
These woods can play tricks
on you.
W-what about the --
There's the --
I found
some old graveyard thing,
and it's not
on the map.
Yeah, well, you know...
I wouldn't worry too much
about that.
You know, a few days up here
by yourself, and you're bound
to go a little bit
nutty.
No.
I-It -- I was hearing
weird things, man.
There was like --
There were figures
and shadows.
I-I heard
two men fighting or something?
It's --
Look, I-I know
it sounds crazy, okay?
I just --
I'm not
a mountain man.
Thank God you found me.
That's what
we're here for --
You know, to help confused
people find their way.
So, uh...
Do you think
your team will be long, or...
Yeah,
they know I'm here.
You know, we keep track
of each other, yeah.
They won't be long.
Don't worry. You'll see.
Hey, man, again,
thank you.
I just -- I feel much better
having you here.
Really?
Good.
That's the way
it should be.
Here, hold this
for a minute.
I ain't got good reception out here,
so I'm gonna walk
over here and use this, but, uh,
I need you to stay put.
Where am I gonna go?
Ah, I hear you there.
Stay put.
Yeah.
Hey, come on!
Where'd you go?!
Oh, no. No.
I can't do this in the dark!
Hello?
Stop.
Please, just stop.
Get back here.
Don't make me hunt you down.
You gonna shoot me?
I just want to find out
who was peekin'
in the flap of my tent.
Who are you?
Who am I?
What's more important is,
"Who are you?"
It doesn't matter
who I am.
Oh, I beg to differ
with you, young man.
If you don't tell me,
I'm gonna get Mordecai
to run you off
'and make sure you never
come back here again,
and I can go back inside
to my nice, warm abode
and continue having
a quiet evening.
Mordecai your gun?
Now what kind
of moron names his gun?
Mordecai.
M-Mordecai's that dog?
Well, he ain't my kin.
Look, son, I'm freezing
my tail off out here.
Either we can go inside
and continue this discussion,
or you can go back
to where you come from
and, uh, we'll call it
a night.
Come on in.
My name's Gabe.
You look like you've seen
better days.
Yeah, so do you.
You want something
to drink?
Uh, whiskey.
I have, uh, coffee.
Bet you're hungry,
too, huh?
Yeah, I'm starving.
Well, I do have
some, uh, chicken.
You have chicken?
It's over there
in a cooler.
Sorry it's not warm.
I am not one
to complain.
So you say.
I see
it's to your liking.
Mm-hmm.
So, what brings you
to my neck of the woods?
I crashed my truck.
Mm-hmm.
What?
Well, why didn't you stay put
until somebody rescued you?
My head was spinning.
Everything was fuzzy.
I just --
I-I got confused.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, that happens.
Look, do other people
live up here,
other, uh,
forest people?
"Forest people"?
You mean like...
little people
with colored overalls
and tall, pointy hats?
No, I mean are there
other people up here
besides you?
Nope, just me and Mordecai.
That's about it.
Why?
Have you seen
any of these little, uh,
forest people?
No, no, but --
Never mind.
Actually, I have seen
a few strange things
in these woods.
Like what?
A grown men wandering aimlessly
for days on end,
calling from the rapid beat
of his own heart,
brash
from the raven's cry,
furious, self-destructive
as a grizzly,
all the while acting like
he's been raised by wolves.
Strange things --
strange things, Eli.
Yeah, well, now I see why
you don't have any guests.
You have to admit...
I had you going there
for a spell.
You know what? No.
I don't have
to admit anything.
Aha!
That's your trouble --
not admitting.
You don't know me.
You don't know anything
about me or my life story.
So enlighten me.
No.
I-I don't owe you anything,
old man.
Come with me.
W-what? No.
Why would I do that?
Are you always
so obstinate?
You're a guest in my tent.
You've eaten my food.
And if you want to enjoy
the warmth of my fire,
you'll help an old man get
some more wood.
Well?
So, you have
a family?
Yeah.
Kind of.
You, uh, "kind of" have
a family?
Yeah.
I've got a girlfriend
and a daughter.
So you have people
who care about you?
They'll be looking
for you.
Nobody knows I'm lost.
I've been, uh --
I've disappeared
before.
So, no.
Nobody's looking
for me.
Oh, I disagree.
It sounds like you've been lost
even longer than you think.
Hand me
that piece of wood there.
Nice.
Bring the rest.
Well?
Could I ask you
a question?
Fire away.
"Fire away."
That's a good one.
Why haven't you asked me
the way out yet?
What?
You're lost,
and you haven't asked me
the way out of these woods.
I have, uh--
I have this map.
You have a map
of these woods?
Yeah, it's this right here.
If I leave in the morning,
I can find my own way
out of here.
Not with this, you won't.
Who gave you this map?
The, uh --
the park ranger.
"The park ranger" --
Here?
Yeah, he was --
He was looking for me.
I'm sure he was.
Well, he disappeared.
Look, man, it doesn't
matter what I say.
Anything I tell you, it's just
gonna make me sound crazy.
So can we just drop it?
If you'd like.
Why don't you tell me
about your daughter?
My daughter?
Yeah.
It's been a long time since
I've been around little ones.
What's she like?
She's amazing.
She just turned 4
a few months ago,
and we might be putting her
in preschool soon.
I think.
I-I don't really --
I don't know, 'cause I don't
really make those decisions.
What's her name?
Hannah.
"Hannah-Banana,"
That's what I call her...
yeah, if, um --
if I tuck her in
at night.
"If?" Why?
You work late, or...
Nope.
I'm jobless.
Well, I'd say raising
a little one's
a pretty important job.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, I guess --
I guess you're right.
You know, I...
I don't know why I'm telling you
all this stuff.
I don't even know
what I'm doing here.
You're right.
You don't.
That's what got you here
in the first place.
Yeah, I guess
you're right.
So, tell me more
about, uh... Hannah.
What else
do you want me to say?
That I'm not around
to tuck her in at night or...
watch her paint
her paintings
or when she wants
to dress up,
or that I'm just
this deadbeat,
jobless dad
w-who cares more about
spending time at the bar
and watching football
than taking care
of his family?
Is that
what you want to hear?
Hey, just consider me
your sounding board.
Right.
So, are you churchgoers?
Yeah.
They go.
But not you?
You know what, man?
I don't think this is any of your business.
You know, frankly,
you're right.
Everything you told me is
none of my business,
but it just seems
like you, uh,
need to get a few things
off your chest.
Come on, Mordecai.
Hey,
you're still here.
God hasn't been a part
of my life for a long time.
So I figure...
why involve Him now?
You think that's funny?
I don't need
a man-made map
for this
ever-changing wilderness,
and neither do you, Eli.
It was you, wasn't it?
You did this.
Y-You're the one who's been
keeping my fire going
and got me all turned around
in the woods.
No.
Open your eyes, son.
There's a lot more
going on here than --
No, you open your eyes,
old man!
It's my life, okay?
I'm in charge of my life.
I control my destiny,
no one else -- me.
You got it?
- Oh, I got it.
I get
that you're not getting it.
But it'll happen.
It'll happen
when you're ready.
What'll happen?
You gonna do something?
It's hard to understand
but, trust me, it will happen.
No, I-I don't have
to trust you.
If you don't trust me,
trust God.
He's looking
after you.
There's a battle going on
for you
that's even bigger
than you can believe.
Stop it.
Ohh.
I feel like
I'm going crazy.
That's what happens.
It's all part of the process.
I'm sorry.
No apology needed.
May I pray for you?
Y-You want to pray
for me?
Are you serious?
If you'll allow it.
All right, um, just --
just don't expect me
to do any of that...
praying-after-you...
whatever stuff, okay?
Of course.
Heavenly Father,
I'm with Eli.
He's suffered
in these woods.
I pray to you, God,
that you will heal him.
Lead him out of this wilderness
and back home to his family,
who need him
and love him.
I ask this, that you warm him
in Your love.
I pray this
in Jesus' name.
Amen.
Come on inside.
I'll get you some blankets.
No.
No, this isn't happening.
I didn't dream this.
I didn't dream it!
Come on!
Hello?!
Gabe!
Mordecai!
I can't --
I can't believe it.
What's going on?
Okay!
Okay, God,
if this is really you,
let me see you.
Come on!
Show yourself!
Big, mighty, powerful Jesus!
Come on!
You want me
to believe you're real,
show me something!
Come on, give me fire
right now!
Come on!
Do it again!
Give me food, give me shelter,
give me something!
Yeah, I knew it!
I knew it wasn't you!
I mean, why would you want
to help me, huh?
I mean, me!
Is this punishment, torture?
What, you want me
to die out here,
freeze to death?
My little girl back at home
not knowing that I was sorry --
I'm not supposed
to die out here.
What
about the calling of my life?
What about your calling?
God, please...
don't let me die, not now.
I put my trust in you.
Please help me.
I need you.
Hey, buddy,
are you okay?
- Daddy!
- Hey, Banana.
Come here, baby.
Ohh.
Hannah,
go to your room.
But I want to see Daddy.
Hannah. No, that's okay.
Do what your mom says.
Go on. Go.
What are you doing?
Listen, um, I know --
I know that --
"Know" -- Eli,
you don't know anything.
You don't know
how hard it is
to tell my 4-year-old daughter
why her daddy disappears
and doesn't show up
for a week.
You don't know.
No, um...
you're right.
Where were you?
Um...
That's all you have
for me -- nothing?
I don't have
any excuses.
No more, um --
I don't have
any justification,
no more --
no more lies.
This time was different.
I wish I could undo
all the -- all the lies
and convince you
that -- that I've changed,
but, um...
I just wish
you could believe me.
I do, but I understand
if you can't.
The other night, um...
I left the bar, and I-I drove
into the mountains.
And, um, I crashed my truck
into the woods, and I got lost.
And that's where
I've been ever since.
I don't want
to fight anymore, okay?
You're right.
I-I'm a horrible father.
I'm a horrible boyfriend.
I don't expect you
to believe me.
But, Ganeen,
I'm different.
I can't even explain it
to myself.
Try me.
Really?
Really.
This is all very...
un-Eli-ish of you.
It is un-Eli-ish,
isn't it?
I think it's God.
God?
Eli...
what happened to you?
I-I don't know.
It was some kind
of, um...
like a battle.
I never --
I never told you --
Well, I never told
anybody this.
Um...
There was this one week
when I was 10.
My parents dropped me off
at my Grandma Meredith's place.
She always believed in me
when no one else would,
you know?
She told me
that she had been fasting
a-and praying for me.
She believed
I had a calling,
a great purpose
in life.
A few years later,
she died.
I was, uh...
I was, uh --
W-what kind of God
would take someone like that
away from you?
I guess...
I guess
I've just been, uh...
running ever since,
hiding,
just fighting,
you know, until now.
I was h-- I was hoping
you would pray with me.
You want to pray?
- Mm-hmm.
- With me?
Please.
Um...
Hey, God.
It's, uh --
It's been a while.
And, uh...
Well
a lot's happened.
And, uh...
I can see
that it was you, Lord.
I can see that it was you
in everything.
And, um...
I know you have
a lot more to teach me,
and, Lord,
please help me.
Help me to do right
by Ganeen.
And, uh, help us
to be better,
to live with honor
and, um, to not hurt
each other or you.
Please, Lord.
In the name of Jesus...
amen.
Wow.
It's been a long time
since I was in Sunday school.
You guys seem really smart.
I'm a little nervous.
Yeah.
But it's good.
It's good.
It's good that you're here.
Who knows my daughter, Hannah?
All of you?
Good.
Did you know
that she prays for me.
Did she tell you that?
Did she talk about it at all?
You know, she prays a lot.
How many of you, uh --
How many of you kids
pray for your parents?
That's good.
That's important.
Um...
We need it.
It makes -- It makes
a lot of difference.
Yeah, um, did Hannah
ever tell you guys
about the time
I was lost in the forest?
What?
How lost were you?
I was so lost --
for days --
that everywhere I turned
just lead me right back
into the forest.
I couldn't find my way out.
I was so lost.
I was certain I was never gonna
get out of that wood.
You guys ever have
to go to your room
because you didn't listen
or, like, you didn't do
something you were told, yeah?
That was -- That was kind of
what happened in the forest.
Um...
God, when he wants us
to listen,
sometimes he has
to do something
to pull us aside and say,
"Hey, pay attention."
But, you know,
God doesn't stop there.
The Bible says that Jesus
then equips us to --
to do good works,
to do what we were
always meant to do.
Yeah.
My grandma told me that.
She always used
to tell me that and a lot more.
When your heart is
in the right place,
get ready.
Some amazing things will happen.
Are you ready?