Hello,
this is Lou Vinetti
reporting live from KJRX.
I don't know if anybody
out there can hear me or not.
Only hours remain before Earth's
magnetic field declines to zero,
and as most of
you know by now,
once that occurs
solar radiation will destroy
the atmosphere.
And God be with us all.
Turn the car off.
I think it's gone.
Start the car.
Dammit.
We'll have to go back.
Get out of the car now!
Come on! Jump!
Ahhh!
No!
Flights across the globe
have been grounded for 24 hours
as the comet
Copernicus passes Earth,
which will be the largest
celestial object
in recorded history
to pass this close.
It is expected to create
a global
electromagnetic disturbance.
When the comet was first
discovered six months ago...
Good morning.
Hey, Miss Penny.
Hey, Cyn.
Zoe, that's Cynthia's order
in the fridge over there.
Okay.
So I'm taking the science club
on a field trip to watch
the comet.
I heard.
That's very brave of you.
You're coming along
too, right, Zoe?
Yep.
Dad is letting me off work
early so I can come, right, dad?
I suppose.
Next up to discuss what
unforeseen dangers
we might be facing we are
joined now via satellite
by our own
Dr. James Mayfield.
Hey, look who's on TV.
Now, doctor, can you
explain why you believe
it's possible that
the comet could hit us
when almost everyone else
has predicted
that it will pass us by.
Wait a minute,
Lou, all I said was
that you can't
you rule it out.
Having just passed the sun,
gasses in the comet's icy core
will be heating
up like a hot spring.
It will affect the comet's
speed and trajectory
in ways that we just
can't predict.
Fascinating.
Now I understand the storm's
hazard department
has sent you to Northern
Alaska to observe
the comet's swing-by.
That's right.
We'll be just inside
the Arctic Circle where
the comet is expected to pass
over its orbital fulcrum,
meaning the closest
it will be to Earth.
It's a very exciting opportunity
for us to observe
geomagnetic anomalies
in the Earth's magnetic field.
Thank you, doctor.
That was local hero and astrophysicist,
Dr. James Mayfield,
via satellite from Alaska.
Getting a signal?
Yep.
Logging in
to the satellite.
Last two Cubans.
I'm saving them for
a special occasion.
That's against
the law you know.
Yeah well relax, Peter,
we're in Alaska.
The U.S. Trade Embargo
says no American citizen
can smoke a Cuban cigar
anywhere in the world.
Alright, we're in.
Show time.
You could get ten years.
Good point.
I better smoke
both of them.
Hey, Pam,
satellite link is up.
You should be getting
our EM readings.
Copy, James.
Reading it now.
Across the globe eyes are
looking skyward tonight.
Millions of teacher and
students in every nation
get the chance to glimpse
something the great
astronomers of the past
could only dream of.
Okay, everyone,
I'd like to show you something.
Just as our planet
has a magnetic field
so does the comet.
Geeze.
The comet's going to be
going past Pluto
by the time
this guy finishes.
Zoe, could you come
up here, please?
Hold this up
for me, please.
So we're going to imagine that this
compass is Earth.
As the comet passes
the magnetic fields interact
creating intense bursts
of electromagnetic waves
which can interfere
with modern technology,
so, ladies, no sulking if your
boyfriend doesn't return
your text
messages tonight.
Yo, it's a freaking comet,
not your mother undressing.
Hey, move it.
Leave him alone.
Hey!
Stop it!
Stop.
You're both going to be
reimbursing the school
for the cost
of a new telescope.
This guy started it,
Miss Penny.
No, I didn't.
He was picking on him.
It's Mrs. Mayfield now and
I don't particularly care
who started it.
You're both paying
for a new telescope.
I'll be contacting your parents about the exact cost.
It's bad enough you
married my father,
now I can't even get
fair treatment in class.
Go wait by the wait by
the washroom, Shane.
The data is looking
a bit fragmented.
The electromagnetic interference
is coming on strong.
Yeah.
Our friend Copernicus
seems unusually magnetic.
Where's my lighter?
Viewers are probably experiences
increased interference
as Copernicus reaches
what is expected to be
its closest
proximity to Earth.
Comet is at orbital fulcrum.
It should be passing over your
area in just a few minutes.
We just got word that the comet
has reached orbital fulcrum.
This is extraordinary.
We will continue
to broadcast...
We may lose our signal.
We apologize for that.
An electromagnetic
storm from the comet
is affecting our electricity.
Whoa! Whoa!
We just had a surge in
the electron acceleration.
The fields EM levels
are skyrocketing.
The radiation belt is being
pushed in to the atmosphere.
Pam, are you reading this?
Yes.
I'm measuring a radiation
spike in the belt's safe zone.
4.5 million
angstroms and rising.
Wait, that's odd.
I'm getting a second
set of separate readings
from the comet.
Magnify sector LP4.
I see something
in the tail.
Copernicus is fragmenting.
A piece of the comet
is breaking away.
We can't see anything.
Can you read
the fragment specs?
Projectile diameter
is 300 meters.
Velocity of 30
kilometres a second.
What's the trajectory?
Descending at...
45 degrees.
It's going to hit Earth.
Use the belt's electron
trajectory to triangulate
a point of impact.
Working on it.
Latitude 51.
Longitude 179.
James, that's only 100 miles
from where you are.
James, did you hear
what I said?!
Get out of there!
Notify IEW
to issue an alert.
Repeat, notify IEW
Pam, do you copy?
Dammit!
Where is the projected
point of impact?
I don't know.
I lost her.
Maybe I can
amplify the signal.
Shockwave!
Get back in the car!
What's the point?!
We're dead!
We can't outrun
this blast!
Avalanche bunker
at the bottom of the hill.
What?
Step on it, man!
Try and put in the data
in case we don't make it.
James.
Peter, get out of there!
Come on!
Reports of massive damage
and casualties have been
coming in from Alaska.
Northern Canada and
Eastern Russia.
Communication is still
down throughout
these affected areas.
As the death toll rises
we're getting estimates
the as many as a quarter million
people may have perished
in this history-making disaster.
One piece of
good news to report:
local resident
Dr. James Mayfield
has miraculously
survived the blast
despite being within a few
hundred miles of ground zero
when the comet struck.
He is expected to be
arriving home today.
James.
I thought I lost you.
It's good to be home.
Hey, buddy.
Hey, dad.
You okay?
Yeah.
Welcome home.
Thanks.
Who wants coffee?
I would love one.
Well, uh, I'm sure you guys
have lots of science stuff
to talk about.
Shane, I just got home.
Sit down with us.
I'm kind of tired.
I feel like laying down.
He got into a fight
and broke a telescope.
I'm making him and the other
kid pay for it.
Sorry.
No, no.
Don't be sorry.
I don't envy
either one of you.
I wouldn't want
a step-mother for a teacher
or a step-son
for a student.
Yeah, well now that
you're home
you're going to have to do
all the disciplining,
otherwise he's never going
to let me get close.
Deal.
Of all the different
scenarios that could happen
if a comet hit Earth,
I wonder Mr. President,
does the impact
of the comet create
any lasting effects the public
should be concerned with?
We're still investigating
that possibility,
but right now it doesn't appear that there's anything
the public needs
to be worried about.
You've gotta be joking.
What?
A 300 metre projectile hits the planet at 30 kilometres per second
and he's saying there's
nothing to worry about.
Maybe he just doesn't want
to scare the public...
unlike some people I know.
My science advisors
have reported
that the immediate
crisis is over,
so the important thing for
the American people to know
is that they are safe
and they can go on about
their daily lives.
This is unbelievable.
James, I know you went through a terrible ordeal in Alaska,
but you're home now,
so let somebody else
do the worrying
for a change.
Enjoy being with
your family.
You're right.
You're right as usual.
The United States of
America stands...
What is that
terrible sound?
Is it an earthquake?
Take cover.
Shane, you okay?
Yeah.
What?
What do you mean
it's been classified?
Just what I said.
All the data
we collected in Alaska
and uploaded to the government
has been classified
and neither you nor I have
the clearance to access it.
In fact, we shouldn't
even be talking
about this right now.
The whole department
is under a gag order.
The tremor we just had
was preceded
by some kind of
EM disturbance which could mean
there's been serious damage
to the magnetic field.
Yeah, I recorded an
electromagnetic spike earlier
but I didn't know
what caused it.
We need the comet data.
Who classified it?
The administration.
Great.
Not even a comet hit is
immune to public spin.
Well maybe there really
was some damage to the field
and they don't want
to disclose it to the public.
We need to find out.
You've reached the office
of the President's
science advisors.
Due to
extenuating circumstances
this office will not be taking
calls until further notice.
What are you doing
up on the roof?
Tracking the sun.
And why would you be
tracking the sun?
It's not where it's
supposed to be.
Why would you say that?
Yesterday the sun set
behind Eagle Peak.
What do you mean?
It's never set
behind the peak.
Exactly.
Hello?
Hey, is this Shane?
Yeah, who's this?
It's Zoe.
I was just calling
to tell Miss Penny
that the pastries are ready.
Pastries?
Yeah, we're donating them for
the school's disaster fund drive
so she can pick them
up whenever she wants.
Okay, yeah, I'll
let her know.
Okay, bye.
Bye.
Zoe just called.
The pastries for
the fund drive are ready.
You want me to go
pick them up for you?
That would be
great, Shane.
Thank you.
Can I help you?
How's it going?
Good.
You're here to pick up the stuff
for your mom, right?
She's not my mom.
Okay.
Step-mom.
You have my sympathy.
I'd die if my dad married
one of my teachers.
Hello?
Hey.
My God.
What is it?
The sun is ten degrees off
where it should be
this time of year.
How could that be?
Okay, in like an hour?
You still meeting Kevin
at the park today?
Uh, yeah.
Okay, bye.
Here it is.
Thanks.
I'll be at the park
with Kevin.
Oh yeah?
Yeah.
I'll see you there.
Cool.
Hey, James.
Hey, Lou.
I haven't had a chance to talk
to you since the interview.
So what's this great
story you've got for me?
Remember how we used
to come out here
and watch all
those sunsets?
Maybe that's what you
came out here for.
I came out here for
the babes and the booze.
Do you remember how this
sundial was always
right on the money?
Yeah, I remember.
Hi, Shane.
Hey, Zoe.
What am I, chopped liver?
So Shane, buddy,
I've got a little problem
because of you.
You see this car?
My dad's making me
sell it to pay
for the stupid
telescope you broke.
We broke.
Whatever.
The point is I think we can
settle this little problem.
How's that?
Drag race.
You win me.
You win and I'll pay the $4,000
we owe for the telescope.
I win, you pay.
Come on,
what do you think?
You're not afraid of getting
your ass whipped, are ya?
You wouldn't win.
Ouch.
You hear that?
Greaser boy thinks
he can beat me.
Let's do it.
Dr. Mayfield said his
suspicion was first aroused
when he noticed the sun
setting behind Eagle Peak.
Now I can tell you from my own
experiences growing up here
that the sun has never
set behind Eagle Peak before.
And then there's our
trusty sundial
which has
never been wrong...
until today.
Ready guys?
Get set.
Ahhh!
Get out!
Get out, James!
James, Get out!
You okay?
Yeah, you alright?
I can't believe
what just happened?
Poor Kevin.
Oh my God.
I can't get a reception,
what about you?
Nothing.
What is that?
It looks like an aurora.
Here?
I thought those things
only happened up north
in places like Alaska.
Something bad is happening.
Dr.
Mayfield, what exactly is the problem with the axis
changing ten degrees?
I mean,
so what if the sun sets ten minutes later.
A shifted axis tilt means
the Earth's axis of rotation
is out of alignment
with its magnetic poles.
This could have
serious consequences
for the Earth's magnetic field.
The seismic activity
and the electromagnetic
interference with communications
that we've been experiencing,
this could all be
just the beginning.
The beginning of what?
A catastrophic
pole reversal.
You mean like what happened a million years ago
when the North and South
Poles change places?
That's right.
Back to you.
Yeah.
Alright.
Alright already.
James, buddy,
we are famous.
What are you
talking about?
You don't know.
Know what?
You're story caught fire.
My report was picked up
by all the big networks.
Really?
There is some weird crap
going on all over this country
that the government
does not want to talk about,
but your theory
makes more sense
than these
alien invasion stories
so the networks
picked it up.
Good.
Maybe it will force the administration to come clean.
Yeah, well, anymore
earth-shattering developments
I'm your man, right?
See you, Lou.
I'm your man.
Good morning, gentlemen.
Good morning,
Mr. President.
How are you, sir?
Who leaked the axis
tilt to the press?
Dr. James Mayfield, sir.
Mayfield?
That's your son
isn't it, General?
Yes, sir.
Dr. Mayfield is my son.
Then what the heck is he doing
leaking classified information.
I'm sorry, sir.
I'm not aware of
his activities.
We haven't spoken in
nearly five years.
You don't say.
Well, maybe now would be a good time for a family reunion,
because if you don't put
a muzzle on him, we will.
What exactly was his
involvement with this?
Our Storm Hazard Research Department contracted Dr.
Mayfield
to monitor the comet's
effect on the radiation belt.
So wasn't this guy on the same
gag order as everyone else?
Yes, sir, and his research
was classified.
But to be honest, sir,
the data he updated
could not have revealed an axis
tilt as it was collected
prior to the comet hit.
Don't argue semantics
with me, doctor.
A gag order is
a gag order.
I don't need 400 phone calls
coming in to the White House
every hour about a pole reversal that's not going to happen.
It's not going to happen,
right, Dr. Elman?
It's a preposterous
thought, Mr. President.
The consensus is that
the Earth's axis
will slowly fall back
in to place as it rotate.
Glad to hear.
However this doomsday hysteria
is exactly why we need
to keep the people in
the dark right now.
Your son?
Sir?
Is he smart?
Yes, sir.
How smart is he?
Too smart for
his own good, sir.
That's what it
sounds like.
You better bring him in.
Yes, sir.
James.
It's really happening.
All the telltale signs.
This is unprecedented.
What is?
The pole reversal.
Shane didn't come
home last night.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
His car's not here,
his bed hasn't
been slept in
and I can't reach
him on his cell.
You said he was going
to the park last night.
Oh my God.
I just heard on the radio
that the park was ripped apart
by a major earthquake
last night.
Let's go.
What's going on?
Dr. Mayfield, we need
you to come with us
to the airbase, sir.
Base?
For what?
I don't know, sir, but we
have an executive order
to take you to the base,
by force if necessary.
I'll find Shane.
I'll call you as soon as
I know what's going on.
This way.
Anything?
Nothing.
This is so weird.
I always get
a signal here.
Hey, dad.
James.
Should have known
you were behind this.
Long time no see.
Five years,
not too long.
I guess it
just seemed so to me.
Did you get my
birthday card?
I did.
Thank you.
Very considerate.
How's your son?
He must be getting
awfully big by now.
Yes he is.
You probably wouldn't
even recognize him.
Probably not.
Have a seat, James.
So you've caused quite
a stir in Washington.
How's that, sir?
Violating a government
gag order for one thing.
I didn't violate
any gag order.
That axis shift was
my own research.
Don't play games
with me, James.
You're either on the team
or you're not.
Here we go.
You know full well the intent of a government gag order.
Everything you worked
on was classified.
The public has a right
to that information.
It's not your call, James.
You're a science rat.
You don't make policy.
Scaring the American
public is against
this country's greater good.
You think you're
a good soldier.
You're just a lapdog
for political bosses.
You'd probably shoot me
yourself if they told you
it would serve
the greater good.
What am I doing here?
Obviously it's not
because you miss me.
I had the President of
the United States tell me today
that my son was a national
security risk.
So what?
He wants to burn me
at the stake?
Lucky for you,
he wants to hear you out.
Oh, you mean he wants
to cover his ass.
Increased electronic
interference continues
to be reported from
around the world.
This new development
coupled with the increase
of reported seismic activity
and the appearance
of what seems to be auroras
around the globe
has many people
figuring for the worst.
Oh my God.
Are you guys okay?
What happened?
Where's your car?
This thin skin is
the Earth's crust.
Spinning liquid in
the core is the engine
which generates our
protective magnetic field.
Dr. Mayfield, we didn't
bring you here
for a geology class.
The shift in the axis tilt
caused slippage
of the crust around
the core.
Consequently the Earth is
now out of alignment
with its magnetic field and
the misaligned crust
is causing increased
seismic activity.
Yes.
We're aware of all that.
We just want to hear
specific evidence
pertaining to your
far-fetched notion
of a pole reversal.
I'm assume you're aware
of beached whales,
birds migrating in the wrong direction,
bees swarming.
Yes, yes.
Creatures realigned with
the magnetic field
for navigation were confused,
a short-lived result
of the comet's
temporary distortion
of the magnetic field.
Answer me this then
Dr. Elman:
why are polar auroras
suddenly appearing
in places they shouldn't?
Again, a temporary distortion
of the magnetic field,
similar to what occurs when
there is a bad solar storm.
What are we talking
about here, gentleman?
Aurora Borealis?
Auroras normally occur when the earth's poles attract solar particles.
The fact that so many polar
auroras are appearing elsewhere
indicates that new magnetic
poles are developing.
I saw a polar aurora
here last night.
We are now sitting
on a magnetic pole,
which explains all
the electromagnetic interference
and the seismic activity
we've been having.
Dr. Mayfield, many strange
anomalies have occurred
in modern times without
catastrophic consequences.
These fields are
like rubber bands.
They bend
and stretch and thin,
but inevitably they always
return to their original state.
Only this time, Dr.
Elman, the rubber band has snapped.
Mr. President, the mini
poles indicate
a geo-magnetic reversal
has started.
As the North and South
Poles disintegrate
the magnetic field they
support will collapse.
Static discharges will create
electromagnetic shockwaves
which will fry
everything electronic.
We will be thrown back
into the Stone Age.
The North and South Poles
will disappear
remerging at opposite ends
of the globe,
at which point our protective
magnetic shield
will be completely gone,
exposing us to cosmic rays which
will incinerate the planet,
just like what
happened on Mars.
Dr. Mayfield, must
we be so melodramatic?
This is real science,
Mr. President.
This planet has seen many
geo-magnetic reversals,
just not since
we've been here.
As a man of science I am sure
you can appreciate the need
for thoughtful,
rational discussion;
however, your melodrama and
sensational media appearances
gives one the impression that
your intention are perhaps
more to do
with self-promotion.
I've had a long day,
gentlemen.
Signing off.
What did you expect,
James?
You just told them the world
was going to end.
This isn't global
warming, dad,
where we can spend years
dragging our feet
and debating the facts.
They'll find out
soon enough.
Wait.
That's the same sound
I heard just before
the quake last night.
Stop the car.
Turn off the car.
My God.
I've never seen
anything like this.
Save your data, everybody!
Storm Hazards.
What just happened?
Oh my god, James.
It was a massive 40
kilohertz EM pulse surge,
unlike anything
we've ever seen.
40 kilohertz?
Yes.
All the cities that were
hit were blacked out,
and not only that,
most of the satellites
in orbit got fried.
What could possibly have
created a surge like that?
It's gotta be connected
to the polar auroras.
Were the hits random?
I don't know yet.
We lost power during the spike,
which was lucky for us,
or else the EM surge
would have fried everything.
We're just getting our
emergency generators going.
We're pulling up data now.
I'm seeing about two dozen
points where 40 mile wide
electromagnetic waves
struck Earth.
Overlay the locations of
the mini poles on your screen
and tell me
what you see.
Overlay the locations
of all detected mini poles.
Oh my God.
All the hit areas are
where the mini poles are.
Then that's it.
The solar particles
attracted by the poles
are building up massive
electrostatic discharges.
Pam, your office has to tell
all those hit areas to evacuate,
including Lindenville.
The discharges are going
to get much stronger
as the field fails.
It's going to be hard
to issue an alert
with a global blackout,
but we'll certainly
do our best.
Can you run a timeline
projection on your mainframe?
Give me a couple hours.
It will take a while
to process the data.
James,
how do we stop this?
I don't know that we can.
We just had the first
worldwide blackout in history
and you and none of your brain
trust can explain why?
What we know
right now for certain
are that the affected cities
were struck by large
electromagnetic shockwaves.
Just as Dr. Mayfield
had predicted.
General Mayfield, have you been
able to locate your son yet?
Not yet, sir.
He's in one of
the blackout areas.
Well I want to speak with
him as soon as he's located.
Yes, Mr. President.
So, tell me Dr. Elman,
can you still say
with a certainty
that we're not experiencing
a pole reversal?
I don't have an answer
right now, sir.
Are we going to see
more of this?
Give me the worst
case scenario.
Mr. President, until we've
assembled our teams
I don't want to speculate
on something
that's not my area
of expertise.
Don't try to cover your
ass with me, doctor.
We've got power outages
across the country.
American lives
are at risk.
So tell me,
to the best of your ability,
are we going
to see more of this?
I believe so,
Mr. President.
Then I have no choice
but to declare
Federal Marshall Law.
General Mayfield--
Yes, sir.
--You'll supervise
west coast operations.
Yes, Mr. President.
We'll start setting up
shelters in the affected areas.
James.
Thank God.
Did you find Shane?
Yeah, he was at the park.
I've been trying
to call you.
Our cell phones
are useless.
Only the landlines
are working.
Where is he?
In the kitchen.
But one of the kids he was
with last night was killed
in the earthquake.
Oh no.
What's going on?
There's no power and I saw
an EM wave in the sky.
It's bad.
We have to get out
of Lindenville.
Shane.
You okay?
What's happening, dad?
Is the world
falling apart?
No, no.
Just going through
a rough patch.
I've packed for us both.
I'm not going with you.
What do you mean?
I'm going back
to the base.
What?
What are you
talking about?
Why?
I have an idea and I have
to talk to the President.
I don't want to, Cyn.
I just don't see that
there's a choice.
You know what,
you're right.
There is no choice because
your family comes first.
No wonder Shane doesn't
think you love him.
Listen to me.
This is not a drill.
This is the real deal.
The survival of the planet
depends on actions
taken in
the next 24 hours
and those so-called government
science advisors
don't have a clue.
I have to do this,
for us.
Okay, we're here,
smack in the middle of a mini
pole's magnetic centre,
the most dangerous place
to be right now.
Everywhere inside this circle
is going to get bombarded
with EM pulses and torn apart
by seismic disturbances.
I want you guys out of
this circle as soon as possible.
Go to this town here,
Little Brook, and wait for me.
What are you
talking about, dad?
You're coming, right?
I can't.
I have to go back
to the base.
I don't believe it.
You're abandoning us.
That sucks.
Shane, try to understand.
There's a global crisis
going on.
You think
I don't know that?
I saw one of my classmates
crushed to death
in a car last night.
I know, I know.
I'm sorry.
So you don't care if the
same thing happens to us?
Of course I do.
That's why
I have to fix this.
We'll be okay.
Leave me alone.
Shane, come on.
If an EM wave hits turn
the car off until it passes.
The electronics won't be
short-circuited
as long as
the power is off.
If the power is on,
you and the car will fry.
How long will you be?
A day, maybe two.
Be careful.
Yeah.
You too.
Shane.
No, no, no.
Take those ear buds off.
Stay away from electronics.
You will get electrocuted
if an EM wave hits.
I'm serious.
It's dangerous.
Get rid of it.
I'll see you soon.
Hey,
I love you.
Everybody is advised
to stay tuned
to this emergency
broadcast channel.
Federal Marshall Law
has been declared.
Lindenville residents are
ordered to evacuate their homes
and take shelter
at Lindenville Parish.
We repeat...
Why are they telling
everyone to go to the church?
Didn't dad say it was
dangerous to stay in town?
Oh, what's this?
Road's closed.
You're supposed to take
shelter in the parish.
We're going
to Little Brook.
Ma'am, we have orders
to divert everyone
to the Lindenville Parish.
That's ridiculous.
It's not even safe there.
Ma'am, please.
Just back it up, okay?
Let's go.
Come on!
Turn the car off.
I think it's gone.
Start the car.
Dammit.
We'll have to go back.
Get out of the car now!
Come on! Jump!
Ahhh!
No!
Ahh!
I can't hold on!
Yes, you can!
Don't let go!
Help!
Anybody! Help!
Grab it.
Come on!
We need to evacuate everyone
from the mini pole sites.
Evacuate?
We just started rounding
up people for the shelters.
No, no, no.
You can't do that.
The plasma charges building up
from the pole reversal
are escaping through
the mini poles.
This whole area is going
to get hit worse
and worse
as the field fails.
Alright.
I'll notify the soldiers
but communications
have been spotty.
What about the President?
Have you still been
able to contact him?
Yeah, the emergency
hotline is holding up.
Good.
I've got a crazy idea.
I need to access Storm
Hazard's mainframe.
Follow me.
Storm Hazards.
Pam, talk to me.
I'm briefing the President
in a few minutes.
James, the computer
projection...
it's not good.
I need to see whoever
is in charge.
Inside this circle is
the most dangerous place
on the west coast.
We're here,
the epicentre
of the mini pole
creating the electromagnetic
and seismic disturbances.
We need to move all these
people outside
of this circle to here.
Where did you get
this information?
My husband,
Dr. James Mayfield,
he's a government
astrophysicist.
He's briefing the President
right now.
I haven't heard
anything about this.
My orders are
to keep everybody here.
I know, but I'm telling
you it's not safe here.
Lindenville has become
the magnetic centre
of a mini pole.
What is that,
a mini pole?
No, no, no.
Turn the power off.
The electricity will
attract the next EM pulse.
You have to shut
the generator down.
Shut it down?
I don't think so.
You're not
listening to me.
We're in danger here.
Ma'am, Federal Marshall Law
has been declared.
I can't just move hundreds
of people
because you show me some
map with a circle drawn on it.
You know what,
call General Mayfield.
He'll vouch for everything
I've just said.
Storm Hazard's lab
just ran this projection.
This is what the magnetic
field normally looks like.
This is what it looks like now,
punctured by mini poles.
This is 12 hours out,
24 hours out,
48 hours out.
Magnetic field
at zero gauss.
Gentlemen,
we have two days
before our planet loses
its protective shield
and solar radiation burns
us all to a crisp.
Anyone here take issue
with Dr. Mayfield's projections?
No, sir.
Alright then,
so who here has a game plan
to stop this pole reversal?
Alright.
This is the way I see it.
What if we detonate a nuclear
explosion of a magnitude
equal to that of which the comet
fragment hit Earth
in the opposing hemisphere
so that it pushes back
with equal force?
Are you crazy?
How do we know it wouldn't
make things worse?
What about fallout?
Fallout?
The pole reversal
completes in 48 hours
and then
it is bye-bye planet.
Does anybody else
have a better idea?
That's what I thought.
That comet fragment hit us with
the force of 100 megaton bomb.
We don't have
a warhead that powerful.
What's the most powerful
nuke in the US arsenal?
We have a new
50 megaton prototype
that's at the nuclear
test site.
Okay, well can formulate
a dual detonation
that will equal 100.
And?
We can't get through
to the general.
Communication is down.
Well we can't just leave
these people here.
This place is a
ticking time bomb.
I suggest you find
a cot and you chill.
Anything?
Nothing yet, sir.
Zoe.
Hey.
When did you get here?
Just a few minutes ago.
Excuse me, everybody.
Can I have your
attention, please?
I'm Cynthia Mayfield, science
teacher at Lindenville High.
Many of you know that
my husband, Dr. James Mayfield,
is a respected astrophysicist.
He's told me that our town
is the epicentre
of the electromagnetic and
seismic disturbances happening
on the west coast
and that it's very dangerous
to stay here.
We need to move
outside the circle.
The nearest safe
town is Little Brook.
You wanna step down
from there, ma'am?
How come the soldiers
don't know this?
Because their
communications are down.
They're completely
in the dark.
I'm not going to ask
you again, ma'am.
Please listen to me.
We could all die here.
Get her off of there.
Is it true?
If you open your mouth
about this to anyone again
you will be arrested.
Is that clear?
Yes.
And I don't want
to see that map again.
Release her.
James, you'll be happy to know
the bomber is on its way.
And two 50 megaton warheads
will launch at 16:00.
Yes.
What do you mean
we lost the plane?
Yes.
Thank you.
An EM pulse took
out the bomber.
The warheads
exploded in mid air.
They have to try again.
Send another plane.
James, the skies
are unflyable.
We'll lose them all.
They have to try.
Send 20 planes.
One might get through.
James.
James, you've got to think
of something else fast.
There's got to
be another way.
: We've got
to get out of here.
Why would the soldiers
keep us here if it isn't safe?
Because they
don't anything.
They're just following
their last orders.
Communications have
gotten so bad
they can't even contact
their superiors.
What do you want to do?
Dr. Mayfield was right
when he said
the comet might hit Earth.
I think we should go.
We're in.
Come on.
It's around here.
This one.
Those poor people.
I feel so bad
leaving them.
You did everything
you could, Cyn.
Gentlemen, I have a new plan
that just might work.
We're going to detonate at
the bottom of the ocean,
the Marianna Trench, the deepest
point of the Earth's crust.
Dr. Elman?
Yes, the ocean crust is thin
enough that the blast
could go right through
to lithosphere and, yes,
it could conceivably push
the planet back into alignment.
The Marianna Trench is over
36,000 feet deep, doctor.
How do you plan
on getting there?
Submarine.
Unfortunately, doctor, we don't
have any that are operational.
What do you mean you don't
have any that are operational?
EM interference crippled
the onboard computers
that control
the nuclear reactors.
Are you telling me there's
not a single sub out there?
That's right.
That's not exactly true,
General.
The Russians have an old diesel
sub they still train on.
She isn't pretty,
but she's running.
She's on the west coast for an international training exercise.
Open that bunker.
I guess they're still ordering
everyone to the church.
Shhh...
I can hear it.
Hear what?
An EM pulse tone.
What's an EM pulse tone?
Electromagnetic shockwave.
It's a burst of
electromagnetic energy
coming from the mini pole.
That sub should be in
the harbour by now.
What is that noise?
A pulse tone.
Cut the engine, dad.
Now?
Stop the car right now!
What was that?
There it is.
Oh my God.
Turn the car off, Michael!
Turn it off!
Everything electronic has
to be turned off:
cell phones, mp3 players,
everything!
Get rid of your
watch, Michael!
I hope those guys remember
to cut their engine.
Cut your engine!
I think it passed.
Michael, what's wrong?
Dad, are you okay?
Can you drive?
Sure.
James, check the engine.
We've got no time
to waste.
The battery and
starter are fried.
It looks like we're an hour
from getting out of the circle.
We need to get my
father to a hospital.
What's wrong?
He has a pacemaker.
I think the storm
shorted it out.
Oh God.
How are we doing?
Good.
Give it a try.
It is an honour,
General Mayfield.
Captain Yolenkov,
this is Dr. James Mayfield.
Captain.
I see the resemblance.
There are two warheads in
the back of that truck.
So, we work together
to save world, no?
Yes.
Dr. Mayfield will formulate
the detonation sequence.
My ship, she's strong as ox,
but not so fast you know.
Yes, we know.
The closest town
is Clarksville.
We past it a
few minutes ago.
Maybe they have
a hospital.
No.
Don't go back.
I'm okay.
Just get out
of the circle.
Oh no.
Not again.
: We've gotta get
out of here fast.
Get out or
I'll blow your head off.
Okay.
Get out or I'll
kill all of you.
Please, my father is
having a heart attack.
We need to get him
to a hospital.
Get out or I'll put
him out of his misery.
Take it easy.
We're going.
Get out.
Ahhh!
Ugh!
Dad!
What are conditions
in Mariana Trench?
Expect seismic activity
like nothing you've ever seen.
You should warn your crew
that the steam vents
will be heating up the ocean
causing violent current shifts.
All this from rock
hitting Earth.
Technically, the comet fragment
was made from ice,
but yes.
So tell me, Dr. Mayfield,
you plan to detonate these
bombs at one time?
No, not exactly.
In order to generate 100
megaton explosion
I need to formulate
a detonation sequence
just milliseconds apart.
You know that this vessel
cannot outrun such a shockwave.
We know.
Your crew, captain,
do they know?
They have volunteered for
this mission in order
to save their families.
Outrunning the shockwave
is the least of our worries.
It's fried, Shane.
You know you can't start a car without the battery.
Cars in the old days
didn't have batteries.
They used to be started
by hand cranks.
Yeah, well we don't have
a hand crank
and this is a modern car.
You don't need a battery
to drive either.
All we need to do is
capture an electrical charge
that will help ignite
the spark plugs.
And where are we going
to get that from?
Have you ever seen
anything like this?
No one has.
We're witnessing a geological
event that hasn't happened
on a scale
in millions of years.
What creates such hell?
Massive tectonic movements.
How will this
affect the mission?
Well, it makes it
nearly impossible.
Ahhh!
Dad.
I'm okay.
We have lost one engine.
Power will be
50 percent.
Hi.
Can Shane really do what
he says he's doing?
All I know is Shane loves
working with cars.
He's the biggest greaser
at our school.
Better hurry up
with that, Shane.
100 meters from bottom.
Almost in position.
Dammit!
We cannot stay at
this depth very long.
Do you have
a family, captain?
Of course.
That's why we're going to stay
here as long as it takes.
If we die from a crushed
hull or a shockwave,
what difference does it make?
If we fail
the whole world dies.
This is it.
We're on.
Okay, I've got to set the timer
on the warheads.
Here it comes.
Just about done.
I don't think I should
be holding this anymore.
Almost there.
Shane.
Done.
Antenna.
Tape.
Come on.
We need to move
away, Shane.
Shane, come on.
Let's go!
I feel happy dying knowing it
was to save family on surface,
but I am sad that you
must die with your son.
Until a few days ago
I hadn't seen James
in five years, so...
We're on.
It's done, captain.
Fire when ready.
It will be impossible to
outrun the shockwave
with one engine, but at
least we'll die trying.
I think it's done.
We just have to pray
that one static charge
has been trapped
in the cylinder.
Come on, baby.
Yeah.
You're a genius.
We've got the greatest
show on Earth here, dad.
It's a scientist's dream,
isn't it?
Captain.
If you could take us
in to that volcano,
a steam funnel might propel us up out of the shockwave's path.
The hull is not designed
for such temperatures,
but what have we got
to lose?
Our temperature is rising.
The heat is
expanding the metal.
Brace yourselves.
Ahhh!
Thanks to unprecedented
cooperation between nations
we have survived
the most catastrophic event
to ever threaten our existence.
The Earth has been healed.
The human spirit
has triumphed,
despite all that has
been lost.
But we will honour
those lost
with our resolve
to rebuild
and we will rejoice in what
we have been given...
a chance for a
new beginning.
10:00 a.m., perfect time.
And finally, our fragile
planet owes a huge debt
to Dr. James Mayfield.
He's here.
Dad!
This is your grandfather.