- Hey, baby, I'm gonna
go get my cell phone.
I'll be right back.
- Yes!
- What are you
doing in there?
- What have you done
with my daughter?
- Where is she?
Where is my daughter!
Let me outta here!
Somebody help me!
Help!
- Somebody help me, please.
Go ahead and scream
all you want.
Cuz nobody can hear you!
- God, help me please.
Protect my little
girl and my husband,
wherever they are.
♪
♪ baby put on your
white t-shirt...
♪ All thin and
warm and perfect...
- All that stuff.
- Awesome!
- Yeah.
- I'm allergic to the woods.
- I hope my mom packed all
my nasal sprays and stuff.
- I just want to make
sure, you know.
- It's me!
- What's wrong with you!
- That was not good!
- That is not funny!
- It's just a mask. Relax.
- That was so wrong!
- You all ready?
- Yeah!
- I heard about that scream.
I heard it way over there.
Y'all ready for this?
- Girl's Van is packed.
We're ready to go.
- All right. Okay. Cool!
- You ready?
- I don't know if
you can handle this.
- I don't know about you,
but I think you two
should be the ones
who's afraid.
- Oh, yeah.
- We're gonna deal with
that, but you know what?
God hasn't given us
a spirit of fear.
- Did you see some of
the guys in your group?
You two ought to be afraid.
- We're afraid, right.
- Seriously, if you guys are
up for this I want you guys
to take over all of
campsite b, all right?
- Yeah!
- That way we keep
everybody separated.
You guys on one side,
girls on the other.
We'll come together
for group time,
have Bible studies
then we'll split up.
We'll be close enough
if you need us
just holler,
but not too close.
- You don't have to worry
about us 'cause
we got a secret weapon.
- Yes, we do.
- Do tell. Let's hear it.
- We brought the chocolate.
So listen, after
the group hours,
I don't think we want to
have a drop of trouble
getting the girls
over to our side.
- Sounds good to me.
- For women only.
- That's right.
- I hear you.
- You may not partake.
- Definitely not you!
No!
- I'm gonna check
on everybody else.
Make sure you guys
are all packed up.
Let's meet back in
about ten minutes.
We'll have a word of
prayer and hit the road.
Let's go camping!
- Thank you.
Thank you so much
for being here today.
We have a great show
in store for you.
Bonnie Johnson is here
promoting her new movie,
run, hide, pray.
And currently topping the
charts with her hit single
white t-shirt, that's
right, Tara Leigh cobble.
And I'm excited to have with
us today the number one
best selling author
in the country
to tell her story
of survival.
You won't believe it.
Of course our very own
domestic diva
standing by in the
kitchen ready to share
her favorite holiday
recipes with us.
- That's right, Emily.
Today I'm gonna show you
how to make my family's
famous harvest casserole that
will leave your guests
wanting more. Yum,
you're gonna love it!
- So don't go anywhere.
We'll be right back.
- Come on!
- You're gonna need this.
It's supposed to get
really cold tonight.
- Hey!
Wait! Wait!
Wait!
Help me! Please!
Please!
- Hey lady, what are
you doing out here?
Are you okay?
- Help me, please!
- Get in.
- Okay Emily, we're ready.
You're on in 60.
- Oh.
- Thanks.
- Let me get that for you.
Where are you going
with those donuts?
- Welcome back.
Our next guest is near
and dear to my heart.
It's actually a story that
I covered when I was
still a local reporter
out in the field.
- Okay, okay.
I still can remember the
night that the call came into
the news room that a
young mother was missing.
I was one of the first
reporters out on the scene,
and police were everywhere
searching for answers but
finding very little.
It was such a somber scene,
and it seemed quite hopeless.
Fortunately our story
took a turn for the best.
I'm gonna let her come out
and tell the story herself.
Let's bring out
Laurie Curtis.
- Thank you for having me.
- Thanks for being here.
You look great.
- Thanks. So do you.
And congratulations
on your own show.
This is so exciting.
- You must have been so
scared when you did
decide to make a run for it.
- Yes. Absolutely.
But I kind of looked
at it this way.
I knew I was fighting for my
life so I'd rather take my
chances trying to escape than
to hang around and see what
he had in mind for me.
- Sure. Sure. I can
understand that.
So tell us what
happened next?
Did the police ever
catch up with him?
- Well, the police
have been very helpful.
I told them everything that
I knew and I even tried
to help them locate
where the barn was.
And they were able to
find out who he was
and where he lived.
But once they got there,
he had been long gone and
unfortunately, he's been
evading the police, I guess,
for about a year now
but they assure me
they're still on the case.
- It's such an
incredible store,
you're such an amazing woman.
- Oh, well thank you.
I give the credit
to the lord.
I know that without him,
I wouldn't have
gotten through it.
I just know that all good
things come from the lord,
and that he takes care of us,
and I knew if I had faith
that I would see my daughter
and my husband again.
So he answered my prayers.
Here I am.
- Well we're so thankful to
have you here today
alive and well and here
to tell your story.
Speaking of your little girl,
she's here today with
us in the audience.
Do you mind, can
we bring her on out?
- Sure. Sure.
- Well, Laurie and marin,
thank you for being here
today and sharing your
incredible story.
And everyone in our audience
today is gonna receive a free
copy of Laurie's book.
- We'll be right
back after this.
- And we're clear.
We'll be back from commercial
in 90 seconds everyone.
- There you go.
- This anybody's?
- I got mine.
- Got everything?
- Get my back pack on.
- Hey!
- Come on. Come on!
- Where? Where's spiders?
- Y'all gonna go to the lake?
- I think I am.
- Do we have the directions?
- We don't need directions.
- You sure?
- Somebody get Trey to help.
- No. We'll get Trey later.
Let him rest.
- This is so easy.
- You're crazy.
- Look at the guys.
They still can't
get their tent up!
- Do you think we
should go help them?
- Guys, this is
ridiculous. Come on.
- Come on, they need real
women. Let's go.
- Let's show 'em
how it's done.
- Hold up, hold up, hold up.
- Oh, no, what is going on!
- We got it. We got it.
- Obviously, you don't have it.
- It's broken!
- It's not broken.
Y'all are broken.
- We got it.
- No, we got it.
Get on out of here.
Is somebody under here?
Oh, my gosh!
Just get out of here.
- Just get out.
- I love the tiaras.
- Quadrant two,
vector six, clear.
Quadrant three,
vector two, clear.
Subject perimeter clear.
- That's a relief.
What is that?
- What do you mean?
- What is that?
- It's a disguise
for the stake out.
- Stake out?
We are not on a stake out.
We're simply here to
watch Laurie's house.
- We want to blend in.
We don't want to
be conspicuous.
- Blend in?
What is that?
- This?
It's my paint ball gun,
you know, for protection.
- Could you just be serious?
- Okay.
Quadrant five,
vector two, clear.
Quadrant four,
vector three, clear.
Five of diamonds.
- No.
- Five of diamonds.
- No again.
- Ace of spades.
- No.
Do you ever get that right?
- Sometimes.
- Can't we just
be serious here?
- Four of clubs.
- You ever think about
shuffling the deck.
They're all...
- Ha!
- Did you invite him?
- Sorry, dude, I thought
it was a stake out.
- What next?
- Hey, guys, I'm here
for the stake out.
- Stake out, stake out.
This is not a stake out.
Mr. Curtis simply asked me to
watch his house while he's
gone out of town.
It's not a stake out, we're
just watching the house.
- Dude, I like your
disguise, but I thought you
had a pta meeting.
- Yeah, I got out of it.
- Can we just
be serious here?
- Hang on.
- I brought donuts.
- Sweet.
- Can I get in?
- Please, just get in,
get in, and just be quiet.
- Man, these are good.
- Sugar high, though.
- Want another donut?
- You've got...
You've got...
Go like this.
- Did I get it?
- No, other side.
- Yeah, whatever.
- These are good.
- You guys just remember
what goes up must come down,
so you might want to layoff
of these sugar donuts.
- But they're so good.
- Uh-huh.
- I like the jelly.
- I think it went
really well tonight.
- So this is what it's like
being backstage, it's really
cool.
- Yes, it's pretty neat.
I like to do the talk shows,
they really treat you like a
star.
Well, I know she's going
to love princesses on ice
tonight, and are you sure
you don't mind keeping her?
- Heavens no, we're
looking so forwards to it.
- We always like
to have marin.
- Well, try to stick to the
bedtime, and no soda
at least after 9.
- Right, we promise.
- What happens at Mimi and
papa's stays at
Mimi and papa's.
- Right.
- Are you ready to go baby?
Let's go sugar.
- We don't want
you to be late.
- Big girl.
- Love you guys.
- Proud of you.
- Thank you.
- We'll see you soon.
Okay, here we go. Bye.
- See you soon, see
you soon, love you.
- Love you.
- Okay, bye bye.
- See you guys.
- Mrs. Curtis, Mrs. Curtis!
- Oh, yeah, of course.
Thank you guys.
- Can we get a picture?
- Sure of course, yeah.
- Can you take it for us?
- Sure.
Smile.
Got it.
- All right, thank you.
- Thank you.
- Sure, thank you guys.
See you.
Ah!
- I'm so sorry.
Do you mind signing
this for me?
- No, not at all.
You scared me.
- Sorry.
- That's okay.
There you go.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
- It was so much fun.
I really enjoyed
doing the talk show.
I'm home safe now.
I'm locking it right now,
and everything looks fine.
The dead bolt, too.
Yeah, I think the special
forces are out there.
They are.
You know you don't have to
hire them every time
you go out of town.
Okay, honey, if it
makes you feel better.
I haven't seen him.
Lancer, Lancelot?
He's probably just upstairs
digging in the trash or
something.
Okay, well you go
onto your meeting.
Oh, it's going to be fine.
I've got a movie.
Okay, well, I will
talk to you later.
All right you call
me or I'll call you.
Love you, bye.
Lance? Lance?
Hey, good boy, are you okay?
What's wrong, buddy?
Hey, Carlie, this
is Laurie Curtis.
My dog's acting like he's
not feeling too well.
Can I bring him?
You're open now?
Awesome, thank you so much.
- Hey, Mrs.
Curtis, hey, Lance.
- Hey, Carlie,
thanks for waiting.
- No problem.
- He's been like
this since I got home.
I don't know what's going on.
I don't know if he's sick to
his stomach or what's wrong
with him, but he just
doesn't look good to me.
- You know, something's
definitely wrong with him.
I'm going to have to have
Dr. Bailey check him out.
- Okay, he ran out to grab
some dinner real quick, but
he'll be back in
a few minutes.
It's been a very busy day.
- Well, do you think
he's going to be okay.
- I'm sure he'll
probably be fine.
But if it's okay with you,
can I keep him here overnight
to run some tests?
- Sure, absolutely.
- Here's your information
from last time.
If I could just have you
check your home or cell phone
number, whichever one is
more convenient for you.
- Okay, great, my cell.
- Okay.
All right and I will go ahead
and take him back, and I'll
have Dr. Bailey call you as
soon as we figure out
what's wrong with him.
- Okay thank you.
Hey, good boy, be a
good boy, all right?
They're going to take
good care of you.
Okay, thanks Carlie.
- No problem.
Have a safe night.
- All right, you, too.
- I'm not watching
that by myself.
- Oh, man.
Okay we need to
go to surgery now.
- Hello?
Hey, Dr. Bailey.
- Laurie, I'm
glad we found you.
Look, we found out what was
wrong with Lance, but there
may be someone in your house.
- What?
- Look, you gotta stay as
calm as possible, but there
were two adult male fingers.
Laurie, that's not
the worst part.
They were wearing
black leather gloves.
I don't know, maybe
broke into the house.
Look, Lance bit their fingers
off trying to
protect the home.
I don't know, but we
called the police already.
They're on their way, but he
could still be in the house.
Okay please look,
be calm, be calm.
He could be lying around
somewhere, loss of blood,
in shock somewhere.
Please look around,
anything messy,
blood anywhere, please.
- Laurie, can you hear me?
Get out of the house now!
If you can hear me, get
out of the house now!
- Help me, please, help me!
He's in here, he's
in here! Help!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa! It's okay.
You two take the right side.
Ford, we'll take the
left side of the house.
- Clear.
- Take the stairs.
- Clear at the far end.
- Clear, sergeant.
- Clear.
- And he's in the closet
downstairs or upstairs?
- Downstairs.
- Okay.
- Clear the closet.
- It's clear.
You guys got anything?
- Nothing, it's clear.
- Corporal, this is what
I need for you to do.
Secure an entire perimeter
around the house and the
whole neighborhood.
- Yes, sir.
- Set up a
command post also.
- Contact ccbi immediately.
- Yes, sir.
- Have them
process the scene.
- Yes, sir.
- 460 to dispatch.
460 to dispatch.
- Dispatch go ahead, copy.
- I'm at Laurie
Curtis' place.
We have a suspect at large
and he is wounded, copy?
- The Laurie Curtis place?
- Affirmative.
I need any assistance we can
get from any local
police departments.
Also get the canine unit
en route immediately.
We need to lock this
whole area down.
Do you copy?
- Copy.
- He's back.
- That's exactly
how it happened.
And people think I'm lying
when I talk about it, but I
don't even see why I would
make something like that up.
- Well, it is pretty
hard to believe.
- Come on, man.
- No, I'm not calling you a
liar or anything, I'm just
saying it's pretty stretched.
- Why would she lie about
something like that?
- I mean, it's like
something out of a
movie, you know?
It's crazy.
- Well, I believe
you, Madison.
- Thank you, Lacey.
- Well, did they get him?
- Honestly, the last thing I...
- Did anybody...
- Shhhh.
- What? I just want to know the
score of the game.
- Shhhh.
- I heard something.
- Sit down, dude.
- No, I thought
I heard it, too.
- Yeah, me, too.
- Maybe it was just
a squirrel or
something, you know?
- Yeah, it could
have been anything.
- You know, the police
finally found out who the guy
was based on where they
found Laurie Curtis.
Apparently he was just a
regular guy according to the
people at his church, but he
got in a bad relationship
with some girl, and she was
kind of after him
because he had a good job
and some money.
And so eventually he figured
it out, and he got
fed up with it.
So he tried to end it, but
she wasn't going that easy.
- It's just the
relationship's not working.
- What's not
working about it?
- All of it.
- Tyler, you're going
to have to be a bit more
specific than that.
- We just seem to be going
in our separate directions.
You don't even go to
church with me on Sunday.
- Church has nothing
to do with anything.
- But it does, it has a
lot to do with what I feel.
- We're not having
this discussion again.
- Dasha, I think it's time
you go your way, and I'm just
going to go mine.
- We can work it out just
like we have
every other time.
- It hasn't worked.
I think it's time
for you to leave.
- No.
No.
- I'm sorry.
- You're sorry?
You're sorry?
For everything that I've
done for you, you're sorry?
- Yes.
- It's not over, not
until I say it is.
- So she went to the
police and made some nasty
accusations like he'd been
beating her and
things like that.
And unfortunately for
him, she was
pretty convincing so...
- He doesn't love me.
- I'm sergeant Jake lyons.
I'd like to come inside and
ask you a few questions.
- Okay, is everything okay?
- They gave him
five years in prison.
He didn't do very well there.
The police started getting
really worried because he was
extremely violent and
introverted and so they put
him in isolation.
And then about
three years went by.
Eventually, his attorney came
back and proved that his
girlfriend had been lying
and so they set him
free on probation.
- That still doesn't explain
why someone would go after
people like that, though.
- Well, people all respond
differently under pressure,
and I can't imagine being
convicted of a crime
I didn't commit.
It must be awful.
- Yeah.
- All right you guys,
gather around and listen up.
Here's the situation.
We got a suspect on the run,
probably on foot, and we have
strong reason to believe
that he is seriously injured.
Now, I know some of you made
big plans for tonight, but I
just cancelled them.
Relax, and here's what
we need to do from here.
We need more manpower
to aid with the search.
Let's activate a full recall.
Wake them up if you have to.
Let's get something very
clear right now, folks.
We're going all
night if we have to.
I want this guy apprehended
before the sun comes up.
Now, where's my map of the
area around highway 56?
- Got it right
here, sergeant.
- All right, highway 56 is
here, here's lake Mitchell
and these are the
surrounding woods here.
Now according to the
report, the suspect entered
the woods somewhere
around here.
We believe he's heading
east towards the highway.
- Okay, here's what
we're going to do.
I want units here,
here, and here.
I want to seal off
this entire area.
I want check points set up on
any road that leads anywhere
near that highway.
Is that understood?
- Yes, sir.
- Any questions?
- No sir, sir.
- No sir.
- Let's make it happen.
- You got it, sergeant.
- All right, who's
in charge here?
- That would be me.
- Not anymore.
How about some coffee?
- I would love some.
- I meant get me some.
- Officer Simpson, get
this man a cup of coffee.
- So what does the FBI
want with this guy anyway?
- We believe he's involved
in more than just these
local abductions.
We've been watching the grid
to see if he was going to
pop up anywhere.
I guess he's a bit more
obsessed than we thought.
Anyway, we really
want this guy.
And I know you've had
mayberry's finest working on
the case, but the big boys
are here now, so you girls
can turn in for the night.
Catch up on your
beauty sleep, perhaps.
- Agent manson, you
know what I think?
- No, what's that?
- I think everything was
just fine until you...
- Sergeant, sergeant,
serge, come on now.
- What's the status
on the canine units?
- Um...
- Today would be nice.
- Looks like they're
all on their way.
The first one should be there
in about five minutes, and
the rest should
be there in 20.
- Come on, people.
At this pace we'd be lucky if
this guy hasn't managed to
walk to the state line by the
time our net is deployed.
Look, radio them tell
them to step on it.
I want everybody there
in ten, you got it?
- Yes, sir.
- Now let's move, people!
- He's a good boy.
- It just seems so wrong
for all of that to happen to
one person.
- Seriously, it reminds me
of those sayings that go
around on e-mail like when
someone wrecks their car, and
it falls into the river, and
just when you think they're
about to drown, all the
sudden they kick in the
windshield, and then
they start swimming.
- I know exactly what
you're talking about.
So any ways they're trying to
get away from this alligator
and they're able to get away
from the alligator, but they
have the missing leg.
So they're trying to go up
this impossible hill, and as
soon as they get up the
impossible hill, they see
this car, like we're
going to be safe, right?
So they're trying to get to
the car, and as soon as they
get to the car, the car loses
control, hits them
and kills them both.
Isn't that crazy?
- That's so wrong.
- That's really rough, man.
- Hey, I didn't
make it up, okay?
It's got a name, and it's
called something like the...
- The worst luck award.
- We know, Ashley.
- Exactly.
But you know what?
They are kind of funny
in a morbid way.
But they're sad, too.
- Doesn't morbid mean sad?
- Okay, Ashley.
That's no squirrel.
- Aah!
- Are you crazy?
We have a like a grizzly
squirrel back here, and
you're cracking jokes?
- [Mocking) Oh!
I'm so scared!
Oh, Luke, please save me.
Please, Luke!
I want you to save me!
- Get off me!
You smell horrible.
- We could have done
without you on this trip.
- Ashley!
Ashley!
- Hey!
Hey!
Come back here!
- Ugh.
- Hold up! Hold up!
What are you thinking, man?
We could have killed you!
- Yeah. What's wrong with you!
We thought you were
going to kidnap her.
You're lucky we
didn't mess you up.
- Oh, how sweet.
Her guardian little angels.
- What are you
doing here anyway?
I thought you had some
competition or something
to go to.
- No, I got out early
so I drove out here.
- Yeah. Thanks, man.
I can't believe you.
- Come on, guys.
I just thought it
would be funny.
Come on.
It was hilarious.
- Attention, all units!
Please report to the
rendezvous point on the double.
I repeat, all units please
report to the rendezvous point
on the double.
- Serge, just got a
radio dispatch from 911.
They're sending
over an audio file.
They think it has to
do with the suspect.
- All right. Let's hear it.
- There's somebody
in my backyard.
- Ma'am, are you in
immediate danger?
- No. I think he went
back into the woods.
- Can you give me a
description of him?
- Um, it's pretty dark.
He's probably six foot tall,
dressed in all black.
I think he saw me.
- Ma'am, just remain calm.
We have units
very close to you.
- When and where was that?
- That's two miles east
of Mrs. Curtis' house.
It looks like it
was 15 minutes ago.
- 15 minutes?
Does everything happen
that slowly around here?
At least he
hasn't gotten away.
Contact the ground units.
Tell them they have a
gopher net deployment.
- Yes, sir.
All units! All units!
Suspect has been spotted three
clicks east 15 minutes ago
moving towards highway 56.
Move to intercept.
I repeat move to intercept.
- All right.
People, listen up.
We just got the go
ahead on the man hunt.
Let's be careful.
We need this guy alive.
No shots fired unless you
have to. Let's move it.
- Hey, serge, helicopter
just arrived on the pad.
It's waiting for you.
- Oh, it's about time.
Agent manson, if you
will excuse me.
We've got a bad guy to catch.
You can just sit
back and relax.
Enjoy the show.
If you need more coffee,
officer simps can
help you with that.
Don't worry.
We'll do all the hard work.
But I'm sure as usual you
gotta take all credit for it.
Whirring overhead]
- Corporal, I think
we got something.
- Yeah. He's definitely
been through here.
14 apex command, he's definitely
been through this way.
All right, everybody, from
now on we're going silent.
- You want one?
- Yeah.
- Does anybody have an extra
wire hanger so we don't have
to do this?
- Ah.
- Take mine.
- It will work.
- It's not working.
- Oh.
- It's not going to work.
- Got another marshmallow?
So I haven't seen you
around church much lately.
What's up?
- Oh, um, nothing is up.
I've just been busy.
That's all.
- That's cool.
I know you got
a lot going on.
I just miss
seeing you around.
That's all.
- Thanks, brother Dave.
Who knows.
Maybe I'll be back some day.
- Yeah.
Just don't wait too
long, all right.
- What do you mean?
- Aw, nothing.
Forget it.
- No. Seriously what
do you mean?
- Well, you see
this fire here?
There's this guy and
everybody liked him.
I mean, a really cool guy.
Class act.
Made good grades.
Had a great girlfriend.
Even got along good
with his parents.
Went to church regularly.
He just had it
all going for him.
And then one day out of
the blue his girlfriend
dumped him.
I mean, no warning.
Just like that.
And that just sent a
shockwave through his life.
One thing started going
bad, then another.
Pretty soon his grades
started to slip.
And that led to more fights
with his parents, and then
before long he dropped
out of church completely.
It's so funny how we run
from the one place that can
actually help us, you know.
Anyway, this guy's life
is in a free fall.
I mean, even his close friends
have just given up on him.
Just wrote him off.
Next thing you know several
weeks have passed and he's
sitting at home by
himself, depressed.
Alone in the dark.
Hadn't even left the house in
a couple days and he's just
sitting there by
the fireplace.
That's the only light
in the entire house.
Then he hears a
knock at the door.
- Kind of scares him.
He knew he hadn't invited
anyone over, so he ignores it.
A few seconds later
the knock is back.
This time a little louder.
Little more intense.
He says all right, I didn't
invite anybody over.
So he just ignores it.
A third time
boom, boom, boom.
- Even louder.
So finally he gets up and he
walks to the door, and as he
puts his hand on the doorknob
and opens it, he looks out
and sees this huge
dark silhouette.
As he's peering into the
darkness trying to find out
who it is, his eyes adjust.
And he sees an old friend
from church standing there.
It's a freezing cold night
and his friend is just
staring at home, and he
says, "can I come in?"
And he guys is like,
"well, yeah. Come on in."
So he reluctantly let's him
in and they walk into the
living room.
Again there's no lights on,
so now there's two guys
sitting there staring
at the same fire.
Neither of them
saying a word.
So a few minutes go by
and then a few more.
Before you know it, a
half hour has gone by.
These guys have said nothing.
Finally the friend that
invited himself over gets up
and the guy thinks he's
fixing to leave, but instead
he walks up to the fireplace
just like this, and he takes
those fireplace tongs and
he reaches into the fire and
he grabs one red hot coal,
and takes it out and he holds
it up and then he sets it
right in front of them on the
brick hearth, and he
just watches it.
So his friend looks at it.
They stair at it as
it was bright red.
And then it turns kind of a
light orange and then a soft
pink, and before
long it turns gray
and goes out completely.
Completely cold.
So he stares at that
for a few minutes.
And then his friend without
saying a word grabs the same
tongs, picks up the coal
that's completely lifeless
and he sets it right back
in the middle of the fire.
And immediately the coal
burst to life, alive with
flame, red, all the
coals igniting it.
And they just stare at
it for a few seconds.
And then the guy gets up,
pats his friend on the back
and he walks out
without saying a word.
And just before he gets to
the door, our depressed
friend stops and
says, "hey, wait!
You're right.
I appreciate what you just
said even though you didn't
speak a word.
Your sermon came
through loud and clear.
I needed that.
I have grown cold, but I
promise you this, I'll be
back where I belong among my
friends back in church
this Sunday. I promise."
- So what happened next?
- Well, since you asked I
watched my friend put his
hand on my doorknob
at the house.
He opened it and he let
himself out of my house and
he walked into the
cold night air.
- That was you?
- Yeah. That was me.
And by the way, I've
kept my promise.
I've been back at church ever
since, where I belong among
my friends.
Now when the struggles of
life come my way and the
cares of this world seem to
weigh me down, I run to the
place that can help
me and not from it.
Make sense?
- Oh. Ok. Fine.
You can all pick me up
this Sunday morning.
- All right!
That's what I'm
talkin' about!
Shaggy!
That was good.
It will be good
to have you back.
- Take that.
- Got any chocolate?
- Little boy grabs his
sister by the hand.
He goes up to the door and
he turns the doorknob and he
opens the door.
And then he sees this huge
black coffin staring down at
them, its mouth just
opening and closing.
Opening and closing.
The little boy and the
little girl they scream.
They run to the bathroom.
It's their last chance.
They lock it and the little
boy is so scared, he hops
into the bathtub and he
closes the shower curtain.
And the little girl is in the
corner just cowering, rocking
back and forth.
Well, finally she gets up
and she opens the medicine
cabinet and she grabs the
cough drops and she throws
them at the coffin.
And it stops the coffin!
- Lisa, that's awful!
There was nothing scary
about that at all.
- Seriously.
- I want my life back after
you telling that story.
- You can't get it back.
- That scared me, you guys.
- What?
- That scared you?
Are you serious?
- Hey. Hey, can you
guys hear that?
- Yeah, it sounds like a
motorcycle or something.
Who would be riding out
in the woods at night?
- Look. I think that
guy just crashed!
[Thud)
- Let's go check it out.
- My gosh.
No!
- Guys, is he ok?
- What's going on?
- Get away from him!
Get away!
Back up!
Let me see your hands!
Put your hands where
I can see them!
- You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can and will
be used against you in a
court of law.
If you can't afford an
attorney, one will be
appointed to represent you.
Do you have any questions?
Do you understand that?
- Your lawyer is
here to see you.
Over here.
- Step back.
- Let's see what
we can do here.
I got to tell you with this
kind of evidence, you really
could be in here for life.
- Wait.
There's something I
need to tell you but --
can they hear us?
- Yes, we're
being monitored.
Just a minute.
Write it down.
- There's no way.
- Yeah.
- Your attorney said you
need to make a phone call.
You got two minutes.
- So you're just going to
let me rot here in jail?
It's not right.
One man shouldn't pay
for another man's sins.
- Oh really?
Isn't that what you've been
preaching to me for years?
- That's not fair,
and you know it.
- Well, life is not
always fair, brother!
♪ When we hurt, when
we ache ...
♪ When we feel the
sting of pain ...
♪ When we're at a loss
for words ...
♪ But we know there's
something wrong ...
♪ How can we do anything ...
♪ But praise you alone ...
♪ You are my god and you'll
never change ...
♪ You are my rock and you'll
always remain ...
♪ When others fall down and
lose their way ...
♪ You will stay the same ...
♪ When we don't feel
as strong ...
♪ When we feel we
can't go wrong ...
♪ When we're frozen
with fear ...
♪ It's your voice we
long to hear ...
♪ How can we do anything ...
♪ How can we do anything but
praise you alone ...
♪ You are my god and you'll
never change ...
♪ You are my rock and you'll
always remain ...
♪ When others fall down and
the ground falls away ...
♪ You will stay the same ...
- What happened?
What happened?
- What did we miss?
- It's all good.
She's probably
upstairs just resting.
It's all good.
Where are you guys been?
Asleep?
- Well, kinda.
- Is this pepper spray?
- Yeah.
- That's your protection
is pepper spray?
- You want me
to try it on you?
- What an embarrassment.
You're pathetic.
- What? I brought the donuts.
♪ You are my god and you'll
never change ...
♪ You are my rock and you'll
always remain ...
♪ When others fall down and
the ground falls away ...
♪ You will stay ...
♪ You are my god and you'll
never change ...
♪ You are my rock and you'll
always remain ...
♪ When others fall down and
the ground falls away ...
♪ You will stay the same ...
- Waiting.
Waiting.
You haven't seen her yet.
- Wow.
- Come on.
Come on.
- With all this, you
could be in jail for life.
- Wait a minute.
Before we go any further, I
have to ask you something.
You're not Superman, are you?
- As a matter of fact, I am.
- Ok. Well --
- and I'm off.
- Out of jail.
- See! See!
This is what you get!
This is my husband!
- What are you doing here?
How did you find me?
- You're going to pay!
- Cut.
- Heather is down!
Heather is down!
- It wasn't on purpose.
- Die!
Did you get that?
This is what happens when
you come on the set
without authorization.
Bugs were harmed
in the filming.
Did you get that?
- How do you
turn the key on?
How do you turn the key on?
- Right there.
- All right, Amy.
- Duct tape.
This really is strong.
1002 uses.
- Mmm.
I've been enjoying your
breath since third street.
- Mmm.
Fantastic.
- That's a rap!
We're done!
No more.
No more!
♪ Baby, put on your
white t-shirt ...
♪ All thin and warm
and perfect ...
♪ Grab your jeans
and sandals ...
♪ Make the weather
worth it ...
♪ Hike down to the river ...
♪ Grab the rope and
swing right in ...
♪ My smiling love, my
rugged warrior ...
♪ You own this heart ...
♪ I'll keep it for you ...
♪ My smiling love, my
rugged warrior ...
♪ God, you stun
my senses ...
♪ I want to drink it all ...
♪ Appalachia to Montana ...
♪ I hear your
creation call ...
♪ Head down to the river ...
♪ I'll throw myself
right in ...
♪ My smiling love, my
rugged warrior ...
♪ You own this heart ...
♪ I'll keep it for you ...
♪ My smiling love, my
rugged warrior ...
♪ I love everything wild ...
♪ Give me life untamed ...
♪ You're the picture
of adventure ...
♪ And you're calling
my name ...