"Prehistoric Worlds"
Earth, a planet seemingly born
to create life, to nurture it,
to be shaped and colored
by it and to shelter it.
And yet, of all the organisms
that have ever lived
on Earth, 98.5% have gone extinct,
because our splendid
sanctuary has been visited
by the apocalypse, five times in all.
Everything we see on Earth
today is the end survivor
of at least one or maybe
more mass extinction events.
We are the descendants
of those who survived extinction.
Five times,
nearly every living thing was wiped
off the face of the planet,
five hells of ice and fire,
devastation in the seas,
on land and in the air above.
After each mass extinction,
there's always winners, survivors
that proliferate to become
the rulers of the Earth.
After each annihilation, the handful
of survivors gave rise to
an explosion of life forms.
You have to imagine organisms
that are radically
different to those of today,
with some extraordinary forms.
From the beautiful
to the bizarre, and with an arms race
of predator and prey leading
inevitably to giants,
these are the stories
for Earth's lost worlds
and the fantastic lives and fearsome deaths
of its wondrous creatures.
At least 3 1/2 billion years ago,
life got a toehold on
a still hostile Earth.
Perhaps in a boiling volcanic
pool somewhere on the planet,
microbes were born, for all we
know, alone in the universe.
Marvelous forms of life would evolve
and colonize every corner of the planet
in a precarious balancing act,
an equilibrium so fragile
that a few degrees of change
in the world's temperature
could mean disaster.
And so it happened,
some 450 million years ago,
that the first great dying took place.
At the time, during a period known
as the Ordovician, the continents clustered
in the Southern Hemisphere.
Thanks to temperatures just two
degrees warmer than today's,
the icecaps were almost
non-existent, and the oceans,
some 600 meters higher
than their current level.
It was a very different world to ours.
The continents were
barren, but in the seas,
after billions of years of
simple microscopic life,
extraordinary creatures appeared.
The oceans played host to
the first earthly paradise.
Life is boomin'.
It's blowin' and goin' in the
oceans, for sure.
So in the Ordovician sea,
you had animals like trilobites,
like little pillbugs.
Trilobites are moving around.
They have eyes.
They have legs.
They have segmented body parts.
And they're cruisin'
around on the seafloor,
eating organic matter or
other smaller animals.
You also have corals,
not the same ones we have today
but different kinds of corals.
And there's a group of
animals called the crinoids,
which we call sea lilies,
because they look like plants,
but they are in fact animals.
They have a place where
they attach to the seafloor.
They have a long stem.
And it looks like a flower, but in fact,
it is the body of the animal.
In this first Eden,
at once familiar and
strange, the shallows teem
with creatures going about their business,
like these fish,
some of the first creatures with bones.
And these conodonts,
which looked like tiny eels.
But the conodonts' paradise was not
without truly terrifying hunters,
like the cephalopods,
ancestors to the octopus.
These are nasty marine predators.
If you are out swimming
with one of those things,
it's not a pleasant concept,
to be eaten by a squid.
I mean, it's reverse calamari, right?
The calamari eats you.
For millions of years, life proliferated
in the waters around the continents.
But for reasons we still don't understand,
the ocean temperatures
dropped by four degrees,
causing an abrupt and brutal ice age.
Evaporated seawater that reined down
on the land no longer
flowed back to the sea.
It accumulated as ice.
As the ice grows, the sea level goes down.
And so if you live in the
shallow marine ecosystems,
and you have a freezing
period, which starts
to move the water from
the oceans on to land ice,
you decrease the area
where animals can live,
and you can get extinctions.
After this first cold wave,
temperatures started to climb again.
The ice melted and sea levels rose.
These climate convulsions
pounded the already
weakened creatures that
still clung to life.
And the one-two punch of cold and hot put
in motion the first mass
extinction in Earth's history.
By the end of the Ordovician,
85% of species had been wiped out.
But a handful of hardy
survivors made it through,
including some of the primitive bony fish,
which would navigate a singular pathway
through the tree of life,
one for which we should
be eternally grateful.
It's descendants branched out to give rise
to all the vertebrates
that have ever existed.
Without it, no dinosaur would
ever have walked the Earth.
No bird would have taken wing.
And no mammals or reptiles
would ever have emerged.
And there would be no humans
telling the story of life.
After this first mass
extinction and the ones to come,
life branched out into
billions of different forms,
each family, each group,
each species being part
of a vast spreading tree.
There's always winners in
the lottery of extinction.
And whatever those survivors are,
that's where the next radiation happens.
That's where the next
evolutionary burst happens.
So if you want a simple way to think
about extinctions on planet Earth is,
the survivors are the winners,
and their descendants are the ones
that populate the next time period.
The desolation
of a mass extinction sets the stage
for an evolutionary renaissance.
Within tens of millions of years
of the Ordovician catastrophe,
the survivors had given rise to a new
era, the Devonian.
It was a completely new world,
full of new prey and new predators,
some quite astounding.
In the sea, we call it the Age of Fishes,
because now the fishes have evolved,
and they're diversifying,
and you get some whoppers.
And one of the greatest fishes
of all time is this animal
called Dunkleosteus.
Dunkleosteus is the super predator
of the Age of Fish,
right at the top of the food chain.
It probably swam in a constant search
for large enough meals,
even specimens of its own kind.
In the natural history museum in Paris,
a plaster cast of Dunkleosteus'
impressive jaw testifies
to the killing power of
this giant of the Devonian.
This is the well-honed
weapon of a fearsome hunter.
Paleontologist Gael
Clement studies placoderms,
the large family to which
Dunkleosteus belongs.
This animal's part
of the group called placoderms, which means
that they have thick,
bony plates under their skin.
Here, we see the jaw,
with these sharp points,
which are not teeth,
because teeth didn't exist yet.
It's actually the jawbone,
which presents this pincer form,
so it can crush and chop up
the prey in which it fed.
And while Dunkleosteus terrorized the seas,
the continents were being transformed.
The beginning of it, on land,
they're little, tiny things,
and by the end there were forests.
The Devonian is when you
get a land environment
that starts to look like
something you might recognize.
You go from nothing to forests.
But trees release water vapor into the air
and may have triggered epic
storms over the continents.
Torrents swept dead and
decomposing plant matter
into the oceans, choking them.
Oxygen levels plummeted.
Global cooling and volcanic
turbulence may have
worsened the crisis in the seas, as well.
For marine life, sustenance grew scarce.
Eventually, the food chain collapsed.
The Devonian extinction strangled 3/4
of the worlds marine life to death.
But on land, the forests kept thriving.
Any creature looking
to survive the disaster
at sea would have to seek
greener pastures, literally,
and that would require
some anatomical innovation.
So you have a variety of fish
that actually are
maneuvering their way around,
in shallow water,
and they have these lobe-like fins,
that actually, if you look at the fossils,
and actually you can start to see the rays
of the fins actually have distinct bones,
and it's this lineage of fish
that eventually evolves into amphibians.
With the seas suffocating
and the lush land beckoning,
the menu required updating.
Pioneering fish like Tiktaalik,
a descendant of the bony fish that slipped
through the first mass extinction,
had already been experimenting with life
where the shallows meet the land.
It had gills to breathe in water
but also a primitive lung for breathing air
and four robust fins that
would later become legs.
Fleeing the choking oceans,
Tiktaalik and its family,
the sarcopterygians crept out of the water
and slithered through the
second great extinction.
And the world would never be the same.
A new chapter in the history of life began.
And again, in the race of
life, the winners give rise
to new branches of the evolutionary tree.
In the new age of the Permian,
the first modern trees developed.
Photosynthesis enriched
the air with oxygen.
At the same time,
the continents drifted together
to form a supercontinent,
Pangaea, a vast new territory
for land-going animals
to explore and exploit.
Animals unlike anything
the world have ever seen
before evolved to handle
life on terra firma,
where conditions like temperature
varied much more wildly
and harshly than in the seas.
To protect their offspring,
big predators like the Gorgonopsians began
to lay the first eggs with hard shells.
All the early land animals
walked on four legs,
hence the name tetrapods,
a body plan that's as revolutionary
as any in the story of life.
And some were quite flamboyant.
What you got are animals
that looked like a big iguana
with a great big sail on its back.
It's likely that these sails were
for either impressing the other sex
or for moderating heat.
You could rotate towards the sun,
and your blood is warmed up
by this big warming surface,
or you could rotate away from the sun.
You can cool it down.
These pelycosaurs, with their iconic sails,
lived alongside dicynodonts,
herbivores with a new innovation, a beak,
designed to excavate the
tough roots on which they fed.
These huge animals were probably hunted
by the biggest predators in Pangaea.
Like the Titanophoneus, or titanic killer,
a reptile that could grow
to a length of five meters.
In the seas,
100 million years after the collapse
of the oceans, vibrant,
new lifescapes flourished.
You would've just loved
scuba diving in the Permian,
and you got all these incredible creatures
that are out swimmin' around.
There's corals.
There's cephalopods.
The fishes have gotten big now,
and you've got your first sharks.
Certainly one of the most amazing
is this animal called Helicoprion.
It basically had this
whirl of teeth mounted
in its lower jaw,
and it would slam into its upper jaw,
and it was a slicing mechanism.
It swam around in the sea,
and it just chopped stuff in half
and then came back and ate it.
The massive fossilized teeth
from this buzzsaw shark
suggest it could've grown
to a length of 12 meters.
On land and in the water,
the biodiversity of the
Permian was simply spectacular.
But it was doomed.
The most devastating natural catastrophe
the Earth has ever seen
so far awaited them,
a cataclysm that would
transform this paradise
into hell on earth for millions of years.
Some 250 million years ago,
in what is now Siberia,
the Earth tried to turn itself inside out.
These vast cliffs, called traps, formed
when the planet belched
lava, over and over again,
for tens of thousands of years.
Iceland, one of the most
volcanically active countries
in the world,
is entire built by lava flows.
It is an open-air laboratory for geologists
like Patrick De Wever,
and embedded in the rock,
he finds the barrels of a
lava flow's smoking guns.
When there's an emission of lava,
there are holes in the mass of rock,
and these holes are filled with gases,
which come out at the
same time as the magma.
There are different types of gas.
There's water vapor.
There are sulfur oxides and carbon dioxide.
We know water vapor is a greenhouse gas,
which tends to raise the temperature,
as does carbon dioxide.
But sulfur oxides have a double effect.
On the one hand, they cause acid rain,
and they also partially block out sunlight,
leading to a drop in temperature
and lower light levels,
which means a reduction in photosynthesis
and so perhaps fewer plants.
And since animals feed on plants,
fewer plants mean herbivores start to die,
and then in turn,
the carnivorous animals die, too.
The Permian-Jurassic
extinction was the mother
of all extinctions.
Basically, a lot of our
friends that had been with us
for the entire Paleozoic,
things like trilobites,
the last trilobite goes.
Lots of these earlier marine organisms,
they've survived through much
of the earlier extinctions,
sorry, can't make it through.
On the other side of the world,
in China's Zhejiang Province,
researchers Sylvie Crasquin
and Marie-Beatrice Forel are
in search of one creature
that survived the Permian
disaster in the seas,
hoping to find the secrets
of how to cheat extinction.
Here, at the dividing line
between the abundant Permian
and the disaster-ravaged time just after,
the researchers locate
what they're looking for,
tiny crustaceans called ostrocods.
Ostrocods had an ability to adapt to some
of the most stressed environments
in the history of the planet.
In her Paris laboratory,
Sylvie puts her prizes
under the microscope.
Ostrocods from before the
disaster are pretty large
for miniature marine life.
The ones from immediately after are not.
Just after the crisis,
conditions were extremely harsh.
You can imagine that ostrocods went
into energy-saving mode,
meaning they reduced the metabolism
as far as possible to consume less energy,
which is why you find smaller ones,
which also had smaller eggs,
and with reproductions
cycles that are much shorter
than those usually
observed in the Paleozoic.
After the devastation of the Permian,
life hit the reset button once again.
On land, the few tetrapods that survived,
descendants of the first
land-going vertebrates,
would evolve into reptiles,
dinosaurs and mammals.
Millions of years later,
by the start of the Triassic,
the branches of the tree of
life are once again blossoming.
The Triassic is a time
of tremendous innovation,
because the decks have
been cleared so severely
in the Permian-Jurassic.
So you basically wipe the slate not clean
but pretty clean.
The Triassic is this really crazy place
where these things now radiate again
into all these different
kinds of shapes and forms,
lots of really cool,
weird animals in the Triassic.
In the ocean, marine reptiles had emerged,
like the ichthyosaurs,
which roamed the seas,
hunting fish and squid.
Corals bloomed and built reefs once again.
Ammonites proliferated,
along with sea urchins and starfish.
In the skies above,
the first flying reptiles
called pterosaurs beat their huge wings.
On land, great herbivores with
tough leathery armor grazed
in conifer forests.
Their defensive carapace
hints at the presence
of fearsome predators,
like the agile Coelophysis,
which probably hunted in packs,
the two-legged,
40-pound Coelophysis was one
of the first dinosaurs to grace the earth.
It would take tens of millions of years
and another global catastrophe
before giant dinosaurs
completely dominated the world.
Some 200 million years ago,
Europe and Africa tore away
from the American continent,
forming the Atlantic Ocean.
The Earth entered a new
period of volcanic upheaval.
It set in motion the fourth mass extinction
in the planet's history,
wiping out 3/4 of land-dwelling species
and 96% of ocean species.
And the great Permian
experiment lay in ruins.
But once again,
life would rise like a phoenix
from the ashes.
The dinosaurs survived.
The mammals survived.
The pterosaurs survived.
So on land, you have these lineages now
that are off and racing.
In the highlands of Central South Africa,
the rocks preserve a
record of this renaissance
and a world dominated by some
of the most massive
animals that ever existed,
the mega-dinosaurs.
Paleontologist Jonah Choiniere
and his students from
Witwatersrand University
in Johannesburg are excavating fossils
from the Triassic and Jurassic periods
that may shed light on this
revolutionary transition.
It'll come out.
While his students extract a fossil
from the Triassic, Jonah goes in search
of sediments from the Jurassic.
These rocks in this
cliff, these are Jurassic.
So they're about 200 million years old.
Down below us, on the Triassic,
all types of animals
are found in the rocks,
but as we come up into the Jurassic,
dinosaurs become much more common.
In fact, almost everything
we find here is a dinosaur.
Immediately after the extinction event,
dinosaurs are small,
but just for a short time.
Suddenly, they explode
into enormous body sizes.
And in fact, within a few million
years, you have things
that are twice the size
of today's elephants.
In the Triassic, it's anyone's game.
But as soon as we get into the Jurassic,
it's clear that dinosaurs
are the winners of the day.
Okay, slowly, gently.
One, two, three.
You guys okay?
Hey, guys.
Hey, just in time.
Hi!
You flipped it, fantastic.
Okay, we've taken bigger ones down before.
Okay, you ready, on three, two, three.
Most of the fossils collected
in South Africa,
in the past century, are housed
at Witwatersrand
University in Johannesburg.
The wealth of this collection
underlines the sheer variety
of species during the Jurassic.
The fossils on these shells are the bones
of Ladumarahi Mafube,
a giant dinosaur from South Africa,
which lived in the Jurassic Period,
about 200 million years ago.
And this is the foot bone
of Ladumarahi Mafube.
This is the only known
specimen of Ladumarahi,
and we'd been looking in South Africa
for well over 150 years, for dinosaurs.
The name Ledumahadi means
a giant thunderclap,
and Mafube, which is the species
name, means dawn,
so together, it's a Sesotho term,
meaning a giant thunderclap at dawn.
We can tell from these bones
that this animal weighed
about 12 tons, and that's amazing,
because it shows that dinosaurs soon
after the end Triassic extinction were able
to rebound and attain enormous sizes.
We can tell from the bones of Ledumahadi
that it must've walked on all four legs,
in fact, much like a modern elephant,
but with a slightly more
crouched limb posture.
This type of dinosaur is a sauropodomorph,
and we know that they had long necks
and tiny heads and giant bodies
where they would've fermented
the food they swallowed whole.
Dinosaurs like Ledumahadi
would've made tremendous advantage
of the openings in the environment
and the ecosystems left vacant
by the end Triassic extinction.
After life was almost
wiped out in the Permian,
fascinating new creatures emerged on stage.
With the arrival of flowering plants
and pollinating insects,
evolution went into overdrive.
The development of new species
sparked the genesis of others.
Herbivores grew larger
and more diversified,
along with the carnivores that fed on them.
These gigantic suarapods
were the biggest land animals
that have ever lived.
Some of them as much as 100 feet long,
20 feet tall, up to 88 tons,
these massive, incredible animals.
During the Cretaceous,
evolution went to extremes.
The jaw of the T-Rex exerted so much force,
it could crush the bones of its
prey and swallow them whole.
The largest flying creatures
the Earth has ever seen ruled the skies,
pterosaurs, whose wing
span could reach 12 meters.
And in the oceans,
creatures also grew immense,
like plesiosaurus, a ferocious predator.
And then there was the mosasaur,
a reptile that grew up to 18 meters.
The dinosaurs dominated
the face of the Earth
for more than 175 million years,
covering two geological periods,
the Jurassic then the Cretaceous.
Today, their only descendants are birds.
Once again, a cataclysm shook the planet
and brought the giants low.
As the Cretaceous drew to its close,
the world began to
resemble the one we know.
But India, which was not yet
joined to the Asian continent,
underwent a massive volcanic
episode like the one
in Siberia that ended the Permian.
The Deccan Traps bear witness to eruptions
that occurred over several millennia.
They date from some 65 million years ago,
around the time that the
dinosaurs disappeared.
Until the 1980s,
many scientists attributed
the dinosaurs' extinction
to this volcanic outburst.
Then came a theory that was
out of this world, literally,
that the dinosaur killer
was an extraterrestrial.
In 1980, this crazy idea was proposed
that an asteroid hit the planet
and caused the extinction
that wiped out the dinosaurs.
And we all thought, that's nuts.
That's like National Enquirer science.
Little green men come take our dinosaurs,
asteroid strikes, give me a break.
So everybody laughed,
thought this is a joke.
A joke that scientists would be forced
to take seriously.
In the badlands of Western Canada,
paleontologist Francois Therrien
from the Royal Tyrrell
Museum makes his way down
through millions of years
of fossil-rich sediments.
This valley,
carved out by the Red Deer River,
has yielded thousands
of dinosaur skeletons.
And one layer of sediment
bears the reddish signature
of a dinosaur killer.
So we can see here this
salmon-colored rock here.
This line marks the end of
the age of the dinosaurs
and the beginning of the age of mammals.
For geologists and paleontologists,
this line here represents a
record of a catastrophic event,
a meteorite impact,
that occurred 66 million years ago.
At the base of the layer,
we have the last pollens
of the last plants that grew
at the end of the Cretaceous,
followed by iridium,
which is an element extremely rare
at the surface of the Earth
but extremely abundant in meteorites.
This line here marks the
extinction of the dinosaurs.
And still, at the end of the 20th century,
not all researchers accepted the theory
of an extraterrestrial impact.
It would've left a massive
scar somewhere on earth.
So where was the crater?
Scientists began looking for it,
analyzing and dating each
major crater they could find,
but none coincided with the
extinction of the dinosaurs.
In the end, it was two
geologists from an oil company
who discovered it by chance.
Nestled in Mexico's Yucatan Peninsula,
half hidden by the waters off the coast,
lay a crater more than 100 miles across.
It was 66 million years old.
And the horrors of the
most famous extinction
of all could no longer be denied.
So if you were on planet
Earth 66.02 million years ago,
walking around in a beautiful forest,
triceratops is grazing next to you,
you were worried you might
run into a Tyrannosaurus rex,
but you don't see one right now,
life is good, trees are flowering,
suddenly, in an instant, a blinding light,
and you're dead.
The asteroid impact was an amazing thing,
because unlike all the other extinctions
that preceded it,
this one was global and instant.
It took a second or two for the asteroid
to pass through the
atmosphere, on the way in.
The asteroid, of course, is gone.
It's vaporized.
It's now molten rock,
shattered, target rock.
All that stuff blows back out,
through the hole in the
atmosphere, into low-Earth orbit.
The Earth rotates underneath it.
And then all that debris
starts to rain back
into the atmosphere.
As it rains back in, it heats
up, and the sky gets hot.
The heat from the sky makes it
to the ground and starts fires.
So no matter where you are on earth,
within hours,
you are feeling some serious hurt.
If you're anywhere in North
America, forget about it.
The initial explosion takes care of you.
There's smoke.
There's dust.
Blocks out the sunlight.
If you're a plant,
there's no photosynthesis.
If you were a big animal,
if you survive the initial
blast somewhere on earth,
there's probably nothing to eat.
You probably don't make it
through the first winter.
A magnitude 13 earthquake,
a gigantic tsunami,
the raining blocks of rock
that are flown for hundreds of miles,
and the oceans have taken
a great insult as well.
The chemistry of the oceans have changed.
The phytoplankton were
turned off for months.
The zooplankton have then crashed.
The marine food system is down.
In total, 3/4 of species vanished forever.
All the big dinosaurs
were wiped off the map.
But while the titans
died, the stage was set
for some tiny survivors
to take over the world.
The Royal Tyrrell Museum is home to one
of the world's largest
dinosaur collections,
including a specimen of
the most terrifying of all,
Tyrannosaurus rex.
But here, scientists are also resurrecting
the little animals that
would inherit the Earth.
Craig Scott,
head of conservation and research,
studies the mammals of the Paleocene,
the time just after the fifth extinction.
I'm essentially a paleo-dentist,
because the vast majority
of specimens that I examine are teeth.
The fossil record of mammals
is largely a dental record.
You do get the occasional jaws,
and sometimes you get some
postcranial remains as well,
but for mammals of this age and older,
the record is primarily dental.
Well, from looking at these teeth,
I can tell from the shapes of the cusps
that this animal was probably
eating some resistant foods,
maybe really hard insects,
or it might have even
been crushing mollusks,
so the shells of snails and clams.
And I can also tell by looking at the teeth
that they have a very good resemblance
to living relatives of
hedgehogs and shrews.
Those mammals
that survived the fifth mass
extinction were no larger
than a rat, but the fossils
that Craig Scott is analyzing
illustrates the speed
with which they evolved, diversified
and became giants,
exploiting the ecological niches
once monopolized by the dinosaurs.
So this is the skull of an
animal called a pantodont,
and pantodonts were large,
almost hippopotamus-like herbivores
that lived during the
Paleocene and the Eocene.
They represent the group of mammals
that achieved the largest body
size during the Paleocene.
And some of these animals made it up
to the size of a very large cow.
So within 15 million
years or 20 million years
after the extinction event,
mammals went from animals
that had an average body size
of maybe a small rabbit up
to something that's similar
to living hippopotamuses.
So that's quite a leap.
And a mere 10 million
or so years after that,
mammals got even larger,
and they achieved body sizes equivalent
to living elephants and rhinoceroses.
The great extinction
events were revolutions
in the story of life, because the thread
of life never completely
snapped, and five times,
cataclysms opened up new
worlds to the survivors.
After each, new branches on
the tree of life would bloom
and fill the void left by the dead.
And across the Earth,
that little shrew-like animal
multiplied, transformed
and became all the fantastic
mammals we know today.
Some even returned to the seas.
They evolved into unique forms and adapted
to every climate, every environment.
Side-by-side, with other survivors,
they created a world
as colorful and diverse
as any that had gone before.
This is the sixth earthly
paradise, and it is uniquely ours,
because one among this mammalian multitude,
a species of primate rose up
on its hind legs to dominate
and remake the earth like
no other species before it.
Some lineages were important in times past
and disappeared,
because they didn't survive extinctions,
but what we have today
is this composite world.
Humans and trees and whales
and fish and birds and primates,
you can go back,
in their individual lineages
and find out when their lucky moment was.
When did their ancestors
survive key extinctions?
When was their point
when their ancestors
radiated and diversified?
And we're all survivors,
at this point in time.
Human beings now study the forces
of nature that propelled them to dominance,
a restless Earth with a
volatile and vulnerable climate,
an equilibrium we know
to be alarmingly fragile,
supporting a complex web of life,
all on a home where death could come
from the skies, in an instant.
But the next mass extinction
may already be upon us,
and for the first time,
it may be more akin to mass suicide.
Previous crises have
all had a natural cause.
They were either caused
by volcanic eruptions,
meteorite impacts or a climate change.
The difference with this crisis is
it's 100% caused by humans.
As such, it's happening
at a much faster rate,
and it's far less predictable.
Right around every extinction we've seen,
one or a couple of species
surges in dominance.
And that's what we're seeing today,
with humanity taking off at the expense
of other animals on the planet.
The timescale that we're talking about now
for the current crisis is
incredibly, incredibly fast,
much, much faster than anything
that we've experienced before.
Mankind is destroying its own planet
at a phenomenal rate.
Even at our human scale,
we can see species becoming extinct.
Whatever happens,
life will regenerate on Earth.
And it'll only take a few million years.
But what the actors
will be in that new play
that plays out over the
future of life on this planet,
it's anyone's guess.
On the unimaginable timescale
of our planet's evolution,
we now know that history repeats itself.
And the lesson of that history is clear.
When catastrophe strikes,
molten, frozen or hell from the heavens,
the creatures that dominate
will likely vanish,
but the Earth itself will not,
and life will always find a way.
HI/SDH Parts removed By
DvX3M