Steel man,
shuffle the deck.
shuffle the deck!
Deal the hand.
Deal the hand!
[Gunfire]
[Baby crying]
Daddy.
Daddy!
Joker's been found.
Deal another.
Deal another!
[Gunshot]
Baby...
Aah!
Take her to the outskirts.
No one must know
who she is.
When it is Chandra's time,
the medallion
will let you know.
Now go.
Be careful.
She's all I have left.
[Crying]
[Beeping]
[Alarm sounding]
We're really
brothers, my friend.
Look into your mind
and see the other.
You know who he is.
The other--
you remember him,
don't you?
He is really you.
The other.
...the other.
Remember the other.
Remember the other!
Remember the...
[Neck snapping]
[Beeping]
Chandra,
you won't remember me,
but when it is your time,
the protectors
will come for you.
Let's go, Sebastian!
Come on!
You're late, Paul.
There's still
a lot of resistance
about your going,
but the governmental
guard came through
and gave
their approval.
I spent six years
researching this, Paul.
I could waste
years researching
what was completed
and documented
over 30 years ago
in the city.
Prototype was
nobly conceived
and badly executed.
And the last I spoke
with Professor Phelps,
he agrees
that no one here
will censor
your decision to go.
Dr. Zalazny.
Yes?
Be careful.
This time,
it's my program.
Where's Sebastian?
I don't know. Why?
He's playing the chip
with my fucking money.
Did he win?
If he's processing,
they'll kill him.
If I catch him,
I'll kill him.
I don't think he's
processing.
He left it with me
to fix it.
Kid's damn lucky.
The thing
stopped a bullet
the other day.
I'm glad you think
this is so funny.
You can help me find him
and bury the little shit.
Listen, I care about him
just as much as you do,
so don't make me
feel guilty for
trying to help him.
He'd process
with or without
my help.
So, let's talk about
something else.
Oh, yeah?
What's that?
You, uh...
You found yourself
another place
to live yet?
We're going to go over
this again?
I got more than enough room
for you to stay here.
Have you ever heard
the term,
"You're beating a dead dog
with a broken stick"?
I'm just offering you
a place to stay.
You don't have to be
reading so much into it.
Hey!
I got something
for you today.
Thanks.
I have to find
Sebastian.
[Speaking swedish]
Tie me up, Hawkins.
Spank me.
I like a man who's hairy.
Fuck me, Hawkins.
Aah!
The city is not
a very safe place
for a woman by herself.
I assumed I wouldn't
attract as much attention
if I came alone.
Are you Taurence?
You are a very
daring woman.
Your still being alive
seems to prove your point.
Dr. Alex Zalazny.
The lab?
You have the code control?
Yes.
[Door opens]
Prototype?
The shell.
The rebirth chamber?
Yes.
There's no access panel.
The third level
of the program?
of the program, please?
The operational
program
should answer
your question.
I have a question
for you.
Yes, doctor?
It seems they disappeared
without any explanation.
Who?
Dr. Roberts
and his team.
That would be
a better question
for Dr. Roberts.
He hasn't been seen
in 30 years.
Sorry to hear that.
I am going to need
an assistant.
I'll help you,
Dr. Zalazny.
There's
a sleeping room
down the hall.
I suggest you stay
in the building.
It wouldn't be wise
to go out.
Thanks for
your advice.
I'm sure I can take care
of myself.
Hey. Chip.
[Snapping neck]
[Snap]
You are an addict,
and your total effort in life
is to obtain money
to feed your habit.
Now you're launched
on a full-scale teen-age
crime wave of your very own,
you feel let down
and tired,
but more persuasion,
a greater need to belong,
and it isn't long
until you try again.
You try new things,
the hypnotics,
as they're called--
seconal, or reds,
nembutal, or yellows,
phenobarbital,
and the stimulants
amphetamine, dexedrine,
and benzedrine, or bennies.
You begin to lose track
of your friends
because now you belong
to a group,
a group that must move in
a veiled world of secrecy.
Yo, gypsy!
Stay out of here, demon!
If I see you
around here again,
my sword shall exorcise
your demonic soul!
[Bleep bleep]
I'm telling you,
Sebastian.
You shouldn't
fool with Delaney.
One of these days,
he's really gonna kill you.
Are you hungry,
Hawk?
[Coughing]
One of these days,
he's gonna shoot you
in the back.
Did you get around to
fixing my processor?
Yep...
But I don't think
I'm gonna give it
to you.
Why not?
Because if they
catch you
processing again,
they're gonna cut
your balls off
and sell them.
Besides,
your sister
doesn't want me
to give it to you,
either.
What did she say?
You're lucky
to have someone
who cares for you.
You shouldn't screw
around with her.
Come on, Hawk.
Give me my processor.
Nope. I told you.
I'm not gonna give
it to you.
Come on, Hawk.
Give me my processor.
I told you, I'm not
gonna give it to you.
Hey!
Let go!
That hurts, man!
Hey!
[Beeping]
40 megs CPU
with access hookup
and turbo.
All right!
I'm warning you.
Don't let them
catch you.
For this you steal
and live a life
of degradation and crime.
Demon, I shall exorcise
the devil out of you.
Delaney!
Put the gun down.
Let the kid go.
It is the task put to me
by the Holy Father
to cleanse the evil
of this evildoer!
Come on, Delaney.
Put the gun down!
He's just a kid!
Shish kebab, gypsy.
Ah! My eyes!
Oh!
Oh! My knee!
You suffering bastard, you!
Why--
Joe!
You suffering demon,
I told you
not to sleep here.
Wake up!
Remove your sinful body
from my hotel.
He-- he's dead.
Dead?
Dead.
What do you
mean, dead?
He hasn't paid
his rent.
Damn.
I'm telling you.
Mine!
One more--
one more chance.
That's all I need.
Yo, girl.
Remember, you got
to give my boy
Action a whirl.
I ain't doing shit
until I get my chip!
I ain't touching you
until you put on a rubber.
Yo, Action...
Use my skin.
[Beeping]
[Hawkins]
Hey, you ditch-drain bastards!
Come on, motherfuckers!
Hey, you! Yeah, you!
Goddamn assholes!
Come on!
Oh, yeah, gimp.
Kick his ass!
Oh.
[Beep beep beep]
I'm tired, Hawk.
[Alarm sounds]
What are you doing?
Can't feel anything,
can you?
What are you
talking about?
Your legs.
You can't feel anything
in your legs.
No. No, I can't feel
anything in my legs.
How far up?
It's just my legs.
I can't feel
anything in my legs.
You know what I mean.
What are you
asking me that for?
You know how sometimes
when you dream,
you can't remember
whether it's in
black and white or in color?
That's how I feel
with you, Hawk.
When I dream of you,
I can't remember
if you're in your chair
or if you're walking.
I think you're walking
in my dreams.
So tell me, Hawkins.
Do you want
to walk again?
No, doctor.
I like sitting here,
pissing in my pants.
I guess I made
a mistake.
I chose
the wrong guy.
So, why are you
offering me this gift?
It's not a gift,
Hawkins.
It's a process.
It's a process
called rebirth
that involves
the regeneration
of your mind
and body.
You don't mind if I
smoke, do you,
Hawkins?
So...
You want me
to think about it.
No.
Here's the card.
Be there tomorrow,
10 A.M.
If you're not there,
I'll find somebody else.
When I--
when I come out--
rebirth.
What-- what do you
mean by rebirth?
Your body will be
regenerated.
The cybernetic suit will
let you live and
breathe.
But what about me?
What happens to my mind,
my memories?
We'll record them,
and then we'll
re-implant them.
What about the memories
that I've forgotten,
the ones we don't record,
like my subconscious?
What happens to them?
If you don't remember
them, Hawkins,
then they really aren't
important, are they?
Get lost.
Damn it!
Double down.
Four across.
Chippy chips.
You owe me
another 50!
You son of a bitch!
You're processing!
I know it!
Ooh.
Ha ha! Ho ho!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Ahh. Ahh. Oh.
Oh. Oh.
You mind
if I take his play?
You...
Think you're
a p-p-p-p-player.
Street rat.
Go ahead.
Let him play.
Want to play?
Let's play.
Tie me up.
Spank me.
Fags.
Three down.
Split them up.
The cards didn't fall
the right way for you.
You got real lucky,
street boy,
real lucky,
but don't-- but don't--
but don't think
it's going to keep
coming that way.
Shit!
Four down.
Four across.
Take all.
All right, you little
street faggot!
Your streak is over!
Over.
Call card.
[Beeping]
All right.
Three of diamonds.
You little bastard!
You're processing me.
I ain't processing you,
you stupid
s-s-s-sack of shit!
Hey!
Play the hand.
No p-p-p-processor.
Tell the little punk
to keep away.
Three down.
Four across.
Double down.
Call card.
Three of hearts.
You little
b-b-b-b-bitch!
You fucked
with the cards.
[Crack]
Come on!
Stupid!
What did I--
They could have killed you
in there, Sebastian!
So, if I
did die,
would you
place a red rose
on my chest
and kiss me
before they
close the lid?
Next time, they're
going to blow you away.
No one's going to
blow me away.
Besides, the mute
decided to be
our big brother
protector.
You stay away from them,
do you understand me?
Don't get your feathers
ruffled over it.
He's not my type.
Do you understand?
Yeah! All right!
Good.
The next time you steal
my chip, Sebash,
I'm going to
fucking kill you!
It's Sebastian!
Sam Sebastian to you.
Beef hash.
Hawkins, you okay?
Are you all right?
You were right.
Right? What are you
talking about?
Dreams.
Dreams?
What do you mean?
When I dream,
I don't remember if I'm
in my chair or I'm walking.
Hawkins, what are you
talking about?
If I could walk,
things would be different.
Wouldn't they?
Yeah. You'd be
at the Agency.
I wouldn't know you.
No!
I mean between us.
I don't think this
is the time to
talk about that.
Why?
Because I don't want
to deal with this!
Do you love me, Chandra?
I don't want
to deal with this!
Hawkins, I told you
there can be nothing
between us!
But if I could walk...
Damn it, Hawkins.
You had to do it,
you had to change
things.
Wait-- I got something
I want to give you.
Here, take it.
Hawkins, I don't
want your gun.
Take it!
I don't want
your gun!
Goddamn it!
Take it.
[Typing on keyboard]
He's dead!
[Thunder]
Do you wantto
walk again,
Hawkins?
Do you want
to walk again?
He's dead!
Bless this light.
Come on, Hawkins.
If you don'tremember
them, Hawkins,
then they really
aren't important.
So, who's his family?
I guess we are.
Why did he leave?
I don't know.
Hello, bitch.
Ah, shit!
Aah!
Let go of me.
That shit ain't
working this time.
So, why are we
so lucky that
you're blonde?
Begging for it
bimbo bitch
happens along.
It's payback time,
bitch.
Fuck you!
Ow!
Oh, shit!
What the fuck
is that?
Fuck me, Hawkins.
Boot him up.
Hawkins,
can you hear us?
Yes.
I can hear you.
Do you know
where you are?
Yes.
It's gonna take
time for your body
to become acclimated
to the suit.
I became weak,
Dr. Zalazny.
Yes. You'll become stronger,
but it will take time.
Do you remember
who you are?
Yes.
I am Hawkins Coselow.
Where did
you go?
I was searching
for the woman.
What woman?
The woman
in my memory.
Did you
find her?
Yes,
I found her.
Is she the one?
I...
I don't know.
"And... who...
"Hath...
"Kept...
The..."
"Co--
Comm--"
"Comm...
"Command...
"Ment...
"Commandments
"from the time--"
What the hell
are you doing here?
I know you.
How'd you
get in here?
I've been here
before.
Wrong answer!
I knew Hawkins.
Is he--
is he dead?
No.
Hawkins is alive.
Where is he?
He is... here.
What do you
mean "here"?
I am Hawkins.
I was reborn.
It was an experiment.
I wanted to walk.
I wanted to be
strong again.
I...
I love you,
Chandra.
Is that
why you're here?
I...
I am alone.
Can you feel,
Hawkins?
Yes,
I can feel you.
Can you feel, Hawkins?
[Sobbing]
You feel me?
Chandra.
Hawkins?
Please don't kill me!
Please!
Chandra.
It's me.
Who are you?
I am your father,
Chandra.
I don't have
a father.
How can you
be my father?
I made this program
so we could meet
when you would be
old enough to understand.
But I don't
understand.
You were born in the times
of the mad minds.
It ended with my death.
You're the last omega,
Chandra.
Omega?
We were taken out
of the cities
and implanted.
It was meant to turn us
into teachers,
shamans.
We were called a lot of things,
and then we were brought
back to the cities
to become leaders.
What cities?
They're all gone.
You were implanted
at birth,
and it was my hope
that one day you would
become our leader.
Who...
Who are the people
that brought me here?
They are the protectors.
They have been raised to
sacrifice their lives for you.
Well, if you're
my father,
who's my mother?
You are an omega now.
It will take some time,
but soon you will feel
the powers that lay dormant.
Tell me
about my mother.
♪ Il est ne ♪
♪ Le divin enfant ♪
♪ Chante tous et bois ♪
♪ Resonnez musette ♪
♪ Il est ne ♪
♪ Le divin enfant ♪
♪ Chante ♪
♪ Tous... ♪♪
Stay away from me.
Be careful.
She's all I have left.
♪ Il est ne ♪
♪ Le divin enfant ♪
♪ Louez hautbois ♪
♪ resonnez musette ♪
[Sniffs]
♪ Il est ne ♪
♪ Le divin enfant ♪
♪ Chantons tous ♪
♪ Son avenement ♪♪
I believe, doctor,
you were to limit
your studies
to the medical
aspects of
prototype.
You've known all along.
What did you think
happened
to the medical
program?
You think they
passed out of existence
like dinosaurs?
Unsuccessful implants?
Failure of
the omega interface?
It's all bullshit,
isn't it, Taurence?
Bullshit?
The program was
a failure, doctor.
Ridiculous.
The omegas did
successfully adapt
to their implants.
Their failure was in
the overriding
of the primary
programming directives.
So the government
created prototype
to assassinate
the omegas?
Assassination,
doctor?
Prototypes weren't
designed as assassins.
They were the next
step in cybernetics.
Total rebirth.
100% cybernetically
integrated entities.
It was
an assassination program.
It was the logical
conclusion
to an experiment
that had gone
out of control,
doctor.
That was
over 20 years ago.
Yes, doctor.
A different time.
A time you're not
familiar with
or able to judge.
Maybe you're right,
Taurence,
but why would
the government
let me come here and re-create
another prototype?
You came here
for medical
research, doctor.
Your unsealing of
the prototype lab
will assist us
in the conclusion
of the program
it was intended to.
The conclusion
of what program?
What are you
talking about?
Omega, doctor.
There is one left.
One that was
implanted at birth.
One that I believe
remains inactivated
until now.
You see, doctor,
we couldn't allow
the same mistake
to plague us again.
Am I going to get
out of here alive, Taurence?
Aren't you being
a bit overly dramatic,
Dr. Zalazny?
It's like the stories
of the people
that hunted down the
Nazis in the Second
World War.
History to most...
Except the hunters.
Dr. T. Roberts.
Dr. Taurence Roberts.
It's you, isn't it?
Yes, doctor.
Where are you going?
Home.
Where else
would I be going?
My work
is completed here.
Good night, doctor.
Uh, yeah.
Good night.
What are you
doing here?
I said,
what are you doing?
What does it
look like I'm doing?
It looks like
you're leaving.
Well, are you?
Yes, I'm leaving.
Did I do something?
No.
I have to go away with
some people for a while.
Why... why?
Look!
I can't stay here,
all right?
We can't pretend
we're brother
and sister anymore!
You understand?
Don't follow me.
Stupid bitch.
The A01
or the A002 programs
will not operate
without the omega
shell program.
Can I leave
the suit
and return
to what I was?
No.
You will die.
To live,
I must eliminate
the omega signal.
Yes.
Why was I created?
You were reborn
to carry out
the omega program, Hawkins.
I am no longer
the same Hawkins.
It will take time.
You will acclimate
to your environment
in the suit.
One day, you may be able
to live outside of it.
It will not be
the same Hawkins
that leaves
the suit.
If I die, will you
build another?
Yes,
I will build another.
30 years ago,
the government
ended the program
and sealed the lab.
Dr. Zalazny's research
has allowed me
to complete my work.
Yes.
I understand.
I...
I am alone.
We are all alone, Hawkins.
No!
Aah!
You need me, Hawkins!
No!
[Back cracks]
[Metal cracking]
Don't kill him!
Chandra.
Hawkins.
Hawkins, it's me.
It's Chandra.
Hawkins.
Please.
Can you feel me?
It's me.
Hawkins, please...
Sebastian!
No!