You can let me try.
What a great tie, Garrett.
Is that new, Garrett?
Do you mind if I get
the same one, Garrett?
Stop. You're awful.
I think Kyle spends more time in
the boss' office than his own.
Okay, okay. Trivia
at tuck's bay tonight, okay?
I hope to see everybody there.
Okay? Everybody.
- First round's on me, baby.
- Okay, top shelf.
What do you say, Russ?
Loosen' up a bit.
You're hopeless.
The human care bear.
Russell, you're going, right?
- Yeah. I wouldn't miss it.
- Okay, good.
Diane,
you wanna carpool with me?
No. I can't. I'm sorry.
- Aw.
- Work.
You should go tonight.
- I would if I could, but i...
- no.
Kyle has been in Garrett's ear
at every one
of these after-hours functions,
making his case for partner.
I wanna be named partner
because I deserve it,
not because I'm good
at useless trivia.
Yeah, well, if it came down
to useless trivia,
I'd be ceo by now.
Four wins in a row?
- See, you don't need my help.
- Maybe not.
I wouldn't mind the company.
And Betty steals my pretzels.
That promotion should be yours.
You do deserve it.
Don't let Kyle sweet talk it
out from under you.
Thanks, Russell.
Appreciate that.
And you get a chance to make a
good impression at the retreat.
That...
Jake, sweetie?
He's in his room.
Did you get my crab rangoon?
You didn't say
you wanted crab rangoon.
You're my sister,
you're supposed to know
my order by heart.
- Bottom of the bag.
- Bless you.
Hey, go easy on him.
Jake?
Honey, don't you think
that's a little loud?
Honey!
- What happened?
- Nothing.
Jake, you promised me.
No more fights, remember?
This happen before
or after school?
After.
So I won't be getting a message
from the principal?
No. The message is from coach.
I'm sorry I couldn't make it
to your game today.
It's fine. We lost anyways.
This is the third fight
this semester.
Is he still seeing
the school counselor?
Yeah. Twice a week.
You know,
I just was on the phone with her
and she was telling me
about all the wonderful progress
he was making.
You think
she was over-selling it?
He's got a black eye, Lori.
He's had a rough road.
It's gonna take some time.
Yeah.
I know.
I just wish I could do more.
What's that?
It's a invitation.
The firm is hosting
an employee retreat.
A day of wine tasting
at Garrett's house.
- Sounds fun.
- Yeah.
I should really go.
But?
Well, it says
"spouses and significant others
encouraged."
I'd be the only one there
without a date.
And, you know,
I just really don't wanna deal
with all the sympathetic looks,
you know?
Yeah, sympathy is awful.
You know what I mean.
I mean, I already feel like
people walk on eggshells
whenever they're around me
because of...
You know,
I just would rather not go.
Why don't you ask
that cute coworker of yours out?
- You know, Mr. Trivia.
- Russell?
No.
Why not?
Because he'd get the wrong idea
for one.
Why can't it be the right idea?
Lori, I just, you know,
I just don't feel like dating
right now,
especially someone I work with.
It's just...
Di...
It's been two years.
Yeah, I'm just not ready.
I have an idea.
Now, don't say no right away.
The companionship collective?
It's like a dating service.
And they pair you up
with activity partners.
So you want me to rent a date?
You said yourself you don't want
anything serious.
- I don't think so.
- Why not?
Look, wouldn't I
just be better off
with, like, a dating app
or something?
These are professionals.
They hang on your arm,
they say all the right things
and then you say goodbye.
It's the perfect solution.
You get the benefit of a date
without all the baggage.
You can't keep avoiding
your coworkers.
They're gonna start
to take it personally.
So you're really gonna go,
right?
I don't know.
You need to stop hiding out
from life.
I'm not hiding.
Are you still taking
those sleeping pills?
No.
I worry about you.
You don't need to worry.
I'm fine. Really.
- Goodnight.
Diane?
Hi.
- If you'll follow me.
- Right. Yes.
- How are you today?
- Very well. How are you?
Very good.
Thank you.
- There are a lot of questions.
- We're very thorough.
Y-You know, I'm just looking
for a plus-one to a work event.
Well, we understand
the pressures
that come along
with social gatherings
and the value
of keeping up appearances.
We strive to provide you with
the best possible experience.
How did you hear
about our services?
My sister.
If you wouldn't mind making a
note of that in the bottom box.
All of this is confidential.
It won't leave my office.
Including my address?
Your companion will meet you
in a public location
and all correspondence
is monitored by our system.
Your safety is our priority.
You'll be taken through
a gallery of our staff.
There will be
a small bio included
that will list likes and skills.
Skills?
For events that require dancing
or horseback riding
or something specific.
So I get to pick my date
out of a catalogue?
Not quite,
you'll rank your choices
and then we'll have to take
a look at the schedule.
Shouldn't take
more than 15 minutes.
You are officially booked
for next Saturday at 1 P.M.
But the event's not until 2:00.
We encourage people to meet
their matches ahead of time
to establish a rapport.
Okay.
Thank you for choosing
the companionship collective.
Thanks.
You look pretty for your date.
It's not a date.
Okay, what do you think?
Pendant or pearls?
Pendant.
Here.
Can I borrow these sometime?
- Just don't steal 'em.
- I won't.
I don't know.
Maybe this is a bad idea.
You always do that.
Doubt your good ideas.
Self-sabotaging behavior.
Please don't attempt
to psychoanalyze me, Lori.
Would you like to join me
on the couch?
How does that make you feel?
My ride's here. Gotta go.
Text me his picture
when you get there.
- Why?
- For safety purposes.
Goodbye, Lori.
- Love you.
- Love you, too.
Miles?
- Diane?
- Hi.
- Nice to meet you.
- You, too.
I, I don't know
what happens next.
How about coffee?
Of course.
I'm serious. I'm really excited
about a wine tasting.
My last date
was at a tractor pull,
and let's just say
I wore the wrong shoes.
I'm talking your ear off.
I'm sorry, it's...
No. I'm sorry. It's not you.
I'm just, a little...
Nervous?
Well, I've never done this
before.
- You know, hire a...
- a companion.
Not that there's anything wrong
with what you do. I...
I know, it's unorthodox.
But I promise you, it's much
more common than you think.
And you're in good company.
So how does this work exactly?
You set the parameters.
And so for the next four hours,
I am whoever you want me to be.
Friend, boyfriend, husband...
No. Nothing like that.
Um, no, I just need someone
by my side for the day,
you know,
to take the pressure off.
Well, there are a lot
of expectations put on people.
Sometimes it's easier
to just play the game.
I suppose we should
get our story straight.
- Our story?
- How we met.
First date.
In case anyone asks...
Yes, um...
Let's see,
we met through friends?
- I asked you out.
- They'd never believe that.
Why not?
That I wouldn't beat you to it.
Thank you. Well,
we should probably get going.
No photos.
I'm sorry.
That was
incredibly rude of me...
No. It's-it's fine. It's just my
job, it requires a low profile.
It's really hard
to be a convincing date
if you're all over social media.
Yes. Of course.
- You ready?
- I think so.
Don't worry.
No, we're in this together.
Okay.
Diane! Diane, hey!
- Hi, Betty.
- I'm so glad you came! Hi.
Hello, I'm Betty.
I work with Diane.
Miles.
Now I see why you've been
holding out on trivia night.
Yes, I have been
a little selfish
when it comes
to Diane's free time.
Do you need help?
Yes, please.
I need to take those
to the kitchen.
You don't mind if I borrow him
for a second, do you?
Not at all, please.
Okay. I'll be in the kitchen.
Yes. Okay, thank you.
Right this way.
- Yeah.
- This way?
- Right in here.
- Okay.
I promise, this is my,
one of my last act.
I won't have more than...
and he said this is all just
basically old...
Russell! Ha-ha.
Hey! You came.
Well, someone told me
I should make more of an effort
to network
outside of the office.
Smart someone.
Someone seems to think so.
Um, I'm glad you're here though.
I was feeling a little awkward
about flying solo.
- So there's...
- Russell!
Have you met Diane's boyfriend?
Miles.
Russell! Yeah, of course.
I recall Diane
mentioning you once or twice.
Can't say the same.
Well, we were just about
to go mingle.
It was nice meeting you.
Nice meeting you.
Wow. Go, Diane.
Yeah, the first beauty pageants,
men, they got the tiaras,
women, women got a...
But it was,
it was full of diamonds.
It was,
it was precious gemstones...
- Hello.
- Hi.
This is quite the spread
you have here.
It looks delicious.
And your home is so lovely.
Truly, it's beautiful.
Well, thank you very much.
But all the credit
goes to my wife.
- I'm glad you're here, Diane.
- I wouldn't miss it.
I guess you've heard
that Mark Henderson is retiring
at the end of the year.
We're looking
to promote from within.
Garrett!
Have you tried the Merlot?
It is not to be missed.
Actually, I'm gonna wait
until all the guests arrive
before sampling.
In that case,
I would suggest you hold off.
Why is that?
Well, you wanna start
with something lighter.
Like the chenin blanc.
The sugars of the Merlot
will linger on your palate.
- And you are?
- Miles. My date.
Looks like
Diane brought a ringer.
The man knows his wine.
My grandfather
owned a small vineyard.
I grew up around it.
Well, in that case,
I'm looking forward
to hearing your take
on our offerings.
- Absolutely. I'd be happy to.
- Garrett Jones.
It's nice to finally put a face
with the name.
Diane speaks very highly of you.
She does?
I spotted my wife
in that corner.
Let me introduce you.
Grace.
Spending that time in the temple
made me realize
that money's not the only wealth
in the world.
And that's when I knew I had
to get out of acquisitions.
Altruistic. Quite a story.
It's interesting.
Sorry, this is, this is Jake.
- I should probably check in.
- Jake?
Her son.
I'm aware. I was only worried
something was wrong.
No, no, it's nothing like that.
Um, excuse me.
Would you like
another glass of wine?
Yes, please.
Hey, thanks, man.
So how'd you do it?
Defrost the ice queen.
You seem so threatened by her.
She's the one
who needs to be worried.
I don't think
that belongs to you.
Yeah, okay.
You don't think
it's a little bit odd
we hadn't heard a thing
about a boyfriend?
She doesn't have
to tell US everything.
Whoof! But that miles
is a absolute dream.
- Whoof.
- Easy.
You should be happy for her.
After everything
she's gone through...
I can't imagine
losing my husband that young.
You're right.
I know I'm right.
I'm always right.
Right, but you won't let anybody
forget it.
- Right.
- Well, you were amazing.
- My coworkers loved you.
- They were really nice.
I can't believe
you didn't tell me
that your grandfather
owned a vineyard.
He didn't.
I was playing the part.
Right. Of course.
Um, well, thank you.
It was honestly my pleasure.
Do I tip you or...
No, no, but the company's
gonna send along a feedback form
in a few days.
Good reviews go a long way
in booking jobs.
Yes. Absolutely.
Um, well,
please consider this
a thank you, then.
Bye, Diane! Bye, miles!
So nice to meet you.
You, too, Betty.
- Bye, Betty.
- Bye.
- Get home safe. Okay.
- I-I will.
My coworkers
are gonna be so upset
to find out
that we've broken up.
Let 'em down easy.
Goodnight.
Hey.
How was it?
It was good.
Was he nice?
- Very. Yeah.
- Cute?
Lori.
That's a yes.
- Hate to say I told you so.
- You love to say that.
Well, seems like
the fake date was a success.
I guess so.
It makes me happy to see you
getting out there, di.
Wouldn't it be nice to meet
someone you could do
things with,
someone you really care about?
Okay, let's not get ahead
of ourselves.
It was one date.
Well, you went out,
you had a good time.
The world didn't end.
- You're so right.
- I know. I'm a genius.
So...
How did you two meet?
Miles.
Um, through my sister.
Been seein' each other long?
Okay, why the sudden interest
in my love life?
Well, I'm just making
polite conversation.
Okay.
Okay. You know what?
I'm a little surprised
he never came up before.
Well... hi.
- Hi, you have a minute?
- Yes. Yes, of course.
I'm hosting a small dinner party
at my house tonight.
- Are you free?
- This evening? Yes.
- Absolutely.
- Wonderful.
And, feel free to invite miles.
It's a social gathering.
Um, you know,
I'm actually not sure
if he is available tonight,
but...
It's a shame.
Told you he really likes miles.
Good morning.
Companionship collective.
Yes, hi,
I was wondering if miles
has any availability
for this evening.
- I know it's short notice.
- -I believe so.
Great! Wonderful.
Please hold
while I check his availability.
Yes. Yes.
Betty asked me
to give this to you.
You going
to the partners' dinner tonight?
I am.
Guess I'll see you there.
Ms. Cooper?
Hello? Yes, I'm here.
I'm sorry. He's booked.
Would you like to schedule
with someone else
for this evening?
No, no. That's okay. Thank you.
Miles?
- Hey.
- I thought that was you.
- Small world.
- How are you?
- Good.
What are you doing here?
Do you have a kid that goes
to this school?
I volunteer for the school's
big brother program.
- Really?
- How are you?
Has your boss come to his senses
and promoted you yet?
Not yet. Um...
No, but he is actually hosting
a dinner tonight
with all of the partners,
and he invited me, so...
Well,
that sounds like a good sign.
Yeah.
You know,
it's, it's funny I ran into you.
Um, I actually tried calling
the company
to see if you were available
tonight,
but they said
you were booked, so...
Yeah, that fell through.
- Really?
- Yeah. I just got the text.
It happens more often
than you think, honestly.
You know, people get cold feet
or their plans change.
So you're free?
Seems so.
Would you wanna go with me?
I-I mean, I don't mean
to put you on the spot,
and please don't feel obligated
to, to say yes...
Diane, I'd love to.
You would?
Yeah.
Well, great, great, um...
Here, actually,
let me just, call...
No, no, no. Well,
we, we can do it off the books.
Isn't that breaking the rules?
Well, technically.
I didn't mean to suggest
that you would be doing it
for free, you know?
I'm not, no. I'll be getting
a meal out of it.
That's very cute.
Okay, looks like
I'll have just enough time
to go home and change.
Yeah, great. Me, too.
If you don't mind,
can I get your number
just in case I'm delayed...
Yeah, of course.
- Hey, sweetie.
- Hi.
- How was practice?
- Good.
- This must be the infamous Jake.
- Yeah.
Hey, I'm miles,
I'm a friend of your mom's.
Hi.
Okay, well,
we are going to get going.
- I'll see you in a bit.
- Yeah.
- Okay?
- Okay.
- How was practice, sweetie?
- Good.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Second date.
This guy must have
really made an impression.
It's not a date.
Then why are you wearing
your favorite perfume?
Because
it's my favorite perfume.
I thought the whole point
of hiring somebody
was to avoid
romantic entanglements.
It was.
You seem entangled.
Look, all of my coworkers think
that we're already involved.
Plus, my boss has made it clear
that he expects
to see him there tonight.
So I'm just keeping up
appearances.
If you say so.
Well, goodnight, Dr. Lori.
Have fun on your not-date.
I'm-I'm so sorry.
- Did I, did I scare you?
- No.
Yes.
Sorry. That was my fault.
I wasn't paying attention.
You look beautiful.
Thank you.
You ready? We can take
a minute if you like.
No. No, no, no. I'm fine.
Okay, we'll...
We need to look convincing,
right?
Right.
- That's a lovely bracelet.
- Thank you.
It was a gift.
And he told me something
that will forever stay with me.
To know others is wisdom.
To know oneself
is enlightenment.
I think we're gonna
go to the bar.
It was nice meeting you.
- How do you do it?
- Do what?
Keep track of all the lies.
I prefer to think of them
as characters.
Do women ask you to be
a lot of different things?
Usually doctors, lawyers.
And if they wanna tick off
mom and dad at Thanksgiving,
I'm in a band.
Do you ever lose yourself
in all of this?
Sometimes.
But not with you.
With you
I feel like I can be myself.
I'm glad.
Excuse me, everyone.
If you'll join me at the table,
dinner is served.
But right now I need you
to be someone else again.
Okay, so I admit,
I spent most of the game
in the sand trap.
Sir, that course is notorious.
Have you ever played
claremont Greens?
Them Greens is smooth
as pool tables.
Ooh. I have not.
I'll set up a tee time. Yeah?
- How about this weekend?
- That's a wonderful idea.
Diane, do you play?
Um, no. But, well,
I take my son to mini golf.
Diane has a mean short game.
Well, what about you, miles?
Do you play?
Do I play?
Yeah, a little.
What's your handicap?
Ten.
"A little," the man says.
Looks like I found my partner.
I feel like we've met before.
We have. The wine tasting.
Before.
I don't think so.
You're sure?
I just have one of those faces.
Yeah.
Yeah. That must be it.
Do you need a ride home?
No. No.
Honestly, you've done
so much for me already.
It's my pleasure, really.
Lovely party. Lovely.
Goodnight.
On second thought,
that'd be great.
- Thank you.
- Well, I'm right over here.
Listen, if you're up for it,
I'd love to show you something.
It's one of my favorite places
in the city.
Thanks again for jumping in
on such short notice.
- You really helped me out.
- It was my pleasure.
I like spending time with you.
Can I ask you something?
Why do you do this?
I mean, work for
the companionship collective.
You know what, I'm sorry,
it's none of my business.
No, it's alright.
I lost my wife.
And I never got to say goodbye.
Truth is, I, I don't know
that I'll ever got over it.
But doing this
just helps me realize
why I should put myself
out there.
You know, I understand.
My husband, Robert,
he, he died...
A little over two years ago.
It was all
so very unexpected and...
- I'm sorry.
- No. It's just...
It's my bracelet,
it's pinched me.
I feel like we're the same
in certain ways.
I know what it's like to have an
idea of what your life will be,
only to have it disappear.
I keep trying to move on.
I keep trying
to put myself out there,
but...
I don't know,
just doesn't seem right.
I know Jennifer would want me
to be happy.
So I try to start there.
I should probably get you home.
Yeah. You know what,
it's late. I...
I always walk a date
to the door.
But this is a fake date,
remember?
Well, fake or not, my mother
raised me to be a gentleman.
You know, for the record,
you don't really have to go
to the golf course this weekend.
Is your handicap really a ten?
No, no. It's an eight.
But I just didn't wanna
show anyone up.
Well...
Goodnight, Diane.
Goodnight.
You're gonna see him again?
Um...
Um, I mean, I don't know.
I don't really have
a, a work function this month.
I don't think so.
You really like him, don't you?
No, I don't. I-I mean...
I don't know.
It's okay to have feelings.
It's just, you know,
you did hire him.
I don't want you to get hurt.
No, I know.
I think it's great that
you're opening up like this.
You know, I think it's a sign.
A sign for what?
That you're ready
to start dating.
I heard you crushed it
at the partner dinner.
- From who?
- -You know...
I don't reveal my sources.
- Come on.
- Okay.
I overheard Garrett
talking to Betty.
Garrett?
What did he say?
He said you crushed it.
God, I hope so.
Let me tell you,
if I got this promotion,
it would change everything.
You know, Jake and I
are just getting by right now.
It would mean more money,
more flexibility...
- You're a shoe-in.
- You think so?
No one works as hard as you.
And, your boyfriend
seemed to be a hit.
Garrett would not shut up
about his golfing prowess.
You know,
he's not really my boyfriend.
What, too soon for labels?
No, I mean, we're not together.
Well, have you ever heard
of this place called
the companionship collective?
Ew! The rent-a-date place?
You make it sound so seedy.
No, I just,
I just didn't wanna go
to this wine tasting alone,
you know?
And now everyone thinks
that we're together
and I just don't wanna
correct anyone.
Please don't,
don't say anything.
No. My lips are sealed.
Thanks, Russell.
Diane?
You know, next time
you could just ask me.
Diane, update me
on the barkley account.
It's right on schedule.
Rumor is, the higher-ups
are getting antsy, sir.
Seems they wanted
their final audit weeks ago.
E-Excuse me.
Rumors from where?
If Diane is feeling
overwhelmed, sir,
I can always take the ball
and run.
This is
an important account, Diane.
You sure you have everything
well in hand?
Yes, I've spoken
to the executive director.
And it's not just the audit,
they also want
additional analysis
on market growth.
But still, I'd rather not leave
them hanging too long.
They won't be.
I've got it under control.
Okay. Russell,
what's happening with pg&n?
Yeah,
they, um, have been looking
to improve their absorption cost
for the next fiscal year,
and, the numbers
are actually looking like
they're gonna line up.
You don't need to worry.
I've got it under control.
- He has a lot of nerve.
- It's fine.
He knows you're more talented,
so he tries to undermine.
Well, he can try,
but I'm determined
to not let him get to me.
- Hi.
It's a bad time?
Um, no, no.
I-I just wasn't expecting...
Sorry, let me try this again.
- Hi.
So I was cleaning out my car
the other day
and found this.
I can't believe I left this.
Y-You know, you didn't have
to drive all this way...
No, I know
how much it means to you.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
So my allergies are acting up.
Yeah, I know what you mean,
I get anywhere near a cat
and my eyes
just turn bright red.
Um, can I trouble you
for a glass of water?
Yeah, of course.
Please, come in.
Thank you.
I played a little in college.
- Until I threw my shoulder out.
- Really?
I had a bunch
of minor league offers, too.
- Wow.
- Yeah.
- From who?
- A bunch of clubs.
Thank you,
I was telling Jake here
that I went to college
on a baseball scholarship.
Yeah. He offered to show me
some pitches. Can he, mom?
Yeah. It's no trouble. Really.
- Sure.
- Yes! Come on.
I've got an extra glove
in the garage.
Or I can follow through.
Good catch.
I think I've read
this same page three times.
It's lost all meaning.
Alright. We need a break.
My eyes are fine.
Well, it's almost noon.
Let's grab lunch.
You know, i-I'd really
rather stay and finish.
- Come on.
- It's okay.
My treat.
Diane, honey!
These just came for you.
- My.
- And here's a card.
I think you've found a keeper.
Gotta hold on to that.
From miles? Your fake date?
He stopped by last night
to drop something off.
It's nothing.
You went on one date, and
he's showing up at your home?
We went out twice.
I guess I didn't realize
it had become real.
It's not.
You don't think
it's strange that he'd reach out
to you after you hired him
to go to one event?
He didn't reach out to me.
I ran into him at Jake's school.
He's part of the, um,
big brother program there.
And you believe that?
Well, why wouldn't
I believe him?
Because he lies for a living!
Russell, that's not fair.
What?
Nothing.
Well, you obviously wanna say
something.
I just want you to be careful.
- Don't worry. I will be.
- Okay.
Miles?
- Hi. Diane, hey.
- Hi. Hi.
What are you doing here?
Are you...
You have
a big brother event today?
No.
Actually, Jake asked me
to come watch his practice.
I hope that's okay.
I should have asked you first.
- I wasn't thinking...
- mom! Mom!
I struck out three guys
with my slider.
- You did?
- Yeah. Did you see?
- Honey, that's amazing.
- You're a natural, buddy.
- You think?
- Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
Well, I think this calls
for a celebration?
- You want some hot dog?
- Yes!
- Yes?
- Can you come?
Um, you know, honey, I'm sure
miles has things he has to do.
Miss out on the celebration?
No. Yeah,
I can absolutely come. Yeah.
Yes!
- All right, um, sure. Yeah. No.
- Sure.
That still works.
- It's amazing, sweetie.
- Yeah.
I used to do like Sauerkraut.
- Sauerkraut. Relish.
- I didn't know...
- I like both...
- Mustard, ketchup, a hot dog.
- Yeah.
- Mustard, ketchup and a hot dog.
- And a bun, obviously.
It's the office,
I-I gotta take this.
- All right, we'll order.
- It'll just take a minute.
- It's on me. What do you want?
- Whatever you get.
- You got it.
- Hello?
Forrestor, Carlisle and Hobbes.
Hi, Betty. Um, yes.
I just got a message
saying it was urgent.
Is, Garrett trying to reach me?
Mr. Garrett
already left for the day.
It was Kyle.
I'll put you through.
Diane, thanks for getting back
to me so quickly.
What's this about?
You know, for the longest time
I-I had trouble placing him.
- Excuse me?
- - Miles.
My sister-in-law, she brought
him to a wedding last summer.
Although, he introduced himself
as Benjamin.
- I think you're mistaken.
- No. No.
She was very open about using
the companionship collective.
She didn't feel the need to
fool anyone with half-truths.
I wasn't trying to fool anyone.
But you did.
I'm sure Garrett will be
very interested to hear
you've been
actively deceiving him.
Kyle, please don't say anything.
You're asking me to lie, Diane?
No, I'm asking you
to be the better person.
I don't believe
that's in my best interest.
Wait, Kyle...
I do enjoy her company.
I hope you like spicy mustard.
Is everything okay?
That was Kyle.
Hey, buddy, can you go
grab US come napkins?
Yeah.
He knows who you are.
He's planning to use it
against me.
- He threatened you?
- Well...
He's gonna go to my boss.
I'll lose everything
I worked so hard for.
- Hey, it'll be okay.
- How can you say that?
I'm sorry,
I have to go deal with this...
- Let me help.
- No. Really.
There's nothing you can do.
Sweetie, let's go.
- Don't forget to wash up. Okay?
- I won't.
Hey, mom, thanks for inviting
miles for my practice today.
He really helped my pitch.
- You didn't invite him?
- No.
Morning.
- Hey, Betty.
- Hey.
Um, is Garrett in?
Yeah, in his office.
He was looking for you earlier.
Okay. Thanks.
Good luck.
Sir.
You wanted to see me?
Yeah. Come on in. Have a seat.
So I've been hoping to have
a little chat, you and I.
Have you given much thought
to your future?
- My future?
- Here at the company.
- Did you talk to Kyle?
- No.
I thought
I would speak to you first.
I've been giving this
a lot of thought,
and I think you would be
an ideal candidate for partner.
Partner?
I have been very impressed
with your work around here.
You've become invaluable
in a very short time
and I think
that you've earned it.
Thank you very much.
I-I don't even know what to say.
Well, thank you is a good start.
- Thank you again.
- All right.
Now get out of here
and do some work.
Yes.
Miles, hi.
Hey.
Just calling to check in.
You were just pretty upset
yesterday when you left.
I-Is everything okay?
Yes. Thank you.
I-I appreciate that.
Actually, I got the promotion.
I guess
Kyle didn't say anything.
That's great, Diane.
We should celebrate.
Um, you know, a-actually,
I don't think
that's a good idea.
I think we owe it to ourselves
to see where this could go,
right?
Take a chance with me, Diane.
Tsk. Okay. When?
You get lunch at 12:00, right?
Meet me at the park.
- Front entrance?
- -I'll see you there.
Hey.
Gotta make this quick, buddy.
I have a date.
- Was that miles?
- Yeah, it was.
I was talking with Betty.
Her son's a grade above Jake.
She said miles isn't a part
of the big brother program.
- I don't understand.
- He's not being honest with you.
I'm sure
there's an innocent explanation.
I'll ask him when I see him.
I know it's not my place
to say anything,
but I think you should stay away
from this guy.
You're right.
It isn't your place.
So I'm just a little confused.
Betty told me that you aren't
part of the big brother program
at school,
she said that there's no miles.
I have to tell you something,
and it's...
I don't know how you're gonna
take this, but,
the agency insists
we use false names.
False names?
So you're not a miles
or a Benjamin.
No.
That's why Betty was confused
because she didn't know
your real name.
I'm sorry for the deception.
The, but the agency
just has really strict policies
on what we share with clients.
Clients?
I thought
we were becoming friends. I...
Are you still
just playing a part with me?
No. Not anymore.
I-I'm sorry. I-I don't know
what I was thinking.
No, I should have, I should have
told you on our second date.
That-that's when I knew there
was something real between US.
I'm Peter. Peter dwyer.
You see, it's my real name.
Please stay.
What are you looking for?
Ideally, a fourth for golf.
Gotcha.
I guess
that when it comes to dating,
I'm a little out of practice.
Well, you went through
a traumatic event.
It takes time.
It must have been very hard.
It was.
It still is. I...
You know, I don't even sleep in
the same bedroom since he died.
I sleep in the guest bedroom.
I haven't told anyone that.
I'm glad you trust me.
My wife...
She had been working late
all week.
It was a big project.
She loved her job.
She should have called me,
but she didn't.
And she wrapped her car
around a tree going 50.
She died instantly.
I know that we got off
to a rocky start,
but I want you to know that
I've been more real with you
than anyone since my wife died.
And I've been wanting to share
myself with you for a while now.
Thank you for hearing me.
I like being with you.
You make me happy.
And I just haven't had that
for a long time.
- Russell, what...
- he's not who you think he is.
- Who?
- Your companion.
It's all been one big lie.
His name isn't even miles.
When I tried to hire him,
they told me his name was Greg.
- When you tried to hire him?
- I was worried about you.
That gives you no right
to insert yourself like this.
And his name isn't even Greg
or miles.
It's Peter dwyer, actually.
- He told you?
- Yes.
It's agency policy
to use fake names.
Okay, but he let you think
he was a completely different
person for weeks.
- And you're just okay with that?
- Well, at first, of course not.
But now that he's told me
the truth...
If he's lying about his name,
what else is he lying about?
Hey, mom?
Can I, um, talk to you
about dad?
Of course, honey. What is it?
Um, so we have, like,
this presentation at-at school
and, we, like, have to
talk about someone
that we look up to.
And I wanna talk about dad.
Honey, I think
that's really lovely.
- When is it due?
- Not until next week.
But when you're ready,
we can talk about it, okay?
That's your school bus.
- You got everything?
- Yeah.
- I'll see you later.
- Okay.
Have a good day, sweetie.
- Bye.
- Hello?
- - Hey!
I had a really great time
the other day.
I'm really glad that I was able
to open up to you like that.
I just haven't been able
to do that with anyone else.
And I was hoping that you would
let me take you out again.
I don't,
I don't know, miles. I...
Did I do something?
No, no. I just, I...
The timing's wrong.
What does that mean?
I think you of all people
would understand.
Come on, please, just...
Don't give up on this.
Look, I, I thought I was ready,
but I'm-I'm just, I'm not.
- Diane...
- I'm sorry.
Just let me...
Lis...
God!
Knock, knock.
It's an apology.
I had no right
to talk about your love life.
But?
No but. I'm sorry.
Thank you.
You know, just so you know,
I ended it.
Really?
What kind of relationship
starts on a lie?
My grandparents
lied to each other for years.
- Like your tie.
- Thank you.
That's the truth.
Hey.
Miles.
What are you doing here?
You're not answering
my phone calls.
Right. I thought
I made myself clear.
I thought you felt the same way
as me.
Look, so did I, but I...
I'm sorry. It's just...
Hey, come on.
We'll just, we'll go inside.
- We'll talk about this.
- No, please.
Just... I can't.
So what,
you're just gonna end it?
Because I thought
we were being honest
with each other,
I was connecting with Jake...
Hey! Leave Jake out of this.
- Okay?
- No, I'm sorry. Hey.
Listen,
I told you everything about me.
No, I actually don't know
who you are.
- What else do you want from me?
- Miles, stop.
- Diane!
Stop!
Is everything okay?
What was that?
Let's just go inside, Lori.
Okay, it doesn't look
like he took anything, so...
Do you really think
he was inside?
I don't know, but I never leave
that front door open.
- Could it have been Jake?
- No, no.
He's spending the night
at a friend's house.
How much do you know
about this guy, anyway?
Well, at this point,
I have no idea.
All right.
Let's find out exactly
who we're dealing with.
Let's see who you really are,
Peter dwyer.
That's apparently a common name.
He said his wife's name
was Jennifer
and that she died
in a-a car accident.
Bingo. Okay.
"Couple involved in car
accident. Husband survives.
Suspicious circumstances
surrounding the accident."
He-he said
she was driving home alone.
Do you want me
to stay here tonight?
No, no. I'm-I'm okay.
I don't think
you should be alone tonight.
Let's go to dinner.
Okay.
What are the police doing here?
They're asking questions
about Kyle.
Is he okay?
He's been missing
for a few days.
His girlfriend filed
a police report this morning.
He came to my house yesterday.
What?
When I told him I didn't wanna
see him anymore,
he didn't take it well.
Diane.
He was there when Kyle called.
He knew Kyle threatened me.
Do you really think he's capable
of hurting someone?
No.
I-I don't know.
Everything I thought
I knew about this person
turned out to be a lie.
I mean...
Who did I let into my life?
Maybe it's time we take this
to the police.
And say what, the man I hired
to be someone else
turned out to be someone else?
If you think he possibly
had anything to do
with Kyle's disappearance,
we have to, don't we?
I'm gonna be late.
I have to pick up Jake.
- Hey, buddy.
- Hey.
Your mom asked me
to come pick you up today.
Um, she didn't mention it.
It probably slipped her mind.
Doesn't sound like her.
Well, you know
how busy she's been.
You hungry?
You wanna get some hot dogs?
- Come on.
- All right.
All right.
I think it'd be good if they put
cheese in the hot dog...
Got that fly ball.
- Betty, hey.
- Hey.
Hey, h-have you seen Jake?
Is he still here? Wh...
No. He already left.
- With who?
- With miles.
You didn't know?
I-I'm sorry, Betty. I-I...
Diane!
Come on.
Of course,
I spoke to the police.
They told me to just stay home
and wait for them to contact me,
but I don't know
how I'm supposed to stand...
- Diane?
- Let me call you back.
Why? Wait.
Jake.
Sweetie.
- Sorry, it slipped.
- God.
You're here.
- Yeah?
- Honey.
What were you thinking
taking a ride from miles?
He said that you told him
to pick me up.
What's the matter?
I thought you liked him.
Honey,
that has nothing to do with it.
Why are you freaking out
about this?
Honey, I need you to promise me
that you will never go anywhere
with anyone
unless I give you permission.
- Okay?
- Okay.
- I mean it.
Sorry, sweetie.
I'm just worried about you.
Did miles say anything to you?
Like what?
I don't know.
Anything strange?
You're the only one
being strange right now, mom.
Miles is really cool.
Yes. I am very relieved.
Thank you, officer.
- Danny's here.
- Have everything you need?
- Yeah.
- Yeah? Pajamas? Toothbrush?
- Mom, I gotta go.
- Listen, just...
I know things have been hard.
I just want you to know
that I'm here for you.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Whenever you need.
- I love you.
- Love you, too.
- All right.
- Okay.
- Bye, sweetie.
- Okay, bye.
Hey, Jake.
Lori.
Yes, he's fine.
He's fine. My god.
What about a restraining order?
I've already filed a complaint
with the police.
I mean, aside from picking
my son up from school,
he hasn't really done anything.
He lied about who he is.
He threatened you.
He lied about how his wife died.
Yeah, but we don't have
any evidence.
He's dangerous.
It's escalating behavior.
At the very least, call
the companionship collective.
Lodge a complaint.
Let them know
what's been going on.
You're right.
Hello?
Hi, yes.
This is Diane Cooper.
Um, I've been seeing
one of your companions, miles,
and, I need to speak
to your supervisor
about him right away.
Are you sure you don't want me
to stay,
especially with Jake being gone?
- No, really, I'm fine.
- I can cancel my study group.
- They'll understand.
- Absolutely not.
I'll see you at brunch tomorrow.
Okay?
Okay.
Goodnight, sis.
Goodnight.
Robert?
I'm right here.
I dreamt you went away.
I would never leave you.
No, no, we don't have
to fight it any longer.
What are you doing here?
I wanted it to be a surprise.
I know you've been scared
of moving on.
That's why
we couldn't be together.
I gave you a fresh start,
you don't have
to be trapped by the past
anymore, Diane.
- Please, just let me go. Please.
- It's me.
It's okay, it's okay. It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
You did all this for me?
For US.
Not just that. You...
God. Kyle...
He threatened you.
So you took care of it for me.
I did.
Okay.
You're right.
I thought
I wasn't ready to move on,
but I...
You deserve some honesty.
Okay.
So here it is.
Sometimes I hate him...
My husband...
For leaving me behind.
He said it was forever,
and here I am, alone.
You're not alone.
You're not.
Did you feel that way
with your wife?
No.
Okay.
I guess you're a better person
than I am.
You really loved her.
I did.
Did she even appreciate you?
Did she even know
how lucky she was
to have you
and all of your devotion?
Did she lie to you, Peter?
Don't call me that.
Did she break promises
with you, Peter?
She said she loved me...
But she was betraying me.
And when I found out,
I had to do something about it.
So you confronted her.
Didn't even deny it.
I told her we could work through
it, but she just... laughed.
She was gonna walk out on me,
on our life.
I couldn't let that happen.
I understand.
We let all these people in
just so they can disappoint US.
I know why you did it...
Why you killed her.
I had to.
It will be different with US.
Yes, it will.
Wait, wait.
Let me just freshen up.
I just, I want this moment
to be perfect.
Why don't you find
something for US to listen to?
Of course.
Is everything okay in there?
Um, yeah.
You know, I just remembered
that my, um, sister's
coming over for breakfast today
and I...
I...
Can't wait to meet her.
I just don't want her
to interrupt US.
We need to start building trust
again, Diane.
Can we do that?
Of course.
I'm so glad
you've come into my life.
Everything is wonderful now
since I've met you.
Stop! Get off me, get off me!
- I thought you loved me!
- Get off me, you psychopath!
- Lori!
- What?
- What happened?
- I-I... miles.
He-he broke in last night.
I-I just...
I-I just knocked him out, I...
- Call 9-1-1.
- Okay.
I'm gonna go check.
Okay, Lori, wait.
9-1-1. What's your emergency?
There's been a break-in.
Please hurry.
69-22 singer street.
My god.
You okay?
Yeah. Thanks.
- Hi.
- -Hey.
Russell.
What did he say? Did they...
- Did they find him?
- No. Not yet.
They will.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
I'm really glad you came.
I'm glad you called.
Yeah.
It's gonna be all right.