(static)
(ambient string music)
(electronic beeping)
(inhales deeply)
Um, hello.
I'm all fine.
Okay, Oliver, how are you
feeling now?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
- You good?
- Yeah.
- Doing well?
I need you to tell me your
full name and date of birth.
Oliver Joseph Delaney,
30th of first, 1997.
You always have to have
all these catheters
and enemas and...
- All that stuff.
- Yeah.
I'm just gonna
give you a bit of this.
[Olly] Okay.
[Nurse] Just gonna
settle you a bit.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
Should I be counting?
[Nurse] Not yet, no.
But I will let you know.
- Okay, sorry.
[Woman] What have you
had for your first outing
morning tea?
[Woman] Sugar?
A smarties cookie, a strawberry
milkshake, and a picnic.
[Woman] A picnic,
a smarties cookie
and a strawberry milkshake,
oh, that's a good look.
I'm just going to give you
some oxygen.
I just want you to breathe
normally, okay?
I tried to sit up today
but that hurt a lot and
I've got a little
button around here
that injects morphine into me.
[Woman] Yeah, so if it hurts
a lot, you can give yourself.
So I'm attaching your drip
for you, Oliver and I'm
gonna start that drip now,
so you should feel it
soon, so if you wanna start
your count from 10, I
reckon now is a good time.
Okay, yeah, um.
10.
Nine.
Eight.
Seven.
Six.
(ambient electronic music)
(muffled speaking)
(laughing)
Woo, woo, woo!
(chuckles)
(laughing)
(muffled speaking)
[Britney] Oh my gosh.
[Olly] Oh my gosh.
(laughing)
[Nat] How about I
just throw it at you all
and you all open your mouths?
Don't, my makeup!
(muffled laughing)
Do it to the boys, do it to the
boys.
("The Prelude To" by Lawrence
English)
Did you just get kicked in the
dick?
(Luke laughs)
Did you just get kicked in the
dick?
(muffled speaking)
Vagina, vag bash, that's a
vag bash, that's a hate crime.
(muffled, distorted vocalizing)
(electronic beeping)
Just when I thought
you were tired.
(lips smacking)
- Mm, very tired.
Oh, hi, darling.
- 'Morning.
- How are you?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- Yeah?
You've got a big
pimple on your back.
(chuckles) Yeah.
Is that from drinking
too much alcohol?
(Olly laughs)
It does, it makes it
so where you get pimples
in that whole area--
Okay, okay!
All right.
How you feeling?
[Olly] Yeah, I'm fine.
- You alright?
- Yeah.
[Mum] Good night?
Yeah, it was great.
Big night?
[Mum] It looks like it.
[Mark] Do you want some
breakfast, man?
[Mum] You should have
something to eat, sweetheart.
I'm fine, I'm just gonna,
I'm just feeling a bit sick--
Why don't you take your
vitamins and have some water
and have something to eat
and you'll feel a bit better.
[Olly] I just woke up.
I know you just woke up.
Hey darl, there's this article
in here
about transplants coming to
Australia that Mark found.
You don't want to read it?
- No, I'm-
- It's just--
Mum, I'm okay, please.
- Have a read, man.
- You should read because,
yeah, it's quite, I would've
thrown it out and he just--
[Olly] Her boyfriend is
actually like a man-child.
Aw that's unfortunate.
Yeah, it's really gross,
it's like where the fuck
do you find them, like the--
- Hey, Luke, buddy!
- How you doing, man?
- Oh, hey, Olly.
Didn't see you there.
- Hey.
- Hey, catch, mate.
(chuckles) How you been, man,
did you go to Gabby's party
on the weekend?
- Yeah, what did you do?
Yeah, Sonny and I, we, uh,
there he is,
we were hanging out at the
Macca's car park, hanging out
with
these older girls.
- (chuckles) Fuck, man.
(chuckles) All right,
we gonna catch up soon.
All right mate?
- Yeah.
[Brandon] All right,
see ya, buddy.
(Luke mumbles)
(Olly laughs)
(laughs)
- Hey!
- How ya going?
- Good, thanks.
- You all right?
- Yeah (laughs).
What are you up to?
(Nat mumbles)
[Olly] What are you doing?
Uh, I think we're just
gonna go to the movies.
Oh, okay,
are you guys like dating?
[Luke] Mm.
Yeah.
(Luke and Nat giggling)
Kinda.
That's awesome.
- Thanks, man.
- That's really,
really cool, guys.
Well.
- Yeah, well.
See ya.
[Nat] See you.
- See ya babe.
Aw.
(Olly laughs)
- See ya.
- See ya, bro.
(Olly chuckles)
Make sure you
use protection, guys.
[Luke] Go away.
- Be safe!
- [Luke] Go away.
[Nat] Ow!
[Luke] Really?
(Olly chuckles)
(gentle electronic music)
[Mum] Darling.
- Hey.
- How are you?
[Olly] Yeah, good,
how are you?
Yes, good, busy day,
how was school?
It was fine (sighs heavily).
Have you been waiting long?
What?
(laughs)
Were there many
people before you?
[Olly] Yeah.
Always running late,
it's really annoying.
Like someone else I know.
Mmm.
(Oliver chuckles)
(sighs) You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Don't.
- Why?
Why can't I touch this?
- Stop it.
Seriously.
Can I just listen to my
music if that's cool?
Is it cool if I just
listen to my music?
Darling, you need
to speak more clearly.
(chuckles) You are so--
Do you learn it at school?
Enunciation?
- Clearly no.
- Sorry.
(Olly scoffs)
No, okay.
(sighs) I love it here.
(both chuckle)
- Oliver Delaney?
- Yes!
[Woman] You can go through.
If you can see here, your
right hip is severely damaged.
It's really a miracle
you can walk at all.
I'm not sure how you manage it,
but if you keep walking this
same way,
it will deteriorate to the
point where you'll need
a hip replacement.
How long before that
needs to happen?
Depends how he walks, his
bones are already compromised
because of the osteoporosis.
Maybe 10 years.
I would recommend getting
him into surgery now though
to release and lengthen
some of the ligaments
to help improve his walk.
Ah (chuckles) if you wanna
get him into surgery now,
why not do the hip
replacement now?
No point in replacing tires
if they're not worn out yet.
How do you know
if they're worn out?
Uh, you won't be
able to walk anymore.
You won't be able to put
weight on your right leg.
Plus, you'd feel it.
The pain, I mean.
And you're saying
this ligament operation
will prevent that?
[Doctor] Yes, hopefully.
How long will he
be in hospital for?
[Doctor] Two to three weeks,
but then in a wheelchair
for about three
months after that,
depending on how
quick he recovers.
Well, he usually recovers
pretty quickly, so.
Don't you?
Mm-hmm.
How do you feel?
I'm fine, can we just go?
Sorry about that, darling.
Why, did you do it,
did you fuck up my hip?
Was it you all along?
No, I haven't done anything,
I haven't done anything
about your rehab.
What are you talking
about, you took me here?
You do heaps--
We haven't done anything
for about a month.
(sighs heavily) And I've
been so busy and I'm just--
It's not your fault,
none of this shit
makes a fucking difference,
we'll just have the operation
and it'll sort it out, okay?
We don't, fucking rehab shit,
like me like doing squats
doesn't do diddly-squat, okay?
So like, fucking hell,
it's fine Mum, seriously.
Let's just go.
So what you're saying is
squats don't do diddly-squat?
That's exactly what I
just said, that's verbatim.
(chuckles)
Seriously Mum, it's fine,
it's not your fault.
It's life.
Okay, well, look, you go
in hospital on Monday, right?
[Olly] Yeah.
So it's Saturday
night, I think we'll have
all your friends over and
we'll have a big party.
Yeah?
- I can't believe I said that.
- Can we have alcohol?
(chuckles)
Can I have alcohol?
You can have two drinks.
Two drink, can people bring
alcohol?
Fuck, just don't tell me
about it, don't tell me.
(laughs) I won't tell
you, my lips are sealed.
I won't tell you a thing.
Okay?
- Thank you.
- All right, love you.
- Thank you, Mum.
Oh, I hate that place.
(laughs) I love it,
it's my favourite place.
It's my Disneyland.
(music blaring)
(friends laughing)
- Olly!
- What?
Mum, I'm fine,
I'm fine, I'm fine!
- Come and have water!
- I don't need any water!
Yes you do!
(laughs)
Why aren't you guys
dancing, it's a party.
(Nat mumbles)
All right.
Well, hello.
- Hey.
- Hi!
Ow!
Oh my God, just in
time, the party's so good!
The party's so good, isn't
it guys, it's the best party.
It's better than last week.
- You're fucked!
- No, I'm not.
I'm having fun.
Who's that?
Is that your dad?
No.
It's my mum's boyfriend.
[Britney] He's a fucking babe.
Come dance with me,
come dance with me, babe.
Come dance with me!
- You have fun.
- Come dance with me!
No, oh my God, get off me!
(music blaring)
(students laughing)
Excuse me, I'm really
sorry, please, sorry.
(Olly breathing heavily)
(door knocking)
I'm coming!
[Mum] Olly, darling, you okay?
- Go away!
- I'm coming in.
No, go away, what the
fuck, get out, what the--
It's all right,
it's all right.
[Olly] Ow, what the fuck
are you doing, go away!
Get outta here!
I'm just--
[Olly] No, fuck,
please go away.
- It's okay.
- Please go.
It's okay, it's okay.
- Go away!
- Don't hit me.
It's all right, I just--
- Please go away!
Please go away.
I'm not going away, Olly.
[Olly] Fuck.
All right, darling,
I'm going to going away.
Go away!
Don't--
- Get away.
- Okay.
Hit me, fine.
[Mum] What happened,
did you get a bit drunk?
What do you think happened,
what do you think happened?
[Mum] Why'd you do that?
Why'd I pee myself,
'cause I felt like it.
I really wanted to pee myself.
- Why'd you drink so much?
Fuck off, you fucking
hypocrite.
Why?
- You fucking hypocrite.
- Why am I a hypocrite?
- Pot kettle black shit.
Fuck you, get out, get
out, get out, get out!
Get the fuck out, get
the fuck out right now!
(Mum chuckles)
- Now!
- All right, darling.
I'm gonna go get
some new pants--
[Olly] Don't get me new pants!
A glass of water
and a can of Coke--
[Olly] There's
water right here!
And you're going
to calm the fuck down!
- Ooh.
- Okay?
And furthermore, all of
your friends are going home.
[Olly] They're not going home!
It's one o'clock in the
morning, they're going home!
This is my house,
the party is over!
If you sent them home,
I'm actually, listen to me.
I'm gonna fucking kill
you if you send them home.
If you actually send them
home I'm not even joking.
You're not leaving, if you send
them home,
I'm actually gonna kill
you, you promise me
you're not gonna send them home.
[Mum] Okay,
here's what we don't do.
We don't threaten
to kill each other.
Fucking bitch.
That's what you are.
Fuck!
Ow.
It's not that bad.
[Olly] How would you
know, can you please stop?
Oh, fine, okay, look,
I've gotta go back to work,
so I'm gonna see you later.
- Mm-hmm.
- Drink lots of water, okay?
(lips smacking)
Bye.
[Olly] Bye.
(breathing heavily)
(metal rattling)
(Olly grunting)
[Nurse] Are we ready,
one, two, three.
Ow!
[Nurse] Okay, shh, shh,
shh, there's people sleeping.
[Olly] Can you do it just
a little bit, can you please
just do it a little
bit gentler, please?
Almost done.
Okay, just go over this side.
(giggling)
- Hey man.
- (chuckles) Hey.
- Hey babe.
- Hi.
We got you these.
Everyone drew on them.
I drew a really, I can't--
You drew a rhubarb.
(laughs)
- [Olly] A rhubarb?
I thought it was appropriate.
'Cause, yeah,
'cause you're sweet.
- Are rhubarbs sweet?
- And I'm pretty sure
it says that rhubarbs are the
most intelligent vegetable.
Cool, why are
they big fat undies?
'Cause you've
got a big fat bum.
[Olly] (laughs)
But why undies anyway?
'Cause you're not wearing
any underwear (chuckles).
Oh, cool, so now I've got
my undies for my fat ass.
Yeah, how you feeling?
I'm good.
- You feeling, yeah?
- Yeah.
- How's your leg?
- How's that, boop.
(chuckles)
(laughing)
Thanks so much for this, guys.
Fat baby.
(laughing)
[Olly] Fat baby?
- I do.
- Fat baby?
(laughing)
What?
It's what Gemma said.
[Olly] Fat baby, can I see?
- You had to be there.
- I was at Gemma's.
[Olly] Can I see?
Jo just drew a fat baby.
He's always
doing shit like that.
- Jo is like--
- Oh my God.
[Luke] (chuckles)
See I told you.
Um, I drew you guys something.
- That looks so real.
- I know, he's really--
Present!
Oh wow.
Oh my gosh.
Present!
Holy crap!
- That's crazy.
- Got nothing else to do.
- Did you draw these?
- Yeah.
[Nat] Babe, they're awesome.
Wow.
Far out, man.
- You're so good.
- Thanks.
Hey, sorry to be a bitch,
but we're gonna be late
for the movie.
[Luke] Oh shit.
What movie?
We're gonna see-
Knife Wars.
- Knife Wars (chuckles).
I got some DVDs and stuff
if you guys wanted to--
It's not out on DVD.
(laughing)
Um, some of the other,
like, um, who's meeting,
Jo and I think Gabby's
gonna be there too.
- And Gemma.
- Gemma.
- Fucking Gemma.
(friends laughing)
Oh yeah.
- Bye.
- See you babe.
I love you (lips smacking)
I'll come see you soon.
[Olly] Okay.
Boop.
See you babe.
- See you, man.
[Olly] See ya.
("A Prelude To" by
Lawrence English)
(keys clicking)
[Reporter] Finally, after
months of government approvals,
the controversial full-body
transplants
are making their way to
Australia, with trials
to start in the coming weeks.
Pioneered in Germany, the
transplants are for people
suffering from a terminal
illness
or with an untreatable
disability,
a chance at a whole new life.
Ow.
(metal rattling)
(grunts)
Ow.
(breathes heavily)
(body thuds)
Ow.
(groans)
(breathes heavily)
Okay, give me your arm.
- Ready?
- Okay.
On three, so one, two, three.
[Mum] Hi darling.
Hey.
How you feeling?
Yeah, I'm fine.
- Mmm?
- Mm-hmm.
[Mum] Mark's got
you some more DVDs.
Oh.
Hopefully you don't have 'em.
[Olly] Thanks, thanks so much.
[Mum] Have you eaten,
sweetheart?
Yep.
[Mum] Oh, did you (chuckles)
how was it?
Hospital food.
(groans) Yuck (chuckles).
What have you guys been up to?
Oh, we just had a work,
a dinner thing for my work,
so it was a bit (laughs).
You been drinking?
I had a couple little
wines, dinner, so nothing--
I was actually just about
to go to bed guys, actually.
I'm sorry, guys--
- I'm not drunk.
I didn't say you were drunk,
I just said
I was about to go to bed, so.
Is that cool?
I'm tired.
But I haven't
seen you in ages.
I haven't gone anywhere.
Yeah, but darl, I thought
we could spend the night
together and watch
one of those DVDS.
Lovey.
Look, I'm fine, I'm
just, I'm just really tired
and I just want to go to bed.
What?
I'm sorry.
Why are you apologizing, you
haven't done anything wrong.
I'm sorry, it's been
a really fucking hard
couple of weeks, and I know
it's been hard for you too.
I can't imagine, I (sighs
heavily).
I haven't been around--
- Can you just fucking stop?
Okay, I'm sorry, this is
the reason why I don't wanna
fucking see you 'cause
you fucking do this shit.
I just said I'm fine, I'm tired,
I'm really fucking shitty.
I'm grumpy,
please just go, okay?
It's not you, it's got
nothing to do with you.
So please just go.
Can you give us a
minute alone, please?
Thanks, darl.
- Yeah.
I'm just tired.
I'm really fucking tired.
I don't know.
(sighs heavily)
Fucking hell,
it's just been shit.
I know, darl, I know,
but it's nearly finished.
I've just been,
I've been reading up about,
you know that article
and those body
transplants and just,
oh, I've just been
thinking and just
that would just be fucking,
I dunno.
Oh, fucking hell.
Is that something
you wanna do?
Is that like, what?
Is that even possible?
I mean I don't know,
I could look into it.
I don't know, do you want me to?
Yeah.
Thanks, Mum.
- Don't worry.
- I love you.
(ambient electronic music)
Just straighten up your
torso too, if you can.
Yeah, good.
[Olly] Can you help
me get this off, Mum?
[Mum] Sure.
[Olly] Sorry.
[Mum] No, that's okay.
I didn't even know they
did those in Australia.
Yeah, they um, yeah, no,
they've just started doing trials
here, but they've been doing
them in like, the States
and Europe and stuff
for years like,
I mean it's been done before,
it's not dodgy or anything.
So you're gonna have
like a completely new body?
Yeah (chuckles).
How am I gonna recognise you?
You're not,
but I'll tell you it's me.
I'll be like, it's me,
and you'll be like, "Who?"
And I'll be like, me!
And then we'll just
repeat that for eternity.
Aw, sweet,
that's gonna be fun.
(laughs)
It's gonna be so weird, man.
- Yeah.
- That's great.
Thanks.
What are you thinking?
Oh, um, no, just,
(chuckles) it's just wow.
Fuck.
Yeah. I, um,
there's actually something
else I want to talk
to you guys about as well.
(chuckles)
- There's more?
- Yeah (chuckles).
Um, so with the transplants
as well and stuff,
(chuckles) they, um, they
have these cases where...
(chuckles) I don't know,
I'm sorry guys, basically,
it's just that like, what I'm
thinking,
I'm thinking of doing, I'm
not even sure I can do it,
but like, I think maybe I
might have my new body like...
be a woman.
(chuckles)
- Oh my God.
- (chuckles) Yeah.
Um.
Are you, do you think
you're a transvestite?
No, it's not that, I just,
I've just been reading it, I
just thought like, that might
be good, I don't know, it's
fucking stupid, I'm sorry.
That's fucking cool, that's
really cool!
Very, very cool.
- I'm sorry, guys.
- Why are you apologizing?
Look at me.
We love you so much.
Thanks (sighs).
No, no, I mean, you know,
I can look into it if that's,
I mean, if that would...
Yeah, I'll look into it.
(sighs heavily)
Yeah?
[Mum] (sighs) Yeah, darling.
I'm sorry, Mum.
No, don't be sorry,
it's fine, I love you.
[Nat] Do you like girls
or do you like guys?
(chuckles)
Um...
(chuckles) Guys I guess,
I don't know.
I always thought you liked
me, well, that's a shame.
You're so vain.
(laughs)
I wanna do it,
I want the operation.
Please.
(sobs)
Okay.
Okay, okay.
(sighs)
Okay.
(ambient electronic music)
(muffled speaking)
I love you.
(electronic beeping)
(breathing heavily)
[Olly] It didn't work?
It worked.
Do you wanna have a look?
(sighs)
[Olly] I love you.
I love you.
You're beautiful.
(melodic electronic music)
(door knocking)
(muffled speaking)
Come in.
Hi guys.
(laughs)
Sorry, I'm sorry.
No, no, it's okay (giggles).
Come in.
Come in!
(laughs)
Come on.
Can I show you guys some
of the stuff I can do?
[Nat] Yeah (laughs).
I prepared this
one earlier, right.
Look at this, look at my boobs.
These babies.
[Nat] Are they real?
[Olly] Yeah, feel 'em.
You wanna feel?
- No.
[Olly] (laughs) You sure,
are you feeling left out
'cause you don't have bosoms?
(laughs)
(Nat chuckles)
(Luke groans)
Oh, sorry, couldn't
help myself (chuckles).
This is weird.
[Luke] Very fucking weird.
[Nat] So what are
people gonna call you?
[Olly] Uh, I was thinking
Olivia.
I was thinking, I know
it's similar but at least
if you guys stuff up,
you're not gonna, you know,
it's not gonna be too weird,
Olly, Olivia.
Sounds like a nickname, right?
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah.
But do you think that anyone,
you know, is gonna know or?
No, babe (chuckles) you
don't look like Olly at all.
(laughs) That was the
idea but, yeah, that means
please, call me her or she or.
[Luke] Yep, sweet.
- Babe.
- Let's do it.
I'm happy with babe.
That'd be weird.
(Olly laughs)
I can call you babe.
- Okay, okay.
You gotta be
really careful, Olly.
There's a lot of
dickheads out there.
People could freak out, man.
Yeah, okay, um.
Olly, really, like (clears
throat) people can be assholes.
No, totally, yeah, no, I
get it, I actually get it,
like, I really do,
it's awesome, um.
I know it's pretty weird, guys
(chuckles).
[Nat] It's cool.
- It's cool.
- Yeah.
It is pretty cool, right?
But are you happy?
- You like my boobs?
(Nat and Olly laugh)
Awkward turtle.
How weird is it having boobs?
It's pretty good,
they weigh shit though.
(laughs)
Back pain.
Joking, it's fine, they're not
that big.
What the fuck, isn't that
for like sheep or some shit?
(chuckles) Yeah, but like
they do it on humans too.
Like in the States and in
Europe.
Do you not watch the news?
- No.
- Yeah.
So he's just in like
some random's body now?
Yeah, like you know if
someone gave an organ?
Well, someone gave
their whole body.
Fuck, that's gross.
Britney, don't.
It's gross.
- Please don't tell anyone.
- Okay.
Please don't tell a soul.
No, I get it.
Seriously.
I get it!
And please be
nice to him tonight.
He's so fragile at the moment.
I'm always nice.
(chuckles) Stop touching
my hair (chuckles).
Why the fuck are you a girl?
I don't know, I just
wanted to be, I guess.
I wanted to be a fucking
princess.
It doesn't mean I become one.
Brit.
Sorry, it's just so fucking
weird, you're like hot now!
(laughs)
Spoke too soon.
("Set Free" by Grrl Pal)
[Nat] Yeah, it'll explode.
(laughs)
- And then, like.
- I thought you had
to like lick the top.
- Yeah, lick the top.
Mix it up.
[Britney] Like slowly.
And then like from
the balls at the bottom,
all the way up to the top.
- Aw, do you do that?
- Yeah.
- I don't touch the balls.
- I read it in Cleo.
I've never tried it so.
- You should try it!
You haven't done that.
No!
- You have done a BJ!
- Have you done it to Luke?
- Shut up!
- Have you?
Shut up.
Britney.
(laughs)
Is that what happens when
they come in your face?
Yeah, pretty much, well, you'd
be really good at wanking
a guy off then.
(girls talk at once)
But I couldn't really wank.
- Why not?
'Cause my penis
didn't work very well.
[Nat] Oh.
But now I've got a vagina,
so it doesn't matter!
(ambient electronic music)
♪ Do you feel, do you feel ♪
♪ Do you feel set free ♪
[Britney] No, pout,
you have to pout, Olly.
(Olly mumbles)
Olly, put your lips together,
yeah.
(Olly groans)
Oh, sorry.
Britney, be nice.
- I am being nice.
- You're being really violent.
[Britney] It's on your
tooth, it's on your tooth.
(Olly groans)
Open your mouth.
Stop it.
What the fuck are you doing?
(girls speak at same time)
You're so pretty, Britney.
She's pretty but she's a
fucking bitch.
Shut up!
(house music playing)
(girls yelling)
Nat, get me a drink!
(music drowns out voices)
[Olly] Kiss me!
Hey, come here!
Help me out.
He's getting his dick sucked!
(laughing)
They were
sucking Fletcher's dick!
They're so looking at you.
(music drowns out voice)
Britney, I can see you arse.
- Shut up!
- It looks hot!
- I can see your arse!
- I can see your tits.
[Nat] No, you can't.
Hey!
("Broken" by Featurette)
♪ So broken
- Hey!
- Hi!
How are you?
What's your name?
- Olivia.
- That's a pretty name.
Are you new?
- So are you.
(laughing)
I don't know!
I'm Brandon.
Brandon's a very pretty name.
Come here, I wanna
tell you a secret.
[Olly] Okay, what's the
secret?
Olivia, Olivia!
Come to the bathroom with me!
Nah, I'm okay.
- Babe, you're drunk!
- Hey, fuck off.
Come to the bathroom with me.
- You're drunk, go away.
(music drowns out voice)
Do you wanna go somewhere more
private?
I need to go to the bathroom.
I need a bathroom.
Luke!
Hey man.
You took so long to get here.
I can tell, you've
had quite the head start.
I'm sorry, sorry about
that, that would've been
so fucking weird, it's
really weird for me too.
I just wanted to say I'm
sorry, I didn't mean to.
I just--
- It's all right.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Are you sure?
What are you doing?
- What do you mean?
- With Brandon.
I don't know.
'Kay, have you seen Nat?
Um, yeah, she was
here like a minute ago--
I'm gonna go find her.
Okay.
("Memorize" by Featurette)
(music drowns out voice)
♪ The lights and the shadows ♪
[Brandon] Hey!
[Olly] Hey.
- Remember me?
- Yeah.
How are you?
(music drowns out voice)
Are you all right?
[Olly] I'm good.
Come here.
You wanna go and
get a drink of water?
[Olly] Nah.
I think you should
get a drink of water.
[Olly] Okay,
we'll get a drink of water.
(lips smacking)
(Olly breathing heavily)
[Brandon] I'm a drunk guy.
(Olly giggles)
- Is that bad?
[Olly] You're so
fucking drunk.
[Brandon] Do you
wanna suck my cock?
[Olly] Yeah, I wanna
suck your cock.
You wanna suck
my big fat cock?
Yeah, I want your big
fat cock in my mouth.
Oh, shit.
(groans) Are you okay?
(chuckles)
(Olly coughs)
[Olly] Sorry.
[Brandon] It's all right.
(Olly mumbles)
[Olly] Just you're so big.
You're pushing me down so far.
[Brandon] Yeah, sure
(mumbles).
Oh, yeah, oh,
fuck, yeah, yeah, yeah.
(groans)
Oh, shit.
(gagging)
Oh, fuck.
You all right?
[Olly] Yeah, I'm okay, you
okay?
Yeah, I'm good.
[Olly] Did you just...
Should we just have sex?
You wanna have sex?
(sniffs) I don't mind,
whatever you wanna do.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Yeah, okay.
Oh shit.
(Olly moans)
Oh, you're tight.
(moaning)
What the fuck?
Oh shit.
Are you okay?
Yeah, yeah, no it was great,
keep going, it felt good.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah, yeah.
It was good, just keep going.
(lips smacking)
I think we should go back to
the party.
It was good.
Hey, you want me
to suck you off again?
[Brandon] No, I'm all good.
I'm just gonna go
back and get a drink.
(lips smacking)
(Brandon grunts)
(sighs)
Hey.
Morning.
(bright drumming music)
Babe, where the fuck
were you last night?
What time did you leave?
I ended up being pretty late.
But where were you?
I was (giggles) in
one of the bedrooms.
And how the fuck is
that not the first thing
you told us?
(laughs) I lost my V place
(laughs).
[Britney] You fucking dirty
slut.
[Nat] Who with?
Uh, Brandon.
Olly.
What's that supposed to mean?
What?
Brandon's fucking hot.
- Really?
- Fuck, yeah, he's a babe.
How was it?
No, it was great, it was
really good.
It's a big dick (chuckles).
(bright electronic music)
- See ya.
[Olly] So what do you
have on first (mumbles)?
[Luke] I don't know, I
don't wanna talk about school
over the weekends (mumbles).
So...
is everything okay?
[Luke] Yeah, why?
Are you angry with me?
I just don't get it.
[Olly] What?
You've had this, you've had
this operation, it's awesome
but I just don't see why
you gotta fuck it all up.
I mean it's Brandon, do
you know what he'd do
if he found out?
- He's not gonna find out.
- What are you talking about?
How long do you think you
can keep this a secret, Olly?
I'm not gonna not love
my life because I'm afraid
that someone might find out,
like I'm sorry but look,
even if that happens, then
I'll just deal with it then.
[Luke] Whatever.
[Olly] You don't have to
look at me, I'm not a cripple.
[Luke] It's just fucking
stupid.
(Olly chuckles)
[Olly] Why are you so angry at
them?
Are you jealous it wasn't you?
It's just fucked.
Do people know?
Yeah.
How?
I don't know.
- Did Britney tell someone?
- Olly, Olly, it's okay.
No, Britney wouldn't have
told--
[Brandon] Hey faggot!
- Are you fucking serious?
- Get the fuck outta my way.
What the fuck, Brandon?
Your little faggot friend
raped me the other night.
Go fuck yourself, Brandon!
Sex under false pretenses,
that's rape!
Oh, grow a fucking dick!
Yeah, I can have him reported.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Olly, I can have you reported.
What are you gonna do,
you gonna bash a girl?
That is no fucking girl!
Fucking touch him, I
will fucking kill you.
Nat, get the fuck outta my
way.
I'm being a gentleman about
this, get the fuck outta my way!
All right, I'm bored
with this conversation.
Get the fuck outta my way.
- Fuck off, Brandon!
You think this is funny, Olly?
I gotta live with this for
the rest of my fucking life!
[Student] Man.
I have to live with this for
the rest of my fucking life!
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
You sure?
It's gonna be okay, I promise
you.
Promise you it's gonna be okay.
Okay.
I'm not gonna let anyone hurt
you.
[Olly] Okay.
Okay, you're all right.
I love you.
- I love you too.
It's just me.
Sorry.
How you doing?
Um, I'm good.
Cool, just thought I'd
double-check.
Thanks.
I, um, I didn't mean to tell
them.
It just kinda came up in
training.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
You told Brandon?
Yeah.
Okay.
All right, well, if they
give you any more shit,
just tell me and I'll talk to
them.
Okay, thanks.
All right, see ya.
Bye.
I don't know what the fuck's
going on,
like why would he do that?
He must seriously fucking
hate me right now.
Babe, why do you care so much?
What do you, he's my best
friend.
It doesn't sound like it.
Oh, baby, I'm sorry, I
didn't mean it like that.
I just mean like telling
Brandon, that's fucked.
If he's your friend, he
should be your fucking friend.
If he's being a dickhead,
he's not worth your time.
You should just not see him
anymore.
(chuckles) How can I
not just not see him?
(laughs) What are you saying?
Just don't see him.
But he's my best friend, babe.
Oh my god, you're so stupid.
You're choosing to be treated
like shit.
(Britney scoffs)
I'm in love with him.
When the fuck did that happen?
Since always, like forever.
Fuck.
Fucking god.
You can't tell anyone,
okay, especially not Nat.
Babe, I'm not retarded.
[Olly] So what do you
think I should do then?
Fuck me, I don't know then.
It's just like, I don't
know, I feel like I'm being
such a shit friend right
now, it's like I don't care
if he's happy, like I
actually don't give a shit.
Like be unhappy, but be with
me, that's like seriously like,
it's fucked, it's just not
being a good friend, you know?
And it's like I'm lying to him.
You should tell him.
[Olly] Tell him what?
All this shit.
Tell him the truth, tell him
that you're in love with him.
(chuckles) What good would
that do?
If he knew, he might
stop being such a dick.
Well, it's Luke, he'd
probably freak the fuck out.
Or he'd fuck you.
Yeah, don't look at me like
that.
That just wouldn't happen,
okay?
Babe, you're a hot bitch, why
not?
(chuckles) For starters, he's
with Nat!
He's a guy, you're hot.
I guarantee you he wants to
fuck you, it's just biology
and, look, if he likes you more
than her,
it's not your fault (chuckles).
It's Luke, it's fucking
gross how much he loves you.
Like fuck, he could be in
love with you too right now
but he can't do anything
about it because he's stuck
with Nat so instead, he's just
just treating you like shit.
It's fucked but it might be the
case.
You've gotta stop letting
guys treat you like shit.
You call the shots.
Try this on.
♪ Dare, dare, dare, dare, dare
♪ Dare
♪ Come with me, come with me,
come with me, come with me
♪ Dare, come with me, come with
me
♪ Come with me, come with me
♪ Dare, come with me, come with
me
(door bell ringing)
♪ Come with me, come with me
♪ Dare, come with me,
come with me, come with me
♪ Come with me
[Mum] Who's that at the door?
- Hey man.
- Hey.
You didn't ask me if you
could have anyone over.
I didn't know I had to.
You do.
Don't be too late, all right?
Why?
Because it's a school night.
I won't be here for long.
Good.
[Luke] Your mum's intense.
Yeah, she hasn't changed at
all.
Can I get you anything?
It's fine, what'd
you want to talk about?
Uh...
You know that Brandon shit.
Yes.
I just wanna say I'm
sorry about all that.
I didn't, you know,
mean to fuck everything
up and you're right
and should've listened to you.
Should know better and
thanks for looking after me
and stuff, like it was
really awesome what you did.
It's fine.
I just wanting to start
being honest with myself.
So the whole Brandon thing and
like this,
all of this...
Is because of you.
I'm in love with you, Luke.
(inhales deeply)
Hey.
Don't touch me (scoffs).
That's fucked, you're
my best friend, Olly.
Okay, um.
And what did you
think I was going to say
when you told me this?
How did you think it was going
to go out?
(chuckles) All right, I'm gonna
go.
- Yes.
- Hey babe.
- [Olly] Oh my god.
♪ I'm not feeling like another
I'm sorry, I struck.
♪ I'm not ever gonna be
♪ (music drowns out voice) on
the inside
♪ As if anyone will see
- How are you?
- Hey.
♪ Now I wish like a day
- You look like you're ready
for a good time.
♪ Now part of the scene
♪ You're not ever gonna get with
anybody
♪ So you better come home with
me
(music drowns out voices)
♪ Is not where I wanna be
(music drowns out voice)
♪ But it doesn't sound good to
me
♪ While pitching their attention
♪ They're never gonna see
♪ Not (music drowns out voice)
impossible
♪ So baby come home with me
♪ Whoa
(Olly grunts)
[Olly] Do you know where my
phone is?
[Man] No.
Where are my shoes?
- I haven't seen 'em.
- Where you put them?
No, I carried you home
last night, remember?
You were barefoot (chuckles).
Fucking ride on my shoulders.
Where are my shoes then?
You're a little freak, you
know that?
You should come back to bed.
No, I gotta go.
Bye.
Hey!
Oh, fucking bitch.
(muffled singing)
♪ Say you'll come home with me
♪ Whoa
Where have you been?
I've been calling you all night,
I almost called the police.
I'm sorry, I lost my phone.
How, where?
Where have you been?
Just, can you just leave me
alone--
[Mum] What did you do?
Why do you care?
(scoffs)
Get inside and go to bed.
Come on, now!
Get inside, Olly!
(doors slamming)
(Olly sighs)
(gagging)
[Mark] Oh Jesus Christ.
[Olly] I'm sorry, I'm fine,
I'm fine, I'm fine, I'm fine.
- Please, come on--
- Wait, I'm fine.
(door knocking)
[Mark] Hey, Olly, you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Thank you.
No worries.
I poured you some water,
in case you needed it.
I'm just gonna go and clean the
bathroom
so call out if you need
anything.
So sorry.
(chuckles) It's okay.
What are you doing here?
Lunch break.
Go and check on your mum.
Mark?
Can I please have a hug?
Sure.
Hey.
You okay?
You're very quiet.
Sorry.
Can't believe you went to
school today (chuckles).
You're a fucking tank.
Mm, felt fine.
I threw up all over the
bathroom.
(both chuckle)
It was a good night.
I got way too fucked.
[Britney] But did you have
fun?
Not really (sighs).
Okay.
What's up?
(chuckles) Nothing.
Come on, baby, you can tell
me.
You'll promise not to tell
anyone?
Totally.
- I'm serious.
- Okay.
Of course, babe.
Um,you know my mom's
boyfriend?
(chuckles) Yeah, the babe.
We had sex this morning.
Jesus.
Yeah.
Fuck, babe.
That's fucked.
Thanks (chuckles).
I'm not gonna lie to you, it's
fucked.
Whatever, I should go anyway.
(chuckles)
What?
You are such a shit fucking
friend.
Well, you're pathetic,
you're a fucking slut.
That's worse.
Nice.
So did you go and meet your
friend
and get the work you missed?
Yeah.
Good.
(school bell rings)
Nat?
Can I talk to you?
[Nat] You okay?
Yeah, um, I just wanted to,
um, like
ask you a question and it's
probably gonna sound really gay
but, like, what do you think of,
um, what do you think of me?
(chuckles) What?
(chuckles) What do you think
of me?
And don't lie.
I don't understand.
What do you think of me?
Um...
I think you're awesome,
I think you're funny.
And you're fun and (chuckles).
And (chuckles) I don't know.
Why are you asking me this?
Is that all?
Why?
Do you know what I think about
you?
Do you care?
Babe, are you okay?
Yep, thanks.
Can I talk to you?
Yeah, sure, what's up?
What's going on with you?
Nothing, I'm fine.
You haven't been answering
your phone.
I lost it (chuckles).
Why did you tell Luke
you're in love with him?
I don't know 'cause I am.
I'm sorry, babe, but it's the
truth.
You're not sorry.
Yes, I am, I don't wanna
be in love with him like
(chuckles) I didn't do this
because of you or anything.
I've loved him forever, it's
just,
I was just trying to do
the right thing, okay?
What?
Please just stop trying
to make me feel like shit
'cause I already do, okay?
I'm sorry!
Fuck, stop saying sorry, Olly,
when you don't fucking mean it!
(sighs) Whatever.
What the fuck happened to you?
Like seriously, what the
fuck happened to you,
like what is wrong with you?
- Can you just fuck off?
Yeah.
I'm just trying to help you.
("The Prelude To" by Lawrence
English)
(door slams)
[Mum] Olly?
Yeah, Mum?
Can you come in here, please?
What is wrong with you?
I'm sorry, Mum.
I didn't mean to.
I'm sorry.
I fucked up.
I don't know, I don't know.
I don't know what to do with
you, Olly.
- Do you want me to move out?
- Oh god.
What, and what, go where, with
what money?
I mean you can't even
look after yourself.
I'm sorry.
Go to bed.
Mum, I'm sorry,
I didn't mean to.
I'm sorry.
Oh, stop it, Olly,
it's pathetic.
Fuck you.
Excuse me?
I said I'm fucking sorry,
okay?
Fuck you, if I'm like this,
it's because of
fucking you anyway.
Why the fuck am I apologizing?
Oh, take some fucking
responsibility!
Do you even have
any fucking idea
what it's like to be your son?
Do you even fucking get it?
Everyone fucking hears it
down the fucking street,
you and your fucking boyfriends
and you dare judge me for this!
Fuck you, okay?
Maybe if you weren't such a
fucking slut,
I wouldn't be so
fucked up right now.
And maybe you would have
fucked out Dad away.
Fuck you, Olly!
I left your father for you!
Because he wasn't
good enough for you!
Like everything that I have
done in my life for you!
Get out, get out,
get out of my room!
Fuck, get out of my house,
get out of my house!
(ambient electronic music)
(birds chirping in distance)
(electronic beeping)
I've been to the hospital
today
and they've agreed
to change me back
but I just need to get your
signature.
Here it is.
Then I'll leave you alone.
(ambient electronic music)
[Nurse] Okay, Olivia, here we
go again.
(music drowns out voice)
So I've attached your drip.
(breathing heavily)
I just need a second.
Hey.
Nice wheels.
Thank you.
How have you been?
Okay.
What about you?
Yeah, good.
How's the gang?
Uh, yeah, Luke's good.
I haven't seen Britney in a
while.
Okay.
It's nice to see you, it's
nice to hear your voice.
It is a sexy voice.
Yeah, (chuckles) isn't it
just?
Hey babe.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
- I love you.
(both chuckling)
I love your hair.
[Olly] That's a balloon.
- I brought you a balloon.
- It's amazing.
(both laughing)
[Nat] It's got a star on the
end.
Of course you put it in
your mouth (chuckles).
("A Prelude To" by Lawrence
English)
(students laughing)
Can I have some of your drink?
Please, please?
But I'm sick.
Okay.
Oh, mucus.
[Man In Hat] Did you already
do that?
[Olly] Hey.
Hey!
(chuckles) Um, what can I get
you?
Can we please get two to
that to the 4:20 session?
Totally, do you want
anything from the candy bar?
Yeah, can we get popcorn,
please?
[Olly] How many?
Two.
Two (mumbles).
I'm Olly.
[Sarah] Hi, I'm Sarah.
Hi, Sarah (chuckles).
Um, sorry.
(electronic beeping)
That's 30.
(Britney and Olly chuckling)
Thanks.
- See ya.
- Bye.
What?
Did you know them?
Yeah.
I went down on her once.
What?
The va-jay-jay.
That is disgusting!
Like a taco.
("Blink" by Denni featuring
Aphir)
(vocalizing)
♪ One time, who are you ♪
♪ And who will you be
when the morning comes
♪ Who will you be
at the rising sun ♪
♪ But who am I one time ♪
♪ Who am I ♪
♪ Who will I be when
the night comes forward ♪
♪ And who will I be when
the sky comes cold out ♪
(woman vocalizing)
♪ And so I sang to man ♪
♪ With no voice today ♪
♪ And he took it
in with a smile ♪
♪ But not much did he say ♪
♪ And then I spoke to a lady ♪
♪ And she had
pearls in her ears ♪
♪ And we talked
about the world ♪
♪ And then we talked about
feelings ♪
♪ So I gave in to a child ♪
♪ Though I've always
been within ♪
♪ Collected tickets
from my pockets ♪
♪ For what I don't ♪
(music drowns out voice)
♪ And I think ♪
(women vocalizing)
♪ Time to be ♪
(melodic electronic music)