Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Michele, Michele.
Miss me, miss me, miss me?
What do you want from me?
Michele,
Michele, Michele.
Join me.
Michele, Michele!
I'm right here.
Calm down.
Oh, no, no, no, I don't
wanna go back to sleep.
No, please, no.
Everything's
gonna be all right.
No, please.
Calm down, take deep breaths.
Dr. Flanagan.
Good morning, Detective.
How's she doing?
Well, physically
there's nothing wrong.
However, she is still
suffering from PTSD.
Oh, I know all about post
traumatic stress disorder,
but it has been a week
and she's the only one
that can provide us answers.
Keep it short and avoid
going out of her comfort zone.
- Got it.
- All right.
- Thanks so much.
- Mm-hmm.
So I'll bring in some pizza?
Detective, does the
doctor know you're here?
Yes, Mrs. Chadwick,
I have his approval.
Hi, Michele.
I'm sorry to bother you but I
do need to get your statement.
Oh, Dr. Flanagan.
Don't you think it's
too early for Michele
to be talking about this?
Well, as I mentioned
to the detective,
she needs to keep it short
and not exceed what
Michele can handle.
I'm gonna record
your statement now.
Please state your
full name and age.
Michele Chadwick, 22.
It's okay, just
take your time.
Tell me everything you remember.
Where do you want me to start?
Why don't you start at
the beginning of the trip?
Okay, well we had
been talking about
this camping trip
for like a few weeks.
And the night before,
Sophia and I...
Yo, this list reminds me
of when we were at camp
and they would tell
us to bring stuff.
That was my idea.
That's where I got
the inspiration from.
Besides, I've trying to make
it simple for all the guys.
Oh, what do you
expect, they're jocks.
One of us happens to be
dating one of those jocks.
You know what, Travis
is the exception.
He's got brains,
- amongst other things.
- Ugh.
And you're right, I really
shouldn't be judging them.
Yeah, especially somebody
who's a psychology major.
Text from Rachel.
"I can't make it tonight,
see you in the morning."
Thanks for the
short notice, Rachel.
I knew she was gonna do
that so I packed extra.
"Okay, see you tomorrow."
You know, this is you and
all your animal lover stuff.
Hey, animal lovers
can't be animal eaters.
Oh, so you're calling
me animal hater?
Maybe.
Dude, I'm so excited
for this trip.
You know, hot
springs, the pines,
getting all of us together.
Yeah, I know, and
you got marshmallows.
Lots and lots of marshmallows.
Of course.
More marshmallows.
More animal-free stuff.
You're stupid.
Hey.
Hope I got these right.
Morning, sunshine.
Thank you, Travis.
Sorry about last night, guys.
I had to close up shop.
We're just glad
you could make it.
Did you forget something?
There's more in the back.
Well, I think I got everything.
So, Travis, how many
footballers are coming?
Girl, you did not just
call them footballers.
You wanna mingle, you
need to know the lingo.
They're called soccer players.
What's up, chaps?
Hey, guys.
Okay, guys, quick
intro for Rachel.
This is Nate, he's
in two of my classes.
Yep, that's me.
Enchanté.
Okay and this is
Brandon and Jessica.
Brandon's also on the
team and Jessica--
Is his girlfriend.
Ah.
Definitely see you
guys are a couple.
Good, so then there shouldn't
be any misunderstandings.
No, no misunderstanding
here, sweetie.
So, what is this
place we're going to?
Beckon Falls.
I actually was on
SNL for like a minute.
Who?
Who was?
14 miles?
Hey, you can do it.
Of course, I'll be fine.
I don't like the way that
blonde bitch looks at you.
Yeah, well, be
nice Jess, all right?
- Sorry.
- It's okay.
How you holding up?
Between Pilates and Cardio
Barre, I can walk all day.
You all right?
Why does everyone think
I can't walk this far?
Okay, sensitive.
You don't do that
much hiking, do you?
It shows?
Well, for one, the
pack is too heavy.
I thought it seemed
a little bit big
but I just brought whatever
Sophia told me to bring.
Uh huh.
Here, let's trade.
I think I can handle
yours better than you can.
- You sure?
- It's okay.
Yours is so much
lighter than mine.
Last time I went fishing
and hiking and camping,
I was in the Boy Scouts.
So you were?
Yeah, since I was 10.
Cute.
All right, the directions
point to the right.
But that doesn't make any sense.
Like, that road looks
like its going back down
- the way we came.
- Just give me the directions.
That's weird, I
can't get a signal.
Oh, I forgot to mention,
there's no cell service out here.
Even I knew that.
The lake is supposed to
be at a higher elevation.
That road leads down.
Look, on the soccer field,
you might be team captain
but this is my turf
and I don't need some
stupid map, it's obvious.
Hey, chill out, dude!
This isn't a competition.
I know what I'm doing!
If Sophia's cousin says to
go right, we're going right!
Okay, easy boys.
Come on, what Brandon
says makes sense.
Okay, let's just
follow the directions
and if we don't start
heading upwards,
we'll turn back around.
Okay?
All right.
You heard the boss.
Let's go.
Nate, are you sure you
don't mind carrying my stuff?
Yo, I got it.
All right, you're a lifesaver.
Hey, no problem.
Hey, I see you
brought a mini rod.
Yeah, of course.
She told me there's
a great fishing spot.
What?
Oh, that's cool.
I always thought there was
something different about you.
Maybe you could show
me how to catch a few?
Yeah, for sure.
All right, guys,
let's take a break.
Finally.
I'm sure it'll start
going up hill again soon.
How far do you
think we've come?
Should be about halfway.
Hey.
I'm sorry.
For what?
For being short
with you earlier.
You're a tough little cookie.
I know you can handle it.
Guys?
I see some anger in the clouds.
It's not looking good.
Yeah, we should probably
start pulling out our rain gear.
Hey, look over there.
Is that a building?
Yeah, that's a
house all right.
Looks abandoned though.
Let's check it out.
Come on.
What's this place doing here?
All right, move.
I'm going in.
Are you nuts?
Well, all right.
Yep.
Well, there's no electricity.
It's all right, we'll survive.
Yeah we will.
Why do you guys
think it's abandoned?
Who cares, it's ours now.
You say something?
I didn't say anything.
How convenient.
Woo!
Guys, guys, guys.
A little elbow grease and
this place will be good as new.
There you are.
What the hell is that?
What?
That voodoo stuff.
Weird.
You okay?
Yeah.
What you got there?
What you got?
I found it.
- Well does it open?
- No.
Okay, cool.
Finders keepers.
Do you hear that?
Hear what?
Never mind.
Okay, well we're
going to start dinner.
Okay, I'll be right there.
Okay.
Hey, did you find her?
Oh yeah, she's coming.
Let's just go get
dinner started.
I will choke
that blonde bitch.
Oh, I love it
when you get angry.
I know you do.
Hey!
We gotta go get dinner started.
Sorry, there's just something
about a mountain man, you know?
Okay.
Come on.
We will finish this later.
Oh, we better.
No, we won't.
I'm just gonna go help
Travis out, all right?
Nothing like a
bunch of busy beavers.
You did not just
call us beavers.
I don't think she
meant anything by that.
Figure of speech.
Oh, I guess I just expected
more from a college girl.
Okay, you know, the beaver's
one of the most diligent
and hardworking
animals on the planet.
Right, Jess?
Yeah, that's what I meant.
Now give me something to do.
Here.
Do something with those.
Hey.
You were right about the road.
We should've taken
the other one.
We cool?
Yeah, cool.
We should head back
the other way tomorrow.
You got it.
Who's thirsty?
Yeah!
My dude.
Hey, Brandon, where'd
you score that bottle?
Courtesy of my pops.
My dog.
All right.
Yeah, yeah.
Oh,
can you handle this?
Try me.
Say when.
When! When!
Are you trying to get me drunk?
Uh.
Mmmm.
Have a good time over
there with Goldilocks?
What?
I saw you completely
undressing her with your eyes.
I was just pouring some rum.
Mm-hmm.
Besides, the only one
I'm undressing with my eyes
- is you.
- Uh huh.
Hmmm? Hmmm?
Shut up.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Hey, so, you have
a thing for Brandon?
What?
No way.
I just like pushing
Jessica's buttons.
Oh.
Okay.
To pushing buttons.
To new friends.
Yeah.
New friends.
So do you still have
any energy leftover?
Oh, I think I am wide awake.
Oh, let me see what you got.
Oh.
Yo, that food was
on point tonight.
Thank you.
Teamwork.
Is she doing that
for our benefit?
Probably.
That's so Jess.
Hey, how about some
ghost stories or something?
Oh, I love scary stories.
Do you know any?
No, no, no, no, I
get scared too easily.
Listen to my music,
thank you very much.
Fucking wuss.
Well I know one.
All right, well let
me know when you done.
Okay, go on, go on.
Just stop keeping
us in suspense.
All right.
There once was this
very sexy girl.
Okay, why does
she have to be sexy?
I mean, can't she be
intelligent or plain?
Who's telling the
story, you or me?
Okay, go on, tell your story.
Okay.
So, this intelligent and kind
of plain-looking girl, Nina,
starting partying way too much.
All right, you
made your point.
Just tell you story
how you want it.
All right.
This hot chick named Nina
started partying way too much.
Her grades were slipping,
so her parents grounded her.
Now, if her grades improved,
they have her a second chance
but with an early curfew.
Now, as you can guess,
on her first night out,
Nina was having such a good time
that she didn't make
it back on time.
And when she finally
did get home,
she found all the lights out.
She tried the front door,
wasn't locked.
So instead of just
going on inside,
she went around back and
climbed the old oak tree
beneath her bedroom window,
as she had done so
many times before.
Next morning, Nina
wakes up early.
It was quiet,
so she thought maybe
her folks went into town
without waking her.
When she reaches the
bottom of the stairs,
she sees blood everywhere.
She runs in the living room
to find her parents'
mangled bodies.
She screams when she
sees written on the walls
in their blood the words,
"Lucky you didn't
open the door."
Asshole, you trying to
give me a heart attack?
Look, I'm sorry, I
heard this story before
and I thought it would be funny.
Yeah, that's your
problem, you don't think.
At least, not with your head.
Whoa.
Coming back to bed?
Mmmm, in a minute.
Goodnight, everyone.
- Night.
- Goodnight, guys.
See y'all.
Well, goodnight.
Night.
Night, guys.
Night, y'all.
Hey, it's okay if you
guys want the other bedroom.
Oh, it's all right, we
can just stay with you.
One big slumber party.
There's my personal heater.
This is her weapon.
Why do you hurt these
poor children of Christ?
What harm have
they done unto you?
I do no hurt them.
Abigail Barker,
you are charged with
sundry acts of witchcraft,
committed unto the bodies
of Mercy Lewis, Ann
Putnam and others.
I'm innocent, I
know nothing of it.
I have done no witchcraft.
You are charged
with tempting them
to sign the Devil's book.
It's that said book.
Tis false, I tell thee!
I've done no wrong!
She bears the mark
of Satan himself!
It's over her heart!
There is no denying.
Who do you serve?
I serve no one.
Then you serve not our Lord.
What contract have
you signed with Satan?
You put words in my mouth.
I have made no contract, I
never saw him in my life.
Anne Putnam saith that the
devil is her god, not I.
Have you not in your
heart to tell the truth?
I do tell the truth.
I never hurt these persons.
I am no witch!
Have you not given consent
that some evil spirit
should do this in your likeness?
No.
I am innocent!
All accusations
against me are false!
Abigail Barker,
I find you guilty
of being a witch!
And I here order to proceed
with your execution!
You are a liar!
I am no more a witch
than you are a wizard.
Take her away!
You will pay for this!
What's wrong?
Whoa.
Hey, it was just a little quake.
Is she okay?
- Come here, sweetheart.
- A little shaken up.
Sweetheart, it was
just a little earthquake.
Let's go.
Hey, is she okay?
Oh my God.
And that's when I noticed
that her eyes had changed.
Did
anyone else notice
the change taking place?
I don't know.
It's okay, just
take your time.
I don't know.
I can't remember.
- Honey, what is it?
- What? What?
She's right there!
- She's right there, Grandma!
- There's no one here!
No, no, she's right there!
No, she's right there!
- Who did you see?
- Sophia's right there!
She's right there!
We
don't see anything.
Yes, there's, Grandma,
please save me, Grandma!
You've had enough excitement.
Grandma, Grandma--
This has got to
stop right now.
Please, Grandma, no!
I'm gonna give you
something to relax.
No, no, I don't wanna
go back to sleep, please!
Doctor, please,
it is very pressing
that we finish her statement!
I understand
but right now I can not
allow you to continue!
All right, I'll
pick this up later.
Mrs. Chadwick--
Do you realize how difficult
this is for all of us?
I understand that
and I respect it
but its very difficult
for the other parents
involved as well.
I'll check back later.
Damn it.
Michele?
Detective.
Yeah.
Where's my grandma?
She left.
So, how you feeling?
Better.
I don't wanna sleep anymore.
You know, there's
a lot of people
that wanna hear your
side of the story.
I know, it's just hard.
I'm not trying to keep
anything from you.
That's good.
I just want to find out what
happened to your friends.
You ready to continue our talk?
- Okay.
- All right.
So,
what happened next?
Well, we were sleeping
and then, in the morning...
You guys, there's no
sign of her out there.
Guys, I found her hair
with blood all over it.
You think somebody
kidnapped her?
Why would they only take her?
I don't know
but we've searched
this whole house.
Guys, I'm really scared.
Come on, guys, this is
Sophia we're talking about.
She had to leave
on her own accord.
But why didn't she tell anyone?
And where did all
that blood come from?
That time of the month?
Don't mess around.
Okay, guys, listen up.
We're all gonna
split into groups
and we'll search for her
in different directions.
It's the fastest
way to find her.
I'll head back down the trail.
I'll go with Brandon.
Good, then Michele and I can
search the trail to the east
and maybe Nate and Rachel
can search to the west.
If we can't get any signal,
how are we supposed to get
in touch with each other?
When you guys do find her,
just have one
person stay with her
and the other person head back.
And no matter what,
we're all gonna meet right back
here in one hour, all right?
One hour.
Let's go.
Sophia!
Sophia?
Where you at?
Sophia!
There's no sight of her.
I don't get it, she's
disappeared without a trace.
I don't understand
where she could have gone.
Let's keep looking for her.
Hey, aren't
we at the crossroads?
Yeah.
Sophia!
Do you feel that?
Feel what?
It feels like
someone's watching us.
No, you're imagining things.
Did you hear that?
Yeah.
I think it came from over here.
Come on.
Shit!
Brandon!
Ugh.
Well I didn't expect that.
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
Christ.
I got you.
Is that Sophia?
Yeah, I think so.
- Sophia!
Oh my God.
Did she dig this with her hands?
Sophia?
Sophia, what's come over you?
Sophia.
Yo, it's me.
Nate.
Yo, her hands are like ice.
Stop that!
Stop that, what
is wrong with you?
Sweetie, please just relax.
It's okay, just get some sleep.
Is she breathing?
- What's wrong with her?
- I don't know, I don't know.
We need to get the
hell out of her.
How is she?
I don't know.
There's something
wrong with her, okay?
She's acting very strange.
Yeah, she's lost her mind.
We caught her digging a
whole with her bare hands.
Brandon, don't say that.
I mean, she's probably delusional
from the flu or something.
First she finds a necklace,
then her eyes turn all weird.
Now she digs this
book out of a hole.
I mean, she's gotta
be a little crazy.
I can't even read a
word in this book.
It's English.
I know that, you bimbo.
Fuck you, bitch.
Hey, guys chill out.
I meant, it's old English.
And I still can't read it.
Just give it here.
This looks like some kinda
Shakespearean writing
stuff or something.
Looks like spells.
You guys, it does not matter
what it says in that book.
Right now,
it's Sophia's condition we
should be worried about.
We need to take her
to the hospital.
No.
It wouldn't be safe to
try and make it down now.
Just give her the night to rest
and we can head out first
thing tomorrow morning.
I'm with you, bro,
especially with all
this drama going on.
You know, Brandon,
you've always had a
way with your words.
You're an asshole!
There you are.
I've been worried.
Just couldn't sleep
thinking about her.
Hey.
Come back to bed, okay?
Huh?
Come on.
Let me finish this.
Okay.
You think Sophia's
losing her mind?
Something is wrong with her.
Hey.
Don't keep me waiting
too long, all right?
I won't.
Brandon?
Who's there?
Is that you, Blondie?
If you're trying to scare
me, it's not working!
Where you going?
Come back here, you bitch!
Michele,
what're you doing in here?
I heard footsteps.
I didn't mean to startle you.
I just came back
from my recorder.
No, I'm glad that you did
because I don't wanna
keep this in anymore.
I wanna tell you everything.
All right, come on, let's go.
Just start from the
beginning and tell me
everything you wanna
tell me, all right?
Michele, Michele, calm
down, what's wrong?
- What happened?
- She came back!
She came back!
- No, it's okay, calm down.
- Sophia came back!
Detective,
what have you done now?
Nothing, I came in
and she as in the closet
and started screaming.
- Let's get you back in bed.
- Michele.
I need assistance
and page Dr. Flanagan!
Detective, you need to go!
Calm down.
I'll be back, Michele.
I'll be back.
Jessica?
Brandon, what's going on?
It's Jessica, she never
came back to bed last night.
She's gotta be
around here somewhere.
No, look, I checked!
Yo, guys,
what's up, man?
Jessica's missing.
- You've gotta be kidding me.
- What?
Sophia's gone too.
Ah!
What the hell's going on?
We're fucking cursed!
All right, everybody,
guys, just calm down.
Let's just think this through.
All right, look, you
can stay if you want,
I'm not coming back
here without Jessica!
- Brandon!
- Dude!
Guy, guys, let's just split up
and look for her again, okay?
Split up?
Dude!
Jessica!
Sophia!
Where are you?
Come out!
Sophia!
Jessica!
Nowhere.
Jess.
Jessica!
Sophia!
Whoa, do you feel that?
No.
There's something here.
Oh, hell no.
Don't even go there.
Right now we just need to
find Jessica and Sophia.
Come on.
Jessica?
Sophia?
You're not Sophia.
Who are you?
Abigail Barker.
Don't come any
closer, all right?
I mean it!
What'd you do to Jessica?
She made a good sacrifice.
Did you hear that?
Shit, Brandon!
Sounds like it
came from over there.
- Nate, cut him down.
- Brandon.
Oh my God!
We found him hanging.
Who could have done this?
Brandon was the
toughest guy we knew.
I don't know, man!
There's gotta be
more than one killer.
You guys, what're we gonna do?
We can't leave him here.
Let's just take him
back to the house.
This is so unreal.
Any ideas?
No.
Let's just get the
hell out of here.
I don't know about you but I
really wanna get out of here.
I just can't believe
this is happening.
Nobody goes anywhere
without somebody with them.
I wanna get out of here now.
I'm with Rachel on getting
the hell out of here!
We will as soon as it's safe.
We'd never make it
back before nightfall.
Yeah, Travis is right.
We really should
all stay together.
There's strength in numbers.
Guys?
Hey, did one of you
leave the backdoor open?
No, not me.
I didn't do it.
Yeah, I wasn't in the kitchen.
Well who did?
There.
Let's go make sure the rest
of this house is secured.
Yeah, that's a good idea.
Windows closed.
Travis, I'm so scared.
Hey,
I'm here for you, babe.
I won't let anything
happen to you.
Oh, hey!
How y'all doin'?
Bedroom is secure.
What does that mean,
that the house is safe now?
As much as we can make it.
I wish there was
something we could do
about Sophia and Jessica.
We need to get help.
Have a real search party
out here looking for them.
I hope they're okay.
We just need to
stay safe tonight.
I wonder what's in this book.
I just wanna know why the hell
she dug it up in
the first place.
There's like
spells and chants.
I found one for protection.
Yo, close that book,
it's creeping me out.
Wait till I get back
so that we can actually--
Where you going?
To get warmer sweats.
I'll keep you warm.
Yeah.
That's exactly what
I was afraid of.
What, no, I'm being serious.
The group said we have
to stick together.
Yeah.
I'm gonna go get those,
I'll be right back.
Wait, you guys,
listen to this.
"Thrice around the circle bound,
"all evil sinks into the ground.
"By light of day
and darkness night,
"I am protected by thee might.
"Goddess of the moon and stars,
"I call to thee
which tis me right,
"protect me from
all evil's might.
"Protected me from
all evil's harm.
"Protect me from
all evil's might.
all evil's harm."
Hey!
You all right?
Yeah.
Sounds like a
weird nursery rhyme.
Why don't you put that
away and come here?
I wouldn't be reading
those if I were you.
You don't know what they are.
Rachel?
Hey guys, come here.
Michele, Michele.
You're all right,
you're all right.
Nate, watch my back.
Gotcha.
Shit!
Where the hell did she go?
I don't know.
We have to leave now.
Shit!
I so fucking hate her.
Get her out of here!
- Ow!
- Are you okay? Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm okay, I'm okay.
Just put a little pressure
on it so you know you can walk.
- All right, I got it.
- Ready?
Yeah, let's go.
Come on.
- Nate! Nate!
- What? What?
I can't run anymore.
- I can't run anymore.
- What happened?
My knee.
Okay, let's just get off the
trail and find cover, okay?
Okay.
Nate, Nate, seriously,
I can't go on.
Okay, then let's
just relax, okay?
I don't know what
the hell that was
but that was not Sophia.
Look, she looks
like she's possessed.
I don't know what's
wrong with her!
Crap, look, we just
need to get out of here
as quick as possible, period.
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Protected me from
all evil's might.
Protect me from all evil's harm.
Protect me from
all evil's might.
Protect me from all evil's harm.
She's gone.
Yeah, I don't see her.
Nate,
my knee hurts so bad.
You should just go.
No, I'm not leaving you here.
We stay here for the night
and leave at daylight.
You're strong, I know you.
Michele, we gotta move.
I know.
My knee's feeling just
a little bit better.
It still hurts?
Yeah.
Try this.
Okay.
I think this will work.
- It'll work?
- Yeah.
Nate.
What are we gonna
tell their moms?
Travis' mom.
All right, look, let's not
concentrate on that right now.
Let's just concentrate
on getting out of here.
Sorry.
Hey, it's all right.
Be strong.
Take it one step
at a time, okay?
There you go.
We're almost there.
- All right?
- Yeah.
We made it.
Please tell me
you have the keys.
Yeah, I do.
You stay here, okay?
No, no, no.
No, Nate, no.
Sophia!
Sophia, why?
I'm Abigail.
Sophia, it's me, Michele!
Blood must be shed.
But they're our
friends, Sophia.
They were useless to me.
You stay away from me.
You stay away!
That doesn't work.
Ow!
Sophia, listen to me!
Let me help you!
Michele, oh my God, help me.
Please help me.
Sophia, what can I do?
Give me my book!
And if I don't?
You don't know
what you're doing.
You think you can negotiate?
One sure thing,
the book is mine!
Abigail,
let Sophia go!
Too late now!
She is gone!
You crazy bitch!
No!
Hey!
Leave her alone!
Hey, you!
And I don't remember
anything after that.
Well,
Michele, I think
that clears it up.
The hunter corroborated
your story, however,
we have yet to confirm the
perpetrator's identity.
Detective, it's Sophia!
Abigail possessed her,
why can't you believe me?
Calm down, calm down.
You need to get some
rest, all right?
I'll have a transcript
made of this recording
and we'll go from
there, all right?
I promise.
Did you guys find Jessica?
We did.
Is she?
I'm afraid so.
Michele?
Time for your meds.
Good afternoon,
Detective Henderson.
Judy.
Are you done?
Actually, we're done.
Take care, Michele, I'll be
in touch soon, all right?
We'll talk.
Detective, you're
not gonna find Sophia.
Not unless she wants you to.
I'll be in touch.
Detective Henderson.
Howard, how are you?
Fascinating person,
this Abigail Barker.
She was a real person then?
Oh yeah, absolutely.
She was born in 1670.
What else can you tell me?
Well,
this Abigail Barker was
put on trial in 1692
and she was found
guilty of practicing
acts of witchcraft by
the local magistrate.
She was then tortured,
which was standard
practice at the time,
and then eventually executed.
Really?
Okay, wait a minute.
How easy would it
be for my witness
to have access to
that information?
Well, anyone can research it,
but I suppose "why"
would be my question
and then,
how would they even find
this book in the first place?
Which, by the way,
happens to be a compellation
of spells and incantations.
To tell you the truth, I as
hoping you were gonna tell me
that Abigail Barker was
just a bunch of folklore
and that book a
bunch of nonsense.
Now I can get back to work
and get that book carbonated.
What else do you got for me?
Well, I don't know
if it's relevant at all
but I also found
some documentation
of accusations against
witches using amulets
to transform
themselves into animals
and even powerful
creatures, supposedly.
You've gotta be kidding me.
No, it was actually
documented multiple times
during the witch trials.
Well, that's about
all I have for now
but keep me posted on
what happens, okay?
Most
definitely, thank you.
All right.
Goodbye.
Howard.
Who is that?
You know who this is.
No, I don't know you.
Oh, but you do.
It's Abigail.
No.
That's not possible.
Aren't you a believer?
Take a seat, Professor.
I said, sit down!
I don't understand.
You're no different
than they were.
It seems the professor has
been telling tall tales
to Detective Henderson.
People love tall tales,
wouldn't you say?
I suppose.
When I was younger
I used art and spells
to connect with nature.
I only meant good back then.
The folks people lied
and labeled me a witch!
They did unspeakable
things to me!
And I now you know the rest!
But they couldn't destroy me.
Because I choose darkness.
My ally.
We have just been
waiting to find someone
to give me my vessel.
The book of spells.
Ah, you're a smart
man, Professor.
So I'm sure you understand
that until I find my book,
I only need a little blood
sacrifice here and there.
Professor, let's see what
dead flesh feels like.
Sleepy time.
So Dr. Flanagan said that I
could go home in a day or two.
Don't you think
it's a bit too soon?
Why do you say that, Grandma?
You're still having episodes.
The neighbors
are talking, huh?
You know I don't
care about that.
So then why do you have a
problem with me coming home?
I don't.
How's Travis' mom doing?
Well,
as well as can be
expected, you know.
They all blame me, huh?
Honey, until this thing
gets all sorted out,
people are gonna talk,
they're gonna come to
their own conclusions.
Yeah, well I'm a victim
in this too, Grandma!
I know you are, sweetheart.
You know,
Sophia's parents have put up
a reward for her safe return.
She's not coming home!
She's dead!
I mean, how many times
do I have to keep
telling people this?
Sophia is not Sophia anymore!
Sophia killed Travis, she killed
all of my friends, Grandma!
Oh, honey.
That's why I don't
want you to be
in such a hurry to come home.
Grandma, I don't wanna stay
in this fucking
hospital anymore!
It's like a fucking
prison in here!
I miss all of my
friends' funerals.
Lieutenant.
What's up?
Hey, Nikki.
Detective.
Looks like Miles had a chance
to call 911 before he died,
so approximate time
of death, 9:10 PM.
He's got a single knife
wound to the chest,
was also stabbed in the hands.
There's some claw marks
in the back of his neck.
God.
How did they get in?
No sign of a break-in.
We had to pick the front
lock to gain access.
Locked from the inside.
What's this?
He wrote a name
with his blood.
Don't touch anything.
Forensics is on the way.
Okay, that's odd because Miles
was doing some research for
me on an Abigail Barker.
So we have a suspect?
Not exactly, the Abigail
Barker we're talking about
died in 1692.
I guess that was too easy.
Hey, what about that 911 call?
He only asked
for an ambulance.
The line went solid after that.
Okay, I'm gonna wanna
get a copy of that call.
I'll get you a copy
and put it in the folder.
Hey, how's that
Chadwick case coming?
Slowly, we're dealing
with a very fragile victim.
Victim?
Thought she was a suspect.
Another girl went missing
and right now she's
the only survivor.
Well,
physically, you're
in excellent shape.
Any pain?
Nope.
How about the nightmares?
Oh yeah, those haven't
come around in awhile.
Ready to go home?
Sure.
Well I'm gonna change
your medication a little bit
and if you have another
day without any incidents,
you can go home.
Sounds good to me.
Lower her dosage
to 25 milligrams
and let's keep an eye on her.
What about her
nighttime pills?
Just give me a
call in the afternoon
and we'll make a decision then.
Dr. Flanagan, am I gonna
have to take these pills
once I go home?
Well, with this medication,
you can't quit cold turkey.
We have to decreased
your dosage gradually.
I want you to contact
your family physician
in the next two days.
We'll send you home
with some instructions
and my notes to your doctor.
Okay, because I'm ready to go.
Yeah, I bet you are.
What do you got for me?
I got nothing.
I've dusted head to
toe several times.
I can't even find
a partial print.
What about these
claw marks, here?
Any idea where they
would have come from?
They appear to
have been made by talons.
However, that's not
what killed him.
He died from a single
knife wound to the chest.
What about under
the fingernails?
Clean.
Whatever it was, the poor
guy didn't have a chance.
Hey there.
Hi, Beth, I'm
ready to go home now.
I bet.
I should hopefully have your
paperwork done within an hour.
You done with this?
Oh yeah, thank you.
Let me know if
there's anything else
you need in the meantime.
I will.
What are you doing?
Stop!
It'll feel good.
Somebody help me!
Help!
Help me!
Don't bother screaming,
no one can hear you talking.
It's so good to be home.
Come here.
Everything's gonna be
fine now that you're back.
Thank you, Grandma.
You're always so optimistic.
Why don't we order some pizza?
Sounds great.
Okay.
Excuse me, can I help you?
Where is she?
Excuse me?
That whore!
You need to leave right now.
I don't think you heard me.
I said, where is that
bitch of a whore?
You need to leave!
Where?
Where is she?
She's gone home.
Goodbye.
What's going on here?
Too late, Doctor.
What the hell are you?
Shoulda heeded my warning.
Hey, there's one more slice.
Oh no, I'm too full.
Oh, okay, you want more?
Sure.
Okay.
I'll get it.
Detective.
Mrs. Chadwick.
What can I do for you?
Is Michele home?
Yes.
What's going on?
May I come in, I need
to speak with you both.
Sure.
Wait here.
Honey, it's the detective.
Michele, I'm gonna
get right to the point.
There's been a tragedy
at he hospital.
What happened?
This afternoon, Dr.
Flanagan, his main nurse
and a security
guard were killed.
Oh my God.
It's Abigail!
Strangely enough, several
witnesses have confirmed
that the perpetrator's identity
does fit the
description of Sophia,
with the exception of her eyes.
No, it's Abigail, I
told you, she's coming!
I've got two officers
guarding your house
and in the morning they will
take you down to the station
to sign your statement.
It was Abigail, I
told you she's coming.
So you do think
we're in danger.
I'm not taking any chances.
I've got two officers guarding
the perimeter of your home
and I'm not leaving until
I know it's secured.
Mmmm.
Want me to fix you
something before you leave?
Oh no, I'm just
gonna get some coffee.
Okay.
Oh, Grandma, they're here.
So I'll see you later.
Good luck, baby.
Call me if you're gonna be late.
Okay.
Your ride is here.
Are you all right, miss?
Yeah.
Just a little chest pain.
Okay, ready to go?
Yeah, let's do this.
We've got another room
down here we can check out.
Yeah, let's use this room.
There you are, I've been
looking all over for you.
What's up?
Stevenson found something.
What does he have?
Not sure but it sounded
extremely important.
I was just about to have
Michele repeat her statement.
I'll get it started for you.
You sure?
Yeah, I've got some time.
Michele, this is
Lieutenant Paxton,
he's going to review
your statement with you.
When you read it, make sure
you look over everything, okay?
Okay.
All right, I'll be right back.
Hey, young lady, shall we?
Have a seat.
Here you go.
Whoa.
Yeah, Henderson can
be pretty thorough.
Looks like you got a
lot of reading to do.
You need something to drink?
No, thank you.
Okay, go ahead and make
any corrections you need
and I will be right back.
I have something
you'll wanna see.
Take a look.
What is it?
It's the tip of the blade.
Is it gold?
No.
It's either a bronze
or a copper blend.
Really?
I'll send it to a
metallist to confirm.
Any idea?
It's very old.
I don't have the equipment
to date it properly.
How are you doing?
I just finished.
Anything you'd like to change?
No, everything
seems about right.
So this is not
an interrogation.
Just a couple things
I'd like to confirm.
Is this the knife you said
Brandon had in his possession?
Yes.
What about this book?
Yeah, that's the book.
Okay.
I just wanted to make
sure everything--
If you ask me...
I have no respect for authority.
Sophia, come on, it's me!
I'm Michele, I'm your friend!
Oh please, come on.
Come on.
Sophia is dead.
I couldn't have killed you.
You were protected.
The book is mine.
Hey!
Stop!
Oh my God!
I need am ambulance now!
Michele.
Oh my God.
Michele, you're all right.
Sophia.
What?
You should just
save your strength.
I need help in here, now!
Can I get a ride?
Sure.
What's your name?
Abigail.
Reawaken.
♪ Reawaken
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org