NETFLIX PRESENTS
[man] Tomato sauce runs in the veins
of the Trancoso family.
Generation after generation,
we've perfected our techniques
to create this premium tomato.
Irrigation is automatic,
enriched with liquid fertilizer.
Our tomatoes
are treated like our children:
balanced diets, only the best schools,
and a personal trainer.
Therefore, they can be worth
eight times the price of regular tomatoes.
Now I'm going to show you a preview
of the campaign my son, Teto,
has been working on.
It's a campaign for our new tomato sauce
which brings together tradition,
innovation,
and, most importantly, love.
Teto!
["Table for 2" by Alok & IRO plays]
ONE MONTH EARLIER
♪ You don't need a million reasons
to smile without a reason ♪
♪ I've got one, will you stay? ♪
♪ And it's always the perfect season
to never stop believing ♪
♪ Love works in mysterious ways ♪
♪ It's raining in the desert
I heard it on the news ♪
♪ The sun won't even shine no more
Since I'm not there with you ♪
♪ I pick you up with flowers
Roses, red or blue ♪
♪ A mattress and a table just for two... ♪
PATY DO ALFERES
60 MILES FROM RIO DE JANEIRO
♪ I promise that it's true ♪
♪ A table just for two
It's only me and you ♪
♪ I could make you breakfast
And you could be my muse... ♪
[helicopter whirring]
♪ Just four walls without you left a ♪
♪ A book with empty chapters
A dock without a bay ♪
♪ And tell me what is the meaning
of life without this feeling? ♪
♪ And the sky is gray... ♪
Ana.
♪ I heard it on the news ♪
♪ The sun won't even shine no more ♪
♪ Since I'm not there with you ♪
♪ I pick you up with flowers
Roses, red or blue ♪
♪ A mattress and a table just for two... ♪
- Good morning.
- Morning, son.
- How are you?
- I'm good.
- Good morning.
- [Teto] Good morning.
- Here, let me serve you some coffee.
- Please.
[woman] Anything else you guys need?
The yolk broke!
I'll make you another one.
- Oh, Rose, stop spoiling the boy!
- No worries.
- No, it's okay
- Are you sure?
- [Teto] Yes, it's fine.
- [Rose] Okay.
Listen, is your son home?
Igor must be getting ready to go to class.
- I need him to do me a huge favor.
- Really?
There's a girl in my room.
I can't deal with it now.
[Rose] Is it Leila, from yesterday?
No. I think... this one's Ana.
A different one.
Thanks.
That's how I like it.
[upbeat music plays]
Come on!
Let's go, Raissa!
Good morning, sunshine! Rise and shine!
- No!
- Yes. Out of bed.
I chose the worst roommates!
Weren't we going to skip class today?
But we can't skip our internship, right?
Paula, have you forgotten
my bachelorette party?
No, but if we start early at the hospital,
we'll be done before the bus leaves.
Can't we skip one day? Just one!
You know I would in a heartbeat,
but I can't skip any more days.
I picked the worst people
as bridesmaids for my wedding.
That's easy for you to say
when you're set in life. Right, sweetie?
True. Plus this internship is my chance
to get a residency at the hospital.
Paula, your residency is guaranteed.
- If it's up to Dr. Victor...
- What about Dr. Victor?
[imitates Dr. Victor]
"Paula... excellent case history!"
[imitates Dr. Victor] "Watch the way
Paula does a lumbar puncture."
Don't be ridiculous! Let's go, Raissa.
Hi.
Teto?
[stammers] No.
Teto had to leave
and didn't want to wake you up.
I can give you a ride.
[sighs]
[Rose] Here you go!
- Happy?
- Very. It's perfect.
- Igor's going to drive your friend home.
- Thanks.
You need to grow up, Teto.
But I'm glad to see you up before noon.
What did you expect
with that helicopter flying overhead?
While you were asleep,
I went to Rio for a meeting and came back.
And now I have to go to the factory.
- I want to talk about your birthday.
- Okay. Cool.
- Meet me at Trancoso at five?
- I'll check my schedule.
I'll check on you later, okay
- [Paula] Bye.
- [patient] Bye.
Paula, as usual, excellent case history.
Thank you, doctor.
I have a surgery now.
Do you want to scrub in?
- We have to go, don't we, Paula?
- Next time, doctor.
- For sure.
- No, no. I'd love to,
but we have a previous engagement.
I just thought you really wanted this job,
- but...
- But I do!
I do want it. I really do want it.
I'll stay.
Good. I'll be in the OR.
- Sorry. There was nothing I could do.
- No problem.
- You guys are the worst, period.
- Sweetie!
Don't worry.
[heart rate monitor beeping]
Paula... I'm glad you stayed.
- Of course, doctor.
- Victor.
- You can call me Victor.
- Okay.
No, I'm very grateful
for the opportunities you give me.
You know why, right?
Because of my case histories?
Because you're very special to me...
Paula.
[woman] Here, sir. It's just two.
Girlfriend, you came!
[squeals]
What about the surgery?
Here you go.
I made up an excuse that I was sick
and left.
I've never been so humiliated.
It was horrible.
I really thought I'd get the residency,
- but because I was good.
- You are good.
No. You're the best.
[Teto] Hey, hey, hey! Come over here.
- [man] What's up?
- [Teto] Where were you?
I had class.
- Let's do something.
- No can do. I have to study.
Study what, man? Let's do something.
Let's have fun!
Let's make a bet.
Twenty bucks if you win.
I win, and you forget about studying
and come riding with me.
- Deal?
- Deal.
["All The Lies"
by Alok, Felix Jaehn and The Vamps plays]
Go!
♪ I know goodbyes, they hurt ♪
♪ I need to hear you say it ♪
♪ One time before I go ♪
♪ Whisper it slow
Of all the lies I heard ♪
♪ "I love you" was my favorite ♪
♪ Say it slow ♪
[Teto chanting] Victory! Victory!
[Teto laughs]
I'm tired of beating you, dude.
You're so weak.
Next time, I want to pick my horse.
When I pick, I win.
Blaming the horse now?
- Really?
- I'm going home, Teto.
If I'm to get into college in Rio,
I have to study.
You're not going anywhere.
You lost the bet, man. You lost it!
Now you'll have to come buy
my birthday present with me. Come on!
[tires squealing]
Try not to go over the speed limit,
Mr. Teto.
You only live once, old man!
[shouting and laughing]
Guys, did you see that?
What a loser. Right, guys?
Small-town playboy?
Playboys are losers anywhere, right?
♪ Of all the lies I heard
"I love you" is... ♪
TOWN OF THE TOMATO FESTIVAL
♪ I need to hear you say it... ♪
Really?
He thinks he's so hot!
♪ Whisper it slow ♪
♪ Of all the lies I heard
"I love you" was my favorite... ♪
[sires wailing]
- I'm screwed.
- Keep it cool.
- Teto! So, it's you, kid?
- What's up?
I was test-driving the car,
and I had to step on the gas.
What a beauty.
- You like it?
- Are you getting it?
That's up to my dad.
I'd love to get it for my birthday.
Happy birthday. But drive carefully, kid.
- Okay. Thanks.
- [woman] Hey! What's going on?
- It's all good, Fernanda.
- Get that radio.
You think you're off the hook,
Mr. Tomato Prince?
- Are you done?
- No! Out of the car!
Move it!
Hands on the hood!
Teto, you naughty boy...
I miss you, you know?
Turn around.
I'm going to let you go,
but you'll have to get me
an invitation to your party.
- Sure.
- Hm-mm.
Consider it done.
Go on.
And slow down!
TRANCOSO TOMATOES
Man, you've slept with all the women
in town.
Not all yet.
But with this car, I probably will.
- Even you, since you can't get any.
- My crush isn't like that.
- Selma? From your class?
- Yeah.
That's why you're a virgin.
You're obsessed with a girl
who doesn't see you.
- How can you stand that?
- I stand worse.
Teto, honey, long time no see!
Look how handsome you are!
- Teto, my man! What's up?
- Generally, the sky.
[all laugh]
- [man] The kid's amazing.
- [woman] He's a genius.
You see why this car
would be a perfect gift for me?
Yes, but I want to give you something
that gets you somewhere.
Yeah, the damn car!
But I don't want to give you a car.
I want you to earn it.
Right.
I want you to come work at the company.
That's your present.
A job. What do you think?
Good.
Cool.
- Great!
- Great.
Monique, please.
- What can I do for you, Mr. Teodoro?
- Sweetie, some water, please.
The kitchen is down the hall.
Monique is a junior executive
here at Trancoso.
I want you to pay close attention
to everything she says and does.
So, Teto, do you know
what you want to do yet?
Not yet.
How did you decide you wanted this...
- this junior thing you do?
- I didn't really have a choice.
Necessity makes you
grab every opportunity you get.
I also studied hard.
Back in Rio, my school referred me
to Trancoso's trainee program.
Out of ten trainees,
they picked me for an assistant position.
Congratulations.
Last year, I was transferred here
and promoted as a junior...
And now I have to babysit too.
Monica.
Monique.
Have we ever hooked up?
What?
Because it seems you hold a grudge
against me.
Why? Like all your ex-girlfriends?
[Igor laughs]
Really, why are you picking on me?
Your dad wants me to teach you
how I got here.
It wasn't with everyone
praising the ground I walk on.
Monique.
Look, I really admire your story,
and I appreciate your effort.
- But I can't deal with this now.
- You can't deal with it?
I'm celebrating my birthday
in a suite at the Tomato Festival,
and there's a lot to do,
a lot of people to invite.
It's a real headache.
But if you're free, stop by, okay?
[uptempo dance music plays]
♪ Open the dance floor ♪
♪ Open the dance floor... ♪
Look at the bride!
Come on, Paula!
Don't look so glum! Liven up!
- Yeah, Paula.
- Forget work, forget Dr. Victor.
- Just for now.
- Okay.
- Maybe you'll meet a rich farmer here.
- [Paula laughs]
That's why I'm studying so hard, right?
To marry a rich farmer. Right.
[musician] Come on, Paty!
Shout if you want to see him!
Good evening, Paty do Alferes!
[electronic dance music plays]
["Festa Boa" by Henrique and Diego,
feat. Gusttavo Lima plays]
♪ The party is good today
And we will pop up ♪
♪ All these beautiful people
Are going to have fun ♪
♪ I already called the girls
The most beautiful ♪
♪ The party is crowded
and playing the best beats ♪
♪ I asked for champagne
And the girls came all over... ♪
- Evening.
- Your name, please.
- Igor Souza.
- Your name is not on the list.
- But I'm Teto's friend.
You're not here. You can't enter.
- But I must be on there somewhere.
- You're not.
- There he is. Can I go talk to him?
- [man] Of course not.
Teto!
- He's coming here.
- Yeah.
Why so late?
He's with me.
- Your bracelet.
- Thanks.
How could you not put me on the list?
What list? Listen, it's my birthday,
but I have a present for you.
- What?
- I invited Selma from your class.
- No. Not Selma. No!
- What, dude? She's here.
I'm not ready.
- What do I say to her?
- Whatever. I'll introduce you and leave,
- then you kiss her. It's easy.
- Easy for you!
- No...
- Selma?
- [Teto] Hi, Selma.
- Hi.
- Let me introduce you to my friend.
You're in my class, right?
- Yeah. Igor.
- And this is Teto.
I know who he is.
By the way, happy birthday, Teto.
Thanks. I'll leave you two alone.
Enjoy the party.
There's tomato salad,
tomato hors d'oeuvres, tomato pie...
- Everything tomato.
- Don't worry about that.
A tomato prince is more than enough
for me.
Oh, boy.
I know why you invited me.
Hold on...
Sorry.
- Igor, she's crazy.
- Get lost, man.
You're mad because the girl likes me?
It's not my fault!
How do you know
if someone likes you for real,
or for your money, your status,
or what you own?
Can we talk about this later?
This isn't the time.
Everyone says you're great,
and you believe them, right?
You're happy with every bet you win,
but you can't see
that none of that matters,
that you always have an advantage.
You'll only know the real you
when you take off this prince name tag.
Chill, bro.
When I'm gone,
you'll miss me being upfront with you.
These people are just sucking up to you.
I'm a real friend,
and I'm not even on your list.
You're not on my friend list
because you're family.
You're my brother.
And you know what?
I don't need this shit.
Hey! Stop right there, Teto.
Are you leaving?
Am I late? Is the party over?
No. Actually, it's just starting.
- If you look over there, you'll see.
- Okay.
- It's going to start now.
- See you later.
- Roger that.
Folks, today's the birthday
of the tomato prince,
- Teodoro Trancoso Neto.
- Tomato prince.
[Alok] And he has a surprise for you.
Get ready for the tomato fight!
Here we go!
Oh, my God! Tomatoes!
Come on, let's go!
[DJ] Hands in the air!
Hands in the air! Are you ready?
[dance music plays]
Everybody, I said "Hey!"
[crowd] Ho!
[DJ]Hey!
[crowd]Ho!
[DJ] One more time!
If they throw a tomato at me,
I'm gonna be mad.
[girls scream]
I'm gonna kill...
Sorry.
What was that?
Are you crazy?
- What were you thinking?
- That we're all having fun.
You're wrong.
- [Raissa] Excuse me! Are you crazy?
- [man] Give me a kiss.
- [Raissa] Are you nuts?
- [woman] Get off!
Leave her alone! Are you crazy?
- Hottie.
- Get off me!
Let go of me!
- Let her go! Are you crazy?
- Don't touch me, boy!
- Son of a...
- Jerk!
That's Teto. Come on! Let's go!
♪ Girl... ♪
Assholes!
Are you okay?
♪ Your beautiful hair... ♪
And then what?
[crowd singing]
♪ Your guitar-shaped body... ♪
See if it's broken.
Tilt your head back. That's it.
♪ It's crazy, crazy, crazy... ♪
[DJ] Tell you what...
Put your hands in the air
if you're crazy tonight!
- [Teto] I can't. It's hurting like hell.
- [Paula] Calm down. Sit over there.
I broke my nose. He broke my face.
My nose is broken.
- Look at all this blood.
- Calm down.
- It's mostly tomato sauce.
- If it was broken,
- you wouldn't stand the pain.
- I'm not!
Trust me. I'm used to this.
It isn't broken.
- Are you a wrestler?
- No.
I've just graduated from med school.
- In Rio?
- Yes.
- [Raissa] Hey...
- May I?
- I have painkillers. Want some?
- Yeah.
Raissa, are you crazy?
- That'll knock out a horse!
- But I want some!
Stop whining. Let me take a look.
You're going to set his nose here,
right now?
Avoiding calcification
- if it's broken.
- What?
On three, all right? One...
- [bone cracks]
- [screams]
- That was on "one!"
- Done.
You're mad because I hit you
with a tomato? Is this revenge?
I'm pissed at whoever
had this dumb tomato fight idea.
- So?
- [Paula] What do you mean "so"?
- It's just for fun.
- Fun?
Jeez! So many people going hungry,
and the guy wastes all this food
on a tomato fight?
It's absurd!
I think this bachelorette party is over.
Shall we?
- Are you the bride?
- No.
I'm a bridesmaid.
Katia's the one getting married.
This Saturday.
I have family here,
so we came for a visit.
- Is your wedding in town?
- At the Municipal Theater in Rio.
- It's another level, man.
- [Katia] Respect me, my love!
My cousin just got here.
I have to meet her at the door.
Me too.
I don't want to be a third wheel.
- [Paula] Me too.
- Argh!
Are you okay?
I'm a little dizzy.
I'll meet up with you guys.
- Definitely, girl!
- Okay.
- Come on over in a little bit!
- Yeah.
Does it feel better?
It still hurts.
- Where can we get it rinsed off?
- There's water inside here.
- [Paula] Wow! What is this place?
- [Teto] The greenhouse.
There's the water.
- Lift your face to stop the bleeding.
- But it hurts bad.
- It's fine now... Lift!
- Okay.
- Careful.
- Does it hurt?
- Just a little.
- The bleeding's almost stopped.
I don't think it's serious, but...
if I were you, I'd go home.
- Can someone drive you home?
- No, it's okay. I live here.
- Here.
- Yeah.
- Here at the Trancoso farm?
Oh, my God. You know these people?
My dad is the farm's... caretaker.
- So I live here.
- I see.
- Okay, got it.
- Yeah.
I want to go to college in Rio.
This town's become too small for me.
- You'll like Rio.
- I think so too.
New people, right?
Right.
I feel like I'm missing a lot
by staying here.
[soft instrumental music plays]
You're all good now!
[laughs]
- [Paula] Great.
- You're an excellent doctor.
Thanks.
I'm going to find my friends.
Okay. Do you like riding horses?
I don't know. I've never ridden. Why?
Want to ride now?
Now?
What do you say?
I'll show you all the animals.
- I can't now.
- No? Okay, then.
I need to go find my friends.
And you should rest.
- Doctor's orders.
- Okay, doctor.
Tomorrow then?
- [Teto] Tomorrow?
- I'm going back to Rio tomorrow.
- But nice meeting you.
- You too.
- Bye.
- Thanks.
You're welcome.
I'll see you.
Perhaps in Rio, right?
[birds chirping]
[car horn honking]
[soft instrumental music playing]
[Teto] What is this?
I can't believe it!
Happy birthday, son.
Consider it an additional benefit
of your new job in our company.
Well, Dad, I wanted to talk with you
- about this whole working...
- Teto!
You're an adult now.
I don't want my grown-up son
acting like a teenager.
I've given you a car,
a job at the company...
From now on,
no more money or allowance.
- The rest is up to you.
- No, I do want the job at Trancoso,
but not only because I'm your son.
I want to earn it.
- [Teto] Get it?
- Okay.
Hey. Let's talk a minute.
I want to make you an offer.
Thanks, Teto, but no betting for me.
I need to get to class today.
And I want to help you. It's a real offer.
No advantages, no privileges.
You need to understand that my dream
is going to Rio.
- And college is the only way to do that.
- You were right.
I'll miss you when you go.
You're my brother, my friend.
- You're right.
- Relax. It'll be a while.
I'm off to Rio and want you to come along.
So it's up to you.
- [Igor] You're going to Rio after a girl?
- [Teto] She's different.
[chuckles] Sure. She rejected you.
She's a rare specimen.
I confess I liked
being treated like a regular person.
It must've been a shock.
So I signed up for the Trancoso
trainee program in Rio.
I want to be chosen
without being identified.
So what's the bet?
You sign up too,
but you use my name, and I use yours.
- Dude...
- No, listen!
There's only one spot.
We'll compete against each other.
If you win, this car is yours.
So?
["The Edge Is On The Sun"
by Diego Fragoso et al. playing]
- [valet] Good afternoon, Mr. Teto.
- What's up, Zé?
Can you wash the car?
It needs some TLC.
Manuel, could you help us
with the luggage?
[valet] Careful, Manuel. It's heavy.
Are we really staying here,
facing the sea?
It's my dad's pied-à-terre
for when he comes to Rio.
- [Teto] Good afternoon.
- [woman] Good afternoon.
["Long Road"
by Diego Fragoso feat. Walter playing]
[Teto] Come on in.
♪ I'm saying don't worry ♪
♪ Love will bring you home... ♪
This is a pied-à-terre?
I'm gonna take my dad's bedroom,
and you stay in mine.
I have somewhere to be,
but make yourself at home. Okay?
♪ And it's a long road... ♪
Your invitation, sir.
I forgot it.
- Okay, go ahead.
- Thanks.
♪ For you ♪
♪ It's a long road ♪
♪ For you, you, you ♪
["Sometimes" by
Diego Fragoso and Gianni Petrarca plays]
[Teto] Hey, dude. How's it going?
- Hello. Can I help you, sir?
- How about we switch outfits?
- I need to work.
- How much will you make tonight?
This suit is worth about $2,000.
You can keep it.
[guard] Hey, broom boy!
There's a guy throwing up on the porch.
Go on. Go on!
[Teto] Excuse me. Thanks.
[Teto gags]
Here, man. Clean it up yourself.
Look here, son.
I spilled food on my dress.
- You did? That's too bad.
- Yes.
Do you have a rag to wipe it off?
Pay attention, boy!
There you go.
- He's coming here.
- May I sit with you guys?
Come on.
Let me introduce you to someone.
Paula, are you avoiding me?
I came over to talk
because I feel like you're avoiding me.
Not at all, doctor.
- Excuse me, son...
- Not now.
I'm busy. Find someone else. Not now.
Teto?
I can't believe it!
How are you, beautiful?
You're calling me "beautiful"
because you forgot my name, right?
Of course not, beautiful. No way.
So, what are you doing here?
The bride, Katia, is my cousin.
- What are you doing here?
- Working.
The tomato prince working as a janitor?
Is there a problem? Any judging?
[Paula] Excuse me.
- [Ana] No judging at all.
- Listen,
I can't stand here very long,
or I'll be fired, you know?
I'll talk to you later, okay, beautiful?
I will take care of it. Just leave.
- No!
- What?
- The guy from the farm.
- Right.
- Yes, the guy from the farm.
- Teto.
- You remembered! Cool.
- I did.
- What a coincidence!
- Totally.
- You, here.
- Yeah.
- Totally.
- I told you I was coming to Rio,
- remember?
- Yeah, I remember.
So here I am. I left everything behind
and chased my dream.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Wow!
Awesome! I admire your courage.
Some things are worth the sacrifice.
Like meeting you here.
Paula?
- We're not done talking yet. Right?
- Buddy, we're talking here. Excuse me.
[laughs] Come on. Let's go.
You're welcome.
That idiot was hitting on you.
He was, wasn't he?
- I think so.
- I thought so too.
Well, Doctor, excuse me.
["Ocean" by Alok, Zeeba and IRO playing]
Let's get out of here.
Uh-huh.
Have you been to the beach
since you got here?
- No, not yet.
- Really?
So you've never seen the ocean?
I can't believe it!
That's so exciting!
- I showed you the ocean?
- Yeah.
- How nice.
- It's really exciting. I'm...
- My heart is...
- I can imagine it.
- It's big, isn't it?
- Indeed.
We didn't have money to travel.
So my dad would make me pick tomatoes
during school vacations.
Ever since I was little.
Oh, my God!
I'm sorry, but that's exploitation,
- having a child work like this.
- Yeah. It was tough.
Sometimes all we had to eat were tomatoes.
That's rough.
But that's life.
You know, if you want to be someone,
you have to work for it.
That's how it is.
Tomorrow, for example,
I'm starting the trainee program
at Trancoso Rio
to try and start working there.
There's only one spot for grabs.
We'll see, right?
With your determination,
I'm sure you'll get in.
I have to go now.
- Early day tomorrow.
- Sorry.
- I'm really sorry.
- No, my bad because... It's okay.
I'm graduating med school.
I have to get a residency,
so I have to focus.
- You get it, right?
- Sure.
Bye.
- Good morning.
Didn't you say nobody would know you?
No way!
Are you kidding me?
They canceled me already!
Sweetheart, would you
help me out here?
Hey!
Damn it!
[Monique yelps]
[Teto] Are you okay?
- Do I look okay to you?
- Are you hurt?
No.
Getting canned was much worse.
- Were you fired?
- Yeah. I just signed a release.
- I'm sorry.
But I'm glad to be back in Rio.
I was sick of fresh air, country music,
organic food...
I never want to see a tomato again.
Excuse me.
We're living here in Rio too.
We're in the Trancoso trainee program.
I wanna start from the bottom
just like you.
- [scoffs]
- If they pick me, of course.
Get real, Teto. If they pick you?
You think no one will know who you are?
- See?
- I'm unknown at the headquarters in Rio.
But your name's still
Teodoro Trancoso Neto.
Excuse me. I have a resume to send out.
We're prepared for that.
- [man] Good morning
- [all] Morning.
Which one of you is Teodoro Trancoso?
- It's you.
- Right. That's me.
Nice meeting you. Célio Porto.
I'm the marketing director here.
- Hello.
- Can I call you Teto?
Well... sure.
Great, Teto.
I'm sure a young man
with your enterprising DNA
will do very well here.
- Welcome.
- [woman] Good morning, everyone!
Good morning, Célio.
Gather round, people.
I'm Alana, talent development consultant.
I was hired by Trancoso
to implement this trainee program.
Are you excited? So let's get started.
[Alana] Come on! The trainee program
offers participants one month
of experience here at Trancoso.
Upon completion, you all get
a certificate, but only one of you
will be hired.
Let's learn a little more
about the company's raw material.
Tomato is the vegetable
I know most about.
Tomato is a fruit.
- What's your name?
- Te... Igor.
Igor.
I hope you know more about coffee.
Why?
Yes?
I want you to pay special attention
to the president's son.
- Teodoro?
- Yes.
He's the famous Teto.
Paty de Alferes' own Don Juan.
Don Juan?
That kid?
[Célio] His father put a stop to that,
but the kid's always lived la vida loca!
[both laugh]
Okay. Don't worry.
I'll keep an eye on him.
[instrumental music plays]
[groans]
Teto, right?
- Yeah. Hi.
- I'm Alana.
- Nice to meet you.
- You too.
Rough hands! From working out?
I've never worked out.
It's from riding horses.
Oh, horses.
But riding is exercise too.
It's good for posture...
- Excuse me. Your coffee.
- [Alana] Thanks.
[gags, yelps]
Oh, my God, Igor!
This is the worst coffee I've ever had!
- Sorry, the machine was broken. I can...
- I can brew you some, if you want.
- Really?
- Farm-style.
Excuse me.
Igor? Igor.
Please print this out
for tomorrow's presentation.
How do I do this?
[machine beeping, whirring]
Hi, ma'am. I'm almost done.
You can call me Alana.
Sorry.
- It smells great.
- Yeah?
Mmm!
- Mm! Delicious.
- Great! I've made a lot of coffee.
I'm pretty impressed, Teto.
You could've come here,
in your dad's company,
giving out orders. Instead,
you decided to start from the bottom.
My experience as a recruiter has shown me
that admitting you have things to learn
is the first step
to becoming a good leader.
[Alana] Congrats.
[Igor] Thanks.
["Favela" by Alok & Ina Wroldsen playing]
Hi, Monique. How are you doing?
I need your help.
Could we meet?
♪ Her baby cries... ♪
[GPS] Turn right.
♪ She picks him up
and tells him beautiful lies again... ♪
[GPS] Rerouting.
♪ She come from the favela-la ♪
♪ Hills of Santa Teresa-sa ♪
♪ Underneath the Redeemer-mer... ♪
[GPS] Turn right.
Signal lost. Recalculating.
Monique, I think you gave me
the wrong address.
The GPS is taking me
to a really weird place.
- I need help.
- [Monique] Where are you?
♪ Favela ♪
♪ She works the favela night... ♪
[dog barking]
♪ Favela... ♪
Are you out of your mind?
Who drives a car like this here?
[tuts] Let's go to my place.
- [shots]
- That's gunfire! Get down!
[motorcycle revs]
Get up. You're embarrassing me.
I grew up here.
It's most people's reality. Come on!
Hey, there's even horses here!
I'm starting to feel at home.
Come in.
Excuse me.
- Cool digs.
- You're sitting on my bed.
Sorry.
[baby cries]
Hold on.
[Monique] Are you awake, sweetie?
Let's try not to wake mommy.
- Come here with auntie.
- [woman] Monique.
- [woman] You can give him to me.
- [Monique] No, no.
Don't worry. You have to get some rest.
Shh! Be quiet.
- Cute baby. Is he yours?
- He's my nephew.
But be quiet. I don't want him to wake up.
- Okay.
- My sister is sick,
so it's good that I'm in Rio.
But tell me, what do you need?
I need you to teach me
how to get the position
the way you did.
No privileges, just effort.
So now you want a teacher?
- My rates are high.
- Well, there's a tiny problem.
Dad cut off my allowances.
I don't want to ask him for money.
[exhales]
I'm very moved by your rich boy problems,
but I have more serious things
on my mind...
like getting a job, feeding a baby,
and getting my sister a doctor.
Do you need a doctor?
Do we really have to spend all this
- on a graduation party?
- Paula, it's once in a lifetime!
But why so fancy? Not everyone is loaded.
- Not everyone has to go.
- Go where?
To our graduation party.
I suggested this amazing club,
- but she wants a beach luau.
- Much cooler.
I like Paula's idea better.
But I'll go either way.
Loser.
If you don't tell him off, I will.
Calm down, Raissa.
I've sucked it up so far.
- He's not going to mess up my residency.
- Isn't that the guy from Paty?
- The one that got punched.
- Yeah.
[Paula] Teto?
- [Paula] Hi.
- I'm glad I found you.
[Paula] How are you?
I'm good. And you?
I really need your help.
Look at this. Look, Mateus.
Look!
[imitates car engine]
A car!
I have a hunch,
but we should run a few tests to be sure.
Isn't there any medication
she can start taking?
Well, I can't write prescriptions.
I'm not a doctor yet.
You aren't?
An intern? You promised me a doctor!
- She's about to graduate.
- And I'm about to kill you.
Look at my nose. Perfect, right?
A guy punched me, and she fixed it.
She's good.
Listen, Teto. You don't know me,
and you will not screw with me.
- Is that clear?
- That's not my intention.
I want to make you an offer.
If you help me,
and I get the position at Trancoso...
my car is yours.
- That car?
- Yes. Convertible,
four-by-four, brand new.
It's worth a year of your salary.
[scoffs]
That car's worth much more than that.
But are you seriously going to give me
your car
- if I help you?
- Yeah.
Only if I get to be hired.
Otherwise, I promised it to Igor.
[Paula] Uh-huh.
Right, perfect.
- She'll be there tomorrow.
- [whispers] You got it?
Thank you so much! Take care. Bye.
- [Monique] So?
- You're all set.
I scheduled your sister for an appointment
and some exams
- at the hospital tomorrow.
- Thank you!
I can't thank you enough, Paula.
- Thanks.
- No problem.
Teto, I love your girlfriend.
- Beautiful soul.
- No.
- No, we're just friends.
- We're just getting to know each other.
- We'll be dating in a couple of days.
- [Paula] What?
- The day after tomorrow.
- He's such a joker!
[Teto] Sorry about the hassle, okay?
[Paula] Don't worry about it.
You don't know how good it is
to feel useful, you know?
Reminds me why I want to be a doctor.
Let me make it up to you.
Go out with me.
[both chuckle]
You've got a lot of nerve, kid.
I was serious when I said
I didn't need any distractions.
Look at me.
Am I a distraction?
I'm a serious guy. Look.
- So?
- Okay.
- Okay. When I have a day off.
- Tomorrow.
- Tomorrow? No, kid.
- Why not?
[doorbell chiming]
[Monique] Hi. Where's Teto?
- [Monique] Teto!
- [Igor] He's asleep.
[Monique] Teto?
Teto! [tuts]
- Get up!
- No, no, no.
- [Teto] Stop it.
- Don't be lazy!
First lesson: if you don't have money
or references,
stay ahead of the game.
While people are asleep,
before problems arise,
you have to have the solution.
Is she helping you out?
Yeah.
You lose, cutie pie.
I'm getting the car. Right?
- Get up. Come on.
- No, no.
[uptempo instrumental music playing]
- Hey.
- Good morning.
- Are you guys starting early?
- No. Just me.
Excuse me.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
One for you.
Everyone please take good care
of this manual.
It's very important, so...
- Where did you get that?
- Igor printed it out.
Alana...
our marketing department changed
strategy last night again.
Igor? Who told you to print this out?
- No one. I just thought...
- No! Trainees shouldn't think!
Shred all these pages, please.
I'm sorry, Célio.
Let me give you a hand.
Teto, come join the group.
You're missing important information.
Come!
If they're picking on you,
you need an ally.
How do I get one?
This is our new tomato sauce.
Management wants you
to make suggestions for the ad campaign.
It's a good opportunity
if you want the job.
Excuse me, Mr. Célio.
Do you have a minute?
- Sure.
- [Teto] So...
I was thinking of this marketing exercise
we were just given,
and also the ad campaign.
And I'd like to take some samples home.
Is that okay?
- [Célio] Igor.
- That's me.
Igor, you want to take work home?
- Catch!
- Stop, kid.
- What do I do with this?
- I don't know.
You've already stood out,
so just think up a strategy
- to impress people.
- Speaking of impressing...
I want to take Paula on a date.
I want to impress her. I need your help.
Mmm!
I was thinking of taking her
somewhere nice.
But it can't be too expensive...
because I told her
my dad's the farm's caretaker.
Are you kidding me?
You get a great girl, and you lie to her?
I should hit you, not help you.
How will I know if someone likes me
- or my money?
- Blah, blah, blah.
- Got it?
- Okay, I'll help you.
At least in Rio you can still have fun
on a tight budget.
First, do you know how to take a bus?
Well... in theory, yeah. It's easy, right?
["Favela" by Alok & Ina Wroldsen playing]
[Monique] Pay attention.
When your stop is coming up,
make sure you're near the door.
Excuse me. Sorry.
Driver, wait!
Driver, hold on!
[Teto] Jeez!
Hey! Did you see that?
Come with me.
[Monique] And forget the playboy bars.
There's only one place
that will impress her.
That's so cool.
What is this place?
- You've never been here?
- No.
- It's cool.
- I love it.
- Do you know any steps?
- I know this one.
- See?
- What the hell is that?
Country-style dancing. You dig?
Never mind that. I mean funk dance steps.
- Show me what you know.
- Funk?
[Brazilian funk music plays over speaker]
You suck.
You've never danced funk, have you?
I'll teach you.
- One. Two.
- One...
- [Monique] Three. Four.
- Two...
And one.
Two. Three. Four.
One. Two.
Come back on three.
And four is the base.
One. Two. Three. Four.
That was awful!
Four. And one.
Two. There you go!
- No! No, no!
- Come on. Let's go.
- No, I don't know how!
- Just follow my lead.
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ For you are the one ♪
♪ Stay here with me ♪
♪ No use to wait til sunrise ♪
♪ For you are the one ♪
♪ Baby ♪
♪ Baby, stay here with me ♪
♪ No use to wait til sunrise ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Sunrise, baby ♪
If my mother saw me here,
she'd have a fit.
- Because you're dating a poor guy?
- Yeah. No. Kinda.
[both laugh]
My parents were always broke
while they were married.
Since their divorce,
my mom's only dated rich guys.
That way, she could have her freedom,
she said.
But it's always been the opposite.
I think when you...
depend on someone else,
you nullify yourself, you know?
You erase yourself.
What is it?
That made me think of my mom.
She died two years ago.
She lived for my dad.
I wonder if she nullified herself.
She probably had her own dreams.
I think your mom would be proud to see you
freeing yourself from your dad,
from your past, and chasing your dreams.
Would she?
I know I am.
[romantic music plays]
Let's go to your place.
No.
- Okay then.
- It's just that it's messy.
It's a huge mess.
You don’t have to be ashamed
of your home.
- Of anything.
- Let's go to a motel.
- Where?
- A motel.
Never mind. No...
No, no, no. That was nuts.
We'll go to my place. I'm calling a cab.
- That was crazy.
- We can just call it off.
No, we don't have to. Relax.
EMERGENCY! I NEED HELP!
I'm requesting it. There.
- Okay.
- Three minutes.
Mr. Francisco! Mr. Francisco!
Wake up, Mr. Francisco.
- Rat! Rat!
- There's no rat here, Mr. Francisco.
- Teto needs your help.
- You mean "ceiling"?
[Teto] Thanks, man.
Is this where you live?
I'm crashing at my uncle's.
- You got it, right?
- Yes. Look, they're here.
Let me go welcome them.
Oh, this way...
- Uncle.
- Good evening, Mr. Teto.
"Mister," uncle?
You didn't have to get the door.
It's my job.
He's something.
I'm Paula. Nice to meet you.
How are you?
Do you want the screwdriver?
- Oh, the little room key.
- Yeah, that key.
- Hang on. Here you go.
- Thanks, uncle.
- Have a good shift.
- [Francisco] Good night.
- [Teto] See you later.
- [Paula] Bye.
Have fun, okay?
[both laugh]
Ignore him.
- Look, this is temporary, okay?
- It's okay, Teto. I know.
I'll find a better place soon.
Relax.
Careful.
Be careful. Don't be shocked, okay?
[Paula] Okay.
Come on, Teto...
it's not that bad.
It's horrible.
Sorry. I'm so embarrassed!
I shouldn't have brought you here.
- It's perfect.
- No, it isn't.
- Really.
- No.
You're sleeping here tonight.
[Paula] Oh, my God.
- Is it heavy?
- No.
Wait, wait... Got it.
[Teto] Careful.
- [Paula] Yeah...
- Much better.
- [Paula] You were right.
- You see?
[soft romantic music playing]
[Teto] What a strange feeling.
What feeling?
That I don't need anything else.
[Alana] A fountain?
- A tomato sauce fountain?
- That's my idea.
We'd put a fountain
in every point of sale,
such as malls, supermarkets,
and so on.
[chuckles]
I'm sorry.
But no. No, right?
We're not rejecting any ideas
at this point.
I really like Teto's idea better.
[Alana] Show them the Trancoso mascot.
The Trancoso mascot
is a character that represents
a happy premium tomato.
Yes. He's well-traveled, sophisticated,
speaks many languages...
- [Igor] He's premium.
- [Alana] Premium.
I also thought we could create
shareable content
to increase social media engagement.
Perfect. That's the goal, Teto.
We want people to promote
the brand spontaneously.
- Exactly.
- But I like the fountain idea.
It speaks to an adult market as well.
Okay. So, if we like both ideas,
let's put both Igor and Teto on it.
Hi. How are you? Could I wait in here?
I'm meeting someone who works here. Teto.
- It's raining.
- I couldn't help overhearing.
- Are you meeting Teto?
- Yeah.
I'll take you to him. Come on in.
Let her go through, please.
- Is she clear? Great.
- Thanks.
- What's your name?
- Paula.
- Is it company business?
- No.
- I'm a friend of his.
- Teto's famous "lady friends"!
- What?
- What do you mean, "famous"?
- No, I said...
No! It's just what people say.
He looks so well-behaved,
- but those are the worst ones, right?
- I don't get it.
I'm kidding, silly!
- It will be interes... What is it?
- Duck! Duck!
- [Paula] Thank you.
- Paula's in there with Alana, bro!
Shit will hit the fan.
Is everything okay?
- It's just that...
- Well, Alana. That...
That girl that just came in...
I can't really deal with her right now.
Right.
- I shouldn't do this...
- [Igor] Hm-mm.
...but I will help you.
There's an emergency exit over there.
Go, go, go...
- Get down!
Sorry.
[Alana] Go. Turn right.
I'll be right there. Wait for me.
Do what you have to do.
I think I'll go home.
Your friend is going to think I'm crazy!
- This Paula's a crazy stalker.
- I see.
Paula! That Alana is crazy!
- She's out to get me!
- Why, Teto?
She doesn't want me to get the job.
She's protecting the president's son.
That's why.
Look at me.
Come here.
Do you trust me?
- You owe me one.
- [car alarm chirps]
Now you have to take me to dinner
at a nice restaurant.
Well, Alana...
Well what? Are you scared of me?
Well... instead of taking you
to a restaurant,
- I could cook at home for you.
- Get out of here!
You cook too?
Hm-mm.
- I'm in.
- Really?
- Let's do it.
- Okay.
- Do you need help?
- No, that's okay.
- Thanks.
- My pleasure.
I hope you like it.
- Spaghetti.
- Taste it. It's my favorite recipe.
- Tomato sauce, right?
- Tomato sauce.
With hot dogs.
[Alana] Mm...
I forgot the wine. I'll go get it.
I'm not eating much. I'm on a diet.
[Igor] That's fine.
[dance music plays from stereo]
I've got these two.
"Chat-e-au Marga-ux"
or "Cabernette Sauvig-non".
Teto...
you are so cute. Did you know that?
Is this how you seduce girls?
- What?
- With this shyness.
- To tell you the truth, I don't know.
- You know.
Sure you do.
[sexy music playing]
[both laugh]
Now I want to see what you know.
- Can I tell you something?
- Shoot.
- No. Never mind.
- No, tell me. Now you have to tell me.
I don't know.
For a small-town...
guy...
a country kid...
you're different than I expected.
What did you expect?
I expected...
[cell phone chimes]
- What's that?
- It's my phone.
Teto, it's Monique.
Her sister is not well.
- Let's go there now.
- We'll stop by a drugstore.
- [Teto] A little further, buddy.
- [driver] It isn't safe at this hour.
[Paula] It's an emergency.
She's a doctor. Someone's sick in there.
I'm sorry, but it's too risky for me.
Risky for you? A woman is dying in there!
Miss, I've turned off the meter.
If you want, try a motorcycle taxi.
- Come on, Paula. Let's go!
- Unbelievable.
Thanks.
Teto?
["All The Lies"
by Alok, Felix Jaehn and The Vamps plays]
♪ Of all the lies I heard ♪
♪ "I love you" was my favorite... ♪
[Teto] Come on.
♪ I need to hear you say it ♪
♪ One time before I go ♪
♪ Whisper it slow ♪
♪ Of all the lies I heard
"I love you" was my favorite... ♪
[Monique] Thank God you're here.
- I'm freaking out.
- [Paula] Calm down. It's okay.
Not again, no!
It's a seizure. Teto, hold her down
so she doesn't get hurt.
We're not sure,
but it looks like diabetes.
- If it is, an insulin shot might help.
- Guys, what do I do?
- Take him, please.
- Me?
- Hold him, and I'll do that. Hold him.
- Calm down, guys.
- It's okay, sweetheart.
- Don't cry.
- I want Mommy!
- It's okay, Mateus.
- Help me out here. Don't cry.
[Mateus cries]
Do you like carrots? No?
I want Mommy!
An egg! Egg, egg.
Shit!
Mommy's coming soon.
It's okay.
I'm making something for you to eat.
Look! Yummy!
It's almost done, okay?
Look what your uncle made you!
Look how beautiful I made it.
Where's that mouth?
Open wide!
It worked.
- She's better, thank God.
- Great.
Look at that! Uncle Teto can cook!
Is it yummy?
I wish I had a picture
of the panicked look on your face
- when she handed you the baby.
- I totally freaked out!
But like you said,
it's great to feel useful.
That's right.
A little face!
- [Teto] A little face!
- [Paula] A little face!
Kids are so easily entertained, right?
It's easy to be happy.
We just complicate things.
[snoring]
Good morning, Teto.
I'm going to make us
some coffee, okay?
Alana? Are you up?
[Alana singing] ♪ Honey, you're the one ♪
♪ Who makes my mouth water ♪
♪ When you dress up ♪
♪ Or strip down ♪
- Good morning.
- [screams]
Mr. Teodoro?
Morning. Nice to meet you.
I'm Alana. You don't know me,
but I've been hired to work for you.
Here in the building?
No.
Not here. At the company.
You slept with Alana?
- How was that?
- Well...
It was good,
but I think I still need some pointers.
- That's cheating.
- Getting pointers?
- No, screwing our boss!
- Come on, Teto!
What have you always said?
- "Is it my fault this girl likes me?"
- No, that's different.
What you did is much worse.
You know it is.
It's what you do.
Only now you're on the receiving end.
Get rid of her before we get screwed.
- You've worked ever since you were 14?
- Hm.
I admire your stamina.
I don't mind.
No? I bet it's stressful.
The rats are the problem.
Rats?
We have to find their hiding places.
Right...
I get it! Rats can eat away at a company
- from the inside.
- Yes!
They build nests. They multiply...
- It's disgusting!
- [Alana] Teto!
You didn't tell me your dad was here.
It's an honor
to take in his words of wisdom.
[both laugh nervously]
Right... Hi, Dad.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
[Igor] Um...
Don't you have that meeting now?
- A meeting?
- Yeah.
Yeah, right.
Mr. Teodoro, it was a great pleasure.
We're late too. We'd better go change.
Yes, let's do that.
Great talk! I loved it.
- Me too.
- Bye, Dad.
I loved your dad!
He's so sophisticated
and simple at the same time!
And his view of the business world...
- He's a genius!
- Yeah, he's amazing.
Like father, like son.
You don't live up to your reputation.
- I don't?
- No. You're much better.
- I am?
- Yes.
Really?-
[upbeat instrumental music playing]
Igor.
I thought you'd given up on the job.
Teto is coordinating
the fountain prototype.
- He'll explain everything to you.
- That was my idea.
I should be coordinating...
Take it easy! Look at the time.
You've no right to say anything.
You're late.
I could expel you from the program,
but I won't.
And you know why?
I woke up in a good mood today.
I know.
["Table for 2" by Alok & IRO plays]
♪ You don't need a million reasons
to smile without a reason ♪
- Let me help you...
- ♪ I've got one, will you stay... ♪
- Did you see that?
- Yeah.
I've had it.
We have to do something about Dr. Victor.
♪ Love works in mysterious ways... ♪
What? Are you going to take a sedative?
♪ It's raining in the desert
I heard it... ♪
It's not for me.
♪ The sun won't even shine no more
Since I'm not there with you ♪
- ♪ I'll pick you up with flowers... ♪
- All good?
Let me show you something.
Hi. Coffee?
- [Paula] I'd love some! Thanks. You rock.
- [Victor] Thanks.
- May I?
- [Teto] Yeah.
♪ I'll stay here forever
I promise that it's true... ♪
[Teto groans]
♪ A table just for two... ♪
My bad.
- High blood pressure, fever, tiredness...
- ♪ I can make you breakfast ♪
♪ And you could be... ♪
- [Paula] Have you had a diabetes test?
- [patient] No, doctor.
[Katia] Doctor Victor.
[snoring]
Thanks.
- Is it good?
- Wanna know?
Come on.
Throw one. Go.
♪ It's raining in the desert
I heard it on the news ♪
♪ The sun won't even shine no more
Since I'm not there with you ♪
♪ I pick you up with flowers... ♪
MEDICAL LUAU
- ♪ A mattress and a table just for two ♪
- And you didn't want a luau!
[all laughing]
Hi, honey.
- Nice.
- You like it?
No! No, no!
- [Paula] I agree.
- [Teto] Right?
Don't forget my graduation party tonight.
Of course.
I'm going straight from Trancoso.
- Teto.
- Dad?
[chuckles]
Son!
- [Teto] How are you?
- [Teodoro] I'm fine.
- [Teto] You're here.
- Who's your friend?
- Paula.
- Nice to meet you.
- You too.
- Going somewhere?
- To Trancoso.
You can be late today.
- We need to talk.
- Okay.
- It's your job, Teto. Tell him.
- It's fine.
This is between me and my son.
With all due respect, sir,
your son is a grown-up.
- I'll talk to my dad.
- No, excuse me,
I didn't want to intrude,
but I couldn't. I'm sorry.
Your son's independent.
He's running his own life
and can do more than eat tomatoes.
Excuse me.
- Sorry about that.
- She's right.
- You have to take the job seriously.
- Okay.
We'll talk on the way to the office.
- Teto?
- He's not here yet.
What?
Oh, never mind. What is it?
You're wanted over there.
I heard your dad's having dinner
with the investors tonight.
- He is?
- Hm-mm.
And I heard that you'll be there too.
I will?!
Of course you will.
I understand you're trying
to start from the bottom,
but I have to prepare you
to swim with the sharks.
Fine.
Can I at least suggest a restaurant?
A nice place.
Sure.
- [Teto] Dude.
- [both] We have a problem.
- Dad wants me at this investors' dinner.
- Alana thinks I'm going.
I picked a restaurant
right by Paula's luau
- so I can go straight there after.
- Alana wants to join me.
- What do I tell her?
- Tell her she can't.
Alana is tough. She'll find her way there
and see you, instead of me.
Have the dinner at the same hotel,
Hotel Fairmont, in Copacabana,
but at the poolside restaurant.
And what about your dad?
And the investors?
They'll pay us the rest after dinner.
- But what should I say?
- Don't say anything.
We have to say something, right?
Relax! I'm used
to these rich people events.
It's better not to say anything.
See, guys? Rich for one day,
and that's how he treats us.
- Mr. Teodoro?
- Ah!
I'm Mr. Teodoro.
- [Francisco] How nice to see you again!
- [Alana] It's my pleasure.
Son!
My son!
Hello. I'm Alana.
Hi.
Hello. How are you?
How are you?
- He doesn't speak.
- What?
He doesn't speak Portuguese. He's French.
[in French]
Ah, no problem. I speak a little French.
- [in Portuguese] Do you speak German?
- No.
He's German. I got confused.
I'm thrilled, Teto,
to have you on our team.
I still have to earn the job. Right, Dad?
You've got the job. It's all set.
Don't do this. Please.
Look who's arriving.
- [man] What's up?
- [Victor] Congratulations!
Loser!
For God's sake, where's Teto?
- I'll be right back.
- No, no.
- No, not now. Don't!
- I'll be right back.
I need to use the restroom. Be right back.
Why implement talent development
in a company?
Companies that invest in talent
development get better results.
You are very wise to invest in Trancoso.
It's a proven way
to hire the most talented candidates.
Congratulations to the prettiest doctor
in Brazil!
- Thanks.
- Guys,
- shall we make a toast?
- Sure.
- Let's do it.
- [Raissa] Yours.
- [Victor] Look at that.
- Yours.
- And mine. A toast...
- Wait. Hold on.
I can't toast with this drink.
- Why not?
- No. This drink
has this little pink umbrella.
It should be Paula's.
- It's just an umbrella...
- Guys, whatever.
- Cheers!
- Paula, don't...
- No, this is...
- Congratulations to us!
Don't drink it.
- Teto!
- [bike bell chimes]
[man screams]
Teto!
- [Paula] Oh, my God. Teto! Are you okay?
- [Raissa] I'll hold this for you.
- [Teto] My leg hurts like hell.
- [Paula] Where?
[Teto] Everywhere.
- I can't move.
- I have painkillers. Want one?
- Yeah.
- Give me your hand.
- Here you go.
- [Teto] Thanks.
- No! Don't drink that!
- [Paula] Just a sip to take the pill.
[Teto grunts]
- What's wrong?
- [Paula] You're crazy. Let's...
What was that pill you gave me?
- It was Raissa!
- I'm 100%! Look!
What are you doing?
[romantic music playing]
I love you.
- I need to use the restroom.
- No, Teto. Go in the ocean.
No. Are you nuts? That's embarrassing.
- I'll be right back.
- What a prude!
[upbeat instrumental music plays]
Teto, where are you?
Damn, Teto! I was looking for you!
It was busy.
I was looking for another restroom.
Please don't interfere.
The best man should win. It's the rule.
The rule you made up.
I've already freed up the junior executive
position for you.
Monique's position?
I'm the reason you fired Monique?
Tell me, young man,
are you enjoying working with tomatoes?
Yes. It's a high demand product.
Tomatoes are used for many things:
ketchup, sauce, sweets...
- The peel is fibrous.
- Are you okay, son?
You can make anything with tomatoes.
Tomato lipstick, tomato liquor,
tomato pens, tomato jackets...
And it'll grow anywhere,
not just in big plantations like ours.
I can picture an entire town
where tomatoes grow on rooftops.
All you'd see from above were tomatoes.
Tomatoes! Tomatoes!
Tomatoes everywhere!
[phone vibrates]
I need to take this call. But you guys
stay here discussing the wonderful things
this amazing fruit has to offer
because, as you know, tomatoes are fruits!
[laughs]
♪ The night is so cold ♪
♪ There's no end ♪
Oh, my God. He's awful.
[Paula] Teto?
What happened?
Why are you all dressed up?
- Surprise!
- You're crazy, right?
Stay right there.
- [Teto] Could I play?
- Sure. Be my guest. Go ahead.
For you, Paula.
♪ Can you imagine ♪
♪ If we were ♪
♪ A little bolder in our... ♪
Stop it.
♪ Can you imagine ♪
♪ Turning ♪
♪ Our friendship
into a beautiful romance? ♪
♪ Pay attention to the things we do ♪
♪ We're already happier
than so many couples ♪
♪ Put your fear aside and let it happen ♪
♪ I have a proposal for you ♪
[all singing]
♪ Me, you, two kids and a dog ♪
♪ A comforter ♪
♪ A good film
The August chill ♪
♪ So are you in? ♪
Are you in, Paula?
[all] ♪ Me, you... ♪
Teto...
♪ And a dog... ♪
Teto! Teto, watch out!
Teto!
Oh, my God!
- What happened?
- I'm fine.
- You're acting weird. Is everything okay?
- Yeah. I'm great.
- Damn. I forgot.
- Forgot what?
My wallet.
- Wait right there.
- Teto.
- [Raissa] There's Ana.
- [Ana] Hey!
Cousin! I'm so glad you came!
I was able to catch the last bus!
- [Ana] How are you?
- [man] I'm fine, thanks.
So, what's Teto doing here?
He's dating my friend, Paula.
Remember her?
Ah!
[Katia] Paula, come here.
- Remember my cousin Ana, from Paty?
- Yeah. Hi. How are you?
So now we have a tomato princess?
A "tomato princess"?
[Alana] In my line of work,
if you look hard enough,
you might find a gem
where you least expect.
You should look in the trash dumpster
of our building.
Rich people's garbage is amazing.
[laughs nervously]
[all laugh]
Excuse me, everyone. Just a second.
- Take your suit off.
- Me?
- Give it to me. Come on!
- I'm not switching suits, Teto.
I need your suit. Please!
- Come on. I'm in a hurry!
- Chill, man!
I can't undress any faster.
- What will I say at the table?
- Nothing.
Stay here. I'll go say goodbye to Dad,
create an excuse, and come back.
Teto? Igor?
Isn't there a better time for you to do
whatever it is you're doing?
[both] You crazy?
It's not what it looks like!
I thought I could trust you, Teto!
You don't have to come back.
I'll make up an excuse!
I'm fucked.
You are? You're his son!
Imagine for me, son of the servants.
- You don't think of anybody else!
- Now's not a good time. Okay?
You can't deal with it, right?
Well, I can't deal with you today.
Shit!
[melancholic piano music plays]
Hey.
I found my wallet.
Filled with cash, right...
Teodoro Trancoso Neto?
You're such a liar, Teto!
You're such a liar! One internet search,
and I found out how futile you are.
You're ridiculous!
Paula!
- Paula, are you okay?
- Not now, Victor.
- [Paula] Give me a break.
- What's your problem?
My problem?
I'll tell you what my problem is.
My problem is I studied hard,
put in the effort,
and I was proud.
I felt respected at that hospital
until you started harassing me.
- That's my problem!
- Harassing you?
Who's harassing you?
Come on, man. It's amazing, isn't it?
The guy with the upper hand's never wrong.
I've told you a few times.
- I like you.
- Victor!
I gave you a few chances, right?
Why can't you give me one now
- as well?
- Let me go!
I recommended you for the residency.
- Let go of me!
- [Raissa] What are you doing?
Take your hands off her!
You know too well
Paula is the best person for the job.
And everyone knows what you're up to.
If you hurt her chances,
- they'll know why.
- You have it all wrong.
I was just telling Paula
she got the residency.
Thank you, professor.
But I no longer want it.
You've ruined that hospital for me.
[Katia] Paula, are you okay?
[woman] Teto?
Teto?
Paula?
[slowly] No, Teto.
Let's go.
If you ever need a talent development
consultant
or recruiter, just give me a call.
I'll give one to you, Mr. Teodoro.
Call.
[in English] Call.
[in Portuguese] Call.
Good night.
[all] Good night.
[Alana] Good night.
Auf wiedersehen. [laughs]
- Did you have a good time?
- I loved it!
Great! But don't go thinking
you're rid of me.
Shall we go to your place?
- No...
- Right. Your dad's there.
I have an idea.
[upbeat music plays]
[Teodoro] Tomato sauce runs in the veins
of the Trancoso family.
Generation after generation,
we've perfected our techniques
to create this premium tomato.
Now I'm going to show you a preview
of the campaign my son, Teto,
has been working on.
It's a campaign for our new tomato sauce
which brings together tradition,
innovation,
and, most importantly, love.
Teto!
Please, everyone, follow me
into the other room.
For God's sake.
[door slams]
[shouting in background]
What happened?
You were high yesterday,
so I brought you back to your house.
But don't worry.
I didn't take advantage of you.
Excuse me.
What's it, Dad?
Can you explain to me what's going on?
Since I got here,
I've seen you with three different girls,
- not to mention Igor!
- Calm down.
And what the hell is the doorman
doing in my bed?!
[snoring]
I don't know.
It's nothing like what you're thinking.
It's much worse, Teto!
Back home, I knew you were irresponsible,
but I'd hoped you'd matured!
You're mistaken!
I have changed.
Unfortunately,
that's very hard to believe.
- What's up?
- Can I crash here?
- What?
- I can't stay at my dad's anymore.
I don't want anything from him.
If you don't, fine, but I want my car.
Okay, you can stay,
but you'll have to help with everything.
Cleaning, cooking,
and taking care of the baby. Got it?
[instrumental music plays]
Paula!
- Stop. I want to talk to you.
- No, Teto.
Paula, please.
Excuse me, man.
You have to listen to me.
Please just hear me out.
Why should I, if all you've told me
since the day we met were lies?
I lied because I didn't know who I was.
Paula, when you're rich,
people lie to you.
You can't distinguish real friends
from those after your money.
Right. You have to lie
so that people tell you the truth?
It's simple. If you want good friends,
be a good friend.
You want people to think
you're a good guy, be one,
- but you weren't!
- Well, you see,
I didn't know what I wanted. And now I do.
I want the two of us, together.
I'm going away.
I signed up for a physician volunteer
program in the Amazon.
I'll be there for a while.
Really?
Really.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
Good luck.
It'll be cool.
Teodoro, I think this was the best group
of trainees we've ever had.
- And Teto was the best candidate.
- Teto?
He's proactive. He's smart.
He'll make a difference here.
He's my pick for the job.
[exhales]
Célio, I've always respected you.
So respect me and tell me the truth.
I don't need ass-kissers.
But I'm telling you the truth.
Your son was excellent.
Although there was another boy
who was just as good.
Better. Go ahead and say it.
The whole concept for the campaign,
for example, was his.
We should hire them both.
No, Célio. We are only hiring one person.
You pick the best one.
The best one, Célio.
[Monique] Let's go!
Get up! Come on!
- No!
- Come on. Let's go!
Today's your day. Come on.
CONGRATULATIONS, TRAINEES!
Hi, cutie pie.
Where are the keys to my car?
[whispering] Champ! Champ! Champ!
Hello. I'm so sorry, sir,
but I need you to move to another seat.
What?
Yes, please. This seat is reserved
for the company president.
Alana, you two
haven't been formally introduced.
Teodoro Trancoso.
- No.
- [Célio] Alana
was our coach for this trainee program.
- No... But he isn't...
- Shall we start the ceremony?
Sure.
Good evening.
[audience] Good evening.
I'd like to thank
the illustrious presence...
of Mr. Teodoro...
and to congratulate
this group of trainees.
Before handing out the certificates,
I'm going to call Mr. Célio,
and he will announce
which one of you was selected
to be a junior executive.
Célio, please.
Junior executive?
We have several outstanding candidates
in this class,
but unfortunately, only one position.
And the job goes to...
Teto.
[Alana yelps excitedly]
Come on up!
[applause continues]
What's wrong? Go.
That's not me.
It's you. Go on.
[Célio] Here he comes!
- What's going on?
- Later.
Igor?
What's going on here, Célio?
I'd like to thank you all
for this opportunity.
But I can't take the job...
because I'm not Teto.
Teto, come over here!
That is Teto.
[dramatic music playing]
- And who gets the job?
- Nobody.
Exactly.
This job should never have been offered.
It was taken from someone
who deserves it more than I do.
I'm up here to apologize to you,
Monique.
And to all of you
for the situation I've created.
I'm sorry.
[Monique] Excuse me. Excuse me.
[Alana and Monique] Teto.
That Teto.
Leaving without talking to me?
Was it this stupid little plan of yours
- that cost me my job?
- I didn't know.
I didn't mean to take anybody's job.
I didn't know you'd like me...
Or rather, Teto.
I couldn't care less about Teto.
I've spent my entire life taking shit,
being interrupted and underestimated
by guys like Teto.
I was much more interested
in the sensitive,
attentive guy
with this beautiful smile
than in a stupid status of an heir.
So you're not upset
I'm the caretaker's son?
- The son of whom?
- I don't have a cent to my name.
- I live with my parents...
- Just shut up before I change my mind.
It was a bet. We lost, and Igor won.
Only because everyone
thought he was the boss's son!
[Monique] So he doesn't deserve the car.
Wait! I agree with you.
- I don't want the car.
- No, wait.
Calm down. Don't do anything rash.
Of course you want the car.
- What is it?
- Here, Teto.
No returns. A bet is a bet. You know.
Fine, but I want my car. Give me the key.
- Fine. I don't need it.
- No.
This car is worth at least $60,000.
- He wants it. He won the bet.
- Take it.
- [Alana] No.
- [Monique] Thanks.
Guys, how about if everyone
keeps the car?
You mean sell it and share the money?
Among yourselves?
No, not share it. Invest it.
Invest in what, for God's sake?
Something that will get us somewhere.
ONE YEAR LATER
[all] Surprise!
CHEERS, TETO!
Happy birthday, big boy.
I've always believed in you, son.
Me too!
In both of you!
- [Igor] Happy birthday, partner.
- Thanks, guys.
But you didn't have to, really.
I agree, but what could I do?
- The community insisted.
- Right. What could you do?
HAPPY BIRTHDAY
- [Rose] Happy birthday.
- [door buzzes]
- [horse neighs]
- [Teto chuckles]
- There. Now everyone's here.
- That's right.
Hi.
It's been quite a while.
Right?
How are you?
I'm fine. And you?
I had to come here. I was curious.
I was in Roraima
when I heard about your project.
- I was very curious.
- Want a tour?
- Yeah.
- Shall we go?
- Yeah. Excuse me.
- After you.
- Your dad?
- Yeah. He's one of my clients.
Our clients, actually.
The company is co-owned by Monique,
myself, and Igor, who's in college.
And his wife, Alana, works for us.
- Hi.
- Hi! Paula, right?
Yes. One of the "famous" ones.
[all laugh]
- Shall I show you the project?
- Excuse me.
- Okay.
- See ya.
Every resident can earn extra income
by growing premium tomatoes.
It's all organic. Pretty cool.
Wow!
FRESH TETO
- "Fresh Teto"?
- I was against it.
[soft instrumental music plays]
Teto...
I'm impressed.
Paula, I'd like to thank you.
I wouldn't be who I am today
if I hadn't met you.
Look at this.
Look how pretty.
- It's beautiful! Yeah!
- Isn't it?
It's ours.
What are you doing?
Sorry! Sorry!
I waited a long time for that.
Satisfied?
Not yet.
["All The Lies"
by Alok, Felix Jaehn and The Vamps plays]
♪ "I love you" is my favorite ♪
♪ I know goodbyes, they hurt ♪
♪ I need to hear you say it ♪
♪ One time before I go ♪
♪ Whisper it slow ♪
♪ Of all the lies I've heard
"I love you" was my favorite ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh, say it slow ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh, say it ♪
♪ "I love you" was my favorite ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh, say it slow ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh, say it ♪
♪ "I love you" was my favorite ♪
♪ If only you and him were good friends ♪
♪ Known him since you've been at school ♪
♪ Told me I was overthinking like I do ♪
♪ You said I didn't need to worry
We'd get along 'cause he's so cool ♪
♪ Girl, you must've thought
I was some kind of fool ♪
♪ You tell me all the things
I wanna hear ♪
♪ When I'm gone
You say you want me near ♪
♪ You look me in the eyes
Say that we will stay for life ♪
♪ These feelings that we caught
won't disappear ♪
♪ Of all the lies I heard ♪
♪ "I love you" was my favorite ♪
♪ I know goodbyes, they hurt ♪
♪ I need to hear you say it ♪
♪ One time before I go ♪
♪ Whisper it slow
Of all the lies I heard ♪
♪ "I love you" was my favorite ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh, say it slow ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh, say it ♪
♪ "I love you" was my favorite ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh, say it slow ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh, say it ♪
♪ "I love you" was my favorite ♪
♪ Of all the lies I heard ♪
♪ I know goodbyes, they hurt ♪
♪ I need to hear you say it ♪
♪ One time before I go ♪
♪ Whisper it slow ♪
♪ Of all the lies I heard ♪
♪ "I love you" was my favorite ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh, say it slow ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh, say it ♪
♪ "I love you" was my favorite ♪
[song continues]
["The Edge Is On The Sun"
by Diego Fragoso et al. playing]
♪ Take me, you've made it ♪
♪ The edge is on the sun ♪
♪ All my tears can make it ♪
♪ The meaning of the feeling ♪
♪ Ooh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Keeping on, I just can't see this ♪
♪ Nobody will know
But you can save your heart ♪
♪ Fake the way you make it ♪
♪ And waited for the sun ♪
♪ Healing, you're dreaming ♪
♪ The edge is on the sun ♪
♪ Ooh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Take me, you've made it ♪
♪ The edge is on the sun ♪
♪ All my tears can make it ♪
♪ The meaning of the feeling ♪
♪ Ooh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Keeping on I just can't see this ♪
♪ Nobody will know
But you can save your heart ♪
♪ Fake the way you make it ♪
♪ And waited for the sun ♪
♪ Healing, you're dreaming ♪
♪ The edge is on the sun ♪
♪ Ooh-oh-oh ♪