- Jerk boss.
Mediocre policies.
Should have known better.
I should have known better,
should have known better.
What?
- Oh honey, I came
as soon as I heard.
- How sweet of you.
Did you bring me--
- Comfort food?
I brought you cookies and wine.
- Cheep wine?
- Just like in college.
- Mm.
And he let me go.
- That ain't right.
- And he said it was layoffs.
- But I know it's
just he didn't like me
because I stood up to him.
But you know what, Kat?
Greener pastures ahead.
- A agree.
You know what, you didn't need
to work at the mall anyway.
You have a degree.
- In religion.
- Okay, so then
work at a church.
- Work at a, churches
are full of drama,
and you know I don't do drama.
- I just saw a position
today at our church.
- For what?
- Executive pastor.
- Executive pastor?
- Mmhmm.
- Executive pastor.
- Hello, Pastor's office.
Yes.
No.
Is that it?
Okay.
Your 5:00 canceled.
Yes?
Mr. Sandro, I already told you,
once the pastor gets
one free second,
he will investigate a new oven.
Until then you're just
gonna have to make due.
Okay, bye.
- Sabrina, Sabrina,
you don't have to monitor
my time like this.
Mr. Sandro's been
waiting a long time
for me to fix that
oven since February.
- I know, but you have
your 2:00 and your 3:00
and then you have
the deacon's meeting
and marriage counseling,
I just don't think
you can fit him in.
- I always got time for
stuff that's important.
- It is not important.
A new stove is not gonna help
that man cook any better.
- What'd you say?
- Oh nothing.
- Grace Hightower,
how are you dear?
- I'm fine, Pastor,
just fine, and you?
- He's busy.
- Yes, I am, what
can I do for you?
- Yesterday I heard that
there was a job opening
here at the church,
is that right?
- Yes.
We have an opening
for executive pastor.
Pastor Frank quit and so we
are in desperate need of help.
I mean we are in desperate need.
You know anybody
that's interested?
- Yes, Pastor, myself.
- Excellent, I think you'd
make a great candidate.
- Well you haven't
seen this yet.
- Well, that's amazing, Pastor,
I didn't even think
you would think
I was qualified to do it,
but I'll tell you this,
I have great
management experience,
as well as volunteer
service here at the church
as well as college ministry.
- I know, I know.
Sabrina, you think we have
time for an interview?
- Now?
Sir, I'm gonna have
to advise against it.
You have a media team
meeting in only 20 minutes.
- And like I can,
but I'm not prepared.
I didn't even think you
would take my application.
- Actually, we got time
for a group interview.
-  What?
- Yes, Sabrina, Grace,
you both applied for
the same position
so let's step into my office
and have a group session.
So, what makes you a good
fit for this position?
- Well, I am intimately
familiar with the duties
of both the pastor and
the executive pastor
as I've worked for both of
you for the past two years.
- Hm, Grace?
- Well, I worked in a department
store for over eight years
so I have a lot of
executive like duties
that I did over there.
- Like what?
- Managed people,
inventory control, payroll,
I pretty much ran the entire
day-to-day activities
over there.
- Hm, and what is your
greatest weakness?
- Well, I have to say,
my greatest weakness is
I'm too meticulous, focusing
on tasks with perfection.
I mean, I just
don't like to have
things fall through the cracks.
- Hm, that sounds good, Grace.
- That's good.
My greatest weakness
would be um,
I care about people too much.
The last job that I was with,
it was a business
about making money,
but people would come in,
employees would come in
and they would ask for
advances against their checks,
you know, and I would feel
sorry for them, Pastor.
And so I think that's the
reason why I got fired.
- Mm.
- Sir, is there anything
that I can help you with?
After all, that is my job.
- I just got an email from Haiti
and I'm about to leave on
an emergency right away.
- Right now?
- Yes.
And I'm gonna leave
you two in charge.
-  What?
- Good morning, Sabrina.
- Morning.
- Hm, up early.
- I always do, something
the pastor really likes.
- Hm, did he make
it okay yesterday?
- Uh, I haven't heard
from him, but uh,
I will follow up when he
should arrive at the orphanage.
- Okay, good.
Um, so um,
where do I sit?
- I was thinking the lobby.
- Shouldn't I have a desk?
- Well this is my desk
and the only other
desk is the pastor's
and I really don't think it's
appropriate for you to use it.
- Okay so um, what
am I supposed to do?
Just work on my phone?
- Huh, that works for me.
- I have an idea.
Why don't we switch.
Why don't you work
here in the morning
and then I'll come
in the afternoon
and I'll work here on the desk.
- Like I said, this is my desk.
I know where everything is.
It is organized with
optimal efficiency
and ergonomics in mind.
For me to leave this desk,
would send this church
into a downward spiral
of tragedy and disaster,
particularly when
the pastor is gone.
- Mm.
- Actually, it would just be
really awkward with you here.
- Mmhmm, yeah.
Awkward all right.
Oh God.
Listen, Sabrina, I
understand that you feel like
you are more qualified
than me, that's fine.
But the pastor put
both of us in charge.
We've got to stay here and
work together as a team.
- See, it would be nice
if I needed the help,
but I have this
all under control.
Personally, I think that the
pastor felt sorry for you
because you got fired
for being too nice.
- Mm, that was uncalled for.
- Just like you being here.
- This is a church.
We're supposed to be a team.
I'm not here for this bull--
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
what in the Siegfried and
Roy is going on in here?
- Oh, Deacon Thompson, I'm
sorry, did she disturb you?
- Well, I'm having a
prayer meeting over there.
I'm hearing all this
bickering over here.
Now what's the problem?
- Oh, we just were
having a bit of conflict
about a job opening.
- Oh, what job opening?
- Uh, the executive
pastor position.
- Executive pastor position?
First time I'm
hearing about this.
- Well, I heard
about it from Kat.
- The wino's daughter?
Look, as head deacon, I should
at least know about this.
- Well I am so sorry.
I forgot to post it
on the church website,
but probably won't
need it anyway.
- Well why is that?
- Well because the
pastor has placed myself
and her--
- And me.
- In charge in his absence.
So you know,
I guess whoever does the
best will get the position.
- Well what is
this position pay?
- 60 grand, vision,
health, retirement--
- And, we get what?
-  The church house.
- Church house, you
mean the two bedroom,
the two bath, garage, that
grill and basic cable?
-  You sound
like a game show host.
- And a jacuzzi, right?
-  Mmhmm.
- I could use that bump.
- Mmhmm.
- Well, hey, where's
the pastor at anyway?
- Oh, he went to Haiti.
- Haiti?
-  Yeah.
- When the pastor gets back,
I need to talk to
him immediately.
You hear me, right?
- Loud and clear.
- Thank you.
Jacuzzi, oh yeah!
- S'cuse me, can I help you?
- Miss Grace, that you honey?
-  Yes--
- How you doing?
- I'm fine, Miss. Pumpkin.
How can I help you today?
- No, I'm looking for Pastor.
- Oh well I'm here
in his absence.
Is there something
that I can do for you?
- Uh, I'll just
talk to Sabrina--
- No, no, no, that's
what I'm here for.
I'm here to help.
What can I do for you today?
- Okay, well,
I need to talk to the pastor
about these choir robes.
- Uh huh.
- I mean, they're old and
frayed and we keep altering 'em
instead of replacing
'em with new ones.
- Okay well then how
much does it cost?
- I don't know, Sabrina
does all of that.
- Okay, well let me help you.
Let me figure
something out for you.
Okay, how many robes is it?
- 34.
- Okay, okay, wow, that's a lot.
I didn't know we had that
many people in the choir.
- Well you know, it
takes a lot to make
a joyful noise like us,
you know what I mean?
-  Yes, yes.
Okay, so, oh, I'm gonna
find a price point for you
and I'll be in contact
with you and let you know
how much it costs--
- No, look,
I'm just gonna deal
with Sabrina 'cause
working with you is redundant,
but I really do appreciate you.
I mean, I really do.
-  Miss
Pumpkin, how are you?
- Hi.
Sabrina, my girl.
- Miss Grace.
- Yes, oh hi Mr. Sandros.
- I heard you talking
about these robes.
- Uh huh, yeah, are
you in the choir?
- No, I'm a cook and I came
to see you about an oven,
a brand new gas, we've
got to have a gas oven.
- I know and I heard that you're
one of the best cooks here.
- Chicken and dumplings.
- Look, I need some money.
- Okay, but the thing is,
we don't have a budget
right now for an oven,
we really don't.
- Should a budget be an issue
when I'm trying to stop serving
these people burnt food?
I'm outta here.
I'll holler at you later on.
I'm going for the help.
Sabrina,
you up in here?
I need money, girl.
I got to have it.
Where you at?
Oh.
- Hey Miss Grace, looks
like you could use a seat.
- Oh  thank
you, but no thank you.
And you, you're always working.
- Well you know they keep
me working, Miss Grace.
- Yes, but you know, we have
some new young congregates here
that could probably help
you during the week.
- You know what, maybe I should
talk to pastor about that.
That's a good idea.
- Oh, you didn't hear?
- Hm, hear what?
They going to Haiti, huh?
- Yes, he went to Haiti.
- Wow.
- I'm having like a
really rough day today.
- What's going on with you?
- Well, I lost my job--
- I'm so sorry to hear that.
- And, thanks,
and so now I'm interviewing
for this new executive
position here
in this crazy interview style
contest against Sabrina.
- Executive?
I don't see you as an executive.
- What do you mean?
- Oh, no, no, not like that.
It's just you're too nice.
I see you more in
the missionary work.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, I could
see myself doing that.
Maybe one day I'll go out
the country, you know?
- A cultured woman
such as yourself
has never been out
of the country?
I find that hard to believe.
- One day I will go though.
I will go out of the country.
- Yeah and uh, maybe
I could tag along.
- There's no subtly
with you, huh?
- I can be subtle sometimes.
- All right.
Well have a beautiful
day, Mr. Troy.
- You do the same, Miss Grace.
- There's my girl, hi
beautiful, how you doing?
- Hi Bessie Joe, it's
so good to see you.
- Girl, it's good
to see you too,
but usually ain't up
here in this afternoon.
- I know, I'm here to help
the pastor while he's away.
- Girl, you got a good heart.
That's why you love this church.
- Yes, yes, I do have a
heart for this church.
- Because if you love the
church and you love God,
you will be blessed.
- That's right.
- But you know I
won the lottery.
I won $1,500.
- Today?
- Girl no, that was in 1993,
but if I keep the faith and
believe in God, I'ma win again.
- Miss Bessie,
you're a crazy fool.
-  For loving the Lord?
- No, for wasting all your
money on those lottery tickets.
- Really?
- You know, in the Bible it
says you should not gamble.
- Well if I don't
see it in the Bible,
until I do, I'm not gonna quit.
I'm gonna win this lottery,
in the name of Jesus.
Girl, I'll see you later.
- See ya later.
Mm, amen.
- Crazy lady.
- Don't say that about her.
- Look, I got some news.
- What?
- Bad news.
Somebody's been dipping
in the collection plate.
- Who?
- Deacon Thompson.
- Can't say that
about somebody--
- I got proof and I
wanna bust him out
in front of the congregation.
- Okay no, no, no,
before you do that,
look, I have an idea, tell
me the evidence that you have
and then I'll present
it to the pastor.
- Sweetheart, you pretty,
but you ain't that pretty.
You can't solve this problem.
- Usher Mike.
-  Deacon Thompson.
- You know he's dipping
in the collection plate?
And he smokes
Marijuana cigarettes.
- Oh my God, what is
wrong with these people?
- What do you mean?
- Back stabbing,
betrayals, gossip,
this is why I left
he corporate world.
- You know, a lot
of people think
that working at a church
is a bed of roses.
They forget about the thorns.
- Oh man, but what
if the silver linings
of leaving the corporate
world is avoiding politics
and boss butt kissing?
I've been here
for almost one day
and everybody here's
stressing me out.
- One day, Grace, one day.
This job is probably
not for you.
This is probably a
sign of what's to come.
- Oh don't fret yourself, honey.
- Mother Thomas, you always
find a way to sneak up on us.
- That's how you hear all
the good gossip, honey.
- She always does that.
I think, when she dies,
she's gonna haunt us
and we're not gonna even
know the difference.
- You got a funny
way of saying things,
but I'm not sure what you're
saying is good or bad.
- Mother Thomas,
you know I love you.
-  That-a-girl.
Look Grace darling,
don't come in here
and get yourself caught
up with all this nonsense
that goes along with our church.
It was here before Jesus
was walking the Earth
and it'll be here after.
What
matters is your heart
and whether you act or not on
the love that Jesus put there.
Everything else is
babbly nonsense.
Here, have a snack, baby.
-  No, Mother Thomas,
I just don't understand why
the church is so flawed.
- That's the whole point.
The church is the one
place that people can go,
be themselves and still
be accepted none-the-less.
You, of all people,
should know that, Grace.
- Ow.
Dammit.
I mean, shoot.
- See what I mean?
- Hey hi.
It's 5:00, see you tomorrow?
- Oh, I usually stay until 6:00.
- Oh, um--
- It's okay, you can go.
- Okay, it's just that
I have a dinner
meeting with a friend.
- Like I said, you can go.
It's okay, I have
everything under control.
-  Okay.
- You're kind of an
accessory right now anyway.
- Who made you so mean?
- My momma told me to go after
what I want whole-heartedly,
so if that makes me mean,
then you have to blame her,
but then again, you're
talking about my momma
and you know what happens
when you talk about
someone's momma.
- Mm mm mm, Mother Thomas
was right about you,
but I'ma figure you out.
- Good.
- See you tomorrow.
- Hm.
- Dagnabit.
Dagnabit old house.
Yes.
- I am late.
Oh my God, I'm so late, oh.
Oh, is there a meeting?
- It's the weekly
prayer meeting.
It's on the calendar.
- Oh, sorry to interrupt.
- Well ya did, but I
accept your apology.
Oh God, come
on, Deacon Thompson.
- Oh, oh, oh, oh.
Okay, come on, come on.
- Oh my God, what
am I doing here?
- Looks like you're
still sleeping.
- Troy, thank you.
- That was quite an entrance.
- Well, a girl has to
make her entrance somehow.
Coffee you sweet elixir of
life, I love you so much.
- Now you're talking
to your beverages.
Man, you're really
going through it.
- That's not even half of it.
- It's only the first day.
Keep the faith, baby girl.
- You know what?
I don't know if that's a
good thing or a bad thing.
- I don't know what
was going on out there,
but interrupting
a prayer meeting
is just not professional, Grace.
Hey, hi Troy, how you doing?
- I'd be better if you were a
little kinder to your church
brothers and sisters,
Miss Sabrina.
- Oh Troy, you're such a man.
- Thanks Troy.
- Anytime, sweetie.
- Think I need a
little bit more coffee.
What do you mean, Sabrina?
Troy was just joking with you.
I mean, but you
could stand to be
a little bit nicer to people.
I mean I know I am a little
rough around the edges,
but it's only been
my second day.
Come in!
Eh, Ijitsu.
When am I gonna get
that rap song, man?
- When the good Lord
decides it's time.
Until then.
- Oh my goodness, why
you holding my cup?
- Well we went to the church
looking for the pastor
and he wasn't there
and seen your cup so I
decided to bring it to you.
- Wait, you were
looking for the pastor.
Is there something
I can help you with?
- Oh well, this was
my girlfriend, Casey,
but she's my finance now.
- Oh.
Oh, bling, bling, mm.
- We were hoping the pastor
can marry us by next week.
- Oh, well I don't think the
pastors gonna be here in time,
but I could marry you 'cause
I'm an ordained minister.
- Really?
-  Yes.
- Where'd you get your license?
- Church of the Internet
dot com, you heard of it?
- No, but it doesn't
seem that amazing,
but do you speak Spanish 'cause
Casey only speaks Spanish.
- Of course I speak Spanish.
- Oh, um, okay.
Mi Espanol no es bueno.
It's all good.
- Well if the pastor's
not here on time,
maybe you can marry us.
- Well I'ma work on some
marriage verses for you.
- Yeah, well let me know.
We gotta go cake tasting
so talk to you later.
- All right, get the butter
cream, that's the best one.
Oh.
Hello?
Oops.
- Ah ha.
- Usher Mike, what in the Tom
and Jerry are you doing here?
- You caught.
- Caught doing what?
- Deacon Thompson, I knew
you was up to something.
This time I'm gonna
bust you so hard
that the prison ministry
is the only church members
you're gonna see.
- You have no idea what
you're talking about.
What are you doing here?
- I forgot something.
- Yeah, you forgot something
like the money you been taking
out of the offering plate.
- You're kidding.
- Do I look like I'm kidding?
- No, Usher Mike, you rarely
look like you're kidding.
You've been dipping in
the collection plate.
Everybody knows it.
- No sir, no sir.
Everyone knows you've been
dipping in the offering plate.
-  You got the
wrong deacon.
- So what are you doing here?
- If I tell you, Usher Mike,
you've got to promise me
you're not gonna tell a soul.
- It depends.
- Have you ever heard
of an Air B & B?
- Why did you bring me to
the old missionary house?
- We ain't had a missionary
for the past three years.
You know who this house is for?
- Who?
- Frank.
- Thought he had a
house on the West Side.
- Exactly, this house has
just been sitting here
and those young'uns
are about to take it
and they don't deserve it.
- Who, Grace and Sabrina?
- Yeah, I got this place
booked for the next four months
for $150 a night.
- Deacon Thompson, you know
you can get in a lot of trouble
for using the church property
for your own personal gains.
- Hello?
No, no, it's not
today, it's tomorrow.
What day is it?
- Oh no, Troy, we can't do that.
- We have you written down
on the calendar incorrectly.
- Don't go, Troy.
- Okay Miss Johnson, we'll
see you this afternoon.
Have you heard from the pastor?
- No.
- Mm, that's weird.
It's been like almost a week.
Like I'm wondering,
is he still alive?
- Don't say that.
- I'm just saying, is like
a big old storm happening
in Haiti,
communications is down,
I'm exasperated, it's almost
a week and I'm just like.
- Like I've been saying--
-  Maybe this
isn't the job for you.
- Okay, sleepyhead.
- Foreclosure.
- What are you talking about?
- On the church.
Grace, they're gonna
foreclose on the church.
- What?
How is that possible?
-  Oh, it's
quite possible.
- Who are you?
- I'm the executer
on that account.
Kelly Burns.
FRS Properties.
- What is FRS Properties?
- Well as of next Monday,
we'll be the fine owners
of this lovely church
building and the surrounds.
- What, how?
- Well it is hearsay,
but apparently
your executive pastor has been
keeping the mortgage checks
for himself for years.
- Oh!
- Is he here today?
- He quit two weeks ago.
- Sneaky bastard.
He made off with
over $1,000,000,
leaving you with a massive debt.
FRS specializes in foreclosures,
in particular,
inner city churches.
- Who specializes in that?
- A smart company.
Now it's nothing personal,
we only see the color green.
Bank lives do matter,
don't they?
Any who, the paperwork should
go through within the week
so you'll wanna
talk to your church
and let everybody know
and start packing as well.
The details are included there,
minus the dirty details
I included as hearsay.
I do look forward
to working with you.
Toodles.
Let's go make
America great again.
- My God, what are we gonna do?
- I don't know about you,
but I'm going to
look for another job.
Monster.com, Indeed.com, woo,
I am so glad I updated
my LinkedIn account.
- Hey, how you ladies doing?
- I was surprised.
Next thing you know,
right before she leaves,
she's like bye, toodles, let's
make America great again.
It was like the
she-devil took over.
- I can't believe it.
Frank was always
quiet, but this?
This church has been
home to so many people.
How could someone
take that from them?
I think we need to find
Frank and we need to--
- What?
What, get somebody to
put him in concrete boots
and throw him in the river?
No.
I think we need to
tell the church.
- Tell the church what?
- That we lost it.
- Lost it how?
- We're in foreclosure.
Frank stole the money.
- We need to tell Pastor.
- We need to find Frank.
- We need to find another job.
- I think we need to pray.
- Let's pray.
- Lord, we come to you
at a time of despair,
confusion, potential loss.
-  Yes, Lord.
- We don't know what's going on,
why this happened
or what to do now,
but one thing we do know
is that you are with us.
- Yes Lord.
- Yes, yes.
- You said you would
never leave us,
nor forsake us and so
in our time of need,
we cling to that promise
because building or no building,
we are your church.
- Yes Lord, yes, yes.
- And we will stick together.
-  Yes.
- With you as our
leader, our head,
we will find the strength
to make it through.
- Yes.
- We pray for clarity,
the knowledge to
act when appropriate
and most of all, unity.
-  Yes.
- In the name of Jesus, I pray.
Amen.
-  Amen.
- Amen.
- What do we do, God?
What do I do?
Lord help me.
That's it!
That's it, yes!
Hello, Sabrina?
I know it's early
in the morning.
I am so excited.
We're going to save the church.
Call an emergency meeting.
I'm on my way.
Oh, I need you, Lord.
Help me, Lord, give me ideas.
Show me the way, Lord.
- Yes, yes yes yes, that would
be wonderful Pastor Scott.
I will see you
tomorrow at 10:00.
I'll bring my resume.
All right, bye.
Uh, do you think
it's gonna work?
- I guess you don't.
- Well my momma told me
that when it comes to work
to C-Y-A, cover your ass.
- You ready?
- Is everyone here?
-  Yes.
- Thank you, everyone.
Thank you for coming to this
emergency church meeting,
concerning the church health.
- What's that all about, Deacon?
-  Yeah.
- I'm missing my program.
I got to know, find out what
happened to Diane Kreeger
and her mistress.
- Have you heard of
a DVR, Bessie Jo?
- Boy, I don't mess
with that nonsense.
You know the man is watching us.
Don't you know that?
- Calm down, I
called this meeting
because I have some unfortunate
news from yesterday.
It seems our executive pastor
was taking money from the
church for the past three years.
- How much money?
- Well how bad is it?
- We're gonna lose the building.
Calm down, calm down, calm down.
- We gotta find that
man and string him up.
- That's what I'm talking about.
- Perhaps, maybe someday,
but not right now.
Right now, we only have one
week left in this building,
a building that we've called
home for the past 88 years.
I've watched most
of you grow up here.
That is, unless our own
Grace Hightower can help us.
-  All right Grace.
- Oh well, she pretty,
but that's about it.
- I'll believe it when I see it.
- Well she's assured
me she has a plan.
So let's hear the lady talk.
Come on Grace.
- Hello all, hello.
- Praise the Lord.
- I fell asleep reading the
foreclosure papers last night.
And while sleeping,
I had a dream
that I was there when Jesus fed
the 5,000 people in Matthew 14.
And you were all there too.
-  Hallelujah.
- Except for Bessie Joe,
she was off somewhere
gambling fish.
- Hallelujah.
-  That's Bessie Joe.
- In this dream, a
little boy showed up
with five loaves of
bread and two fish
and everybody laughed
at him and they sneered
and they started
packing up to leave,
but then Jesus showed up.
With his eyes deep
with the confidence
of the good shepard.
The apostles, they were scared.
But Jesus was confident.
-  Don't play.
- Oh my God, he just
started passing fish.
Fish all around.
I was way in the
back in the dream.
The fish was going
to get to me, guys.
There were people behind
me, people beside me.
I thought they were just gonna
fight to get to the fish,
but they didn't have to.
We all got fish,
including you guys.
- We all got food
off'a the fish.
And that's when I realized,
our God is an abundant God.
He makes a way out of no way.
And I believe God
showed me that dream
to represent this church.
I believe our miracle is
found in this here document.
- That's right,
what does it say?
- It says that if we can
get this debt paid off
before their next meeting,
the church is ours to keep.
- Well how we gonna do that?
- And how much do we
owe, three, $400,000?
- 1.2 million.
- 1.2 million?
- Oh man, that's
just plain crazy.
- Listen people,
there was nothing that's
impossible for God.
- Okay, okay.
- Come on, guys, he turned
two fish into a million.
What could he do with
the money in our pockets?
- What kind of miracle
are you expecting, Grace?
- Here's what I'm proposing,
I propose that we
give today, give.
- Where your money is, there
the heart will be also.
- Yes, where your money
is, there is your heart.
Right now.
Let's give today, everybody,
out of our pockets.
Let's make it
happen, let's give.
- 99,
100, that's $100,000.
- Plus $40,000 online.
- That's only 1/10th
of what we owe.
- I have an idea.
Have you ever
heard of Air B & B?
We have a missionary
house that we can rent out
for say, $200.00 a night.
- Brilliant, excellent
idea, Usher Mike.
- That is a good idea, but
I don't think we would make
enough money, maybe
more like $200 an hour.
- Hm, $200.00 an hour,
that's a great idea.
Great idea.
- Maybe not.
That's for luck.
- There's no such thing as luck.
- I told you.
- Good speech, Gracie.
-  It's okay everyone,
we still have a few days left.
Keep the faith.
There's always the
second chance drawing.
- Oh, everyone, everyone listen.
I have an announcement to make.
- Oh snap, she about to give
her inheritance to the church.
- Shut up, fool.
I ain't got no
inheritance, just wisdom.
And I'm so proud of
little Gracie here
and I'm proud of all y'all too.
I mean, do you
know, in one hour,
we just raised over $100,000.
That's impressive.
Now the Bible says, when
you really wanna see God,
you need to fast and pray.
So I'm asking everybody
that's here today,
we all starting a fast tomorrow.
Even the deacons.
Now I know, I just know
that if we trust God on this,
he will bless us with the
money to keep the house
and if it's not his will
to bless us with the money,
then he'll give us a new house
and if not, he's gonna
come with something else.
- Home or no home, we
are still a church.
- Amen, sister.
-  Amen.
- Amen.
- That was really
great up there, Grace.
- Thank you, Sabrina.
- I really just wanna
apologize to you
because I know that I've
been pretty harsh with you.
- You sure have and you
got that right.
- You know, I just get
caught up sometimes.
- You know what, God is
working on all of us.
- He is, he is,
but I still think that I will be
the better executive pastor,
but lead pastor, you
got me beat by miles.
- I'll take that.
- Troy wanted to take you out.
- Hm, well,
if he wants to take
me out this week,
unless he wants to feed
me water and crackers,
'cause we're fasting this week.
- Oh, oh yeah, that's right.
- Yeah.
- That's right,
but I really think he likes you.
- Hm, well you know,
I kinda like him too.
Yeah, it's kinda cool.
- Cool.
- Time to go,
ladies, time to go.
- Time to go.
Well good to see you, thank you.
Same you, all right.
For the fast.
I'll work on it.
- What are you doing?
Where are the guests?
- Our guests are
still at the airport.
- What?
- Frank, he's in
there, he's in there!
- What?
- Hold on, we don't
want him to see you.
You're gonna spook him.
- You don't think
leaving him in the car
isn't gonna spook him enough?
- He didn't recognize me,
man, he didn't recognize me
because of the shades.
He just jumped in
my car like I was
some kind of Uber or taxi.
- What are we gonna do?
- I don't know, but we
just can't let him go.
- Get this thing off my head.
What's going on?
What's the meaning of this?
Listen, listen, I was going
to pay the money back.
- When, after your two week
trip to the Dominican Republic?
- Maybe.
- Sabrina, come on
Pastor, you're back!
- Good morning, Grace.
- Good morning, when
did you get back?
- This morning.
- You must be exhausted.
- Yes, I heard
about pastor Frank.
- Pastor, tomorrow
we lose the church
unless we come up with $500,000.
- And that's exactly what
I wanna talk to you about.
My church.
- Hey.
- Good morning, church.
What a beautiful day it is.
It goes without saying that
it's been a tumultuous week
and I play a big part in that
and I wish to apologize to
you all, first and foremost.
As you may or may not know,
I'm part of our
denominational missions board
and there was a major
tragedy in Haiti.
They needed me as
soon as possible
and still need people.
If you feel God's
tug on your heart
to serve our brothers and
sisters in another country,
as a result, I was MIA for
the past couple of weeks.
Though I feel those
who stepped up
to lead this church in my
absence did a spectacular job,
particularly Grace and Sabrina,
I sincerely thank you both,
which leads me to my
next announcement.
As you know, our executive
pastor, Mr. Frank,
quit a few weeks ago and
moved out of the state
and with him, he
took our mortgage
that he stole over the
past couple of years,
leaving us unexpectedly
with a massive debt.
The litigations will begin
shortly, I assure you,
but that doesn't negate the
issues we face as a church.
How can we keep this building?
How can we keep our
home of over 80 years?
I understand Miss
Grace Hightower
managed to muster up
about 60% of what we need,
which is an amazing
feat in itself,
but there is still a deficit
and a large one at that,
so what do we do?
We find ourselves in a
valley, a dark valley
and not from our
own doing this time.
Someone pushed us, but this
shouldn't be a surprise
for God assures us that
this life is filled with
both valleys and peaks.
But what would a peak look like
without experiencing the valley?
Furthermore, the one
who caused us the fall,
what should we say about him?
Do we condemn him or forgive?
As our Lord, I'm
sure already has.
I would argue that
the first step
towards escaping this
valley is forgiveness
and so I urge all of
you to find your own way
to let go of this sin and
once we have forgiven again,
follow in the footsteps of
the one we claim to follow.
Once we have, with his help,
moved past the offense, the
next step is to simply look up.
Though it be dark in the valley,
the sun will yet rise and
though it will take time
for the blessed rays to strive
our darkest faces, they will
and when they do, the path of
the darkness will be revealed
and we can step forward.
I am very happy to stand
here today and say that.
Your prayers have been answered.
It seems that while
I was in Haiti,
a fellow missionary,
who I have never met,
approached me.
He is from a church about
our size in Illinois,
one that has done
great work worldwide
and domestically, even
here in Los Angeles.
This man approached me and said
he felt a tug on his heart
about three months ago
to raise a significant
amount of money
for an unknown congregation
somewhere in
Southern California,
one he felt was located none
other than the city of Angels
and as it turns out,
this man's church
managed to raise exactly
a half million dollars, an
incredible amount of money
for an unknown cause.
Am I right?
Now before you all start
looking for jobs in Illinois,
some of you may know that
despite your valent efforts
in fund raising,
we are short exactly a
half million dollars,
plus a few cents, which is
why it was 100% God's doing
when this man approached me
and offered all of the money
he had to give to
us, to our church.
Hallelujah.
Let's let this
celebration begin.
Amen
Amen amen, hallelujah
Hallelujah
Amen
Amen amen amen
- A little louder.
Amen
We can't hear ya.
Let it happen.
Amen amen amen
Woo, hallelujah
- Believe in our
God, good people.
Hallelujah.
Thank you Lord, thank you Lord.
Everybody, settle down,
settle down, settle down.
Settle down.
Yeah, open up your Bibles
to Genesis, chapter four
and we're gonna start
with the scripture.
Amen?
-  Amen.
- Amen, church.
'Cause we all know we
need a healing right now
and that's what
we're going to get
with the blessings of the Lord.
- Pastor I've got some news!
- Pastor, yes sir,
Pastor, yes sir.
- S'cuse us, Pastor.
Little bit of respect.
- Oh yeah.
- Now ain't that something?
He done got caught.
- God is so good.
-  Yes, he is.
- Now we need to talk
about that job position.
- Pastor, Grace has really
been doing a good job
under pressure.
- I knew she would.
- Thank you, Sabrina.
Man, Pastor, I have
been drowning in water.
This woman here, was
swimming like a dolphin.
She is definitely more
qualified than me.
- You know what, I'm glad
you said that, Grace,
'cause you got the job.
-  Oh my God, Pastor,
thank you, thank you!
Oh.
- Oh my God.
- And Grace?
I'm creating a new
position for you,
associate pastor.
- What?
- Yes.
-  Congratulations.
- Oh my God, what
does that entail?
- Missionary work.
- Is something wrong?
-  God is so good, it's
something that I prayed for
and I hoped for.
- So is that a yes?
- Yes, yes!
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- Actually, I have some
questions about my--
- Okay, all right, all right.
- Congratulations
associate pastor.
- Thank you, Troy.
Now you can call me
Reverend Hightower.
-  Is that right?
- Yes, and I will be able
to point out all your sins.
- Hm, well is it a sin for a
pastor to go out on a date?
- Uh, I guess if she lets him.
- Hm, well let's
go break this fast.
- Let's break this fast.
Yeah, you get the
highest praise
Lord your worthy
Let's go
Hallelujah, hallelujah
Hallelujah, you get
the highest praise
Hallelujah, hallelujah
Hallelujah, you get
the highest praise
Hallelujah, hallelujah
Hallelujah, you're
worthy of my praise.
Hallelujah, hallelujah
Hallelujah, you get
the highest praise
You get the highest praise
You are the
highest name, name
Won't use your
name in vain, vain
Your blood runs
through my veins, yes
Because of you I've
changed, changed
No longer I remain
Oh yes I'm born to gain
You've broken every chain
Yes Lord, you resurrected,
your love, the world rejected
Your love I can't neglect it
Your life was such
perfection, yes
You give me much
protection, yes
You keep me clear from harm,
but when I go through it
You got me from the storm
Hallelujah, hallelujah
Hallelujah, you get
the highest praise
Hallelujah, hallelujah
Hallelujah, you get
the highest praise
Hallelujah, hallelujah
Hallelujah, you're
worthy of my praise
Hallelujah, hallelujah
Hallelujah, you get
the highest praise
I was born a sinner, guilty
You helped me remember
that I'm now a member
Of your holy winner's chants
No longer a beginner
Lord, you searched my inner
and I'm thankful for it
Oh yes, I'm delivered,
I'm delivered
I see the bigger picture,
my soul is now clean
Your spirit shines brighter
than any diamond ring
My woes don't mean
a thing, nothing
If I don't ask you, my
life is nothing, Jesus, no
If I don't have you
Hallelujah, hallelujah
Hallelujah, you get
the highest praise
Hallelujah, hallelujah
Hallelujah, you get
the highest praise.
Hallelujah, hallelujah
Hallelujah, you're
worthy of my praise
Hallelujah, hallelujah
Hallelujah, you get
the highest praise