- Yes sir, I understand.
I understand your
order did not arrive.
I owe you a box of
Fazzle Glue and I'm...
Yes, yes sir you, ah...
you have a wonderful
Fazzle Glue day.
Alright, bye bye.
- I'm gonna have
to fire you, Edwin.
Do you have that password
list I was asking you about?
Uh...
uh, yeah.
Yes sir, here.
I'm not sure I understand.
- Well, what's
not to understand?
- I mean, I --
- We're downsizing.
Is this all of them?
- Yes sir, every one.
- Alright here is a box
for all of your stuff.
- But I've been
here 21 years, sir.
- I know, time flies doesn't it?
- I was eligible for a
pension in four months.
- Like I said, really sorry.
So get all of your
things together.
Betty will have your
last check ready.
- Mr. Clark!
Yes, Edwin?
- Who's gonna do my job?
I Mean, there's a lot of
things going on, I've got...
Of course, your youngest is
qualified he can do that job.
- Well look, who knows?
We may hire you back
once things pick up.
- Yeah would you? That'd
be great because y'know
I think the world of Fazzle Glue
and I'll be here all the time,
I'll work even
more harder and --
- Look.
I didn't mean
"more harder", I meant "harder".
You know what I mean.
Okay.
Alright I'm just gonna,
I'm just gonna go ahead and
clean out my stuff here.
- Eat it all up, Bernice, so
you'll be big just like me!
- You're home?
I must have lost track of time.
Hey.
- What's in the box?
- Just stuff from my work.
- What did they do, fire you?
Oh, well, well good.
You don't need them.
All they ever did was
take advantage of you.
- What happened?
- Mr. Clark says
they're downsizing,
it's just a temporary thing.
- Downsizing, what
a bunch of baloney.
- Well, what about your pension?
- For crying out loud,
you're not getting
your pension either?
- Daddy!
Hi, honey.
- What's in the box?
- Just stuff from Daddy's work.
Hey I got something for ya.
- Another stupid mug.
- That's the latest edition
Fazzle Glue mug, huh?
Cool.
Look, Mr. Clark said
he'll hire me back
just as soon as things pick up.
It's just temporary.
- What'd he say?
- He says it temporary, dad.
- Temporary, right.
- What's going on?
- Your dad got fired.
- Dad!
- What?
You got fired, she asked.
What happened to your hair?
- I decided it was
time for a change.
- It looks like a wig.
- Coming from someone who wears
a Halloween costume everyday.
- Liberty Bell.
- Dad what are you eating?
- Chinese food.
- That's been in the
fridge for over a week!
- Week smeek.
It's got so much MSG in it
to last for over a year!
- Bad day?
- Yeah, a little.
I just need to do my
exercises more often.
So, are you doin' homework?
- Yeah, well it's the only way
I'll ever get out of here, so.
- Hey!
- I'm going to put all
my crayons in my new mug.
Okay, Yellow...
hm.
Blue, Black...
what is this color?
- Oh let me see it, pumpkin.
- That's all you
have to do, mom,
is stop it from shaking and
everything will be alright.
See?
Kinda, little thing
there.
Sorry about that.
- Your wife's
appointment was at 12.
- Uh no, it's uh, no.
It was one o'clock,
I'm quite sure.
- No it was 12.
You'll have to reschedule.
- Uh no its uh, no.
It was one o'clock,
I'm quite sure.
- No it was 12.
- It's okay.
We can come back another time.
- Look, I've got the card right
there, it says one o'clock.
- No, you must
have changed this.
- I didn't change that.
- We'll come back another
day, it's alright.
- No, Jen I got this.
Look, I didn't change this.
- I'm sorry, you'll
have to reschedule.
I'm not leaving here until
I see Dr. White today.
Your not seeing him today.
Dr. White's office,
how may I assist you?
Hold on one moment.
- You must be the doctor.
- Yes, I must be.
- Look, our family has just
been through a major crisis
and your incompetent staff
messed up our appointment.
- You need to hold
on there, missy.
Back off, lady.
- It's okay, it's okay.
- As I was saying, my mother
needs to see you today.
Okay, okay.
- Put that down, put it down.
- So, your condition seems to
be getting worse with time.
Okay, arms up please.
And down, okay.
And are you still taking
the same medications?
- Well my husbands insurance
was changed back in April?
- Yeah, the medications
were costing
more than our mortgage payment.
- Hold on one second.
Sarah would you come in
here one moment, please?
Okay now insurance
companies and I,
we haven't been getting
along very well these days.
I want you to put Mrs.
Durshman on the list
for new Parkinson's
medication please.
- Yes, doctor.
- Okay, thank you.
Okay, there is a new drug.
It has not been released
yet and pharmaceutical
companies are offering it for
free, to selected patients.
- Wow are you serious doctor?
That's fantastic.
- It's done very well
in clinical studies.
I really think this
is gonna make you
feel a lot better,
improve your function.
- That's wonderful, thank you.
- Yes doctor, thank you
so much, that's great.
- Oh, can I say grace?
Of course you can.
- Thank you God, for the
food we are about to eat.
Oh, Amen.
- And God, could you
please help Edwin here
find another job?
God knows he could use the help.
- I can hear you,
dad, I'm right here.
- What?
It never hurts to
ask, you never know.
- You're preaching, not asking.
Dad.
Dad!
- What?
- You're grunting.
- I am not a grunt.
- I didn't say you were a grunt
I said you were making
grunting noises.
- Now, look.
You make me get food
all over Grandma's urn.
- I don't know why you insist
on eating with that thing.
- You know she
goes wherever I go.
- Grandpa even takes her
with him to go potty.
- Right you are, young lady.
Wherever I go your
Grandmother goes.
- Okay that is not Grandma,
that is Grandma's ashes.
- You take that back.
Where is she going?
- I'm going back to my
bedroom to eat dinner
where there is some
peace and quiet.
- I'll get it.
- Would you let me buy a new one
or at least unplug
it while we eat?
- I got it.
It just sticks once in
a while, it'll be fine!
Dad, why can't we just take her
and give her a proper burial
like normal people would?
- We will when I can
remember where the tree.
- What tree?
- Oh it's, um, the tree where
Grandma and Grandpa
carved their names in.
- They carved their
names in a tree?
- Mm-hm!
It's what people did back then.
- Don't do that now
or you'll get arrested
for destroying a tree.
- It doesn't destroy the tree.
- It doesn't help it.
- "My dearest William,
it's been only three weeks,
"yet it feels like an eternity.
"I pray your job is
not too much for you
"and cannot wait for you to
return and come back to me.
"Three years is such a long
time for us to be apart.
"I'm afraid I have
some bad news,
"my father has been
offered a job overseas.
"I'm not sure if he's
gonna take the job
"but if he does I fear we
will be even further apart.
"I don't know how I
will get through this.
"I regret having to
share this bad news
"but I feel you must know.
"The only thing
I can do is pray.
"Pray that we will
be together again.
"I must now conclude as my
eyes have welled with tears,
"with a heavy heart,
your true love, Beth."
- Oh, very nice.
- Good morning, girls.
And to you.
- Do you like my face I made?
- Best face ever.
- Can you go wake up
your sister, please?
- Sure!
Don't mind if I do.
You know, I've been thinking.
We need to catch up on all
the repairs around this place.
See, like that!
I finally have time to do things
like fix the kitchen table
while I'm waiting for them
to call me back to work.
Observe!
See what I mean?
I am number one.
Fix kitchen table.
- Did you wake your sister?
- Mm-hm!
- Dad, you feeling okay?
- I'm fine, it's alright.
- Well, where is she?
- I'll get her.
Liberty!
Hey, Lib?
Hey, come on, honey,
your mom made pancakes.
- I'm not hungry.
- Are you having an attack?
- Yeah.
- Focus on my hand, Jen.
Focus.
Keep focusing.
Good, good.
- Hey, don't worry about that.
I'm gonna get that fixed today.
- Great, now he's a plumber?
Awesome way to
start my vacation.
- What was that?
- I think you should
call a plumber, dad.
- Oh, okay.
- I'll be out in a minute, okay?
Where is she?
- She's in the bathroom.
Oh, well here she is, everybody.
Okay, ready?
Oh my gosh!
- What are you doing?
- I'm --
- No no, stop wiping.
Don't wash her down the drain!
- I got it.
Dad.
- Yeah?
- I think we should
take Grandma's urn
to the tree and bury
her ashes there.
- Well, it's a great
idea but Grandpa doesn't
remember exactly where
the tree is anymore.
Do you, dad?
- I can't remember much
of anything anymore.
- Wait, I have Grandma
and Grandpa's letters.
There has to be something
about the tree in there.
- What letters?
- The ones Grandma gave
to me before she died.
- She gave you letters?
I don't remember any letters.
- Can you get 'em?
- Yeah, I have a box of them.
- Do you remember
anything about letters?
- No.
- The tree has to be
mentioned in here somewhere.
- Do you remember
these at all, dad?
- No.
Could you, please?
- "My dearest William,
"I'm so happy to inform
you that my father
"turned down the offer
to move us overseas.
"I prayed every night and
God must have heard me
"because we are now
staying here at home."
- She must have
prayed awful hard
and God answered her prayers.
If they had have moved, then
that would have
been the end of us.
Please, can you go on?
- "I go the tree once a
week, I know it sounds silly
"but it makes me feel
like I am with you."
- Dad, that's the
tree, do you remember?
- "It's a bit of a ride
on my bicycle to Two River
"but when I am there I
can feel your presence.
"I think I will write my letters
"to you when I'm
here at the tree."
- I remember that tree.
It's about an hours
walk from her house.
It only seemed like five minutes
when I was with you Grandmother.
- Yeah, but the tree
is in Two River.
- Do you even know
where that is?
- Not exactly, but
it can't be very far
from Grandpa's old
house, remember, dad?
- I'm sure we can find it.
- Well okay, that's
what we should do.
We should get in the car
and drive out to Two River
and bury your Grandma.
- I couldn't ride
that long in the car.
- We can take the RV.
I'm off work, the
kids are on break.
We can make a mini
vacation out of it.
- I need my flashlight!
My sleeping bag!
My blanket!
My teddy bear!
I just need everything,
we're going to the tree!
We're going to the tree.
We're going
to the tree.
- Come on!
Haha! Haha!
Come on, Earnest, you
have to be real quiet!
- Do you wanna to read
another letter, sweetie?
- This one Grandpa wrote.
"My Darling Beth,
"I can't believe how long the
days and nights have become.
"I realized there
was a chance that
"we would never hold each other
again and I almost gave up.
"But what kind of man would I
be if I didn't do everything
"humanly possible to be by
your side 'til the day I die?
"I am so pleased
that you are not moving.
"You really have no idea what
that would have done to me.
"Another month has ended
and we are that much
"closer to being in
each others arms.
"I have a busy day tomorrow
and the night is late.
"I look forward to your
next precious letter.
"You are forever in my dreams.
"Your
true love, Will."
- That was really nice, dad.
What ever happened to that guy?
- Honey!
- No, really, I wanna hear this.
What ever happened
to that young man?
- He grew up.
- What do you mean "he grew up"?
- He was a kid,
then life hits you
in the keister.
But you, you have it easy.
- What, who has it easy?
- You do.
- Oh, I have it easy?
- You most certainly do.
- Well, you know what dad?
I don't think I do have it easy.
In fact, I think
I have it harder.
- You know what your problem is?
- No, what's my problem?
- You care more about
that stupid Glue company
than you do your own
wonderful daughters.
- Alright now,
I've heard enough.
First of all,
Fazzle Glue is not stupid.
And secondly, they named
me employee of the year
21 years, straight.
That's an accomplishment, dad!
- I'm done talking to you.
- Well, you know what?
You know what's ridiculous?
I'll tell you what's ridiculous.
You carrying around that
stupid urn all the time.
We can't take you
anywhere with that thing.
Was that Ernest?
Are you kidding me?
Oh my gosh!
- We can't do this
trip with Ernest.
We should turn around.
- We can't go back now,
we've gone like 200 miles.
I don't know why you
even let her have
a goat in the first place!
- Oh, that was just
as much your idea!
- Originally, I said no goat.
Where is she going now?
Jen, sit down.
- Jen, focus on my hand.
- I'm calling 911.
Focus.
Yeah, that's good, focus.
911,
what's your emergency?
Oh, hi.
No, um.
No, we're okay.
We're fine now
thanks, sorry, sorry.
- Why do you always
have to do what I do?
I can't
believe you brought Ernest.
- He gets lonely.
- Alright.
Jessie!
Goats don't eat jellybeans.
Alright.
- Hey, I think I may
have found something.
This one is from Grandma.
"My dearest William,
"as I was making
my way here today
"I noticed some men
surveying Jack's property.
"Word around town is
that they are putting
"in a new highway not
too far from here."
- We had to go through Jack's
property to get to that tree.
But I'm having trouble
remembering the highway.
I'm gonna
go check on Ernest.
- Okay, pumpkin.
- It's all coming
back to me now.
I know exactly where it is!
- You guys, Ernest is gone!
- He's down there.
- I'll go get him.
- I'm coming with.
- Mom says you're
doing well at school.
- Yup.
- You thought about what you
might wanna do after that?
- Yup.
Well, I'm
sorry it's so rough for you.
You
sound like Grandpa.
You're right,
I do sound just like him.
- Sorry about your job.
I know that place really
meant a lot to you.
- Well, hopefully
they'll call soon.
- What did you do there anyway?
- You never knew
what I did for work?
- No.
- I was in charge of
all the product orders.
- And you did this for how long?
- 21 years and eight months.
- That's longer than
I've been on this planet!
- Yup, and you know what?
When you were born they
gave me the whole week off.
- Wow, that must have
been real nice of them.
- That was real nice of them!
You know, I don't know what I
did to make you so miserable.
Honestly, what did I do?
- You didn't do anything,
that's the point.
All you ever do is talk
about that stupid company!
- I do talk about
that place a lot.
I was never really
good at anything.
I struggled in school, I
didn't have a lot of friends.
And then they gave me all the
products and all the orders
and finally I was good
at something, you know?
- And then they ripped the
rug out from under you.
- Sounds like he's
getting further away.
- We have to go find him.
- I'll wait here in
case he comes back.
Go ahead.
- Okay let's go find him.
- Where is this goat?
- Ernest!
- Ernest.
- Oh hey, looks like your mom
and Jessie are looking too.
Hey!
- Daddy!
- Hey pumpkin, no luck, huh?
- No, we have to find him.
- Don't worry, we'll find him.
- Have you guys
heard him lately?
- No, not for a while.
- Look!
It's Ernest's poop!
This is definitely Ernest's!
He can't be far.
- Ew, Jessie that's disgusting.
- Yeah, it sure does
look like Ernest's poop,
but let's put it back on the
ground, okay?
- Ernest!
Ernest!
- Alright, go with Mommy.
Come on.
- No luck, huh?
- No.
We're gonna have to
stay here for the night.
I'm gonna go ahead and
get the camper locked up.
Ernest!
- Everything okay?
- Yeah I was just getting
the camper set for the night.
- We have to find Ernest.
Jessie will be
crushed if we don't.
- I know.
Let's get some sleep.
- It's all my fault.
- No dad, it's not your fault.
- If I hadn't --
- Really dad, it's okay.
- We'll get up in the
morning and Ernest will be
right at that door waiting to
be fed, like he always does.
- I'm sure you're right.
- Come here, give me your hands.
Dear Lord, once we
embark on this journey
to finally put our
beloved Grandmother,
mother and bride to rest,
please be with us in days ahead.
And please Lord,
bring Ernest back safely.
Amen.
- Amen.
- Did you hear Ernest?
- Yeah, I did.
- Eddie, I saw a bob
cat a little earlier.
- I know, me too.
- We're just gonna have to
wait 'til in the morning.
Have a little faith,
he'll come back.
- Okay.
- Ernest?
- Ernest!
- What are you doing?
You're scaring him off!
Grab the rope.
Good job!
- Hey, how about another letter?
- "My dearest Will,
"I have enclosed a
photograph of myself."
- Wait, she sent you a picture?
- "It's been a warm summer,
I've taken a part time job
"to save up for when you
come home from your break.
"See you soon, your
true love, Beth."
- I would not wanna
leave a pretty girl
like that all alone.
- Well I can't just
marry her without
a house for her to live in.
I'm saving up every penny.
- To each his own.
- Is that the photo?
Wow, dad!
You must have been a happy man!
Bring back any memories?
- What's wrong?
- I trusted him.
- Trusted who?
- He's getting his memory back.
- I used to read my
letter to someone
I thought was my friend.
- You shared these
letters with your friend?
- Yes, I did.
He didn't have anyone.
I guess I felt sorry for him.
- Why on earth would you
share that with anyone?
- Be nice!
- I stopped once I saw how he
looked at her in these photos.
- Sorry dad, I didn't
mean to upset you.
- I don't wanna hear any
more of those letters.
- Seven-eights.
- You know, I've
never been to Tucson.
It's not exactly Tucson,
it's further south.
- Hey um, I think you should
get out from under there.
This piece of wood, it
doesn't look too safe.
I'm almost done.
Hey, is the 1516's in there?
So,
is that where she lives?
- That's where we'll live.
I need the clamp.
Clamp!
Ah, yeah.
Will?
Will, Will!
Help!
We almost lost you there.
- He's your brother?
- A friend.
He's gonna be okay, right?
- He's in a coma and he's
suffered severe head trauma.
I don't wanna alarm you
but I think the best thing
you can do is say
a prayer for him.
I've seen God do some
wonderful things.
Sam's going into surgery.
I need to tell you
there's a chance that he
may not make it.
"My dearest Will,
"I know you are very busy but
I have written two letters
"and have yet to
receive a response.
"I hope that you are well.
"Please call me on
Thursday of next week
"at eight o'clock PM.
"Forever yours, Beth."
- Waiting for a phone call?
- Uh yeah, a friend
needs help with homework.
- Homework?
It's summer.
- Uh, she's taking
a summer class.
- Don't forget to turn out the
light when you're done, okay?
- Okay, I won't.
- Beth, why are you
sleeping in here, honey?
- I must have fallen asleep.
- Well it's almost 11 o'clock,
come on, let's get to bed.
- Where are we?
- Something's wrong
with the camper.
I'm looking for a place to stop,
a gas station or something.
- But we're in the
middle of nowhere.
- Oh, great!
It's overheated.
- Is it something you can fix?
- I'm sure I can figure it out.
Ow!
Have to let it cool down first.
You're not getting
away this time!
What do you think of that, huh?
Alright, here is your food.
Alright, you stick around here.
It's an amazing view.
I'm proud of you, you know.
- What do you mean?
- I was never very
good in school.
So I made Fazzle Glue
my life's mission.
- It's just a transition,
you'll find something better.
So what's wrong with the RV?
- Ah, the radiator
hose has a leak.
- Anything?
- Yeah, surprisingly
I have one bar.
- Are you gonna call for help?
- Yep.
- Are those the keys?
- That's weird, I didn't
hear them hit the bottom.
- No, neither did I.
Oh hey, I see 'em!
I think I could reach that.
- Oh, you're close,
you're an inch away.
You dropped them.
- Yep.
I dropped them.
- Now are you gonna
call for help?
- Well, I guess so.
Only, now I have no bars.
- Great!
- What are they doing out there?
- Maybe they're
just taking a break.
- Daddy!
- Oh!
- What are you guys doing?
- Dad dropped the
keys in that well.
- Cool!
- No, not cool, pumpkin.
Daddy was careless.
- That's one way of putting it.
- Are you taking a break?
- Daddy dropped the keys
down that old well out there.
- You dropped the keys to
the camper down that well?
- Yes dad, I did.
- Well, what are you gonna do?
- I'm gonna get the keys.
- I'm just curious,
how does someone
drop keys down a well?
- Don't need it right now, dad.
Let it video,
drop my phone down the well,
see right where the keys are.
- Can't we just call someone?
- Mom's phone doesn't
have any signal either.
- How far off the
main highway are we?
- Honey, can you check
your phone for a signal?
- Nothing.
Look, I got this okay?
- And we're recording.
Here we go.
Okay, that's it hit the bottom.
- So what are you gonna do once
you see the keys down there?
- Please, dad, I'm trying
to concentrate, okay?
- Ew, gotta be
snakes down there.
- Cool.
- Alright that's
enough, do you think?
Let's see what we got.
- Oh, there they are!
- Yeah.
- At the bottom of the well.
- And not in his pocket
where they're supposed to be.
- Let's climb down there, dad.
- Hey, grab me a
hanger from the camper.
- Well what do you think
you're gonna do now?
- I'm gonna make a
hook out of the hanger,
slip it through the
rope, drop it down there
to the bottom and grab the keys.
- That'll never work.
- Hello!
- Be careful, pumpkin.
- So are you going
to explain to me
exactly how you put
us in this situation?
- The keys fell out
of my pocket, okay?
- How did the keys fall
out of your pocket?
- They just did.
- In all the years
I've worn trousers I've
never had keys just
fly out of my pocket.
Maybe a coin or
two, but never keys!
- They were at the
top of my pocket
and they just
pulled out and fell.
- Normal people usually
put something important
like car keys deep
inside their pocket,
not on top.
- Well maybe I'm not normal.
- That's an understatement.
- Oh, now that's
teamwork, high five!
Just me, okay.
Okay.
Lower it down.
There at the bottom.
- You'll never see anything
down there, it's pitch black!
- Dad, please!
- Okay, go on and
do your own thing.
- I hear 'em!
- Yeah, me too.
- There it is
again, you got 'em!
- Yeah, I think so.
Woohoo.
- Told you that'd never work.
- I'm just gonna
have to try again.
I'm going
back to the camper.
- There's something
I wanted to tell you.
They're looking for
guys to work on a ranch.
I can make enough money to put
a nice down-payment
on a house for us.
- A house for us?
- Yeah.
But the ranch is in New Mexico.
- New Mexico?
How long will you be gone?
- That depends, the
longer I contract for,
the more money I
can make per day.
- Is it for a couple of months?
- No, no it's not for
a couple of months.
It's for three years.
- Three years?
- I know it...
- That's a long time, Will.
Three years.
- I'll be able to come home
when the seasons break.
Beth, what kind
of man would I be
if I can't make a life for us?
- It looks like you've
made up your mind.
- When I come back, Beth.
Then we'll get married.
You do wanna get married?
- Yes, I want that
more than anything.
- Well then, why are --
- Three years?
- Three years is
really not that long.
- Oh, I have one bar!
Who should I call?
Oh, I know, I'll search
for a towing company.
- Yeah, good idea.
I've lost
the signal again!
- Daddy you can lower me down
there and I can grab the keys!
- We are not lowering
you down there.
You know what, pumpkin?
Let's go back to the camper.
- But I wanna go
down in the well!
- That's just not
gonna happen, okay?
- You know, she hardly
weighs anything.
I can lower her
down really slowly.
She grabs the keys
and we're gone.
- We are not lowering
her down there!
- Please, Mom!
- What possibly could happen?
- She falls, that's
what happens!
- I won't fall, Mom!
- No, I've got a great idea.
Hold on, I'll be right back.
- Maybe I should get Grandpa.
- Everything will be okay, Mom.
- Okay pumpkin, are you ready
for our super secret mission?
- Yes!
- Okay, come on over here.
- Have you lost your mind?
- Oh, someone doesn't look
too thrilled about
your little plan.
- Okay, ready?
Put your foot in there.
- Have you lost your mind?
- How are you doing
down there, pumpkin?
I guess she's okay.
- Are you at the bottom?
- Yes!
- Do you see the keys?
- I got them!
- Looks like we got company.
- Okay, I'm going to need
you to be really quiet
for a minute, okay?
Shh quiet, super secret mission.
- Okay!
Shh, super secret mission.
- Howdy, folks.
- Hi.
- So uh, what are you
all doing out here?
- Uh, we just had a little
engine trouble, you know?
- Hm, engine troubles, huh?
- Yeah, it over-heated a bit.
- Did you need me to
call you a tow truck?
We can get one out
here right away.
- No, no, no.
Are you
sure? It's no trouble.
- No, we're good now.
I mean, it's under control.
We're just letting it
cool down.
- Okay, if you need
anything, give us a call.
You have a safe trip.
- Okay, bye bye now.
- You still got
hold of that rope?
Of course I do.
- Okay, are you
ready to come up?
- She's gonna be
heavier coming up.
We don't want you to drop her.
- That was fun,
can we do it again?
That was so much fun.
I was on the rope and you,
I could hear you yelling
"grab the keys in the dirt!"
It was so much fun!
- Mm-hm, yeah.
- There's your problem,
the hose got a leak in it.
Give me a screwdriver
and a sharp knife.
- I got this, dad.
- Stop with that "I got this."
Get the screwdriver and knife.
- How's it going out there?
- We'll get it figured out.
- Dad, that was so much
fun, can we do it again?
- I don't think so.
Why don't you finish
your sandwich?
- I want to thank you for
taking the time out to, uh.
- Oh, I know it was
important to you, dad,
to come out here.
- Eddie, do you know
why I'm so rough on you?
- No, why is that?
- You're not close to the Lord.
- Well, that's gonna solve
all my problems, huh?
- That's the problem
with your generation.
- Oh, my generation?
- That's right,
you expect all the
problems to be fixed right now.
That's not the way it works!
- Would you give it a rest
with the holy roller stuff?
Man, it's getting old.
I'm sorry that was uncalled for.
- Okay, go ahead
and start her up.
Alright.
Knew it all the time.
Alright, lets go find that tree.
- Yes!
- Okay, it's the next exit.
- Okay guys, we're almost there!
Wait, I thought you
said the next right?
This is a dead end.
- This can't be the right road.
- Look, the maps says
it's the road, see?
- Stupid goat.
- Maybe there's a way around?
- I don't see
another way around.
This is supposed to be the
road that leads to Two River.
- Thank you, Jessie.
- Why aren't we going to
the tree to bury Grandma?
- Because the road's
blocked, pumpkin.
- I think he wants to be alone.
- Do you remember that old tree?
Yes, I remember
the tree.
- I want you to
put my ashes there.
- Don't talk like that,
you're gonna be fine.
- We both know I
don't have very long.
I left something there for you.
- What are you talking about?
- It's nothing really,
it's just a young girl who
wrote a letter to her
true love.
I'm glad we were married.
We had a wonderful
life together.
- Yes we did.
- I'm going to close
my eyes for a moment.
- Are you just gonna leave
him out there all night?
- No.
I'll go get him.
Come on, you can't
sit here all night.
Come on.
- Eddie, take me to that church.
- Let's dance.
- Dance?
Beth, there's no music.
So what? Come on.
You see, we don't need music.
- Beth?
- Dad?
- Where did she go?
- She's gone, dad.
- Eddie?
It's a miracle you're
here.
I've never told you this story.
I was working toward getting
a home for your mother
so we could get married
and start a family.
Somebody almost made
all that not happen.
Paul had his own plan in mind.
- Is this about that boy?
- I don't know what
you're talking about.
- Honey, do you really think
I don't know whats going on?
I was once young too and
in love with your father.
So i understand.
- I write letters to
him almost everyday
but suddenly he
doesn't write me back.
- Sometimes boys
can be pretty dumb.
They can do stupid things.
- Maybe he's met
someone over there.
- Well maybe he has
but I would lay odds
she's nowhere near as
beautiful and as smart as you.
Oh honey, God will work
this all out for you.
"My dearest Will,
"I have asked that you call
so I can rest my nerves.
"Where are you?
"I'm lost without you.
"Please send me something.
"Even if it means goodbye."
- I'm sorry, what did
you say your name was?
- My name is Paul.
I've come a long way to
have a word with Beth.
It's about Will,
it's kinda important.
Beth.
- Do you know this young man?
- It's okay, dad.
- Could I talk to you?
- Sure.
- You uh, you might
wanna sit down.
- So how do you know Will?
- We worked together.
- You said your
name is Paul, right?
- Yes, yeah.
- You traveled all this way?
You must have something
important to say to me.
- Beth.
- He's dead, isn't he?
- No, no, no.
He's not dead, he's, uh.
- Are you going to tell me?
- Yeah, yeah I'm gonna tell you.
Will met someone and
now they're gonna get married.
- I'm sorry, did you say
he was getting married?
- Yes.
- You came all
this way to tell me
he was getting married?
- I found this letter
that you sent to him.
He had thrown it in the garbage.
I asked him if he
was gonna tell you
and he just said
"She'll get over it."
I mean, I felt so bad for you.
I saw the address on
the envelope and...
well here I am.
- I don't believe it,
I need to go see him.
- No, no you don't
wanna do that.
- I need to see this for myself.
I need to meet this girl.
- He's not there anymore.
- Where did he go?
- I don't know where they went.
Beth.
He's gone, Beth.
He's gone.
And she believed him.
They began dating.
His family had money.
The only reason he
was working there
was because he got
into some trouble
and his father
wanted to punish him.
Thought it would humble him.
Turn him into a stand-up man.
I finally woke up, recovered
and was able to
travel back home.
- Beth!
It's me, I'm home.
- What are you doing here?
- What do you mean,
"what am I doing here"?
- I'm home.
- What are you talking about?
- What are you doing here?
I said!
What are you doing here, Paul?
- Look, they said you
weren't gonna make it.
- So you thought you
could just take my girl?
- What's he talking about, Paul?
Paul told me you got married.
- Married?
- Go home, Paul.
- So you never got married?
- No.
- Well then why didn't
you answer my letters?
- I was in an
accident, I couldn't.
A tractor fell on me, Beth.
I've been in the
hospital the whole time.
- Andy.
- Your mother and
I saw each other
every single day after that.
- What ever happened to Paul?
- I don't know and
nor do I care to know.
- Oh sorry, we just walked in.
- Grandpa came here
to talk to God!
- Well that's alright,
my church is your church.
- And we're gonna
go bury Grandma
at the tree at at Two River.
- Two river?
There's a place I haven't
heard mentioned in years.
Ever since the
freeway went through,
Two River has become just
a memory around here.
- So you know where the tree is?
- Well, I can tell you
how to get to Two River,
but they have a lot of trees.
- We just need to
know where to go.
- I'll find the tree
once we get there.
- Dad, are you okay?
- I'm fine, I'm fine.
There it is.
I remember that bench.
- Look, there's your names!
- Oh, the tree's all dead now.
Do you have the urn?
- I don't have it, I
thought you had it.
- I must have left
it at the barricade.
- Don't worry dad, I'll get it.
Here, why don't you sit down?
Let's clear the bench, can we?
- Are you okay?
Can we get you anything, dad?
- I'm fine now.
- You guys wait here, I'm
gonna go run and get the urn.
- Let's give Grandpa some space.
"My dearest Willam,
"I have finally let
go, I have been told
"that you've found another.
"But deep in my heart I know
we will be together again.
"Your true love, Beth."
- Mom.
Grandpa found another letter.
- Grandpa!
- Just a little cat nap, honey.
- Dad, you're killing me here.
- Hey, pumpkin.
Hey.
- Where's your flight suit?
- Dad, that's for little kids.
Okay.
You know what Ernest needs?
- What?
- I think Ernest needs a friend.
Grandpa!
What do you think?
- Mom, your hand!
It's not shaking.
- She's right.
That medication
is really working.
Yeah, it's really
helped.
So who's gonna say grace?
- Um, I'd like to say it.
Dear God, thank you for
bringing us this meal
and thank you for allowing us to
lay our mother and
Grandmother to rest.
- And thank you for
bringing our family closer.
- And thank you
for giving us the
strength to complete
our journey.
- Amen.
Amen.
- Hello?
Oh hi, Walt.
It's Walt from Zebra Glue.
Yeah I haven't heard
from you in a long time.
- He owns your dad's old
company's competition.
- Well sure, yeah they
let me go last week.
Well yeah, this Monday?
Well, yeah!
Of course I remember
where your office is.
Okay, yes, thank you sir.
Alright, yeah, okay.
Thanks, bye.
That was Walt from Zebra Glue.
He offered me a job.
Zebra Glue?
I use that all the time.
Now that's a real company.
- What, he just offered
you a job, just like that?
- Yeah, he said they wanted
someone with real loyalty.
They've wanted me for a
long time but they'd never
think I'd leave Fazzle Glue.
That's amazing!
- I know.
The only problem is the pay...
is double what I got before!
- So does that
mean I get a phone?
- Yes, as soon as
you get all A's.
Okay, let's eat!