What?
A date with a woman in that
village a long time ago
I was cute
Be careful, I think you ’re an insider
Shoot if you shoot
Are you still in the village?
Probably
What?
can not understand
Separate the hands and check the tent and truck
I watch the surroundings
You're the dead body
All right
Who?
Are you serious?
To there
Sit down
This woman?
Why in the tent?
What is she?
"Don't go down"
What is that woman?
The prisoner in the tent
I got my finger cut off
Why don't you kill me
It's a civilian
3 people look around
Right now!
Clerk
What is your mission?
stop
What is our mission?  A simple question
Kill all the humans in the enemy camp
Collect the materials
This woman was also in the enemy camp
Yeah but she...
Shoot and kill
Pull out the gun and shoot this woman
I feel responsible for my brother's death
But she's irrelevant
Shoot as I was told
Command is absolute
There is someone over there
How many enemies are there?
Apparently there are at most 3-4 people
Ask Walker for rescue
Roger that
It ’s a fierce shootout that calls for rescue right away.
This one too
It is a strategy change
Gather in a helicopter
Rescue does not come
You're a lie
Come on!
hurry up!
Fucking bastard
We are the same
let's go
I'll run away
Over here
What?
Nothing apart
If you have something to say
Nothing
Really?
What did you say
To whom?
That prisoner woman
Kia spoke
What story?
"Don't go down"
Is it your mama?
Stop
Wait, lie
There are stairs
Let's go quickly There is quite a lot to the top floor
Fine?
I forgot about the past
I can't forget
Don't worry, it's true
Is it just me?  It doesn't arrive even if it goes up
Are you okay?
I wait here
No good
I have a bad feeling
me too
Are you all okay?
Are you all safe?
It's settled
Look at someone
I go
No
Calm down
Power problems
Buxton?
Buxton!
Shit what?
No good
Don't go down
Run
Go up!
Is that no good either?
Wireless communication
What's happening
God's work
God is trying
Don't say silly
She is right
When did you become pious?
Because of my first mission when I was 19 years old
If you were escorting the prisoners ---
Surrounded by convoys by the rebels
I was caught with the prisoners too
It took 5 months to escape
Behind their hideout ––
There was a clock tower with a long staircase
They are every day
Everything was scattered on the stairs
Like broken glass or safety pins
We took off our shoes...
Walked on it
Repeat over and over again
All day long
I was told that I was a soul judge
So no doubt
This is punishment
What?
Kill the prisoners
Don't talk silly
Thinking about the current situation
There will be danger every few minutes
I have to run away
First I'll find the exit
Don't talk useless
that's an order
Let's go up
I feel like I'm climbing the same stairs all the time
Even if you reach the top
It looks like I'm back down
There is an exit
Hold the gun
With an enemy?
Already one person was killed
What is this?
No way now...
Stop it, no
impossible
That's right
After all it may be punishment
I can not do it
Go down
Don't say stupid
What should I do?
I do not understand
But below is dangerous
Why do you know it is dangerous?
I feel
I'm sorry ---
Believe in God better than you
Stop it Ryan
Certainly I swore loyalty
But it ’s not going to hell
This song again
My mother sang when I couldn't sleep
I can't sleep
It's a creepy song
what will you do?
Let's go up
Until when?
eternally?
Thought to me
Try talking
You should run away before that
let's go
So what?
I'm just beginning to see
Are you going to hell soon?
Ford is noisy
Mostly about prisoners
The date and place of detention are written
That woman is from Calcars
It seems like I was restrained for a long time
aside from that?
The instruction "Do not kill her"
Her synonym is also listed
What?
"The Prophet of Death"
Local superstition
I think you can understand it without explaining
This situation is obviously related to her death
What?  Kia
Is it my fault?
I apologize
If you say too much
I'll kill you
Stop Stanton
Shut up Garrett
Everyone, set the clock
Nolan and Walker watch over the door
Everything else is reconnaissance
reconnaissance?
Do you get it
Same as usual training
It's a situation that doesn't make sense.
There's no need to stay on the stairs
Let's find a solution
Ford comes with me
What?
can not understand
What if you don't come back?
Walker?
listening?
What's wrong?
Don't come
Emma
Lower the gun
Please drop the gun early
Listen to the story!  Lower the gun
Walker!
Come to help
Please
Walker!
What about Walker?
I have to go!
Need a strategy
This is different from training
I know
Really
What is it then?
Obviously supernatural power is working
That power seems to want to stop our actions in the past
I want to save the prisoners
what will you do?
do nothing
eh?
Wait, I don't understand what you mean
do nothing?
I should have decided to die when I took on the mission
Once on the battlefield every danger awaits
Will This is not the battlefield
No, it ’s the battlefield
My mission was to kill people in
the enemy camp and collect information
Mission completed
If you are destined to die here
That kind of contract
Dan's death was a disaster
But don't drag too much
Your judgment will slow down
My brother's death is my responsibility
Prioritized emotions over missions
Either way my brother may have died
But even now, every time I close my eyes
The moment my brother died crosses my head
I just regret
Younger brother wasted
For something big
We are disposable pieces anyway
Just follow the instructions
I understand your feelings
Can Nolan go first?
I have a leg injury, so it takes time to walk
go
Harris, stop it
I'll kill you
That's probably right
This fucking guy
Wake up
Stop it already
I'll go
Standing
I can't
go
Don't be stupid, stand up
Save the prisoners
Correct the past--
The future should change
No, I can't leave
let's go
Who else has limited legs?
Don't pick your finger within 24 hours
Really angry
It ’s torture as Walker says.
Let me rest a little
I ’ve been out twice
I returned to the same past both times
Do you remember where you were at that time?
I divided myself and watched around
Attack from the left
So run to the right and in front of the tent
How can Clark avoid killing prisoners?
Just tell the past about the circumstances
What if a man just like you suddenly appears?
I'll kill you
exactly
You don't have to touch yourself in the past
Our ambush fails if we inform the enemy
What if the enemy killed me?
Come on
It ’s like “Back to the Future”
I like the third work
Ignore the present
I can't think of another good strategy
If you scare your enemies, they may escape from there.
What are you waiting for?
If nobody is gone, let's go home
I think it's impossible
Unbearable for a long time on
the battlefield without supplies and rescue
Am I left?
There are no exceptions for everyone
No
Just drive them away
Separate the hands and check the tent and truck
I watch the surroundings
You're the dead body
Who?
This woman?
What are you doing?
I confirmed my finger
Why does my finger return?
Something might have changed
What is that woman?
Nothing has changed
Clerk
What is your mission?
stop
What is our mission?  A simple question
It's time already
What is your strategy?
Not particularly
Shoot Stanton?
No, all will survive
Is that possible?
Command is absolute
I have to go back to the door
If you start running, you will be shot
But I have to go
Shoot the ground only once
Someone is over there
go
My legs are dangerous
I'm worse
I'll try again
Now let's go back and help the prisoners
There is time between when an enemy soldier gets up and when he attacks
Let's enter a tent while attracting with a gunshot
I
Nolan is impossible, and two people
lack in preparation and training
Shut up and leave it to me
What if I can't make it?
That's right
Wait until you return
now
My back was shot
May breathe
What is that woman?
The prisoner in the tent
I got my finger cut off
Why don't you kill me
What is your strategy?
Same as before
Help Ford after driving away with a gun
Command is absolute
There is someone over there
stop it
Nolan and the two of us go back together
How many enemies are there?
Apparently there are at most 3-4 people
Ford standing
Look!
I'll go
How about two people?
hurry up!  let's go
Die if you don't pick up bullets
I have to stop bleeding
Bite this
Believe
sorry
Hang in there
finished
I won't hold it for a long time unless I see a doctor
What is your strategy?
There
Ford firmly
Otherwise I'll die
This strategy does not work
shut up
He's right
Then, another good idea?
If you reach the helicopter
Escape from here and help Ford
If we die on the battlefield in the past, we will disappear
No abnormalities
Fine?
Pitiful guys
Let's stop him
Still not possible now
Which one?
I'm back again
Thought to fail
Noisy!
stop!  Are you listening?
Damn it!
Let's move
I'll regret it if I take it off
Right
But I'll take it off
Now try a different method
<What?  〉
What is that woman?
The prisoner in the tent
I got my finger cut off
Nolan?
Two people look around
Right now!
Pull out the gun and shoot this woman
Shoot as I was told
I've besieged, release the prisoners
You can negotiate with this
Who are you?
If you don't release the prisoners, you'll kill all
It ’s a lie to be surrounded
If it ’s true, I ’m already dead
Do you get it
So what is your request
Release the prisoners and leave
Then don't kill
Unfortunately...
Command is absolute
Quickly
I don't know how long I will hold
Good luck
For what?
To challenge
The prisoners were destined to die
I'm sure we too
It's the worst
Maybe already dead
You must have thought about it once
I said Walker was torture...
Here is hell
<What?  〉
Someone is over there
Why don't you kill me
It's a civilian
I'll stop
I can't stop it
Is that so?
Two people go
You can get out of here if you save the prisoners
This hell never ends
Absolutely
I'll finish
Where did you do it?
I was in the enemy
I brought it
Now i know why
Nolan may be right
I won't die
The worst strategy
Right
I'm sure there is another way
forget
To the container
Save them if possible
Join the helicopter
It ’s going to be a battle
I want to help as many people as possible
What is that woman?
Pull out the gun and shoot this woman
Shoot as I was told
Someone is over there
What are the materials?
Is that all?
I don't know
Kill all the enemies
what are you doing?
Lower the gun
First aid and return to duty
The important thing is to act correctly
rather than command
Now i know
It will be the worst ending
Doesn't work
Do not remove
I won't remove it
Come with me
Good?
It is a strategy change
Gather in a helicopter
It's all right now
Do not worry
Should be fine
Who are you
"Save the civilian" command
It's not a taxi
Begging because it's okay
There are others, wait a moment
Wait only 2 minutes
It was safe
Can I rent a car?
Do whatever you want
lost sight of
What about Stanton?
I'm dead
Why is that woman?
New order, take her with you
Watch your fingers
what are you doing?  Let's go early
Kia what are you doing
go
You heard?  go
The traitor!
Kia
You are expelled from the unit
Why such a manet?
The instruction was wrong
Keep silent
Stanton!  This fucking guy
Quickly
Where are you?
Radio returned
Is the civilian safe?
Everyone is on a helicopter
Go already
I can't go
Back to help
No
go
Command
Okay, good luck
Did you correct the mistake?
Yeah
If there is a way to stop the battle...
The battle never ends
So be
Very cold
Right
Do you remember the song that mom sang?
I was saved by that song
What is the headquarters?
Speak honestly
Stanton shot Clark
I unavoidably shot him
No materials found, rescued civilian POW
Wait, lie
There are stairs
Let's go quickly There is quite
a lot to the top floor