Crunching leaves under footsteps
panic heavy breathing
Intense sounds
So how long were you
lost before I found you?
I don't know.
I wasn't really keeping track
of the time or anything.
But I just saw this really beautiful hill
and I wanted to climb it and see the view.
And then...
I got lost.
Not a good idea I guess.
- You guess?
That's good that I found you then.
Yeah, thanks again. I don't know what I
would have done if you hadn't found me.
- I mean, a girl can die up
...if she gets lost.
No, I think if a bear came
I could handle myself.
- Yeah?
It's not the bears you need to worry about
Hey!
Where we going?
Is this the way to the trail?
- You sure?
- Yeah!
Are you ready?
- No!
I'm not going in there.
- Oh, come on, I thought you
came out here for adventure?
- Wow, you are really
good at building a fire.
- Thank you.
What's wrong?
- Someone might see us.
- So?
- I don't know.
- Come on.
Hey!
Are you okay?
- I'm having a little trouble
finding my way back to the trail.
- Are you hiking by yourself?
- Yeah.
Oh my God, oh my.
Taylor!
Oh my God!
Oh my God, Taylor!
Taylor!
Let me help you.
Please let me help.
please, please.
Taylor!
Taylor stop!
Taylor.
Shit!
If I remember correctly,...
I'm not the one who ditched my brother
to travel along with some strange girl.
- But... um... would you be
having such witty conversations.
By myself?
Debatable...
...but not impossible.
- OK.
- I guess it's fate.
Fate?
- Well...
- You don't think so?
No...
- But it's kind of romantic, though.
Finding a lost girl in the woods?
- No...
- How we met.
On a trail?
A lot of people meet that way.
- I wouldn't say a lot.
- You make it sound so morose.
Well... what if it is bad?
- Sure.
- but what if it is good?
- Anyway...
- ...you're stuck here with me now.
Ok, whatever.
I think it's you who is stuck with me.
- OK.