♪♪
[birds chirping]
[crickets]
[animal calls]
♪♪
[explosion]
[creaking]
♪♪
[sirens]
Let's get this thing open.
♪♪
[metal- clink]
Come on.
♪♪
[shut door]
[cock's gun]
♪♪
All right kids, this is home.
We'll have operations from here.
3 floors.
HQ ground level.
Medical center 2nd.
Control up top.
Get moving!
Here you go Sir.
[click]
Looking good.
We're my beer?
Male: I got it.
I'm on it. I'm on it.
Male #1: What was this place?
Male #2: Old south side
precinct, maybe... [grunts]
Male #2: before they they built
a new one up on the hill.
Male #2:Communications?
Boss: Rooftop.
Male #2: Ah, great.
Jonathan!
Yes. Yes.
Boss: Get them on the phone.
Assist.: Right away, sir.
[sirens]
[Helicopter over head]
Damn, that freakin'
thing is huge.
Where do you think
they're from?
I have no idea.
Damn.
Say that again.
[whispers]
No. I gotta take
a leak.
You're kidding me, right?
I was 5 beers down
when I got the call.
You better hurry man.
We're going to get out of
here in a minute.
[Radio]
Commander, we have
a second unidentified
craft reported just prior
to the one near by.
[commander over radio]
Destination?
Woman: I'm working on it.
[commander over radio]
Jonathan, I need your
help on this.
Jonathan: Right away, sir.
Jonathan: What do you have?
Woman: It entered the atmosphere
76 degrees relative to the
surface. Velocity of 200mph.
Jonathan: Do you have point of
impact?
Woman: Um, no.
Jonathan: Do you have anything?
Woman: Wait! I'm picking up a
faint magnetic pulse.
Trying to isolate the loca.
Jonathan: That's not right.
Woman: We got it!
We located the crash in
the San Gabriel mountain.
Triangulate the position
according to the mobile, okay?
Time is crucial. Quick. Quick.
Jonathan: Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
Hopefully it's not in somebody's
backyard.
We are prepped and
ready to go, sir.
Excellent.
You guys load up.
Myron.
-Yes, sir.
-Find Davis.
You guys take my six.
You got it.
[urinating]
[radio static]
I hate to break it to you,
but pee pee time is over.
I'm not kidding man.
We're getting out of here now.
You're kidding me, right?
Prewitt is going to rip
our heads off.
Man, i'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
[crickets]
[animal calls]
♪♪
Male: Whatever we run into here,
we're gonna want alive, okay?
No lead.
Tranqu's only.
Where the hell is
Charlie team?
Sir, I'm trying to get them on
the phone right now.
♪♪
[indistinct dialogue]
Male: I took a look inside, sir.
It's empty.
It looks like it might be
2 of them.
Find them.
♪♪
[radio - male voice]
Blood trait located,
Commander.
Execute.
Commander: Stick with it B team.
What's 3 port John look?
Jonathan: 3 more in London,
France, and Moscow.
Commander: What does that bring
the total to?
Jonathan: Count is, 42 on the
ground.
42?
Now, 45.
Commander: I need a topographic
section 996954.
-...9-9-5--
-[Commander interrupts]
Listen son. 9-9-6-9-5-4.
[Jonathan repeats]
9-9-6-9-5-4. Got it.
♪♪
[Guard- indistinct dialogue]
[radio- male voice]
We have contact, sir.
-Report.
-Radio: going down river.
-Commander: Location?
-Radio: Just north of you.
-Commander: Stay on it. Use
your infrared to track it.
♪♪
-Radio: We're loosing them.
- Stand by. I need that map.
No signal. I--
♪♪
Ok, Bravo. Head south, soh
east to try to slow it down with
the tranqu's.
Radio: Roger that, sir.
Push it down stream and I'll
intercept.
♪♪
-Charlie team.
-I'm trying.
I'm trying.
♪♪
[shot tranquilizer]
Guard: Lay down!
♪♪
Lay down!
[zap]
♪♪
[tranquilizer shot]
[splash]
♪♪
Need some help getting
this guy out of the drink.
[animal calls]
[car approaching]
Male: You seeing what
I'm seeing?
I got this.
I bet you do.
[shuts car door]
Are you okay?
Were you in an accident?
Here, you can put this
on if you want.
Come on.
We'll give you a ride.
What's the deal?
Male #1: I don't know. She's not
talking. She's in shock,
I think.
Throw her in the back
and let's get going.
No.
Myron: Yeah sir this is My,
uh C team is going to rendezvous
in about 3 minutes.
[Radio- Commander]
You're 15 minutes late, Myron.
Myron: I realize that sir. We
uh, we were momentary delayed.
Commander: Let's set up a
permiter. Right now.
Male: Yes, sir. All right.
Myron: Jonathan!
Jonathan: Yes! Yes!
Myron: Get her to a local
authority right now.
Jonathan: Who is she?
Myron: I don't know! Ask her!
Myron, I'm glad you can make it.
- Sorry, sir. Bravo team is
down.
2 seats on the craft.
Only one detained.
Okay, you 2 jock up, join Alf.
We need to located the second
EBE.
♪♪
[zap]
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
♪♪
[shoots tranquilizer]
I think we found
the other one, sir.
Nice work, Myron.
Somebody check him.
-I got him.
♪♪
Sam Peter's is on his way.
I want everybody looking sharp.
Give me some scientist.
I want to know if we have a lock
on these machines, okay?
The creatures aren't talking.
Maybe these robots are.
♪♪
[beeping]
[no audible dialogue]
♪♪
Turn the count to the Megaliths.
- Megaliths?
- That's what they're called,
sir.
Six hundred and sixty-six,.
666.
- Last count.
- You can take crabwell a field
day with that.
Same time that these larger
transports appeared on our
radar...
smaller craft entered the
atmosphere crashing near the
San Gabriel Mountains.
On board were 2 EBEs.
Both are in our custody now.
There's 2 of them?
We have them? Here?
-Yes, sir.
That's the lead, Prewitt.
Don't bury the lead.
The first out of your mouth
should have been,
'there's a creature from
another planet being debriefed
in room 15a downstairs'.
Of course.
Sorry, sir.
I think you should
do the examination.
How the hell will I even know
what I'm looking at?
These things look like us.
[cell door unlocks/opens]
[cell door shuts/locks]
So what are we looking at?
It's a tough call.
I mean, they're...
not human.
It looks human.
Yes he does.
2 arms.
Legs.
Endoskeleton.
Dermis.
It's not what they are.
Has he spoken?
Not to me.
Just lays there.
Prewitt: Why not just land in a
the larger craft?
Prewitt: Why take the risk of
that fragile pod, in the middle
of nowhere?
Commander: Didn't you say he
took out a team of your men?
Commander: Maybe they're not as
vulnerable as they look.
Commander: For all we knowe
machines are just a smoke screen
for the real threat.
Commander: Them.
Well, maybe we'll have more luck
with the female.
♪♪
[beep]
[door opens]
Myron: Davis, station yourself
in holding room 1.
Entry only on my older.
-Yes, sir.
Any communication?
Not that I'm aware of, sir.
Hello?
Can you speak?
Talk.
What can you tell me about those
things out there?
Come on.
You didn't travel all this way
to say nothing.
What do you want?
[scoffs]
Jesus.
I supposed you know sign
language?
No, sir.
[door opens/shuts]
[whispers]
Hi.
Jesus Christ.
- I need the numbers.
I need them now.
- Myron: Contact langlian.
See what they can find as far as
linguistics experts, okay?
Sign language. Symbologi.
Freakin' charades professionals.
Whatever they can find.
Gotcha.
And round up some drawing
supplies. Maybe they can't talk.
After I debrief here. i want to
set up with the male in
interrogation one.
Yes, sir.
Test those number again.
Right there.
♪♪
What's going on?
We're about to knock
on their door.
[Commander V.O.]
Initial task has been unable to
operate the megaliths.
Even with any know X-ray and
microwave technology.
We have detected a rhythmic
patter emanating from them.
Broadcasting in the lines--
[indistinct audio]
Myron: What does the signal
mean?
Commander: Maybe their way to
communicate?
These scientist, with
exemption of our soldiers,
are attempting to talk megaliths
with light intervals.
Mathematics.
Universal language.
Myron: What do you intend to
say?
Why the hell are you here?
♪♪
[gunshots]
[zap]
♪♪
I guess that means they're
hostile.
♪♪
Have any of them attacked
yet that weren't provoke?
Nothing.
666 quiet.
-They're waiting for something.
-Obviously.
How are you with our 2 friends
downstair?
No progress.
What if the megaliths ae
looking for them?
Lots of "what if's". Whatf
they caused this? What if you're
warning us?
[sigh]
How will Washington respond?
Full strike.
Possibly nuclear.
UN is woking overtime right now
to find it's achilles heel.
What if they're benevolent?
Lots of "what if's".
Woman: They wouldn't hurt her.
Would they?
What'd you say?
Your thought patters are
amazingly random.
Attaching the meanings and the
sounds is being quite difficult.
Commander, you might want
to come down to the
interrogation room.
[whispers]
He's going to be
happy you're talking.
[laughs]
Who's Angelina Jolie?
[whispers]
What?
Angelina Jolie.
Um, she's an actress.
[scoffs]
[both speak same time]
I was just thinking that you
look like her.
[both speaking]
What did you say?
Woman: Hey what's going on?
Is she reading my mind or
something? Stop! Clear my mind.
Try to clear my mind.
- Look! Cut that out, okay?
It's freaking me out.
Your world is in trouble,
Joshua.
We have watched from a great
distance.
And observed that you have
become a danger.
Your weaponry is too advanced.
You have endangered
your own planet.
And have become too big of a
threat to others in the future.
The end is here.
♪♪
But your world can be saved.
It can save itself.
If you can show me that there is
value in human life,
the destruction can be sto.
Prove this to me and there will
be a tomorrow.
♪♪
[scoffs]
He should be here any second.
♪♪
You have till the sun is down
at the end of this day, to
find a solution.
Myron?
She's talking, sir.
Excellent.
Where exactly are you from?
[sigh]
Why are you here?
She said she wants us to show
her the value of human life,
sir.
or what?
Maybe she should tell you .
What is your purpose here?
What exactly did she tell you?
[TV - woman speaking]
You have until the sun is down
at the end of this day to
find a solution.
Was she actually reading
your mind?
Yes, sir.
Prove that human life has
value. How the hell are we
supposed to do that?
Take her to see the
goddamn Lion King?
How can we even be sure that
she's being honest with us?
It could be a ployed to escape.
I for one am gonna need
a little more information
or questioning.
Exactly. She's proven she can
talk. Now just a matter of
getting the answers.
Plus if she can talk? Theyh
can talk. I think we work on the
man immediately.
Maybe she cares about him?
We can use that to get her to
tell us what we need to know.
Prewitt: It's a good point.
Guard: No, sir.
Let's interrogate individually
and then we'll try a group
session, okay?
Sir.
I believe her.
It's not that simple.
Well the farthest thing she's
asking to experience is
continuing to be locked up here.
Subjected to--
[interrupts]
She's dangerous, Myron.
You're forgetting that because
of the face she's wearing.
Don't you remember how she
defended herself at the crash
site?
You think she's Gandhi with
powers like that?
At least we have to keep trying.
We have to figure out a waf
showing her how valuable life is
inside this facility.
'Cause she's never going outside
these walls.
[clears throat]
♪♪
Hey.
You're going to have to
talk to these guys.
What's your
name?
It's difficult
to say in your
language.
The closest word
would probably be,
"Sky".
Sky.
Okay.
[door opens]
Myron, give us some privacy.
Yes, sir.
[sighs]
♪♪
All right, we tried this the
easy way.
[beep]
♪♪
Let's give her a
nice full dose.
[rumbling]
♪♪
Hurry up.
Doctor: I'm trying.
[rumbling]
shit.
This is dangerous.
Deliver the injection.
[zap]
♪♪
Myron: Sky!
[zap]
[scream]
♪♪
Enough.
[tazing]
Sky.
[grunts]
[punch]
[cocks gun]
Stop it!
[grunts/groans]
You are relieved
of duty, Myron.
Go home.
♪♪
Cuff her to
the chair.
♪♪
Prewitt: As far as we can tell
they use the surrounding energy
to defend themselves.
Administering a counter current
of electricity will disable the
ability.
Commander: Fighting fire
with fire.
Prewitt: Exactly.
How long until the Pentothal
takes effect?
Prewitt: A few minutes.
Commander: And what about the
girl?
Prewitt: We shot her up with a
sedative. She's sleeping like a
baby.
Commander: Maybe Myron should be
present when you question her?
She seems to have formed an
attachment.
Prewitt: Josh Myron is no longer
part of the team, sir.
Where you gonna go?
Colorado.
Go see my father in his cabin.
Going AWOL?
I was relieved of my duties.
Okay, I'm not gonna stick
around this place
and watch them provoke
that thing into a fight.
Here.
Hey.
Take care of your
family. All right?
[opens car door]
[beeping]
[slams door]
[starts engine]
[screeching tires]
Prewitt: Why didn't you speak
to us before?
Male: There are many forms of
communication.
Male: I simply needed
to learn yours.
We speak much differently.
Prewitt: We?
For all your technology, you've
barely stepped out of onto the
doorstep of this universe.
We are...neighbors, really.
What is your name?
Male: My name is of little
consequence.
I was sent here to deliver.
Prewitt: The woman.
And what role does she play?
She is...
the destroyer.
♪♪
Woman: Sir, Washington is ready.
[beep]
Destroyer?
What the hell is that?
Washington is ready
for what?
There's been a case with
the EBE as which position
we need to hit first.
- That's suicide.
- Maybe. This isn't?
What's the assault?
Probably air.
Tapped into the NSE.
Commander: It launched 20
minutes ago.
[jet whoosh overhead]
How's your boy?
He's with his mom.
Pilot: I have visual.
♪♪
[radio]
Pilot: Target's been engaged.
[jet whoosh]
♪♪
[explosion]
[radio]
Pilot: Missiles away.
Weapons ineffective.
[radio]
Pilot: Wait. Something's
happening.
[zap]
[explosion]
♪♪
Question is, do we pull the
tail on this tiger or not?
♪♪
[beep]
[open door]
[door shuts]
[beeps]
[car approaching]
[voice whispers]
Joshua.
♪♪
[voice whispers]
Joshua.
♪♪
[screeching tires]
[Indistinct female dialogue]
♪♪
[beeping]
[helicopters overhead]
♪♪
[beeping]
[power outage buzz]
[zap]
♪♪
[humming/rumble]
Prewitt: Oh shit.
Prewitt: Um...
[door breaks open]
[grunts/groans]
Okay.
It's okay.
I'll get you
out of here.
[grunts]
Okay.
You good?
Let me get these wires.
Listen, just stay close, okay?
Come on.
♪♪
[grunt]
[struggling to starts engine]
Get out of the car, Myron.
Get out of the car!
[hum/rumble]
[engine starts]
...do it.
Prewitt: Myron!
[screeching tires]
♪♪
[sigh]
I can't explain to you
the value of human life.
I mean, you want to know about a
9 millimeter, I'm your man.
I'm not a philosopher.
I don't know the value
of human life.
In fact, if you really want to
know the truth...
I'm not so sure at all it means
anything myself.
[revs engine]
It appears to be
an EMP, sir.
Everything that relies
on electricity is
useless for the moment.
Vehicles-
I know what an EMP is.
How long till
we're back up?
No telling.
Anything word from
Sharon before we
lost power?
No, sir.
Goddamn Dark Ages.
The electric pulse corresponds
to 2 criteria.
It is a result of the
simultaneous magnetic beams.
And it also serves as harbinger
to the seriousness of the
situation.
A harbinger?
A sign of things to come.
Clear the room.
What's going on out there?
Did you thing that there
would not be consequences
to your actions?
So whatever's happening is
because of us?
The actions of your kind are
predictable.
That is why she was sent.
To put an end to the inevitable.
We will find a way to breach
those things.
Since you know us so well, you
know we don't give us very
easily.
Yes.
Unfortunately there is no .
What do you mean?
The countdown has begun.
The man is
talking again.
What's he saying?
The countdown
has begun?
What countdown?
That save humanity
crap?
There's been some
repercussions due to the
tempt of DC Mageliths.
if any of the Pilots survived.
We lost communications due to
the electrical magnetic pulse.
But before we lost
communications we were able to
capture some vital information.
Each of the Mageliths across the
globe has begun to omit a high
intensity energy theme.
Focused on one central
location. The Earth's core.
Result of this will cause
the core's spin to slow.
Cause the core to spin to .
In other words, the Earth is
beginning to tilt off it's
normal axis.
Doesn't make any sense.
Why? What do they stand to gain
from this? Strategically makes
no sense?
[hum]
Well, that's a good sign.
How long do we have?
Well it's only an assumption-
[interrupts]
How long?
The Earth is large,
even for the Mageliths-
[both interrupt]
How long?
What are we talking
about here? Days?
Weeks?
Hours.
[radio - indistinct dialogue]
Hold on.
I want to hear this.
[radio - male voice]
Together we find ourselves in
the midst of a global crisis.
This is our President.
He's the leader of our cou.
That's the guys you should be
talking to. Not - not me.
I'm just- I mean-
What is church?
[no audio]
Some place I was going
to take you to.
Might not be what
you're expecting?
It's kinda what I have though.
In this church, will you
show me your humanity?
God, I hope so.
[scoffs]
I mean I'm not religious
or anything but,
you know when I was
a kid I use to go to
church with my Mom.
The Pastor there had a
way of making things
seems kind of, simple.
Mom?
Yeah, my Mom.
[Thud]
Get out of the car! Both of you
get out of the car, NOW!
GET OUT! NOW!
There's aliens all
over this city.
And you guys are the only
people with the working car.
Male: So get out or I shoot
the bitch. Now! Move it!
Myron: Get out. Go. Go.
Male: Move it!
[slams door]
You all right?
Why didn't you
stop him?
Why would I do that?
Because you can.
With the this thing.
It's not my place
to do so. I'm here
to observe.
All right, fine.
Let's walk.
[sirens]
♪♪
Sir, Josh Myron's file.
Excellent.
Thank you, Jonathan.
Jonathan: Anything.
Prewitt: Carry on.
[sirens continue]
Where are you, Josh?
♪♪
This is what lies
in the hearts of
earthlings?
All this pain.
It's called
Sacrifice.
Why haven't they
run like the other?
Myron: They come here
for shelter.
They feel peace, here.
We have watched your
world from afar.
And we have seen wars
and power struggles...
and great fear.
From the inside there's
so much more.
So much you don't know
about our world.
Wait here.
Excuse me?
I'm looking for
father James.
He's not here.
You are in
the exodus.
He left to help them.
♪♪
[baby coos]
Game over?
What does this mean?
It means, you picked
the wrong tour guide.
I chose you because of the
questions you have in your
heart, Joshua.
You chose me?
That's right.
What happens to the
world shouldn't rest
on my shoulders.
But it does.
You have a purpose.
As I do.
[baby coos]
♪♪
What's it like where
you're from?
♪♪
[indistinct audio]
[sigh]
It was really nice.
♪♪
Sir.
We've got a signal
on Davis.
Excellent.
Where?
The Church on Hill st.
- But-
- But, what?
Well...we lost signal.
So we have no contact
with Davis or the others?
- Well, it could just be-
- Form a small team,
deploy them to the scene.
- How long
until sunset?
4 hours, 15 minutes.
- Well, then hurry.
- Yes, sir.
[radio]
Radio check. Radio check.
Davis, come in.
Myron: So all I have to do is
find father James and we're out
here on the street.
Got a thousand square
city blocks.
No ride.
4 hours till sunset.
Perfect.
When the going gets tough,
the though get going?
Yeah, it's one of my
father's favorites.
You know what? I'm not so sure I
like you being in my head all
the time, okay?
Your thought patters are
very confusing.
You know, some times we consider
our thoughts to be private, here
on planet Earth.
What is it that you
seek to hide?
We need transportation.
Let's try this thing.
[claps]
Come on.
[sighs]
[thud]
Geez.
Look.
I'm gonna need you to
participate here, okay?
If you want me to show you the
value of humanity, you're gonna
have to help out.
Told you, I do not
get involved.
Fine.
Look.
[breathing heavily]
Put these on.
If we're gonna walk, you
might as well wear those.
They might be a little big but,
they're better than nothing.
Hey.
That's our car!
It's the guy who took our car!
Hey! get out of the car!
Man: Josh, put the gun down!
Go, go, go!
Go!
Run!
[screeching tires]
♪♪
[screeching tire]
[screeching tires]
♪♪
Male: Scan the vehicles,
front and back.
Male: Josh?
Come on, buddy.
Doesn't have to be this way.
Take a ride downtown.
Everything gonna be fine.
♪♪
All right, Josh.
Last chance, hand
over the girl.
♪♪
[gunshots]
Josh, man!
What are you doing?
[thud]
Why you doing this, man?
I'm just trying to do
what she asked.
Let's just take her to
headquarters.
She's the only hope
we've got.
♪♪
Male: Josh! Josh!
[screeching tires]
♪♪
Prewitt: Agent Lewis says
they found you wondering the
halls of our facility.
I was curious.
I know the feeling.
Your time is running out.
Sunset, right?
- Yes.
- And what happens
at sunset?
Well whatever it is, it
happens to both of us.
My life is,
unimportant.
And ours?
We see you as
the aggressor.
You are a threat.
You came to our planet.
To avoid our
inevitable conflicts.
So the plan is, eradicate
the problem.
In this case, us, before it
becomes a problem?
So who's the aggressor?
It's just practical.
[whispers]
Practical?
There's so many things
wrong with that statement.
What about, making first
contact that peaceful?
What about communicating
with us?
That is what she is for.
What if she's not shown
the value of humanity?
Then, you will die.
Look.
This is my son.
He's name's Cory.
He's 12 years old.
He's a little boy.
LOOK AT HIM!
There's your threat!
This is worth fight for.
This is the value of human.
Why then are you not
with him now?
♪♪
[dialing]
[phone ringing]
[voicemail greeting - female]
Hi this is Sharon Prewitt, I
can't come to the phone right
now but, leave your name and
number and I'll get back to you
as soon as possible [beep].
[sigh]
Hi, it's me.
[clears throat]
I don't know where you arem
sure it's impossible that you're
gonna get this but,
where ever you are, if you do
just stay there. Okay?
You can't out run this thing.
I'll find you.
I love you, guys.
[beep]
♪♪
Prewitt: Listen, I don't
want people working
reports, all right?
We don't have time for that.
I just want straight
information.
The UN security counsel
authorized the use of
nuclear weapons.
Nuclear strike have been
issued against the
megalith stationed
on the, pacific
island of Nauru.
Why?!
[office chatter]
Commander: Nauru has a
population of 9,000.
They'll produce the least
amount of casualties.
Prewitt: The least
amount of casualties?
Christ, Prewitt!
We have what?
4 hours before sunset?
What do you want
us to do?
We're talking 9.000
against billions!
It's not the time to get
on some moral bullshit
podium right now.
[whispers]
It's crazy.
♪♪
No.
Being a brat.
♪♪
[Jet whoosh]
[radio - pilot]
Target in sight.
[jet whoosh]
[explosion]
♪♪
Why...
[dialing]
♪♪
Tell me we we
destroyed it.
♪♪
What's wrong? What's
happening to you?
In so much pain.
What can I do,
Sky? What do you
need me to do?
Sky!
God dang it!
[radio- female voice]
A state of emergency has
been declared for
Los Angeles country and
the surrounding areas.
Anyone still remaining in
the Downtown area must
evacuate immediately
to disignated shelters where
food and medical--
Myron: Scared me.
[radio chatter at a distance]
I thought it was too late.
As long as there's sunlight,
there's still a chance.
[radio chatter continues]
One day is just
not enough time.
I mean, I've been living here
for years and I don't have the
answers you're looking for.
One day? I can't do it.
Sky: It's all that you have.
[radio chatter continues]
What can I possibly show you,
that you don't already know?
Sky: You cannot reach a
destination, without a journey.
What does that mean?
It means that you are the way.
[radio- female voice]
We just received this report.
Apparently a giant tsunami
wave has obliterated the tiny
island or Nauru. Leaving no
survivors.
[typing]
Our only real alternativet
this point, lies in the captured
EBES'.
It's a great deal of power,
it's obvious.
All of our resources are
focused on locating her.
Jonathan: 2 hours and
34 minutes till sunset.
We need all satellites
pointed downtown LA.
Plug into every traffic
cam, freeway cam, ATM,
signal light.
Her moves are recorded 200
times a day. There's gotta be
something out there.
Commander:
On the ground?
Our guys are crawling
all over every square
inch of this city.
Good, 'cause we're
running out of time.
♪♪
[woman screaming]
Man: Don't you worry.
Hey! Hey!
You have to help us!
What's the matter?
My wife is pregnant.
You have to bring us
to the hospital.
[groans]
Hey!
She's uh, she's going
to have a baby.
Come on. It's
gonna be okay.
-- a small child.
[woman groans]
Okay?
Man: Listen, lift
her up, lift her up.
Myron: We're under
Marshall law. Hospitals
are closed.
Where do you live?
We're right across
from the hospital.
Myron: Hold on.
Hold on.
Let's put here
in the back.
Watch your head.
Myron: Easy now.
Easy now.
♪♪
[screeching tires]
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Myron: Hang on! We're
being followed.
[screeching tires]
♪♪
[woman screaming]
Push.
♪♪
[baby crying]
[man chuckles]
♪♪
[baby cooing]
You want to know the
value of humanity?
You're staring at it.
♪♪
Man: Hey.
Lisa?
She's not breathing!
We need help!
Myron: She needs CPR.
Look out.
Myron: Slide her down.
Slide her down.
♪♪
[grunts]
2 hands.
[myron grunts]
[baby crying]
Don't stop.
We've lost her.
- No, don't stop!
[baby crying]
♪♪
[gasp]
Hey.
[door shuts]
Where are they?
Who?
I don't have time to
play games. The others.
There's no one here
but me and my wife.
And my new daughter, Sky.
Search the building.
♪♪
Tell me, we did it?
The sun's still up.
Did we do it?
Huh?
Did you feel that?
[chuckles]
You got involved when you
said you won't. That's
called compassion.
That's--
That's it.
What you felt in your heart,
that-
that's it!
[chuckles]
That's what it's all about.
Tell me we did it?
What else do we have to do?
[cocks gun]
I must get back to
my transport.
That's it? I just have to get
you back to your transport?
[gunshot]
♪♪
Oh God.
Get out!
♪♪
[cocks gun]
Don't move, Myron.
Don't move.
♪♪
Call a medic!
[beeping]
[chatter]
♪♪
Find anything?
[beeping]
♪♪
[zap]
You're in the custody of the
United States Government.
You're being treated as
a terrorist.
Do you understand?
Prewitt: There will be no
escape this time.
You and I are in this toge.
[whispers]
Sir, he's gone.
Find him.
♪♪
Sam, just listen to me
for one second, okay?
Let's get her back to the ship,
and she can put an end to this.
You showed her the meaning of
life? No offense but I doubt it.
We're so close.
What the hell do we
have to loose?
For all we know, the only reason
why they haven't destroyed the
planet is because she's on it
somewhere. I think we'll hold
on to her.
Already seen what she
needs to see.
Let's just get her to the
megalith.
Current condition, I doubt
she'll be going anywhere.
Let's go.
Sam, we gotta try.
Sam!
Sam, we gotta try!
How long do we have?
At best, you have but one .
Was it worth it?
He's safe.
What?
They're both safe.
Isn't that what you
really wanna know?
You should be with them.
They boy, he's afraid.
She and other are
gathered together.
But she feels alone.
How do I save them?
[whispers]
Sky: The world is ending.
Sky: Don't you think you should
be holding your son?
[sigh]
♪♪
Sam: Everyone evacuate the
building, now!
Evacuate the building now!
That's an order!
[grunts]
♪♪
Where's Prewitt?
Where's Prewitt?!
♪♪
[metal creaking]
Prewitt: Get her IV. We'll
get her out of here!
♪♪
Let's go.
[debris/metal creaks]
♪♪
Prewitt?
Prewitt?!
♪♪
Prewitt, what are you doing?
[screeching tires]
♪♪
Myron, stop the car. God p
me, I will shoot you myself, you
got that?
Sorry, Sam.
Taking her back to the
transport.
[radio]
Sam: Prewitt, you know she's the
only leverage we have left.
[radio]
Sam: Pull over now.
Sky, hand in there.
[screeching tires]
♪♪
You can't take her back to
the ship, Myron.
I gotta get her back!
You take her back to the ship,
they will destroy this planet.
It's a chance we'll
have to take.
You're gonna have to trust me.
She's dying, Sam. And I got to
get her back to the ship, now!
♪♪
You don't stop that car, we
may all die. You hear me?
Too late, Sir.
Myron? Dammit.
♪♪
[yelling]
[indistinct dialogue]
Prewitt: Sam, let him go!
Sam: MYRON!
Prewitt: LET HIM GO!
[metal creaking]
[distorted dialogue]
♪♪
[gunshot]
[metal creaking]
[zap]
♪♪
[narrator- Myron]
My short time on the
other side,
taught me that we need to learn
to live in harmony.
No just with ourselves, but
with the entire universe.
They returned to their planet,
leaving us here to
pick up the pieces.
Families were reunited.
Our cities rebuilt.
Somehow, every night, my eyes
search the stars wondering where
she might be in one of them.
We learned the value of peace.
Just as the memory of
her face would fade,
so would the warning that
she had brought with her.
Our world once divided,
learned to hope...together.
But I knew,
they would be watching.
♪♪