It's your fault.
- You are not allowed to leave alone!
- Okey, auntie.
Clean them later.
Whoever has dirty shoes is half human.
COME FOR ME
Eat, please!
You'll be here only for a while.
I want to go home!
- He captivated the cows.
- He poisoned the water.
People like him attract evil spirits.
- He can count man's teeth...
- We have to kill him! - Drown him!
- They can't swim.
- Burn him!
Limb of the devil!
Black demon eyes.
In dealings with the devil.
Can bring the death.
Yes, he is a vampire.
I'm buying him.
Next time you will try harder.
Mix well.
The unclean spirit will drink the blood...
then will find his own kind.
Evil force will turn into black mud.
He will bring only bad luck.
Son of a bitch!
Our boy is gone.
Try it on.
You whore!
You bitch!
What's the fuck is going on between you two?
Whore!
You wanted another brat?!
You whore!
You bitch!
Why is he staring at you like that?
What?
You whore!
You bitch!
I'm too old for you?!
You fucking bitch!
Lord Jesus...
Thank you for your kindness and generosity...
and for the time when you watch over us.
Amen.
You dirty pig!
You want to fuck my wife?
You boar!
Pig!
You won't be staring at her anymore!
Get the fuck out!
You whore!
You bitch!
Whore!
Are you gypsy?
You know how to cross yourself?
Good.
Hang it up higher!
Above!
Boy!
Come here.
Against evil spirits.
You'll be sitting here.
We will definitely sell some of them.
You want to fuck with our children,
you horny bitch?!
- You fucking whore!
- You bitch!
You won't get away with it, you slut!
Now you will see, you cunt!
Take this!
Don't be afraid, horsie,
I'll take care of you.
Where did he find him?
No!
No.
- No!
- Don't bother!
- Leave it to us.
- Down!
Krauts will appreciate it.
We need to go to this village.
Stop!
What is going on?
We have one Jew for you.
We caught him in the woods.
You need a volunteer!
Stop!
They're bringing some more!
A disgusting pig!
Die, pig!
Pig!
Pig.
Take him away.
Jesus took on himself all the sins of the world...
to redeem us and save us through his death.
Then he ascended to heaven...
and sits at the right side of the God.
He suffered at the hands of many people.
Just like you.
I believe you.
You can do it today.
In the name of father and son and holy spirit.
Amen.
Father?
Can I come in?
Silence! Quiet!
Stop it!
Father…
- I'm getting worse.
- I'm very sorry.
God bless you for your noble offer.
Our master will reward you for your goodness.
You'll like it here.
So are you on your way home?
And where is your house?
Eat.
You must have strength.
I'll take three.
The boy must start going to church again.
- I think...
- You haven't been at holy confession...
for a long time.
Sit down!
You'll be quiet...
or I'll kill you.
- My respect.
- And mine.
See you soon.
Let's pray.
I'm glad you look after him so well.
Father.
Read him the Bible every evening...
and yourself too.
I warned you.
Where did you get it from?
Talk!
Where did you get it?!
Our Father, Who art in heaven…
I've heard about you before.
- Hold him!
- You Satan!
You devil!
You were lucky.
Where you come from?
Are you mute?
You can stay here.
If you want to.
Close the door.
Come to me.
Kiss my legs.
Do you think I can't cut myself?
You're useless!
There is no time!
Remove this car now!
Cossacks!
Run away!
You're not from here, right?
Where are your parents?
So an orphan.
The boy is an orphan.
He will stay with us for now.
It fits like a glove.
The party is like a train...
in which Stalin is a machinist.
Understand?
Am I wrong?
What is it?
What happened?
Was the order not clear enough?!
Not the fuck to leave the camp!
Do not contact local hostile people!
Especially their women.
Silent!
Get the paramedic, fast!
Others... split up!
Remember…
An eye for an eye.
A tooth for a tooth.
Act as real communist.
Then.
Time will come.
Name?
Place of birth?
Date?
You wanted to steal it?!
Don't you understand, dirty Jew?
What?
The best place for those like you
is behind barbed wire!
Wait here!
We will cook cabbage soup.
The way you like it.
Do you remember?
I know, it's not very nice here.
But I couldn't get anything better yet.
We will leave tomorrow.
You don't like it?
Maybe you want salt?
We have some.
When we get back home...
I'll buy you some decent clothes.
How about that?
Mum is waiting for us impatiently.
You know…
we thought you would be safe there.
We couldn't…
There was no other option.
Wait!
Do you at least remember your name?
JOSKA