Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Hi, Tiffany?
I'm Natalie.
I understand this is your first.
Please just lie back and lift
your shirt from your stomach.
There it is.
Eight weeks old and already
has a beating heart.
Most mothers-to-be like
to record the heartbeat.
We can do it on your phone.
Hello?
Boo!
Oh fuck!
I got you!
I told you you were the jumpy
type.
You're an asshole,
Joey!
What, it's funny.
It wasn't funny.
I thought it was funny.
I really need to go
now.
She'll be here any
minute.
Henry?
Hey.
I thought you were about to be
late
for the first time in your life.
What's with this tie?
The demolition crew bought it
for me.
As a joke?
What, you think?
Yeah.
Like your stupid ringtone.
Ah, so you love them after all.
Love is a pretty
strong word,
but I like to make you happy,
so.
Hey, I'm gonna start my
patrol.
Okay.
Oh.
Sorry.
Uh, Mick's waiting for you.
He's kinda itching to leave.
I'll be there in a minute.
Listen, um...
Hey, Tiffany.
Hey, Carl.
How is Maggie?
Took her first steps
yesterday.
Only nine months old.
Can you believe that?
She's beautiful.
Well.
I'll be back with the demolition
team
at four am for the final checks.
Have a good last night guarding
this dump.
His daughter is so cute.
He really adores her.
Better him than me.
You okay?
I will see you tomorrow.
I'm taking my mom to bingo.
I need to go.
Do you hear me?
The dead heard you.
Fuck.
Hello?
Anybody there?
I thought you were in a hurry.
I need to make sure
I packed all my stuff.
Joey to control, level
20 ready to be demolished.
Copy that.
Joey to control, level
19 secure
and ready for demolition.
Are you checking
everything properly, Joey?
Yes.
Lying little shit.
You're moving too fast.
Ensure everything has been
checked.
Every door needs to be checked.
Every corner needs a light shone
into it.
You dropped the ball this week.
It was one guy.
In a secured location.
Do it right.
Joey to control.
You should see the level 19
west stairwell door and alarm.
The sensor's broken,
but the door's secure.
Copy.
Welcome to your tour
of the old dead building.
I'll be your tour guide, Joey
Rambosa.
- Now...
- Joey!
And right here and we
have a real human turd.
I know I can't say turd on the
radio,
but on the private tour we
can get all the fun facts...
All right, Joey, knock it off.
So, this beauty here, she is
34 days old
though we don't know
much else about her
or who created her
but that's how
exciting my job is.
Can literally measure it in
shit.
Joey, that's enough.
Tune in next week when
we play my favorite game.
Guess That Smear!
So dumb.
Level 18 ready to be
blown up.
Okay.
Joey to control.
Level 17 secure, door seal
intact.
You copy, Tiff?
Oh shit.
Yes, copy.
♪ It's the most boringest
job in the world ♪
♪ It never impresses a girl ♪
♪ They pay me fuck all ♪
♪ It is a pain in my balls ♪
♪ It's the most boring job in
the world ♪
♪ In the world ♪
Hey, hey, this is
Henry.
You know what to do.
Are you studying your
security course right now?
Yes.
What are you studying?
How to secure a room that
has multiple entry points.
Ah, using only
a toothpick and a condom?
Hey, Joey, we have an
alarm on level 13.
Moving.
It's an east tenancy door.
No other alarms.
Stairwells reading secure.
I'm here, going mobile.
Unlock east stairwell door,
please.
The security seal's broken.
Door hardware seems to be
intact.
It could just be water
compromised the seal.
Am I authorized to enter?
We are authorized.
Enter with caution.
Every brief in
this dump ends with caution.
Shaking with caution.
No alarm on the shaking.
Okay, will shake the
door now
and not just my booty.
All right, be alert.
Stop the clowning.
Door's an alarm.
Door remains secure.
Entering.
Have you found
anything?
Something to do with
babies.
Photos and stuff of birth
announcements.
Are you saying the
tenancy hasn't been cleared?
Yeah, I guess.
Take photos of
everything and send it to me.
Joey!
Joey, is everything okay?
Yeah, uh.
The babies.
What babies?
Where?
In the jar.
Babies.
One of them has a belly cord.
Fuck!
Do you see them?
Yeah.
What does it say on that label?
The thing is really old,
I can't make out the first part.
Thatcher it says in the middle.
The rest is faded and
unreadable.
This is fucking disturbing,
Tiff.
This is a colossal fuck up.
They can't just demolish the
building
with two dead babies in it.
Ya think?
How could
they have missed this?
This?
They put a damn security seal on
the door
saying that the room was
cleared.
I mean, that's a downright lie.
How many other tenancies
haven't been cleared?
I don't know, but somebody's
getting their ass kicked.
Yeah, well, you know who
that'll be.
What?
What do you know?
Forget it.
Henry signed off on it,
it's his responsibility.
Get him down here
to deal with it.
Oh, oh, don't get angry at me.
We can't cross doors with
intact security seals on it,
those are the rules.
Right.
Said the wrong thing.
You took
photographs, right?
Yes.
Send them to me.
File sent.
Continue with the
patrol.
Right after the seven shots of
tequila
I need to calm down.
Oh, God, Jesus.
Hey, hey, this is
Henry.
You know what to do.
Hey, Henry, call me back
immediately.
We discovered a tenancy
that hasn't been cleared.
Due to the nature of it I
need to call the police.
Metro Police
non-emergency,
how can I help you?
Ma'am, you can call 911 if it's
urgent.
No, it's not an emergency.
We will send
officers in the morning.
I understand.
Okay.
- Thank you.
You scared the shit outta me!
I found this in the room.
And this was outside.
You're not supposed to
take items out of that room.
Look at the drawings in it.
It's insane.
Did you call Henry?
I called the police, I made
them aware of the situation.
They'll be here in the morning.
It's not an emergency.
That couldn't of been easy.
It's called procedure.
Now follow procedure and
get your ass back out there
because there are floors
that haven't been checked.
Yep, and each one of them has
signs
warning of impending death.
"Do Not Enter."
"Demolition Area."
"Explosives, you will
fucking die if you enter."
I mean, seriously, fuck anyone
who doesn't
pay attention to them.
Our standing orders state that
a patrol
may not be broken.
I just saw dead babies in a
jar.
Fuck our standing orders.
Hey!
What is it?
What'd you see?
Don't leave the control room
unstaffed.
Who are you?
This is a restricted area.
The building is dangerous,
you must leave immediately.
There's someone here.
Get in.
What'd you see?
I don't know.
A man I think.
You saw him in the dark?
I know how it sounds.
There was someone in the
darkness
and we have to go find him.
21%.
If we use the lights we
lose the security cameras.
What asshole designed this
thing?
The lowest bidder.
How long until enough charge
builds up?
An hour, probably more.
It's a lot of darkness for me
to search
with a flashlight.
Not to mention the guy
running around in the shadows.
I know.
You're sure you saw this guy?
I saw him.
Shit.
Wow.
Why would you want children with
him?
This isn't any of your
damn business, okay?
East alarm again.
I checked it
and I locked it again...
I'll deal with it.
Alarms have ceased.
If there's someone there
they're still on that floor.
Stairwells remain secure.
Proceed with caution, I
get it.
Proceed with weapons drawn.
Door is secure and locked.
Hello?
Hi, this is Michael's
mother.
He was supposed to pick me up
awhile ago.
Are you keeping him late?
Mick left on time, Glenda.
I'm sure he'll be there.
Oh, okay.
Bye.
Hello?
Can you hear that?
Where are they?
I don't know.
I can't find them.
It sounds like they're in the
walls.
Kids?
It isn't safe to be here.
Joey?
Something is...
He's in the basement stairwell.
On my way.
Somebody's down here.
I'm seconds away.
Be careful.
Drag your sidearm.
Yes, he's in there.
Joey!
Fucking hell, Tiff.
What is it?
Is everything okay?
I'm all good.
I'll make it back to you.
That's weird.
You were right, someone's down
here.
I see their footprints.
It's like they appeared out of
thin air.
No one's
come through that door.
They have a way of
moving through
the building that we don't know
about.
Hey, Joey.
Level 13 is in alarm again.
We still need to investigate.
Fuck it, I know.
Fuel level on the generator's
low.
I'll fill
it when you get back.
Elevator stopped, what's going
on?
I don't know.
What the fuck was that?
What?
What did you see?
I don't know.
An animal or...
Stay alert down there.
I do not get paid enough
for this bullshit.
I heard that.
You were meant to.
The elevator's not here.
Check your six!
Uh.
What happened?
I got spiked!
By what?
Fuck this place,
where are fucking police!
What are you doing?
It isn't me.
Help me!
Open the door!
Open the fucking door!
Jesus.
They're not people.
What are you talking about?
I saw 'em.
I saw 'em, look at these photos.
You're not supposed to
remove...
Just shut up and look at them.
What do you see?
Oh my god.
They're the same kids.
The can't be, they're decades
apart.
I saw them.
Those kids.
They chased me to the elevator.
These children?
Yes, these children and the
others too.
They're not fucking human.
Joey, show me.
What the hell is that?
Is that bone?
Get it out.
Just pull the fucking thing out!
This needs a doctor.
It's moving into me.
It's burrowing into me.
They're singing again.
We have to get you out of here.
I'll protect you, I promise.
Saddle up.
Are you fucking insane?
We need to be able to see
them.
That was all the power we had
left.
What the fuck, Joey?
Is that Mick?
Why is he screaming?
I didn't see him.
No, no, no, come
back!
Get your ass back here, Joey!
Mick!
Mick, where you at?
This is Mick.
Please leave a brief
message after the tone.
What did you do to
her?
Mick?
Kill me.
Tiff!
Kill.
Move, move!
Kids!
They're not fucking kids.
Run!
Inhaler.
You're okay.
You saved me.
You need to control your
breathing.
You're gonna be a great
mother.
They're gonna kill us.
Where's Mick?
Did you find Mick?
Yeah.
He's dead.
No, please don't.
- Please don't go.
- Let me go.
I tried, I tried, I tried.
He was screaming for me to kill
him.
I didn't mean to, I didn't mean
to!
No!
Mick.
There's no body.
What?
I fucking shot him.
He didn't just get up and walk
away.
We need the police here.
We need to get outta
here.
Hi, this is Tiff with 115, I...
They're gonna drag us to hell.
We run.
No.
It's growing.
What is it?
Get it out!
Pull it out!
Get it out now!
Get it out!
- Stop!
- God!
Oh, pull harder!
It's moving.
We're leaving.
Get up.
No.
- Stop!
- What's happening?
The building's going into
lockdown.
It'll trap us.
We need to run while
I'm still of use to you.
We need to get outta here.
You're not just saving yourself
anymore.
They control the building now.
We survive by digging in.
We're armed and we're
sheltered...
We're armed against
ghosts that can't be killed.
We are burrowing like ticks
until Carl
and the demolition team
arrive in the morning, okay?
Just let me get you out!
Fuck you!
I'll lead them away.
You make a run for it.
No, no!
No, no, Joey, no!
We need help!
What is it you want?
Joey.
I can't get out.
The door won't open.
Can you force it?
It hurts so bad.
What floor are you on?
I don't know.
Please try pushing the
basement button.
Please.
Joey.
I love you, Tiff.
I wish I would've told you
sooner.
Hindsight is life's shittiest
teacher.
Joey!
Can you see anything outside?
Joey, it's opening!
Move, run!
Joey, stop!
Don't do it!
My god.
Joey!
What are you doing?
Joey, no!
Joey, please!
Joey, oh my god!
I can't breathe.
Tell me where you are!
It's him!
Joey, run!
What floor, Joey?
God damn it, what fucking floor?
Shit.
No, okay, um.
Do it.
I can see you, you fucker!
If I can see you, I can kill
you.
Joey.
Joey, say something.
Where are you?
Tell me what floor you're on!
What is that?
Henry?
Is that you?
What do you want?
Four!
Oh no.
Three!
It's not religious people.
Two!
Fuck you!
One!
Joey.
Where are you?
13.
Oh my god, Henry?
What happened to you?
Joey!
Joey.
Run.
This is what you wanted.
Let me go, you fucker.
Let me go!
Six.
Don't you fucking touch me.
You shall bring them back.
Oh my god!
Don't you fucking come near me.
Afraid of the light?
You want this?
Go get it.
Everything seems fine.
You can put all of this behind
you now.
Now what is this here?
Excuse me one moment.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org