We got it.
Yeah.
Come on, let's do it.
- Oh, my God!
- Pack it up.
Tear down.
We're heading to Asia.
- Hey. Hey, how close are we?
- No problem.
No, how close are we?
I say, "No problem."
He said, "No problem."
Great.
Hey, man,
do you have to go so fast?
Yeah!
Why?
I don't wanna
lose to my brother.
Wonderful!
Okay, are you trying
to ram us out?
Finally.
Amazing!
Yeah.
Load up your packs.
It's gonna be a walk
the rest of the way.
What do you need those for?
Need what?
- The gun.
- Safety.
You don't go in the middle
of nowhere unprotected, man.
- Who is this guy?
- Hey, where are we exactly?
No name.
No name?
Virgin territory.
This area
hasn't been mapped yet.
It's officially unexplored.
We're hundreds of miles
in the middle of nowhere.
So who else knows we're here?
You're looking at us.
Secrets travel fast
in the caving world.
How many years
you say you been caving?
Seven.
Yeah.
Lying bitch.
What?
There it is.
Hello!
Why?
Why not?
For an opening this big,
there should be enough light
to see further inside.
Yeah.
I've never seen
anything like it before.
Yeah, it's weird.
It's late.
The shadows are playing
with our eyes.
I'll set up the flashes
and we'll snap off a couple.
No, no, no.
We set up camp 20 yards back.
We'll cave in the morning.
It'll take, like, two minutes.
Nothing does.
Set up camp.
We'll cave tomorrow.
Jackass.
Good to know.
Suck it.
You're so...
You want me to shove it
up my ass, I'll tell you no!
I can do all kinds of things
with this right now,
but shove it up my ass?
That's where I draw the line.
That's a whole
new ball game.
In Sarajevo,
we take it up the butt.
Every day.
He's in slow motion.
We call her Florence.
What? Like Nightingale?
Yeah.
- Why?
- Okay, stop!
Because on her first caving expedition,
someone got hurt.
So this guy cuts himself
on his knee.
Oh, wait.
It wasn't just a cut.
No, no, no. You're right.
It was a tiny cut.
Tiny.
Oh, you bitch!
But Florence here
decides that she was
going to wrap it,
and wrapped it, and, yes,
you may have guessed it,
she wrapped it again.
You bitch!
But seriously,
I'd love to lead my own cave expedition.
Of children?
Of grown-ups.
Be the first to explore
a new cave.
It'd be amazing.
Certainly have a lot more
fun than those guys.
Especially Gannon.
How long has it been?
Two years tomorrow.
Yeah, that's what changed him.
What do you mean?
What happened?
It--It won't go in the book.
If I tell you,
you're gonna wanna put it in.
It won't.
You've got my word.
Do you guys know?
No.
We meet Gannon today.
All right, Ori,
you can trust me.
Two years ago,
we were caving in Peru.
Me, Miranda,
Bailey, Domingo, Gannon...
There were some
other guys there,
but they don't
work for us anymore.
And there was
another woman, Rachel,
his fiancée.
It was the beginning
of the rainy season in Peru,
and we were trying to get out
of a cave that was flooding.
And she didn't make it.
We were all, you know,
really close to her.
I'm sorry.
Yeah. Gannon was the only one
that saw her die.
Her body was never found.
Are you saying
there's more to the story?
No.
Then what are you saying?
Nothing.
That's it.
Well, I'm gonna go to bed.
Me, too.
Get some sleep.
So,
you guys thinking
about tomorrow?
You getting what you need
for your book?
Yeah. Yeah, I am.
Caving is a whole new world.
For a lot of people, I mean.
I mean, you know,
you show them a photo,
it opens them up to
a whole new universe, right?
Every photo you sell
furthers caving.
Yeah.
We're lucky to be
making a living doing it.
So... So what are
your thoughts, exactly,
on caving?
What do you mean?
I mean,
what's your philosophy?
How do you approach it?
I wanna know what makes you go down there.
There's something
about caves that's alive.
There's something down there that,
if we're open to it,
we can connect with.
I look for that connection
every time I go down.
I crave it.
You're a Brujo.
His father was.
So you believe in spirits?
Like, spirit of the earth,
spirit of the sun?
Yeah, I do.
And cave spirits?
The most unpredictable of all.
Interesting.
Everyone has
their own beliefs.
What's hanging
from your neck?
It's a cross.
If something as magnificent
or as terrible as God
is possible,
anything is, right?
Right?
- Yeah, but I wasn't saying...
- Throughout history,
caves have been a sacred place
for almost every religion
in existence.
Remember, Jesus was buried
and resurrected in a cave.
I'm sorry.
I wasn't trying to offend you.
So why do you do it?
We haven't found them all.
Everyone knows where
the highest mountains are,
the deepest seas.
But caves...
Caves are the last unexplored frontier on earth.
There's nothing more
exciting than that.
My grandfather used
to climb through caves
to find new mining lines
on the East Coast.
He'd say,
"Apollo had it easy,
"'cause everyone knows
where the moon is.
"But no one knows
where I'm going."
So are there any events
or anything about
caving that you regret?
Over the years, I've found
that it's hard to control
what happens down there.
It's a beast, and not
all beasts can be tamed.
And that's what
you need to understand.
Things happen in caves that don't happen anywhere else.
When you're down there,
you're in darkness,
an eternal,
never-ending world of night.
Down there, miles beneath
the earth's surface,
you're surrounded
by miles of rock.
You know a wrong step
can send you down a chasm
hundreds of feet deep?
And if you get
hurt down there,
maybe break an arm
or break a leg,
there's no ambulance nearby,
no hospital.
Chances are you won't be
brought out alive.
The only way to survive it over and over is to respect it.
Respect where you are.
Respect what it is.
Bailey. Bailey.
Hold on, I'm coming.
- Is everyone asleep?
- Yeah.
Come on, it'll be fun.
Stop!
Wait. What was that?
Bat?
Stop. It's not a fucking bat.
Say "fuck" like that again.
There's something there.
You're just worried
about getting caught.
It isn't fun
if you don't get caught.
How you feeling?
Fine. You?
Ready to go.
Again.
Too bad.
Hey.
It was today.
You gonna be okay?
Yeah.
I'll be fine.
Good.
I'm glad you're here.
I know.
Come on.
How'd it go?
We're about to find out.
All right!
We ready?
- Yeah.
Let's go.
Hold up.
It's a long way down.
Yeah.
Hey, set up a rappel line.
So what are we gonna
name this one?
Hell's Pit.
Do we really wanna
name it that?
What?
It's the Russian word
for "hell."
Then Ad's Pit it is.
Estupidos. Ready.
- All right. All right,
- I'll head down first.
Whoa, whoa. How come
you get all the booty?
'Cause I say so.
Shit!
- What's up?
- You okay?
- Hey, you all right?
- Gannon!
Yeah, I'm fine!
You bitch.
Off-rope!
What do we got down here?
It used to be
some sort of water funnel,
and the water
drained in from above
and funneled out of these
passageways here.
- I got you.
- I have it.
Okay.
All right,
I'll set up the flashes.
- No, we'll keep going.
- Off-rope!
We can take pictures of this
when we get back.
Off-rope.
Ah.
I'm done. What?
He hear us.
Good. Let's, um...
Whoa. What's going on?
What is this?
Never seen that before.
Magnetic plate?
Hey, we all have backup lights,
so we'll keep our eye on it.
Let's cave.
All right.
We got drippers here.
The water
must have funneled out
from the main chamber
at Ad's Pit into here.
Either that or
we're underneath a lake.
We should listen
for water, guys.
Let's pull right.
How about we go straight?
What the...
- This cave is creeped out.
- Yeah.
Well, the wind means
there's more cave, so...
No.
The cave is moaning.
It is making love.
And who's he doing,
Slava? You?
Me? No, no, no,
no, no, no, no.
It is fucking you.
Sorry, guy.
I don't do Russian caves, eh?
Did you ever do
an American cave?
Slava, you ever do
Hey, Slava!
He was right here.
Vlad?
No, that's the wrong one.
That's where
the cord leads to.
We came out of that one.
Well, if the cord's
going down that hole,
that's where we came from.
She's right.
Footprint.
Well, then,
somebody moved the cord.
Or something.
Hold on, guys.
- Blood.
- Oh, my God!
Oh, shit.
Don't worry.
Calm down. Calm down!
Shut up!
Come on.
Did you see that?
What?
Slava?
Come here.
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
What the hell!
What did this?
What did this, man?
Oh, shit!
Sit up! Sit up!
Okay. Hey.
Can you hear me?
What did this to you, man?
What did this?
There's not enough time!
We gotta get him out now!
Oh, shit!
We gotta get him out of here!
All right, all right.
Ori, lift him up.
I'm moving
as fast as I can.
All right.
Hold on, Slava, we got you.
Come! Here!
- Help me.
- Hang in there, Slava!
Vlad! Vlad!
- Vlad!
- Come on!
We need help down here! Vlad!
- Gannon.
- What?
Shit! What is going on here?
We're fucked.
What's that?
Hey, watch out!
Oh, my God.
No one else knows
we're down here?
We're so fucked.
Don't say that.
Does anybody else
know where we are?
Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
- We're so fucked.
- Don't fucking say that.
What, "we're fucked"?
'Cause we're fucked.
Does anybody fucking know,
or are we stranded down here?
- Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
- Just calm down, guys.
We got two fucking dead people lying on the floor,
and you want me to calm down?
We're gonna be okay.
We're stranded in here!
Calm down, y'all!
We're stranded down here.
You guys, stop!
Will somebody answer me?
Just shut up, man.
Everybody shut up!
Now, calm yourselves down
and get control, okay?
Okay?
Okay. Hey, we're all right.
We're all right, okay?
Okay. Okay.
Gannon?
Yes.
Gannon, we lost him.
What did this to him?
An animal? A bear?
No.
That--That wouldn't
explain the burns
or the way his intestines...
No, I can't explain it.
I don't understand.
None of this is explainable
in physical terms.
What the hell does that mean?
Listen, we don't need that
right now, okay?
What does it mean,
huh?
Hold on, hold on.
Stop it.
Will you calm down?
Yeah, can we worry
about what did this
after we find
a way out of here?
He's right. We're not gonna
last too long down here
without any supplies.
Um...
My battery's almost dead.
- Me, too.
- Mine, too.
Weren't they supposed to last
longer than a couple of hours?
Yeah.
Half empty.
I know I charged them.
I know, man.
There's some sort of energy drain going on down here.
Aren't they gonna last long enough for us to get out of here?
It could take days to find a new passage to the surface.
What's the plan?
We find another way
out of here.
I'll lead.
Domingo, cover the rear.
We'll leave the bodies
for now.
Let's go!
What does
the air current mean?
Caving for seven years, huh?
Yeah.
Air currents mean
one of two things,
a surface route
or a deeper cave.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
It's gonna get
a little tight in here, guys.
Still
feeling that current?
Yeah.
How much rock is above us?
Much.
How much?
If we don't reach the surface,
you'll know.
Shut up, Domingo.
Okay, looks like
we get a little more room.
- Did you hear that?
- What?
Stop moving! Stop moving!
What the...
Holy shit.
Don't make any noise.
Quiet.
What are you doing?
What are you...
Shut up! It's not working!
For fuck's sake,
what are you doing?
It sees us.
Go! Go!
Keep moving. Don't stop.
Go, go, go, go!
Come on! Go, go, go!
Move, move, move!
Go, go, go, go!
Domingo!
Get up, man! Come on!
Move, move, move, move!
Come on. Come on.
This cave
has a soul.
Go! Go!
Go, go! We gotta
get out of here, man!
Fuck! Move, move! Go!
Oh, holy shit, it's coming!
Just get out!
Go! Go!
We gotta keep going.
Go on! Get out of here!
Careful! Let's go!
Go!
Move!
Let's move! Move!
Move, move, move!
Okay, okay, okay.
What happened? What happened?
Gannon!
Oh, God.
Where are you hurt?
Not me. Domingo.
It got him. He wouldn't run.
It's some kind of beast
or something.
Fuck you.
Why'd you run?
- What?
- We left him there.
We didn't leave him.
He wouldn't run.
- Are you listening?
- We could've helped him.
What are you talking about?
He was dead! Look at me!
You were gonna leave
before anything happened.
We had to.
This could have been
our blood.
That's the way it is.
It's you or him.
You or her.
Her?
Peru. Two years ago today.
Rachel.
You left her, too, remember?
You watched her drown.
You saved yourself,
and you watched her drown!
Gannon, stop it!
Stop it! Stop it!
Gannon, stop it. Stop!
Stop it.
No, Gannon. No! No!
Get off of him!
- You hear that?
- No!
You better put that
in your book.
People should know
what this man did!
And it only gets better!
You weren't there!
You don't know what happened!
Stop it!
Hey!
Shouldn't we keep moving?
He's right!
We got us this
thing chasing us,
and you guys are fighting?
What is wrong with you?
Now, let's get moving.
This way.
Come on.
This could take us to the top.
Yes.
Come on.
- Oh, God.
- Fuck!
What? What? No. No.
What?
- Fuck!
- No.
No.
Fuck!
Son of a bitch!
Maybe if we backtrack and try
one of the other passages...
Yeah, maybe.
Go back? No, no, no, no, no.
How thick is this wall here?
It's thick, man.
Stop it!
Don't you guys carry drills?
Yes.
What the fuck are you doing?
What are you doing?
Drill a hole in the wall,
genius.
Ambrose, calm down.
Drill a hole in the fucking wall.
Genius.
Yeah,
knock yourself out.
Ambrose.
Is this the longest bit
you have?
Yeah, man.
Don't you have a longer bit?
I need a longer bit!
Stupid jerk!
Ambrose, stop drilling.
Put the goddamn
drill down, boy!
Calm yourself down.
Shit could be around
the corner any minute.
It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay. Relax.
Okay?
I only caved twice.
No shit.
Hey.
With tour groups.
I'm sorry.
It's okay. Hey.
I wanna get out!
I just wanna get out!
I just wanna get out of here!
- We're gonna get out! We're gonna get out!
Ambrose, we're gonna get out.
- Shut up!
We're gonna get out of here.
But I really need you to pull yourself together right now, okay?
Okay?
Okay.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
- It's okay.
- I'm sorry.
You're doing pretty great
for a virgin.
Okay? Okay?
Hey, guys,
we're running out of options.
Coming up
on that intersection.
Well, maybe we should
turn off our lights.
I mean, that's how
it found us last time, right?
We're the only light source
in this hellhole.
If we turn them off,
it's not gonna know which tunnel to go down.
- It's a one-in-four chance.
- I'll take those odds.
- Everybody in agreement?
- Yeah.
Power down.
- Back lights.
- Listen.
Breathe quieter.
Oh, God!
Run!
Don't leave me alone.
Hey, you okay? Come on!
- Yeah, you?
- I'm fine.
- Where's Ambrose?
- Come on!
- Guys, stop. Where's Ambrose?
- He didn't make it.
- He's gone?
- Oh, God!
- I didn't see what happened.
- He didn't make it. Go!
- You know what happened, okay?
We gotta keep moving.
Let's go!
Okay.
Go! Go!
I got the bag. Go!
Fuck! Fuck!
Shut up. Shut up.
Shut the fuck up.
Shut the fuck up!
Come on, come on, come on.
No, we're never gonna
get out of this place.
- There's no way out of here.
- There is.
Shut up!
Just move, move, move!
Coming through here.
Fuck!
No, we're never gonna
get out of this place.
Do you get it?
Wait, wait.
I see a way out.
Oh, shit.
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Go, go, go.
Gannon. Gannon, let's rest.
No, we gotta keep going.
All right?
Get your batteries.
What's going on?
It's draining
our fucking batteries.
Wait a minute. Do that again.
What?
Put your head by the wall.
Pull it away.
The cave's magnetic.
Yeah, but not everywhere.
Come on.
Listen.
If the lights flicker,
we get out of the area
immediately.
Okay? Okay?
Okay.
We don't have
much batteries left.
That doesn't give us much time
to get out of here.
You know it. Oh, shit.
Hey, get your vertical gear
together.
If we hang like that,
we're gonna be vulnerable.
Well, if we don't hurry up...
That thing is
tracking us, man.
What if it's
waiting down there for us?
We can't go back.
Here's a Domingo rig.
We got a water cave.
Water's about three feet deep.
We don't have to rappel down.
We can just swing down.
Look. We know
it's back there, all right?
It's a risk
we're gonna have to take.
How many people are you gonna leave down there, Gannon?
What?
Nothing. Just go. Go!
Come on.
Hey!
Hey, guys.
Hey, you all right?
Yeah, we're fine.
Well, let's go.
We need to talk.
- What?
- It's time for a change of plans.
- Let's walk and talk.
- Let's talk right here.
You're running us around in circles and this thing's picking us off.
I'm trying to find
a way out of here.
And it keeps killing us.
Wanna stand around and chat?
We have guns. We have ammo.
- So what?
- So let's hunt this thing.
- You're crazy.
- Hear me out.
Listen, we can barely defend ourselves,
and you wanna go
- looking for it?
- Hear me out!
There's nothing
to hear, Ori.
We have a cavern.
We use bait to lure it in.
When it goes for it,
we snap off all of our flashes
and we shoot the thing.
We unload on the son
of a bitch. It'll work.
It'll work.
- What do you guys think?
- What if it doesn't work?
Well, then,
another one of us dies anyway.
Miranda?
It's up to you, Gan.
Get your flashes.
That thing could be here any second.
Put the bait in the middle.
The rest of us hide
behind the stalagmites.
Okay.
Who's gonna be the bait?
- Gannon.
- Fuck you. It's your plan, you do it.
- I'm a better shot. We...
- What?
We can't afford a miss.
It's either you
or the girls.
Come on,
that thing's gonna be here any second.
Fuck you.
Lights!
Can you see us?
No.
Feel like
I'm the only one in here.
Look, about Rachel.
Don't do this now.
I'm telling you
what happened.
Yeah, but not now.
My life is on the line.
You accused me
of letting her die.
Now you're gonna
shut up and listen.
Crane was there.
He saw what you did.
Man, you're making this up.
I know where
it's coming from.
You're still hurt.
She played around with you
but still loved me.
- Bullshit.
- And you fell in love
with something
you couldn't have.
Bullshit. Crane was there.
He saw what you did.
Oh, yeah? And what
did he tell you, huh?
What did he say?
- Don't make me say it.
- No, no. I want you to say it.
Get it out in the open.
- Spit it out.
- Gannon, please.
What? You in on this, too?
And how about you, Miranda?
Oh, my God.
We all know.
Even Domingo knew.
What's happening here?
You killed her, Gan.
You had her hand
and you let her go.
Gannon! Gannon!
Rachel! Hold on!
Hold on to me!
Gannon, I'm slipping!
Oh, God!
Oh, God.
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
Hells, yeah!
Gannon, are you all right?
I'm out of bullets.
I got another mag.
- Did you get it?
- Yeah.
Where's it hurt?
My leg.
My leg! Don't touch it!
It's deep. To the bone.
Is he gonna be able to walk?
He's gonna need help.
We'll take care of him later.
Let's worry about this now.
What the hell is it?
Some kind of wolf-bear hybrid,
I don't know.
There's no blood.
That's not a good sign.
What the hell?
What?
This is unreal.
Oh, God! Oh, my God!
Go, go, go, go, go!
Run!
Come on!
Let's go! Come on!
I can't hold him
much longer.
He's leaving a trail.
Damn it.
Stop, stop, stop.
Set him down a sec.
You grab him from behind.
Just... Bailey?
We did it again.
Did what?
We left someone behind.
It's a bad time
for guilt, Gan.
He was still moving.
He wasn't gonna make it.
What do you mean,
he wasn't gonna make it?
Rachel was still moving.
Don't do this to me, Gan.
She would've pulled
both of us under.
Hold on to me!
- Pull me, Gannon!
- I'm slipping!
Get closer towards me!
- I'm trying!
- Kick!
- It's not working!
Oh, God!
Rachel!
No!
Listen to me.
I don't remember
if she slipped out
or if I let her go.
Would you leave me behind?
No.
Maybe
we should split up.
What?
You go your way,
we'll go ours.
He can't follow both of us.
You mean
I'm slowing you down.
No.
Yeah, that's part of it.
He's gonna be fine.
Miranda, we left Ori.
Ori had a spear
coming out of his back.
We couldn't help him.
Look at him, Miranda.
He's just getting worse.
The only way we have a chance
is if we leave him.
- Please, come on.
- Fuck you. I can still walk.
Come on and help.
Help me!
Get away from me.
Forget it.
Just put your arm around me.
- Go.
- Come on!
Go, go.
Come on! Come on.
Yes.
- Did you feel that?
- Yeah.
- Go.
- Go, go.
Come on.
No! No, no, no!
What was that?
What the fuck?
Oh, my God. No, no.
No! No, no, no, no, no! No!
What the fuck?
No, no, no! No!
We're going in circles?
Bailey, I thought
you were mapping this place.
I don't know.
I don't know. I lost track.
What do you mean,
you lost track?
I lost track. I lost track.
I haven't been
mapping anything.
surveying anything.
Just shut up!
- What are we gonna do?
- All right, come on.
Come on, we'll try that hole.
We haven't been that way.
Get up and help me.
Get it together and get up!
Come on, Bailey.
Bailey. Bailey, get up.
Bailey, get up.
Bailey, come on!
Get up!
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
I don't see a way out.
What the fuck?
- Let's try the opposite side.
- No, no.
Hold on!
I'm sorry.
What?
I can't.
- What are you doing?
- I can't. I can't!
- Gannon.
- What?
- I can't!
I can't. Can't.
My batteries
aren't working!
My batteries aren't working!
Mine are all dead.
Try your flashes.
Fuck!
Mine won't work.
They won't work.
No!
Oh, my God, you guys.
Oh, my God.
Did you hear that?
- What?
- It's fucking in here.
Where?
On the right.
Oh, no!
It's a wall.
Which way?
Hold on.
Hold on. Hold on.
Okay, there's a tunnel.
Right here, there's a tunnel.
Go, go, go.
Gannon?
Gannon!
Come on.
Okay.
Go, go, go, go, go. Go.
Right here.
I can't see.
Good.
Our lights. Our lights.
Our lights.
There must be
some power left in them,
just not enough
for that cave.
Oh, my God.
What? What?
- What?
- He's gone.
I left him there.
- I left him there.
- I know.
- We had to. Okay? We had to.
- I left him there.
I left him there.
Gannon's gone.
We don't know that.
He might've gotten out, too.
Right?
Please just say it with me.
He might've gotten out, too.
Okay?
Oh, God. Oh, God.
It's okay. Calm down.
Breathe!
Listen, breathe.
We're almost there.
All right? All right?
We're almost out. Okay?
It's okay.
My God.
What? What? What?
- A leaf.
- What?
Oh, God. Oh, daylight.
Daylight!
Is that what I think it is?
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
That's daylight.
Daylight! Oh, my God!
Yes! Yes!
Yes!
Daylight, daylight, daylight!
We're gonna go home again.
Oh, my God.
Daylight. Daylight.
Oh, my God!
I see the surface.
Bailey, I see the surface.
Bailey, I see the surface!
Oh, I see it!
I see it. Oh, my God!
- Hold on. Oh, God.
- Almost there!
- Bailey.
- My foot's caught on something.
What's it caught on?
No!
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Bailey!
Bailey, wake up! Bailey!
Oh, my God. What happened?
I don't know.
Oh, God.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
- Where are we?
- We gotta get out of here.
- Oh, God,
- we gotta get out of here.
There's a door.
Come on. Miranda, come on.
Come on. Come on.
Okay.
One, two, three.
It won't open!
Bailey, it won't open!
Let us out of here!
Bailey! Bailey!
Bailey, it's not moving.
Look.
It's all our stuff.
It's not all ours.
It's a wing of a plane.
Bailey, there's pictures.
Is that the same plane?
It got them, too.
"Petr."
Russian?
Yeah.
He would have been 24.
Water. Water, come on.
Oh, God.
This is mine.
Oh, my God!
God, help me!
Petr?
You like your name.
He doesn't care.
We-- We're reaching him.
You can't.
We have to try.
What's wrong?
Petr, what's wrong?
- No! No! No! No!
- My God!
Say his name.
It's not gonna work.
Petr! Petr!
It doesn't care!
It doesn't understand!
It's not human!
Oh, my God!