Simon,leave Jesus alone.
It's all right,sarah.
I have somethingfor you.
What is it?
A box I madejust for you.
Look,
it hasa secret place.
What goes in there?
One day, Simon...
You will know.
You must stay truein your heart.
Thank you, Jesus.
You can ride with meonce and a while,you know.
Boy: yeah, I know.
Is the bagin the car?
Uh, yeah,it's in the front.
You two don't planon moving all that stuffyourselves, do you?
Hi, Mrs. rousso.
No, my brother'smoving company is comingout here.
We're just checkingto make sure nothing'smissing.
I do my bestto keep an eyeon the place,
but it's goodto double-check.
My eyes aren't as goodas they used to be.
Thank you,mrs. Rousso.
I'm sorryabout your dad.
I'm reallygonna miss his,
"you'll never guesswho came into the store,"
stories.
Me, too.
Okay, man.I'll see ya.
Okay, Jake.Why don't you startin the attic,
and I'll startout here in front.
Okay.
I just wantto get this done.
Crazy old grandpa.
I bet there'snot one thing up hereworth anything.
Mom? mom?
What is this?
A wooden box.
I know, but...
Is it a jewelry boxor something?
I don't know,bring it down hereso I can see it.
No, I don't think so.
It feels like there'ssomething in it.
It is pretty heavy.
It can't bethe wood.
I don't know, Jake.
Can I have it?
Of course you can.
You didn't feel anythingwhen you opened it?
No. why?
I did.
It was really weird.
Maybe it wasgrandpa telling youto leave his stuff alone.
You know howhe could always tell
when somethingwas moved.
I bet he wasabout to put it outon the floor.
I'm supposed to meet upwith David and playsome basketball.
Okay, honey.
I'll call you later.See ya.
See ya.
I miss youso much, dad.
Think that we canget to that courtwithout any trouble?
( Basketball bouncing )
Yeah. yeah,i think so.
I guess it'sworth a shot, right?
Come on.Let's' go.
Wait. hey.Hey.
Well, if itisn't captain wannabee
and his littlesidekick.
( Laughs )
Look, we just wantto know if--
you wantto know what, jakey?
Look you guys,we don't want any trouble.
Hey Richie, these guysbothering you?
Nah, man.
These two clownscame over here toask us a question.
They can't seemto spit it out, man.
So what's up, Jake?
You need somethingfrom Richie?
Look, we're tryingto play basketball
in the other court.That's all.
Isn't there a jump ropearound here that you girlscan go play with?
( Laughs )
Why aren't youout somewhere playingwith your grandpa?
( Scoffs )
Come on guys,let's go.
Whoa, buddy.
Look at them.
There's a whole lot of them,and just two of us.
Man, why do we causetrouble all the time?
We can just go playsomewhere else.
Oh yeah?And where wouldthat be, David?
There's not onegood court around here
for milesand you know that.
We can't play ball anyway,your shoe's untied.
( Murmurs )whatever man.
Jake?what's in your bag?
What? oh.
It's just some boxi found in my grandpa'sshop.
But, hey, check it out.
Is there somethingin it?
- It feels likethere's something in it.- Open it.
There's nothing in it.
You don't feel anythingwhen you open it?
- What do you mean?- Never mind.
( Cell phone rings )
Let's head back home.
Hey, mom.
I'll be homein a couple of hours.
( Birds chirping )
( Students chattering )
- I'm so sorry.- It's okay.
I'm Jake.
This is David.
I'm...i'm Anna.
And this is Cindy.
Hey, I know you.You help me in math class.
You're beautiful--i mean--
that's beautiful
the fact that
both of our friendsare in the same math class.
Cindy: that's right.
- Are you new here?- Yeah. I just moved herefrom California.
Listen, we gotta getto class for some prep.
See you later, okay?
Yeah, okay.
See you.
Hey, you boys playingwith wooden blocks now?
( Laughs )
Listen,you know that girl
that you werejust talking to?
Well, I'm interested.
So back off.
Got it?
( Spits )
- So you stillhave that box?- Yeah.
Jake, I don't thinkyou should talk to Anna.
I'm not afraidof him, David.
In fact,
I think I'm gonna eatwith Anna in the cafeteriatomorrow.
Oh no.
Now i'mhaving visions.
- Really?- yeah.
Of you gettingyour butt kicked.
( Shouting in foreign language )
( Shouts )
Man: why have you forsaken me?
- Good morning.- Morning, mom.
Jake, what'sin your backpack?
My books.
Doesn't soundlike books to me.
Oh.
You mean the box.
I have grandpa's boxin there.
Go ahead, open it.
You already askedme this, Jake.
Okay.
( Sighs )nothing. I don't feelanything.
Never mind.
- I gotta go.- Jake, should I makean appointment for you?
Are youfeeling okay?
To what?
A doctor?
I'm fine.
I told you.
I'm gettingthese really weird feelingswhen I open the box.
Yesterday, I opened it,and I saw a vision
of a little boyholding it,
in a different placein time.
What do youmean, Jake?
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Like the old times.
No, don't evenstart thinking that.
No. I'm not on drugs.
And no,
I'm not crazy.
Hey, Anna.Have you seen David?
No, I thought he'dbe with you...
Is something wrong?
Maybe he's stillin the lunch line?
Jake, what are youdoing here?
Aren't you goingto say hi to Anna?
Jake, you knowwhat's going to happen,you're asking for it.
I won't bea part of this.
I'll see you later.
What's wrong with him?
What's goingto happen?
I don't know.
Maybe he'shaving a bad day.
What do you havein there, Jake? Rocks?
Jake: there's something I wanna show you.
Anna: oh okay.
( Spits )
- Jake: what's going on here? - Anna: Oh boy.
Jake: oh, it's Richie.
- Hey, Richie.- You don't listen too well,
do you, white boy?
Do you guys wannasit with us?
Why don't you comehave lunch with me, Anna?
( Overlapping shouting )
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Hey! hey!
You got a situation here?
Okay, you two downto the office, now!
Now! now!
Everybody calm down.The situation is okay.
I've got your backpack.It's okay.
Finish your lunches.
Now!
Principal: let's go!
So what'sgoing on you guys,what's the deal?
We don't havea deal, sir.
So you guysboth know the consequencesfor fighting at school,
- don't you?- Yes, sir.
That's why I neverfight in school, sir.
We weren'tfighting, sir.
It was justa misunderstanding.
That's notwhat it looked like
from acrossthe cafeteria.
Okay?
Kids don't normally gatheraround like that
unless there'ssome sort of altercationgoing on.
And if you remember,i pulled you two offof each other.
Now do I haveto pull out the rulebook
so you two can startmemorizing all the rulesaround here?
Or...
Maybe we haveour own little,"breakfast club?"
"The breakfast club"?It's a John Hughes film.
Molly ringwald...
A cool moviefrom the '80s
about a bunch of kidsin detention.
Nothing?
We don't dodetention here.
But I won't hesitateto suspend either oneof you guys
if I seeany more problems.
Do I makemyself clear?
- Got it.- Yes, sir.
I've got my eyeon you.
Okay?both of you.
One on you,and the other on you.
All right,get out of here.Both of you guys.
And I don't wanna seeyou in my office
for the restof the year.
Better watchyour back, white boy.
Jake.
You know, I heardabout your grandfather.
He was always interestedin how you were doingin school.
And he would alwayswant you to do your best.
I know.
Have a good day, Jake.
One more thing.
Did David tell youthere was somethinggoing on
between me and Richie?
Get to class, Jake.
You just couldn't waitto get me in trouble,huh, Jake?
Your little snitch friendhad to go and tellthe principal.
What? do you thinki told David to goget the principal?
Look, Richie,believe it or not,
we're not afraidof you or your friends.
Oh, you're not afraid?That's it you're askingfor it, white boy.
Then why do you alwayshave to have all theseguys around you?
Do you pay these guysfor protection or what?
- That's it!- Leave it alone
get off me, man.
( Overlapping shouting )
Get off me man!
Come on,give that back!
- Come on!- ( Laughing )
Hey! give that back!
Jeez! come on!
( Booms )
Come on, guys.Let's go.
He saw it.
Look at that.Man can't even get a cupof coffee around here
without missingall the action.
Yes, sir.
Have a nice day.
Jake.
I'm here to help.
What's up, Richie?What's bothering you?
You haven't saida word since I got here.
That box
that Jake hadwith him today.
When I opened it,
I got a weird feelingall over me.
What kindof weird feeling?
I had a visionof a boy
- behind a rock, crying.- Oh, yeah.
My mom gets those,only she calls themhot flashes.
Dude,
listen to what I'm saying.
( Video game beeps )
Not like that.
I had a peaceful feelingall over me.
I felt good.
I thinki'm just gonnahave to stay away
from that guy.
What are your plansfor today, Jake?
Anything special?
Nothing really.
Gonna meet upwith David and we're gonnago to the mall later
and shoot some hoops.They're having an open gymlater.
I think they're recruitingplayers for the team,
but me and davidare just gonna shootsome hoops.
Oh, I have a friendcoming over tonight.
Oh, anyone I know?
No, her name's Anna,she's helping me with somehomework.
Should I order youand Anna some pizzafor dinner?
Yeah, that'dbe great.
She's not coming overuntil 8:00 though.
See ya.
Jake, did younotice the tree?
Hey, buddy, wanna playsome one-on-one?
- Gym's open till 7.- Let's go.
By the way, no cryingwhen you lose, punk.
Shut upand play, snitch.
Hey, Anna's comingover later tonight.
Oh, so you didcall her.
- Are you gonnashow her the box?- Aw, shoot.
I was gonna bring itso you could see itone more time.
You just don't stop,do ya?
Look Jake,i can't seewhat you see
or feelwhat you feel.
Maybe Anna will.
What if Anna does feelwhat Richie and I feel?
Why can't you?
I don't know, buddy.
I don't knowwhy I can't see it,or why I can't feel it.
Maybe I'm notsupposed to.
I don't know.
It's just keepingme up at night.
I don't knowwhat to do with it.
All right, well tell mehow it goes, all right?
- You aren't coming?- No, three's a crowd.
And besides,you have to showher the box.
Maybe she can help you.
She goes to church.
You said you seejesus, right?
Maybe he's tryingto tell you something.
Maybe he wants youto go back to church again,jake.
Yeah.
Whatever.
* heedless of the windand weather *
* fa la la la la *
* la la la la *
( carolers chattering )
The same jesusthat was in the box.
- What box?- I'm sorry, what?
You said that'sthe Jesus in the box.
What box?
Oh. never mind.
I was just talkingto myself.
- Can I haveone of those posters?- Here.
Thank you.
Hey...
Merry Christmas.
( Taps )
Jake: mom, come up here, please.
- Mother: what is it Jake? - Just come up here, please
okay, what is it,jake?
Look.
I found outwhat's in here, look.
What is that?
It looks likea nail of some kind.
This is who I see.
Do you thinkit could be oneof those nails?
You sure this iswho you see, Jake?
I thought you saidyou saw a little boyholding the box.
I do seea little boy.
I see a little boyholding the box,
and I see the same boy,except a little older,crying behind a rock.
And then I see jesushanging on the cross.
- Do you believe me?- ( Door bell chimes )
Hi, Mrs. Casper,is Jake home?
Yes, he is.You must be Anna.Come on in.
Let me takeyour coat.
Thank you.
Jake, Anna's here.
Hi.
Mother: Jake, what kind of pizza do you want me to order?
Pepperoni is fine.
- Is that okay with you?- Sure, that's fine.
Awesome.there's somethingi want to show you.
Sit down.
So how did you feelwhen you opened it?
I didn't feelanything.
Okay, look.
There's somethingin here.( Knocks )
What is it?
Some kind of nail.
Jake, where didyou get this?
I found itin my grandpa's store.
He dieda few weeks ago.
So you don'tfeel anythingwhen you hold the nail?
No.what do you mean,jake?
Believe it or not,
when I open the box,i see a vision
of a little boyholding it.
I think I even seejesus hung on the cross.
When I hold the nail
I see a visionof the same boy,
except a little bit older,holding the same box.
It's like...
It's like it'sin a different placein time.
Are you sure?
I didn'tfeel anything?
- Have you had your momor anybody else open the box?- Yeah, but...
- The only person that feltanything was Richie.- Richie?
It's a long storyabout Richie.
That...
Is who I see on the cross.
Do you see the nailthrough his hand?
Could that nail bethe one that hung jesuson the cross?
I don't know.
Is that even possible?
I've never heardof anyone findingthe nails
that crucified Jesus.
I mean, I've heardabout the shroud,
but that's about it.
I heard about it.
People still sayit's fake though.
I have a Bible in my roomthat my grandpa left me.
I think it has picturesof the crucifixion
tell meabout this little boyyou see.
I told you,i see a visionof a little boy
playing with the box.And then the same boy,and the same box,
except a little older.
Crying behind a rock.
Maybe the boy put the nailin the box,
maybe he saw jesusbeing crucified.
I'll be right back.
( Door bell chimes )
Pizza's here.
- Hi.- your pizza.
Yes, how much?
- 144.95.- um, no there--
- 133.95.- there must be a mistake...
- 122.67.- it's supposedto be closer to 20 some...
There's nomistake here, missy.
Hey frank,i got one giving usa hard time--
( laughs )there's no frankover there.
It's just me.
Okay, how muchdo I owe you?
Seven bucks.
I have 30.
Keep the change.
- Thank you.- Merry Christmas.
Jake: mom!
- Check this out.- What? The Bible?
No, I found a noteinside of it.
July 14, 1998.
Today I'm writingthis to let whomeverfinds this letter
know that it'sin my possession.
I have a small wooden box
that is filled with some sort of something
that is beyond my comprehension.
You see the boxcontains nothing.
Yet it feels likesomething is in it.
When I open the box, I immediately get a very peaceful
and beautiful feeling.
You might thinki'm crazy,
but this box is connectedto someone called holy.
It's a feeling that I can't describe.
When I open the box,i see Jesus hangingon the cross.
I can see a young man holding this very box and crying.
While he's watching Jesus being crucified.
I can't help but thinkof my Jake when I getthis feeling.
I'm not sure, but I believe this box is meant to be in Jake's possession.
Carry out something that only he is meant to.
I know that jakewill find this box,
just at the timehe needs it
to fulfill whateverhe has been calledto do.
Jake, what do youthink this means?
Grandpa felt and sawwhat I feel and see.
What if grandpawas right?
What if i'msupposed to do somethingwith the box?
But what?
He never saidwhere he found it.
What if someonegave it to him?
What if grandpa foundthe box where I found it?
What if he left it thereso I would find it?
Someone called holy.
What does thateven mean?
Okay, there isan explanationfor all of this.
There has to be.
You told methat grandpa always talked
about peoplethat came into his shop.
Do you rememberanything about somebody
that gave himthe box.
No. I don't rememberhim saying anything
about anyonegiving him the box.
Maybe somebodysold it to him.
( Sighs )i don't know,maybe he did--
I just don't understandhow I only know three people
that felt what I feltwhen I opened the box.
Why didn't you, Anna,or David feel anything?
Why just me, grandpa,and Richie?
How do you know richiefeels what you feel,jake?
Does he knowabout the box?
He opened it.
He didn't sayanything, but...
I know he felt it.
That's whati don't understand,
Richie is nota nice guy.
Wait, is thatthe same Richie
that cameto your birthday partywhen you were 10
and poppedall of the balloons?That Richie?
- Wasn't he sickor something?- Yeah, that's him.
- ( Door bell chimes )- ( knocking )
Looks like it's timefor me to go.
I'll get it.
Look, don't tell my momthat Richie bullies me.
She'll freak.
I'm Anna's sister,here to pick her up.
Anna!
- Call me tomorrow, okay?- Anna.
- Ready to go home, punk?- I'm so sorry, I thoughtmy mom was picking me up.
- What does that mean?- Is this your sister?
- You can pick me upif you want me to.- Yeah.
Jess, we gotta go.
Open the door.
You don't want meto come in, do you?
Oh is that him?Even you can do betterthan that.
He's not my boyfriend.
Right! later, boyfriend.
Anna: why do you always do this to me?
Maybe you shouldtalk to pastor mikeabout all of this.
Look, mom.
I don't knowwhat to make of anyof this either, but
you know the last timei went to church
was for grandpa'sfuneral.
I just don't wantto go back to the place
I had to say goodbyeto him, you know?
If you think you needto talk to pastor Mike,i can invite him over here.
I'm gonna go to bed.
- Let me thinkabout it.- Okay.
Good night, honey.
Jake: good morning, mom.
- Good morning.- Did you get any sleep?
Uh no, not really.How about you?
Not really.
I opened the box,though.
There's somethingso powerful about it.
It doesn'tscare me, though.
Like I said,maybe you should talkto pastor Mike about that.
He can at leastgive you his opinion
about what you see and feelwhen you open the box.
Hey. I never thoughtabout this, but
this looksjust like Mrs. rousso.
What?
Doesn't that lookjust like Mrs. rousso?
( Laughs )
Right?
Yeah, like a youngmrs. Rousso.
- That's it, mom.- What's it?
Mrs. rousso.
Do you think she knowsanything about the box?
You said that herand grandpa werebest friends.
Didn't they get coffeelike every day?
Maybe she just nevertold us about the box
because we never asked.Come on.
Let's go.
Uh, give me a secondto get ready, will ya?
( Sighs )
Richie, you better tellthe doctor everything,
because if you don't,i will.
Okay, I told you,i'm gonna tell themeverything.
The doctor willbe right in.
Mrs. leal.
- It's nice to see you.- Nice to see you, doctor.
There's Richie.How ya doing?
Looks like you'velost some weight,
how long haveyou had this cough?
I guess, I've had itfor a few days now--
he's had the coughfor a week.
- And he won't eat.- Ma, please!
Why aren'tyou eating, Richie?What's up with that?
I'm just not hungrythese days.
Connie, would youplease excuse us?
I need to takea good look at Richie.
Make yourself at homein the waiting area.
I'll come and get youwhen we're done.
Look, Richie.It looks like I'm gonnahave to admit you.
I'm not takingany chances.
Come on, doc.It's Christmas time.
I know.You wanna be homefor Christmas.
I get it. But lookat the weather out here.
People are runningaround with coldand flu bugs.
Stuff like thatcould kill you.
And you know it.
I'll go outand I'll talk to mom,
and I'll let her knowwhat's going on.
We'll getthe paperwork started.
Hang in there.
- Need help with that, ma?- Oh, no thanks,
- I'm almost done.- All right.
Where's your coat?
This is my coat.
( Laughs )all right look,
I'm gonna go meetthe guys at the arcade.
Those video gamesare a waste of time.
Would it kill youto read a book
every once in a while?
It might.
I don't wantto take the chance.( Laughs )
Richie, I knew it.
You're not well.
Ma, it's okay.I'll be in the hospitalfor just a few days.
I'll be outby Christmas time.
( Coughs )
You know, christmaswon't mean anything to mewithout you.
I just want youto be healthy.
( Door opens )
Richie,this is some paperworkthat you and your mom
need to takeover to the first floor.
From there,they will take youto your room.
You know the routine.
I'm sorryyou have to be here.
I hate this.
Mrs. rousso: What's this Jake tells me?
You havesome questions?
Well, I thinkjake is the onewith the questions.
Huh.well, I knowthis box.
Your grandfathershowed it to me before.
Did he giveit to you?
No. no, he didn'texactly give it to me.
Open it.
I want youto open it.
Do you feelor see anythingwhen you open it?
Have you calledyour father?
His shift is almost donefor the day?
Yes, I called paco, too.
( Coughs )
Why don't yougo home, mom?
I'll wait for dad.
I'll waitfor him, too.
I'll go home later,
I wanna talkto the doctor.
Is this room coldor is it just me?
Congratulations,mr. and Mrs. leal.
Say hi,to your new mommyand daddy, Richie.
Hello,mommy and daddy.
( Laughing )
- He's beautiful.- He's perfect.
Welcome home, Richie.
Lord, please takecare of my son.
( Sighs )
Jake,
you felt whatyour grandfather felt
when he openedthis box.
You know,he even said,
"i have no ideawhat heaven is like,
but if it feelslike it does when I openthe box,
then I can't waitto get there."
When he used to say,"i get a special feeling."
I thought he was losinghis mind or something.
I mean, no offense,maggie, but...
None taken.
- Man, it's cold out there.- Yeah, I know.
Have you heardabout Richie?
No, what about him?
He's in the hospital.
He's sick again.
What do you mean,sick again?
Cancer's back.
He's not doingtoo good.
I mean... I meanit doesn't look good,you know?
I have a bad feelingabout this.
Hey, you wantto go see him, man?
No.
They won't let us in.
Besides, Richie said it'stoo far for us to go.
Fine.
Now, let's go playthat boxing gameover there.
The box.
What box?
The box that Jake had.
That Richie picked upoff the ground.
Remember whenthey fought at the schoolthe other day.
Yeah, what about it?
Well, that night,richie told me something.
It was reallybothering him.
He said thatwhen he opened the box,
something cameover him.
Something...peaceful.
That's crazy, man.
I don't knowwhat that means,
but somethingtells me that we needto go find Jake.
Well do you knowwhere to find him?
No. there's waysto find him.
Let's go.
Man, I still don't knowwhat that little boxcan do for Richie.
Did he ever mentionwhat was in the box?
He always saidhe felt like the box
held somethingspecial inside.
Although, he nevercould find it.
And you know, the box,
the box hadsome weight to it.
I bet you twodon't know this.
Your grandfathertook care
of a homeless manfor a while.
He'd come in hereand he'd get his meals.
And your grandfatherwould pay for it.
He even let him stayin the back of his storefor a few weeks.
I bet you didn'tknow that, Maggie.
Nope.
Anyway, the first timei saw that box,
was shortly afterholy disappeared.
So I alwaysjust believed,
holy gave himthe box.
He never mentionedanything like thatto me.
Although, I guessit's because I probablywould have told dad
to makethe homeless manleave the shop.
Huh. well, I'll be.
He was right.
There is somethingin there.
What is it?
I don't know.
I think it'ssome kind of nail.
May I?
You know,just a few months
before your grandpapassed.
He told me he wasgoing to hide the boxin the store.
( Chuckles )and that if youhad anything
to do with it, Jake,
you would findthe box.
And he believed
somehowthe box would end upin your hands.
At justthe right time.
You mentioned, holy.
Was that the homelessguy's name?
He saidhe was knownas holy.
Holy...like god holy,
or holey likeholey clothes.
When your grandfathertold me he was gonna
let this guystay in his shop,
I did my research.I went around
and I askeda lot of questions.
And everyone I askedsaid he was harmless.
Just a kind old man.
Hey mom, do youknow how Jesus
was nailedto the cross?
Well, he diedso that you and icould have life.
Yeah, I know that,but were the nails
through his handsor his wrists.
I'm not sure.
I see some pictureswith the nails
through his hands,and some pictures
with the nailsthrough his wrists.
I can't reallytell you any morethan I already know.
Do you knowwhere holy is now?
You know,i can't say, Jake.
After he leftyour grandpa's shop,
nobody ever sawhim again. I mean...
Seems likehe just disappeared.
I asked about himfor a while,
but nobody'sever seen him again.
He truly wasa kind old man
that never didany harm to anyone.
And you knowanother thing,
he used to hand outthese little woodencrosses,
I don't even knowwhere he got them.
I we needto get going.I have to stop
by the churchand drop offsome boxes.
- Okay.- thank you, so muchfor all of your time.
- Oh thank you, Maggie.- Bye. We'll see youlater.
You guystake care now.
His "sats"are really low,mrs. Leal.
The doctor willbe in soon.
( Kisses )
( Knocks )
Hi. I gotthe test results back.
It's not good.
Looks likethe cancer is back.
I'm sorry.It's... it's bad.
Please, tell me we canbeat the cancer again.
We did it before,doctor.
I'll run more testsin the morning.
But just so we're clearand all on the same page,he's a sick young man.
Hi, dad.
How was work today?
It was okay, son.
How are you doing?
I'm not feelingtoo well right now.
What does the doctor say?
It's back, right?
He's gonna runsome more testsin the morning.
Are you hungry,richie?
I can ask the nurseto get you something--
mom, I'm not hungry.
I feel really tired.
Besides,the food hereis awful.
Okay,you get some sleep.
I'll be herewhen you get up.
I want to go home, mom.
Please, Connie,go home and getsome rest.
I'll staywith him tonight.
I'm not going,richard.
I'm scared.
I'm really scaredthis time.
You go home,you must be tired
after workingfor 12 hours.
If you're gonna go home,you should takeyour jacket.
I'm not going home.
I'm gonna go tothe chapel and pray.
( Crying )
( Cell phone rings )
- Hey, Cindy.- Hi, Anna, you busy?
No, I'm justreading a book.
- What are you doing?- Nothing.
Listen, have you heardanything about Richie?
No, I haven't heardanything about Richie.
He's in the hospital.
Is he goingto be okay?
Do you knowwhere Jake lives?
I knowwhere he lives, but
he and his momare out shopping today.
Okay, well pacois looking for him.Can you let him know?
Yeah, I'll do my bestto get a hold of him.
- And I'll call youright back.- Okay. Thanks.
- Hey, Anna. - Have you heardanything about Richie?
No, I haven't heardanything about Richie.
Well, he'sin the hospital.
Apparently he'sreally sick.
When did that happen?
Cindy just called me.
Oh, and she saidpaco's lookingfor you.
Wait, why is pacolooking for me?
I don't know.
Look, I'm goingto the church with my mom.
So I'll call youlater, okay?
Okay, bye.
Was that Anna?
Yeah.
She says that richieis in the hospital.
He's really sick.
Did she saywhat hospital he's at?
I wonder what couldbe wrong with him.
I don't know.
Hey Cindy,did you find Jake?
Anna said he's out running errands with his mom.
- Oh, okay.- You know, holiday stuff.
- Yeah. thanks.- Have you heard anything about Richie?
No, I don't anythingmore about Richie.
Well, tell him I said, "hi," okay?
Yeah, I'll tell himyou said, "hi,"
the next timei talk to him.
- Thank you. - Yeah, thanks.
So... did shefind him?
No. she talkedto Anna.
Anna said Jake'sout running errandswith his mom.
Probablychristmas shoppingor something.
So... what now?
I don't know.
I guess we justwait and see.
We have to getthat box to Richie.
I have a feeling...
- He needs it.- Alright man.
Well, if you gosee him tomorrow,call me.
I'll go with you.
You ladies need helpwith anything?
I brought the boxof decorations
that we usedlast year.
And Jake's hereto help if we need him.
Hey, Jake.What are you doing here?
What are youdoing here?
Pastor Mike saidthe ladies were gonna comeand help the place up.
So mom volunteered me,of course.
I thought youstopped comingto church?
No, Jake.You stopped.
Did you hearabout Richie?
No, what about him?
Anna called me today,said he's really sick.He's in the hospital.
No, I hadn't heard that.
Well, you ladiesare doing a great jobas usual.
Hope you're lettingthese boys do someof the work.
- David. glad you came outto give a hand.- Thanks for having me.
Jake! is that you?
It's been a while.How've you been?
I'm fine, pastor.I'd actually liketo talk to you
about something,if you have a minute.
Of course.You boys wanna talkin the office?
That's great.Hey, mom.
David and I are gonnatalk to the pastorin his office.
Yep. i'llwait for you.
Isn't thatjust like a man?They're going on break
- before they even getstarted working.- Typical.
Pastor Mike:What can I dofor you, Jake?
By the way,i know how hard it was
for you to loseyour grandfather.
He did great thingsfor this church.
He's missed dearly.
Thanks, pastor.
It just feels weirdbeing at churchwithout him,
but I feel likehe's with me right now.
What'son your mind, Jake?
It's about this.
Do you knowwhat this box is,pastor?
Do you see anythingwhen you open it?
Yes.
And I'm almost sureyou're going to tell methat you do too.
Aren't you?
I do.
My grandfather feltsomething too,
he wrote a letterabout it in his Bible.
I know he did, Jake.
I told himto write it.
You see, this is notthe first time that i'veseen this box.
A few years ago,your grandfather came byto see me
and his brought this boxwith him.
He told meall about it.
Did he tell youabout holy?
Or the nailthat's in it?
Yes. I know about holy,he told me all about him.
He never told meabout the nail.
May I seethe nail?
Sure, pastor.
Would you lookat that?
I guess your grandfathernever knew about this.
- May I take it out?- Sure.
Like, wait.Holy, who is that?
He's some homeless guythat my grandfathertook care of.
And there'sanother thing,pastor.
Why can'tdavid feel anythingwhen he opens the box?
It's not that davidisn't a good personor anything like that.
We may never know whyonly some people can feelsomething with this box.
Your grandfather told methat he had a dream.
That holy leftthis box with him
in orderto get it to you.
And he might be right.
The lord couldbe using you to complete
a purposewith this box?
For what purpose?
I can't figure it out,i don't know what to dowith it.
( Phone rings )excuse me, gentlemen.
It's pastor Mike.Hey, it's good to--
of course.Yes, what's the address.
Absolutely. of course.I'll be there.
You too.
Sorry about that, guys.Glad I took that call.
Jake, have you told maggieabout all of this?
Yeah. I told herabout everything.
Well, have youlet her hold the box?
Did she get any feelingsor see anything?
No. nothing.
As far as I can tell,the only three peoplethat feel anything
are you, me and Richie.
Richie?richie who?
Richie leal.
How do you knowhe feels what you feel?
I'm not too sure,although I heard todayhe's in the hospital.
And he's really sick.
I got in a fightwith him a week agoand he opened the box.
I know this isgonna sound crazy,
but I knowthat he felt something.I just know it.
Jake,
I just got off the phonewith Richie's dad.
If this is the same richieyou're talking about,
his leukemia is back,and he is very ill.
Why would he call you?Do you know him?
I've known richiesince he was just a kid.
Richie and paco used to cometo vacation Bible school
every summer before youstarted coming to church.
That's it.
We need to getthe box to richieso he can get better.
Can you give usa ride, pastor?
You go tellyour mother what'sgoing on.
I'll meet youat the front door.
I don't know, mom.I got a bad feelingabout Richie.
I know what you mean.I talked to connieearlier today,
she's really scaredfor Richie.
Poor Connie.
I think I mightgo see him tonight.
I remember I usedto take care of Richie
when he wasa little boy.
Connie and richardboth had to work.
They lived right downthe street.
You rememberthat, paco?
You and richiewere a handfultogether.
Man...
Jake betterget that boxto Richie.
What box?
Oh. nothing.
( Cell phone rings )
- Hello.- hey, it's me.
David and Jake are at the hospital.
- They're where?- Yeah, I heard they went there with their pastor.
You're kidding me!
I have a feeling we need to get up there.
Okay, yeah, I just gottaput my coat on.
Okay. Anna and I will meet you up there.
Sounds good.
What's the matter?What's going on?
I need to go see him.
Is there somethingyou're not telling me,paco?
Thank you.
Will the doctor be into see Richie?
It'll betomorrow morning.
He still is waitingfor more test resultsto come back in.
But he usually makeshis rounds pretty early,
so hopefullyrichie's results willbe back by then.
I know he's waitingfor those before he comesto talk to you.
Can we staywith him tonight?
Yeah... I need to gocall the doctor.
His "sats" are not good.
What do you mean"not good"?
Um...let me go callthe doctor,
he might still be herein the hospital.
And whatif he's not?
Mrs. leal, it's okay.We always have
a doctor on call,let me just go get him.
Connie, do youremember
the day that weadopted Richie?
And I went downto the store and gotyou a coffee
- like I did today.- You did that many times,richard.
- We were herewith Richie for weeks.- I know.
But the first time,
do you rememberwhat happened?
What happened?
I was walkingto the store,
and I saw an old man.
He was getting beat up really bad in an alley.
And I remember running towards him
and the guys ran away.
He was hurt really bad.
I picked him up and carried him to the hospital.
He was bleeding. And when they put him
on to the hospital bed,
a little wooden cross fell out of his pocket.
And I remember him looking at me and saying
he would repay me someday,
for the act of kindness.
Maggie: okay, I do remember that.
I was mad at youfor not bringing me backa coffee.
Yeah, I just rememberhow thankful he was.
I wonder whateverhappened to him.
Who knows.
Good evening,we are here to seerichie leal,
I believe he wasadmitted today.
Can you tell us wherehis room is, please?
It's aftervisiting hours.
And you won'tbe able to see himuntil tomorrow.
I know, it's notvisiting hours.
But I'm a pastor,
and Richie's fathercalled me to come and praywith them.
So could youtell me what floorhe's on, please?
Oh, and that'sa great book
you're reading,by the way.
( Sighs )
You know the rules.
You're the only onethat can go up.
They have to stayin the downstairs...
- Nurse, please!- Waiting room.
We haveto see, Richie.
I have somethinghe needs.
Well, can they at leastride the elevator up with me
and wait inthe waiting area there?
Look, I'm sorry.You know the rules.
Now are you borrowingthat book, because I cangive you one to keep.
Look, it'sgetting late.
Now if I let themride up on the elevatorwith you,
they're going to findtheir way to Richie's room.
I was young once.
And I'm not stupid.
Would you like meto drop the book offtomorrow?
I could stop by.
I want to getback to my book.
Now, I'll let themride up on the elevatorwith you.
But they have to stayin the upstairswaiting room.
You visit Richie,they stay in the upstairswaiting area.
Thank you.Now, what floordid you say he was on?
( Typing )
Room 77, 7th floor.
Thank you.
Should I give youthe box, pastor?
No. I want youto hang on to itfor now.
We will get youinto that room,i'm sure of it.
I want you to handthe box to Richie.
( Elevator dings )
Let's hope no oneon the 7th floor
gives us any trouble.
Okay, you guyswait in there.
I don't want drawtoo much attentionto the box right away.
Let me figure outwhat's going on,
I'll talkto the parents,
come back and getyou guys as soonas I can.
I just wish someonecould tell me that
my son is gonna livefor many, many years.
Get married.
Have kids.
I would give anythingfor that, Richard.
Pastor Mike: Richard! I got here as fast as I could.
How's Richie?
He's not doing good.
You helped richardand I so much
when richiewas little.
I've held on to your cardall this time.
I just prayedthat your numberwas still the same.
Your prayers havealways stuck in my mind.
I told richardto call you tonight,and I hope that's okay,
but Richie really needssome prayers tonight.
Hi, we're hereto see Richie leal.
Can you tell uswhat floor he's on?
Are you guyswith the pastor?
- Pastor?- no, we're notwith the pastor.
We need to see Richie leal,it's really important.
Sure, just likeit's important for meto finish this book.
I have to returnit tomorrow.
If you can makeit upstairs withoutgetting caught,
then that'sfine with me.
Richie's in room 77on the 7th floor.
Thank you.
Is there anybody elsei need to look for?
No, I don't think so.
Have a good night.
- Bye bye.- You, too.
Hey man,did you bringthe box?
Wait, how do you knowabout the box?
Well, the other day,
when Jake and richiewere gonna fight,
that night,he said when heopened the box,
he felt something.
Did he tell youwhat he felt?
Did he see anything?
Yeah, how did you know?
I thinkhe feels what I feelwhen I open the box.
Did he tell youwhat he saw?
He said he saw a boy,playing with the box.
But in a differentplace in time.
Like when jesuswas on earth.
Then he saidhe said he saw
the same boycrying behind a rock.
- And then he saw Jesus--- from the cross.
Yeah. I see that too.
He said he feltsomething
he'd neverfelt before.
Like there wasnot one thing wrongwith his whole body.
He said it wasa very peaceful feeling.
I don't know.This is crazy.
Let me seeif I can get a pillowfor you, so you can rest.
No, I'm good.I'm good.
Mr. and Mrs. leal,richie's very ill.
You might wantto prepare yourselves.
It's not lookinggood for him.
Are you telling memy son is going to die?
Tonight?
We're keepinga close eye on him.
Hopefully his doctorwill be here earlyin the morning,
but rest assured,he's very comfortableright now.
I'm sorry.
I brought a coupleof Richie's friendsto come and see him.
Is that okay with you?
Sure. where are they?
They're down the hallin the waiting area.
I'll go get them.
Hey, pastor.
This is Cindy, Anna,and Jimmy.
Paco knowsabout the box.
Well, look Jake.Richie is in a whole lotof trouble right now.
He's very ill.He's running a fever.
We'll have to getyou past security.
So everyone needsto be very quiet.
This hasto happen quickly.
I'll go ahead.Just try not to drawtoo much attention.
Wait. give him a sec.
All right. Come on.
What's going on here?
He's on two litersof oxygen, 88%sat one minute.
And then he'sat 98% room air.
- Oh, Jake?- Wow.
And where do you thinkyou guys are going?
Hi.you work here too?
Yeah.
Okay, it's after hours.And I can't let you goany farther.
Oh.
Well, Richie'shere, sir.
It's really importantthat we see him.
- What's in the bag?- Nothing.
I just really needto see Richie, sir.
It's important.
That's cute.
Let me see what'sin the bag here.
Hang on a second!Hang on a second!
Stop!
You know what,you're the onei want. Let's go!
Sir, please let go!
- Please! - everybody outof the room.
- Doctor, please!- Stand back!
You haveto stand back.
- Where's Jake?- He's been stoppedby security.
Listen to me,find a way to get himin here now!
Open the crash cart,
get me anesthesiaand respiratory, stat!
- Okay.- then get me some epiand get the pads ready.
Listen guys,we need to check every floorin this hospital.
Includingthe parking lot.Let's split up.
We're gonnahave to hit him.
- Put some gel on this.- Let's pray.
We've cometo you at the mostdesperate time
with the mostdesperate need, lord.
- Clear!- we're here becausewhat we need
only youcan provide that.
( Elevator chimes )
Jake!( groans )
Is there somesort of emergency?
Yeah.
You could say that.
- He's in v-tach.Stand back.- We need you, lord.
- Now more than ever.- Clear!
He's on the seventh floor.
Copy.
Lord, we need a miracle.
- Please, lord!- Richard: Jesus.
P.A. system: Code blue, code blue. 305.
- Excuse me.- Don't let him go!
- I need to see him!- Clear!
We need you, lord,we need you nowmore than ever!
Pastor Mike: Bless these men and women who are
- trying to treat Richie. - Give me the box!
- Make their handsyour hands, lord.- Clear!
- Turn it upall the way!- Give them the wisdom...
Give them the energy,give them the focusthey need.
- Clear!- help us bringhim back to life!
It's a miracle only you can provide!
I need to see him!
In your most preciousson's name we pray,
- amen.- amen.
Jesus, amen.
( Crying )
- Call the code.- No! No!
- Oh, god!- I'm sorry.
( Sobbing )
- Doctor, put this boxon Richie's body.- Why?
- Please! trust me!- You can't do that!
No!
Idiots!
Where are yougentleman going?
Anna, I'm at the room.Get everyone up here.
Uh, doctor?
His vitals are normal.
Yeah...i can see that.
Cancel code.
Those readings,does that mean
that the canceris no longer present?
Well we'redefinitely gonna needto run some more tests
in the morning,guaranteed,
but between all of usand the iv poll,
I've neversee anything like thisin my entire career.
If the cancerwere still here,
the color wouldn'tbe back in his face.
And the his vitalswould not be backto normal.
That I can tellyou for sure.
You were very,very sick.
Are you sureyou're okay?
Yeah, I feel fine.
I feel likei haven't eatenin days.
I'm so hungry.
There are too manypeople in the room,
I need you guysgo into the waiting room
and waituntil we canfigure this out.
Give usa moment, doctor.Please.
Can somebodyplease tell mewhat just happened?
Richie...
You, my friend,have just been a partof a beautiful miracle.
Was it a dream?
Hey, guys.What's going on?
Why do I getthe feeling
you just savedmy life, Jake?
No, Richie.
It wasn't me,and you know it.
Well, look.I don't knowabout all of you,
but tonight,i felt somethingin my heart
that I've neverfelt before.
And I wouldgive anything
to feel like thatall the time.
Anything.
Well, I thinki can help youwith that, paco.
In fact,i want to seeall of you
in my officetomorrow morning.
Except for you, Richie.
I'll see youwhen you get outof the hospital.
I don't wantto hear it,
I've told you.You both are fired.
We'll talkabout this later.
Yeah, we will.
I'll see youin church.
Let me knowwhen you get outof here.
I need someonewho can give mesome game.
( Laughs )yeah, sure,
but you start cryingwhen you lose,white boy.
That box.
It's notthe box, sir.
It's what'sin the box.
Merry Christmas,jake.
Merry Christmas,richie.
Well, good morning,everyone.
And merry Christmas.
I'd like to startby sharing somethingwith all of you
that happenedjust a few days ago.
These kidsare about to tell youa true story,
of what Jesus christhas done for them.
I know,because I was there.
So, let'sget started.
Jake?
( Applause )
Thanks so much,pastor Mike.
( Microphone feeds back )
Hello, everyone.
My name isjake Casper.
Wow, there's a lotof people here today.
Well,it's been an amazing week,to say the least.
If you believethat Jesus christisn't performing
any miraclesthese days,
and it's impossibleto love even your worstenemies,
sit back,
and listento our story.
A true story that beginswith a small wooden box.
I call itthe messenger's box.
And somewhere
tucked awayin the atticsof our hearts,
we all havea messenger's box.
But make no mistake,it's not about the boxitself.
It's about what'sin the box.
And if you findyourself in a hopelesssituation today,
no matter what it is.
No matter how darkthat situation may seem.
There is hope.
And that hope
is in Jesus Christ.
You see,
we are notguaranteed tomorrow,
or even the next minute.
So after you hearour story,
I'd like eachand every one of you,
to answerthese questions.
Have you foundyour messenger's box?
Have you opened it?
And if you haven't,
what are youwaiting for?
**