Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Let's go.
Where
you going, bitch?
Don't leave me!
Where you going, bitch?
One more strike, Quintana,
we lock your ass up for good.
You got yourself a record, boy.
One more strike, Quintana, we lock your ass up for good.
Most recent... breaking and entering,
stealing a car, You got yourself a record, boy.
Most recent... breaking and
entering, stealing a car,
disturbing the peace, indecent exposure.
Most recent... breaking and entering, stealing a car,
disturbing the peace,
indecent exposure.
Wow, that's big.
I have to have special underwear, man.
I have to have
special underwear, man.
Really?
Yeah.
But size ain't everything.
Don't make you a man.
For that you need balls.
Bullshit.
Six months at Chino
for taking a piss.
Sometimes folks overreact.
Six months at Chino for taking a piss.
In any event, you didn't do it again.
Sometimes folks overreact.
In any event, you
didn't do it again.
Hell no.
I ain't no sex offender.
Served your time, boy.
And we don't forget what you did, Quintana,
- Served your time, boy.
And we don't forget
what you did, Quintana,
helping the Black Sheep
win a correctional state
bowling championship.
We don't forget.
Bowling championship.
That last strike of yours was for the ages.
We don't forget.
That last strike of
yours was for the ages.
I chopped his ass up.
That last strike of yours was for the ages.
I've never seen any one lick a ball before you throw a strike.
I chopped his ass up.
I've never seen any one lick a
ball before you throw a strike.
That's my style.
I've never seen any one lick a ball before you throw a strike.
Keep on bowling, boy.
I'll see you, Castro.
We're gonna miss you, Quintana.
You look good.
I look like a
million bucks, man.
Woo!
Whoa, man!
Let's roll.
Where we going?
I'm not into dating.
You like me?
We get it on.
But don't let me have to feed you first.
But don't let me have
to feed you first.
Put your fingers
through it, just like that.
Yes. Mm. Put your fingers through it,
just like that.
Yes.
Mm.
I just think it gives it so much more movement here.
Yes. Mm.
I just think it gives it
so much more movement here.
Yeah, I love it.
I just think it gives it so much more movement here.
There's a lot of play at the bottom, right?
Yeah, I love it.
There's a lot
of play at the bottom, right?
Yeah.
There's a lot of play at the bottom, right?
How we doing over here?
Good?
Grateful.
How we doing over here? Good?
I used to have blond hair.
Really?
Bullshit, man!
Can say that shit.
I used to have blond hair,
like they got over. Can say that shit.
I used to have blond
hair, like they got over.
Huh? I used to have blond hair,
like they got over.
Huh?
Oh, shit.
Hey, man.
Going over there?
What a honey, huh?
Orange and shit, huh?
- What a honey, huh?
Still warm.
Orange and shit, huh?
It's been a long time since I took the wheel, man.
Still warm.
It's been a long time since
I took the wheel, man.
Huh?
It's been a long time since I took the wheel, man.
Woo.
Huh?
We're on parole.
I know you got a screwdriver.
Your own muscle car, man.
How's that for a
smooth ride, huh?
Feel that torque, man!
How's that for a smooth ride, huh?
Fucking poetry, man!
Feel that torque, man!
Ah!
Fucking poetry, man!
Hey... where we going, anyway?
I should drop in
on the old lady.
Your... your mom?
Now?
I mean, one of these days.
You know.
What is she like?
Mommy?
Yeah.
Sh! Sh! Sh!
- What is it?
- Sh! Sh! Sh!
What is it?
It's me, Mommy.
Jesus.
I'd like you to meet my moms.
Evening, ma'am.
Is he your friend?
Yeah, Petey.
OK, Mom.
- Yeah, Petey.
Let's go.
OK, Mom.
On your feet, Pops.
Let's go.
On your feet, man.
On your feet, Pops.
Still on the game, huh?
At your age, huh?
Uh-huh.
, Mommy.
You ought to be ashamed.
On your feet, I said, man.
Let's go.
Chop, chop.
I'm coming.
Let's move it.
- I'm coming.
Give him back his bread.
What's your name, man?
Frank.
You from around here, Frank? Frank.
You from
around here, Frank?
He's from up north.
- You from around here, Frank?
- Mhm.
- He's from up north.
Mhm.
It doesn't bother
you, Frank, to do
the horizontal with my mother?
Excuse me.
The horizontal with my mother?
I didn't know.
- Excuse me.
You didn't know?
I didn't know.
You... you have sex with the man's mother in the family bed?
- You didn't know?
You... you have sex with the
man's mother in the family bed?
Hey,.
You... you have sex with the man's mother in the family bed?
Hey, man,
that kind of makes you like my old man, huh? Hey,.
Hey, man, that kind of makes
you like my old man, huh?
Oh.
You know...
you know shit about jail, Frank? Oh.
You know... you know
shit about jail, Frank?
No, not... not personally. You know...
you know shit about jail, Frank?
No, not... not personally.
You know what you got at night to help you sleep?
You know what you got at
night to help you sleep?
No.
Tell him, Petey.
Your hand.
Oh.
You can get your rocks
off with somebody's
mama in the slammer, man.
You can get your rocks off with somebody's
Mama in the slammer, man.
My glasses!
I'm sorry.
I didn't know you had a son.
You didn't know, man.
But now you know.
She's got a son, man.
Make some coffee, Mommy.
And put something on decent.
If there's one thing my buddy's
nuts about, it's modesty.
Yeah, well, it's better
than no mother at all.
That's low, man.
Be polite.
She's a lady.
She doesn't look much older than you.
She doesn't look
much older than you.
Yeah?
Well, she isn't, man.
Hey, wash your face while you're in there, Well,
she isn't, man.
Hey, wash your face
while you're in there,
and take the war paint off, huh?
Hey, wash your face while you're in there,
I want to see your real
eyes, your real skin.
I mean, who knows...
maybe it's the last time I want to see your real eyes, your real skin.
maybe it's the last time
I'll ever see you. I mean,
who knows... maybe it's the last time
I'll ever see you.
And here's a little something extra to tide your ass over.
And here's a little something
extra to tide your ass over.
Thank you.
So you got out.
Right.
How do I look?
Different?
No.
I don't know.
You look like a kid, my kid.
He always drank
like this, pinky up.
Distinguished.
You ever see him bowl?
Couple times.
- You ever see him bowl?
This man can roll.
Nobody fucks with the Jesus.
She smiles like ravioli, man.
Wow, you guys are a
couple of real fuckheads.
Aren't you a little old to be stealing cars?
Wow, you guys are a couple of real fuckheads.
Aren't you a little old
to be stealing cars?
Yeah, I know.
Pretty nice, right?
Too bad you can't afford it.
See the name on the building?
That's me, baby.
Now put your hands up.
You picked the wrong guy, fellas.
You picked the
wrong guy, fellas.
That's the third vintage car I've You picked the wrong guy, fellas.
That's the third
vintage car I've
had stolen in under a year.
We didn't steal it.
Had stolen in under a year.
We just... we just took it out, man.
We didn't steal it.
We just... we just
took it out, man.
We borrowed it. We just...
we just took it out, man.
We borrowed it.
We brought it back.
Why don't you tell your story to the man, OK?
Why don't you tell your
story to the man, OK?
You never fuck with another man's car, or his hair.
Why don't you tell your story to the man, OK?
You never fuck with another
man's car, or his hair.
Marie, you call the cops.
You never fuck with another man's car, or his hair.
You call them.
Marie, you call the cops.
It's your car.
You call them.
How about I fire your skinny French ass, huh?
It's your car.
How about I fire your
skinny French ass, huh?
Marie!
How about I fire your skinny French ass, huh?
Jesus!
Woo!
You looking good, girl.
What's up with Leon?
Oh, it's over.
I'm sorry.
Is this some sort of
fucked up family reunion
that we're having right now?
Do you actually know this clown?
That we're having right now?
Who you calling
a clown,?
I thought you
were in the slammer?
I just got out.
I thought you were in the slammer?
So you celebrated by stealing my car?
I just got out.
So you celebrated
by stealing my car?
That was the first
thing you did, fuckhead?
Well... That was the first thing you did, fuckhead?
Well...
I'll make it up to you, baby, OK? Well...
I'll make it up
to you, baby, OK?
We're on prob, man!
I'll make it up to you, baby, OK?
Frenchie, shut the fuck up.
We're on prob, man!
Hey!
Frenchie, shut the fuck up.
Watch how you talk to a lady!
- Hey!
Asshole.
Watch how you talk to a lady!
Shut the fuck up.
Asshole.
Fucking asshole!
I'm sorry!
Who is the hairdresser here?
Who's Paul Dominic?
That gun don't scare me.
Jesus
Cartoon gangster.
You got the balls to pull a trigger on the Jesus?
You got the balls to pull
a trigger on the Jesus?
I can't hack it
in the hole, man.
Fuck this shit!
I can't hack it in the hole, man.
Should have thought of that first.
Fuck this shit!
Should have thought
of that first.
Fuck!
Ah! Ah!
Ah!
Oh!
In the ass.
Ow, ow, ow, ow!
That really hurts.
That really... ooh!
Fuck you in the ass, man!
Two times, papi chulo!
Whoa, man!
Oh!
Ow!
Dude, I'm a hairdresser.
Nobody fucks with the Jesus, man!
Nobody fucks with
the Jesus, man!
Nobody.
Nobody fucks with the Jesus, man!
Woo!
Nobody.
Fine.
Fucking Boricuas!
Ugh, thank you, baby.
- Fucking Boricuas!
Asshole.
Ugh, thank you, baby.
Hey, what the?
- Asshole.
Get in, Petey!
Get your ass in!
Oh, shit.
Oh, there's blood all over me!
We have to find a doctor!
Where you hit?
Ugh!
Enough to shoot him.
What an asshole! Ugh!
Enough to shoot him. What an
asshole!
Jesus. Enough to shoot him.
What an asshole!
Jesus.
There's blood all over my balls!
Hold tight, Petey.
Hold tight.
He's dead!
Huh?
Petey!
Yeah, I'm OK.
You scared the shit out of me, Petey.
You scared the
shit out of me, Petey.
, I'm bleeding.
You scared the shit out of me, Petey.
I got so much blood on my balls.
, I'm bleeding.
Hang in there, man.
- That's not good.
- Hang in there, man.
That's not good.
Oh, that's not good!
- That's not good.
We got to dumb
this car, change colors.
Keep down.
He can't hack the sight of blood.
He can't hack the
sight of blood.
Quintana!
What's up, man?
- Quintana!
Yeah!
What's up, man?
What the fuck is going on?
Yeah!
I thought you was in the slam?
Man, I was... good behavior.
Woo!
They reformed your shit.
- Woo!
A new man... that's right, man.
They reformed your shit.
A new man...
that's right, man.
I need a new whip, man.
A new man... that's right, man.
Got some dough?
I got something better.
Marie, come over here, man.
You got some scissors?
Fuck yeah, I got a pair of scissors.
Fuck yeah, I got
a pair of scissors.
Yeah? Fuck yeah,
I got a pair of scissors.
Yeah?
Well, my lady friend here is going Yeah?
Well, my lady
friend here is going
to lay a cut on you that will blow your mind, man, Well,
my lady friend here is going
to lay a cut on you that
will blow your mind, man,
make you totally sexy, man.
To lay a cut on you that will blow your mind, man,
I'm already a sexy motherfucker.
Make you totally sexy, man.
I'm already a
sexy motherfucker.
Yeah.
I'll make you more sexy, man.
No, man.
Chop his head up good.
Yeah, I got it.
I'll be right back.
Aw, shit.
Endo... endo-chronologist,
what the fuck's that mean?
How am I
supposed to know?
What am I, a fucking dictionary?
How am I supposed to know?
Oh, what I need is a man
who takes care of balls!
Jesus Christ!
Oh, my balls!
Easy.
My buddy got shot
by a hairdresser.
Fix him up,
or I'll stick my piece up your ass My buddy got shot by a hairdresser.
Fix him up, or I'll stick
my piece up your ass
and pull the trigger.
Pick.
And pull the trigger.
I fuck on the outside.
Pick.
Paul Dominic doesn't
get through the door.
No hairdressers... not at my place.
Paul Dominic doesn't get through the door.
No hairdressers...
not at my place.
I won't have it. No hairdressers...
I won't have it.
In the bushes, in the bedroom,
on his wife's I won't have it.
In the bushes, in the
bedroom, on his wife's
sheets, when she's
skiing, no problem.
I just spread out on her bed.
Sheets, when she's skiing, no problem.
Easy, easy.
I just spread out on her bed.
Easy.
- Oh god.
- Easy.
Oh god.
He's going to need a transfusion.
- Oh god.
He's going to
need a transfusion.
I got to get some blood. Your wife can go.
He's going to need a transfusion.
I got to get some blood.
- Your wife can go.
Wake her up. I got to get some blood.
Wake her up.
Ha, his apartment's
fucking choice.
The bathroom... they've got one of those douches.
Ha, his apartment's fucking choice.
The bathroom... they've
got one of those douches.
It's like a couch. The bathroom...
they've got one of those douches.
It's like a couch.
His wife's pussy must shine.
There's no reason why she should have a stink.
There's no reason why
she should have a stink.
And the one towel...
There's no reason why she should have a stink.
holy shit.
And the one towel...
Wiping your ass is an experience.
Holy shit.
Wiping your ass
is an experience.
Thank you very much.
Wiping your ass is an experience.
How's his ball?
- Thank you very much.
The bullet pierced the
fleshy part of the thigh.
A little to the left, he would have burst a testicle.
The bullet pierced the fleshy part of the thigh.
A little to the left, he
would have burst a testicle.
We get all the breaks, man. A little to the left,
he would have burst a testicle.
We get all the breaks, man.
Hey, man, what you got in the way of cash around here, bro?
Hey, man, what you got in the
way of cash around here, bro?
Hm?
Sorry, you're out of luck.
Really, huh?
Howard, give him the money.
That's a dumb play, Howie.
What you take me for,
some That's a dumb play, Howie.
What you take me
for, some
You got a find lady there, man.
You should treat her right.
You'll need some antibiotics.
Here, for your friend.
I could have been a doctor.
This frog
lady won't stop yapping.
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
This frog lady won't stop yapping.
I feel like the underside
of a turnip green.
You see? See?
I feel like the underside of a turnip green.
You see?
See?
Look at my hair,
motherfucking hair. You see? See?
motherfucking hair.
Huh?
What are you squawking about?
Now I got to buy a hat to cover my bald-ass head.
Now I got to buy a hat
to cover my bald-ass head.
There's a art to this shit!
Now I got to buy a hat to cover my bald-ass head.
You look good.
There's a art to this shit!
Yeah?
You look good.
Shit, I'm a sexy motherfucker.
- Yeah?
Shit, I'd fuck me too.
Yeah.
Guess what we're going to lay on this hair curler.
Guess what we're going
to lay on this hair curler.
You got me.
Guess what we're going to lay on this hair curler.
He's all hung up on this car, right?
You got me.
He's all hung up
on this car, right?
Yeah.
He's all hung up on this car, right?
So we leave it on the side of the road.
Yeah.
So we leave it on
the side of the road.
You with me?
So we leave it on the side of the road.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Sure.
OK.
The cops, they find it.
And lover boy gets it back completely intact.
And lover boy gets it
back completely intact.
And he doesn't know, that fuck,
is that we have completely
fucked his fucking car. And he doesn't know,
that fuck, is that we have completely
fucked his fucking car.
I saw in through one of
the front axles, almost.
One wheel is hanging by a hair waiting to fly off on a curve,
I saw in through one of the front axles, almost.
One wheel is hanging by a hair
waiting to fly off on a curve,
doing 90 on the highway,
just radio One wheel is hanging by a hair waiting to fly off on a curve,
doing 90 on the
highway, just radio
blasting, the hair's flying.
He's just having a good time, man,
when all of a sudden, blasting, the hair's flying.
He's just having a good time,
man, when all of a sudden,
oops! He's just having a good time, man,
when all of a sudden,
oops!
Oops!
Wheel flies off, man!
Isn't that beautiful?
Yeah, I guess.
Can you get me
some gum, and some pants,
and some shorts, and smokes, and some chocolate?
Can you get me some gum, and some pants,
and some shorts, and
smokes, and some chocolate?
And gauze... get me a lot of gauze.
And some shorts, and smokes, and some chocolate?
And gauze... get
me a lot of gauze.
Anything else, sweety?
And gauze... get me a lot of gauze.
Are you sure this is
where you want to be?
Why not?
Are you sure this is where you want to be?
People buy things here.
Why not?
You need money.
People buy things here.
Oh.
You need money.
You probably just
got out of jail.
Whoa, mind reader, huh?
You probably just got out of jail.
Your first paycheck.
Whoa, mind reader, huh?
No.
Your first paycheck.
No, I got a...
I got a rich lady, man.
Oh yeah, man.
She can't get enough of me.
Congratulations.
Yeah.
You don't need that badge.
Your cologne gives you away.
You're lucky.
Really?
Yeah.
I'm in a good mood today.
You got a nice trim there...
kind of brings out the ears. I'm in a good mood today.
kind of brings out the ears.
You like it? You got a nice trim there...
You like it?
Yeah.
You got the bottles every Saturday?
You got the bottles
every Saturday?
No, no, I work on Saturdays...
You got the bottles every Saturday?
Uh-huh.
No, no, I work on Saturdays...
...the big shoplifting day.
Uh-huh.
Yeah?
...the big shoplifting day.
I catch dozens
of bums like you.
Good for you, man.
I catch dozens of bums like you.
If everybody was that dedicated, shit.
Good for you, man.
If everybody was
that dedicated, shit.
How'd you know?
I know you.
Inside and out.
You looking for trouble?
No, no, no.
Just a pair of jeans,
some undies, panties. No, no, no.
some undies, panties.
You're beautiful.
I almost want to touch you.
Oh, you touch me, I'll touch you,
and you know it. I almost want to touch you.
Oh, you touch me, I'll
touch you, and you know it.
Down there on the right.
I'll frisk you later.
Let the customer through.
Where are you from?
France.
So your French.
What?
Oh.
Hey!
Hey, you bastard!
Come back here, you sleazy bastard!
Come back here,
you sleazy bastard!
People will steal anything.
Nice here, huh?
Sitting out under the trees.
We're good together, huh?
Mm.
The simple pleasures, man.
No one bugging us.
I'm going to use the loo,
try my new panties on, man. No one bugging us.
try my new panties on, man.
I hope they don't scratch. I'm going to use the loo,
I hope they don't scratch.
Walk slow, man.
Walk slow.
We're out for a stroll.
You hungry?
No.
It's nice.
It's nice to be.
Just like flies always buzzing around our balls.
Just like flies always
buzzing around our balls.
Not so fast, Jesus.
Just like flies always buzzing around our balls.
It's like they can't live without us.
Not so fast, Jesus.
It's like they
can't live without us.
What about Marie?
It's like they can't live without us.
We're just two simple fuckheads!
What about Marie?
We're just two
simple fuckheads!
Yeah, but how's she going to find us?
We're just two simple fuckheads!
Yeah, but how's
she going to find us?
She'll find us!
Yeah, but how's she going to find us?
And if she don't,
she ain't never been in the slammer, She'll find us!
And if she don't, she ain't
never been in the slammer,
so fuck it!
So fuck it!
Miss!
- Miss!
You didn't pay your check!
Miss!
Get back here!
Fucking Mexicans!
Fuck you, you fucking hicks!
I'll get you!
What the fuck are those
things they're carrying?
My balls!
What the fuck are those things they're carrying?
Fuck your balls, man!
My balls!
Stand up!
The winner!
Woo!
Jesus Quintana!
You fucking asshole!
What the fuck you
doing in there, man?
It was open.
Shit, nobody told me.
Come on.
Get in.
Fucking rock and roll, man.
Let's rock and roll!
Hey!
Hurry up, man!
That's my car!
Get out of my car!
Fuck you, baby!
- Stop!
- Fuck you, baby!
Stop!
Hey!
Put on the gas!
I want to see his name, Paul
Dominique, in the obits column.
Fuck.
You shouldn't do that.
What?
Never wish
another person dead.
What are you talking about?
Never wish another person dead.
Nothing I ever wish for comes true.
What are you talking about?
Nothing I ever wish
for comes true.
Where are we going?
What do you want?
Nothing.
Yeah, man, it's like he had
a beer or something, right?
Got to be honest, man, there's nothing more Yeah, man,
it's like he had a beer or something, right?
Got to be honest, man,
there's nothing more
dope than a fine black woman.
Got to be honest, man, there's nothing more
Blondes have more fun?
Dope than a fine black woman.
Bullshit.
Blondes have more fun?
I lost my virginity to a
in the synagogue.
It was my Uncle Pedro's house.
I lost my virginity to a in the synagogue.
You bastard!
You ditched me!
Marie, I told him not too.
Fucking pussies.
I come out of the toilet,
and you fucking disappear?
Left me cold like
some ..
Hey, it was a one bobo move.
Left me cold like some ..
Admit it, man.
Hey, it was a one bobo move.
First, you stick my ass with the check.
Admit it, man.
First, you stick my
ass with the check.
I dropped everything.
I lost my job, and you run away like a chicken shit.
I lost my job, and you run
away like a chicken shit.
Gutless bitch. I lost my job,
and you run away like a chicken shit.
Gutless bitch.
Hey, I'm not a bitch.
Chill out, woman.
We couldn't afford
to get pinched.
You ain't never been in the joint.
We couldn't afford to get pinched.
You ain't never
been in the joint.
Suppose something had happened to me, eh?
You ain't never been in the joint.
Suppose something
had happened to me, eh?
Fuckheads.
Suppose something had happened to me, eh?
When you think about it,
it's a drag to be famous, eh?
I'll tell you who was underrated, Vanessa Del Rio.
When you think about it, it's a drag to be famous, eh?
I'll tell you who was
underrated, Vanessa Del Rio.
I don't like porn. I'll tell you who was underrated,
Vanessa Del Rio.
I don't like porn.
She got so into it.
She's like Pacino or something.
Oh, there are good actresses and bad actresses,
Oh, there are good
actresses and bad actresses,
even in porn.
Oh, there are good actresses and bad actresses,
What's off season mean to you?
Vacation.
When I was a kid, I
never went anywhere.
Home sweet home, man.
Yeah, shit, man.
We're good together, no?
Eh?
Oh.
Jesus.
Huh?
My jimmy is limp.
So what?
So is mine.
I always wake up with a hard on.
I always wake
up with a hard on.
Come on in, man.
This feels great.
I can't.
I'll start bleeding again.
Man, your feet ain't
gonna bleed, man.
Oh, look at this, eh?
Man, your feet ain't gonna bleed, man.
, Man.
Woo!
You prick!
You stink, man.
Get some crud off, purify the air,
you understand? You stink, man.
Get some crud off, purify
the air, you understand?
Yeah, come on, man,
you'll be all right.
It's all in your head, man.
Stop worrying.
You feel good, eh?
You feel any better?
Maybe too?
Come on, man.
Woo!
You are really pretty, man.
Back off.
Don't be ashamed, man.
I'm not ashamed.
I just don't want to.
How do you know if you ain't never even tried it, man?
How do you know if you ain't
never even tried it, man?
Let me have a go at it, man.
How do you know if you ain't never even tried it, man?
Come on.
Hey!
And by the way, did Paul
Dominique get his job back?
Holy shit!
I'm not doing it!
- Come on, man.
- I'm not doing it!
Come on, man.
It's all right.
- Come on, man.
It's not happening!
It's all right.
Come on.
It's not happening!
It... it's OK between friends.
Come on.
No means no!
It... it's OK between friends.
Hey, man, take it easy.
No means no!
Hey, man, take it easy, man.
Ahh, fuck.
I would have let you.
I'm bleeding.
- I would have let you.
Petey?
What happened?
Lovers quarrel?
I tried to do the right thing.
Hey, Petey.
You know what?
Do you know what I think?
If men knew more
about getting fucked,
maybe they would be better at fucking.
If men knew more about getting fucked,
maybe they would be
better at fucking.
What?
You want to fuck me?
Go ahead.
Be my guest.
Hey, we didn't come here for your ass, OK?
Hey, we didn't come
here for your ass, OK?
Yeah?
Hey, we didn't come here for your ass, OK?
So what do you want then?
Yeah?
I want news.
I want news of your pimp hairdresser.
I want news of your
pimp hairdresser.
Paul is not my pimp.
He get his car back?
You talk to your friend, the... the... the...
the manicurist? He get his car back?
You talk to your friend, the...
the... the... the manicurist?
Dominique, yeah.
So... so how's he doing, eh?
Eh?
Paul Dominique, eh?
Is he happy?
About what?
About getting his car back.
He sold it.
He so... he sold it?
Mhm.
To... to who?
To some car salesman,
some guy. To... to who?
To some car
salesman, some guy.
I don't know.
To some car salesman, some guy.
Some of those people
driving around that deathtrap.
OK, what do we do now?
Jesus.
I got it up.
Yeah, I know, man.
What a monster.
Good for you.
Oh.
Take it easy, man.
I'm getting seasick.
- Take it easy, man.
Don't get so excited.
Take your time, man, negotiate.
Oh.
Nice going, man.
Great performance.
- Nice going, man.
Three and a half minutes, man.
Jesus, want to try?
You got there so fast she never
- Jesus, want to try?
You got there
so fast she never
left the starting gate, man?
You got there so fast she never
Mhm.
Left the starting gate, man?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Mhm.
Come on.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Watch and learn, young man.
Come on.
You have to admire...
Watch and learn, young man.
Sorry.
You have to admire...
...the professionalism, man.
Sorry.
The flexibility, man.
...the professionalism, man.
It's all about finessing.
The flexibility, man.
Nice and easy, man, does it, man.
It's all about finessing.
Nice and easy,
man, does it, man.
We have the whole night ahead of us, right, Marie?
Nice and easy, man, does it, man.
We have the whole night
ahead of us, right, Marie?
Oh!
Yeah!
Woo!
Ah!
Yeah!
Woo!
Ah!
Yeah.
Am I hurting you?
No.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Well, usually,
I hear like a sort of whimper Yeah.
Well, usually, I hear
like a sort of whimper
in the back of the throat.
No, I'm fine.
You realize you're in the hands of a stud, eh?
You realize you're in
the hands of a stud, eh?
, Eh?
You realize you're in the hands of a stud, eh?
Yeah.
, Eh?
You OK?
Yeah.
I'm fine.
You sure?
Are you always like this, Marie?
Like what?
I don't know.
She ain't into your bullshit.
She likes me better.
Right, Marie?
Ain't no pleasure for the Jesus not to give pleasure.
Ain't no pleasure for the
Jesus not to give pleasure.
College shit, man.
Ain't no pleasure for the Jesus not to give pleasure.
I'm into serious bowling, eh?
I'm sorry, Marie, but don't you ever get off?
I'm sorry, Marie, but
don't you ever get off?
Oh, I don't know.
I don't mind.
What do you mean?
You never came, never?
No.
That's deep.
Well, maybe I wasn't made right.
Well, maybe I
wasn't made right.
How are the other girls?
Well, maybe I wasn't made right.
What do they do?
How are the other girls?
They're alive.
What do they do?
You know, they... they...
they enjoy themselves. They're alive.
they enjoy themselves.
They moan, and they thank you with their eyes.
You know, they... they... they enjoy themselves.
They moan, and they
thank you with their eyes.
Their eyes... their eyes roll back in their heads.
They moan, and they thank you with their eyes.
Their eyes... their eyes
roll back in their heads.
You could see the whites. Their eyes...
their eyes roll back in their heads.
You could see the whites.
Maybe you could teach me.
Want to try?
Yeah, man.
Be my guest, man.
I got... I got to recover a little bit, eh?
I got... I got to recover
a little bit, eh?
Don't feel like you
have to say anything.
Silence doesn't bother me.
Don't feel like you have to say anything.
I'm a loner.
Silence doesn't bother me.
And I plan to stay that way.
I'm a loner.
No kids, no man.
And I plan to stay that way.
I don't cheat on anyone.
No kids, no man.
I sleep with everybody.
I don't cheat on anyone.
That way, no one is jealous.
I sleep with everybody.
But not in my place.
I fuck on the outside.
And I remember, not like the bitches who pretend not to.
And I remember, not like the
bitches who pretend not to.
You remember all those faces,
drooling, groping, filthy words
they whisper in your ear.
Why always the left ear?
Strange.
Oops, all
those kind of things.
374 guys I had, you know, inside me.
Oops, all those kind of things.
374 guys I had, you
know, inside me.
Oh, don't give me that look.
It don't even add up to one a week.
It don't even add
up to one a week.
Did you count us in the total?
It don't even add up to one a week.
Of course not.
Did you count us in the total?
Wow!
Of course not.
So you didn't
remember we balled.
Well, I don't call that balling.
So you didn't remember we balled.
Well, I don't
call that balling.
What do you call it?
Well, I don't call that balling.
Well, making love a little.
What do you call it?
And we succeeded?
Well, making love a little.
Well, I'm sorry, no.
But you tried, A for effort.
Oh, shit.
OK, guys, when I whistle,
the coast is clear.
We're busted, flat broke,
and she comes up with this.
Unbelievable.
She's a genius.
Masterpiece.
Do you remember the fun we
had, eh, at the sex parties?
Come on, boy.
Get it. Come on, boy.
Get it.
Come on, boy. Get it.
That motherfucker.
Look out for the shit, bitch.
Look out for
the shit, bitch.
Hey, kiss me.
Where is the register, eh?
Eh?
Hey, kiss me.
You hear me?
I want you to kiss me.
Not now.
You promised
you'd kiss me.
And right now.
I want to know what the fuck I'm missing.
I want to know what
the fuck I'm missing.
Where's the alarm, man?
Hey, I'm in the mood now.
- Where's the alarm, man?
Hey, this is the perfect place.
Is that... is that an alarm?
So fucking kiss me.
It could be a booby trap.
Is the alarm still on?
But how long is it
going to take us, eh?
It's going to take...
But how long is it going to take us, eh?
Is that an alarm?
It's going to take...
I'm going to give you a fucking alarm?
- Is that an alarm?
I'm going to give
you a fucking alarm?
I'm not just a sex machine.
I'm fed up with a guy who
thinks my ass is a bowling lane.
I want to feel something here.
You promised you'd kiss me, fuckheads.
You promised you'd
kiss me, fuckheads.
Oh!
What the fuck, eh?
I didn't do anything.
You'd be better off.
Paul is going to find me.
- You'd be better off.
We still love you.
Paul is going to find me.
I could go to jail.
- We still love you.
I'm an accomplice.
Tell him
we kidnapped you.
I won't be a problem.
Tell him we kidnapped you.
Jesus! Petey!
We got to pull a Houdini.
Hit the mattresses.
Woo!
Woo! Done.
Mmm, that's right.
I'm going to hold you
like a bowling ball.
You couldn't even take
off your tag, asshole.
Hey!
You couldn't even take off your tag, asshole.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
I'm not that easy.
Fucking.
He thought
he could get over.
You.
It was a power move, man.
Old school.
We could have scored.
I could have scored.
No more shampoo girls, man.
I liked Marie because
she was good people.
You know what
you need, my friend?
A night with a real woman, a tiger.
You know what you need, my friend?
A night with a real
woman, a tiger.
OK, I'm all for that.
A night with a real woman, a tiger.
A fighter.
OK, I'm all for that.
You don't know which is end is up, man.
A fighter.
You don't know which
is end is up, man.
You think it's over.
You don't know which is end is up, man.
And she swoops in on that.
You think it's over.
Woo!
Hold my ball, bro.
Hey, where we going?
My reservoir, private grounds,
300 women. Hey, where we going?
My reservoir, private
grounds, 300 women.
You barely touch them, and they are slow dying for it.
My reservoir, private grounds, 300 women.
You barely touch them, and
they are slow dying for it.
Get the picture?
300 women?
A loser.
I think she's beautiful,
unbelievably beautiful. A loser.
unbelievably beautiful.
Go get the car.
Vamos.
Don't be afraid.
Listen, you can't stay here all alone.
Listen, you can't
stay here all alone.
Where are you going?
Listen, you can't stay here all alone.
I don't know.
You got any money?
Someone to call?
No.
You got any clothes in that bag?
You got any
clothes in that bag?
No.
And you got no cash, no
clothes, nowhere to go.
What do you have to offer?
And you got no cash, no clothes, nowhere to go.
Everything.
What do you have to offer?
We're at your service?
Everything.
Jesus Quintana with
a car and cash.
Trouble?
Jesus Quintana with a car and cash.
Everything all right?
Trouble?
Yeah, man, we just got a little engine trouble.
Everything all right?
Yeah, man, we just got
a little engine trouble.
You can put your car. Yeah, man,
we just got a little engine trouble.
You can put your car.
Where is it?
You know, it's at...
at the garage, yeah.
Thank you very much. You know,
it's at... at the garage, yeah.
Thank you very much.
Yeah, but... but the lady, what's...
Yeah, but... but
the lady, what's...
Hit the road, sucker, before I put it in your ass.
Yeah, but... but the lady, what's...
Hit the road, sucker,
before I put it in your ass.
Shit, when you need them,
the bastards never stop, eh?
Here, take it.
Take it.
Go ahead.
And come with us.
Is that heavy?
Shit yeah.
What the fuck?
Hey, watch it, man.
Well, she is just carrying a piece, man.
Well, she is just
carrying a piece, man.
No, asshole.
Well, she is just carrying a piece, man.
That's our piece.
No, asshole.
I gave it to her so
she can trust us.
But now... now she does, right?
I'm OK.
Are you out of your mind?
I got involved in a totally fucked up scene here.
I got involved in a totally
fucked up scene here.
Hey, now fuck you. Be polite.
I got involved in a totally fucked up scene here.
Hey, now fuck you.
Be polite.
There's a lady in the car.
Hey, now fuck you. Be polite.
Everything is fucked up.
There's a lady in the car.
What's your name, hmm?
767.
OK, 767, what you
feel like doing, eh?
Nothing. OK, 767,
what you feel like doing, eh?
Nothing.
We can't keep driving
around like this.
That's not my problem.
We can't keep driving around like this.
I didn't ask you for anything.
That's not my problem.
Don't ask me to make decisions for you.
I didn't ask you for anything.
Don't ask me to make
decisions for you.
Comfy?
My feet hurt.
OK.
We'll get you some new kicks and some fresh gear.
We'll get you some new
kicks and some fresh gear.
Here.
Thanks.
I'll go in alone.
You won't
need to go, man.
The alarm might go off.
You won't need to go, man.
I'm keeping the gun.
The alarm might go off.
I don't like this broad.
She's giving me the creeps.
I don't trust her.
Hey, no one's keeping you, man.
Hey, no one's
keeping you, man.
How much you want, hm?
Hey, no one's keeping you, man.
Come on, man.
How much you want, hm?
Off to an orgy.
You think they get jealous?
No.
She's all yours.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Thanks.
Good.
Slowly.
Why?
You should eat slowly.
Right.
Thanks.
Would you care for
anything else, ma'am?
Oh, no, I'm good.
Would you care for anything else, ma'am?
Kind of slow this time
of year, I guess, eh?
Yes.
But we always have people
passing through, you know,
the restaurant's reputation.
But we always have people passing through, you know,
Oh.
The restaurant's reputation.
What?
You're like in a
guidebook or something?
No, no, actually we prefer not to do that.
You're like in a guidebook or something?
No, no, actually we
prefer not to do that.
Really? No, no,
actually we prefer not to do that.
Really?
No.
- Really?
Why?
No.
Well, the crowds there, they're dreadful.
- Why?
Well, the crowds
there, they're dreadful.
There are just... things
can get out of hand.
And then where would we be with just three stars?
There are just... things can get out of hand.
And then where would we
be with just three stars?
I have no idea.
And then where would we be with just three stars?
I can't.
You can't keep your
eye on everyone.
No.
You can't keep your eye on everyone.
You couldn't keep
your eye on everyone.
How about, um, after
dinner drinks on the house?
Enjoy.
She thought we were going
to leave without paying.
Thank you.
For what?
For everything.
For the... the meal.
I, um, I can only
thank you in the bed.
You can turn the
lights out if you want.
I'm not saying that you
have to turn them out.
But if you want to, it doesn't really matter.
I'm not saying that you have to turn them out.
But if you want to, it
doesn't really matter.
It's been such a long time.
I don't know if I remember how.
You might have to each me.
I mean, you know how they
do it nowadays, you know?
Everything. I mean,
you know how they do it nowadays, you know?
Everything.
We can do everything.
All right?
Madame, that was excellent.
Thank you so much.
Oh, it's my pleasure.
Really, that was such a treat.
I just got out of prison.
So it was very special for me.
And, you know, it's been years.
I've been in a wet, dark cell, no sky.
I've been in a wet,
dark cell, no sky.
And I... that's why my period stopped,
I've been in a wet, dark cell, no sky.
And I... that's why
my period stopped,
I think, because of the darkness.
And I... that's why my period stopped,
I think, because
of the darkness.
You know, first it was a week late,
then two weeks late. I think, because of the darkness.
You know, first it was a week
late, then two weeks late.
Pretty soon, you just forget about it. You know,
first it was a week late, then two weeks late.
Pretty soon, you
just forget about it.
I... I... Pretty soon,
you just forget about it.
I... I...
it's not my fault.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
It's not my fault.
I just... I want you to appreciate the bleeding.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
I just... I want you to
appreciate the bleeding.
I know that makes you cranky, and, you know,
I just... I want you to appreciate the bleeding.
I know that makes you
cranky, and, you know,
you feel bloated, the pain and everything.
I know that makes you cranky, and, you know,
you feel bloated, the
pain and everything.
But that's not what matters.
What matters is the bleeding.
Why are you telling me this?
So you'll be aware.
And you tell your friends.
Because we don't talk about these things enough.
Because we don't talk
about these things enough.
No, we don't.
Because we don't talk about these things enough.
We don't talk about it.
No, we don't.
Do you have a mint?
Yes, like, right... yeah.
Here you go.
You're welcome.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
My name is Jean.
What's yours?
Peter.
Well, there's not going to be
much left of you when I'm done,
Peter.
Well, there's not going to be much left of you when I'm done,
It's now time off with 767.
I have my period.
Everything OK?
No.
No, really.
It's over.
It will be all right, hmm.
Jean Bersome, 767.
She couldn't hack being free.
- Jean Bersome, 767.
She couldn't
hack being free.
Shit.
What?
She's got a kid, man,
in prison. What?
She's got a kid,
man, in prison.
Boy or a girl?
It's signed Jack.
They're all... they're all Jack, man.
They're all... they're
all Jack, man.
How... how old is he?
Just a kid.
If you need anything,
you know where to find me.
That's him. If you need anything,
That's him.
Jack Bersome?
- That's him.
That's me.
Jack Bersome?
Your mother sent us.
That's me.
767.
Well, why didn't she come herself
- 767.
Well, why didn't
she come herself
if she got out two months ago?
Well, why didn't she come herself
Yeah, but she... you know, she went abroad.
If she got out two months ago?
Yeah, but she... you
know, she went abroad.
Where? Yeah, but she...
you know, she went abroad.
Where?
Portugal.
Where's Portugal?
I mean, I haven't heard from her in two months.
I mean, I haven't heard
from her in two months.
She couldn't write? I mean,
I haven't heard from her in two months.
She couldn't write?
What the fuck is she doing in Portugal?
What the fuck is she
doing in Portugal?
She split with a good friend of ours, terrific guy.
What the fuck is she doing in Portugal?
She split with a good
friend of ours, terrific guy.
He's an engineer.
Agricultural.
She said go and get Jack and take care of him.
She said go and get
Jack and take care of him.
And she's very happy.
She'll be back soon.
Who's this agricultural guy?
Don't worry about it.
He's a good guy.
If he's so good, why isn't he here?
If he's so good,
why isn't he here?
He's got a record.
How many busts?
One served, two suspended.
One served,
two suspended.
Not bad. One served,
Not bad.
Is that your car, Plymouth Fury?
Third generation.
The Swedish police used to use that.
The Swedish police
used to use that.
And they never die.
Check it out, man.
This shit's vintage, man.
This is Marie.
She's our girl.
And now I'm yours too.
The only hitch is I can't come.
Coffee?
Sure, just a drop.
You're not hungry?
Yes.
Want some jam?
I don't know.
We share everything.
Hmm?
Go ahead.
We want you to.
It's our pleasure, man.
Your mom was...
she's something special.
Jack.
She's something special.
She's really great.
Come in.
Thanks to us, a good
deal is cooking, hmm?
Yeah. Thanks to us,
a good deal is cooking, hmm?
Yeah.
We're not always doing the wrong thing.
- Yeah.
We're not always
doing the wrong thing.
I'm proud of us.
We're not always doing the wrong thing.
Every about that chick.
I'm proud of us.
Every
about that chick.
And no one's ever courted her.
Every about that chick.
I mean, really, wooed her.
That's what she needs.
She wasn't made right.
She said it herself.
It's like she's missing a...
a chromosome or something.
Her little chest gets me.
A chromosome or something.
You can almost see the heartbeat.
Her little chest gets me.
You can almost
see the heartbeat.
She's like a little reindeer.
You can almost see the heartbeat.
Yeah, but it's a
point of honor, man,
because we went through the matter deep.
Yeah, but it's a point of honor, man,
because we went through
the matter deep.
Yeah, but it's not
always about the johnson
or the coochie, right?
Yeah, but it's not always about the johnson
What do you mean?
It's the brain telling the body to let go, eh?
It's the brain telling
the body to let go, eh?
It's perplexing shit.
It's the brain telling the body to let go, eh?
What was that?
Shit, man.
What is that?
What man?
She's digging it.
We're not involved at all.
Petey, Jesus, it happened!
It happened!
I came.
I came!
Suddenly, everything turned purple,
my hair, my fingernails I came!
Suddenly, everything turned
purple, my hair, my fingernails
were on fire. Suddenly, everything turned purple,
my hair, my fingernails
were on fire.
I felt like I was going to exploding.
Were on fire.
I felt like I was
going to exploding.
Go!
I felt like I was going to exploding.
Oh!
Go!
That ought to cool you off.
But I did it.
I got my Christmas
present finally.
But I think of how we knocked ourselves
I got my Christmas present finally.
But I think of
how we knocked ourselves
out over your hang up.
But I think of how we knocked ourselves
Fully, night and day.
Out over your hang up.
I mean, what does he got that we don't got?
- Fully, night and day.
I mean, what does
he got that we don't got?
What?
One that vibrates?
I mean, we put... we
put our hearts into it, man.
This man's a harder fucker, man, a samurai.
I mean, we put... we put our hearts into it, man.
This man's a harder
fucker, man, a samurai.
Ahh! This man's a harder fucker, man,
a samurai.
Ahh!
Yeah!
What did he do to you?
Things.
- What did he do to you?
Well, what
kind of things?
Nothing special.
Well, what kind of things?
Anyway, I was the one
who did everything.
You?
You don't do anything.
- You?
Well, yeah.
You don't do anything.
He did not have the balls to touch me.
Well, yeah.
He did not have the
balls to touch me.
So I had to do all the work.
And all of a sudden, he busted a nut.
And all of a sudden,
he busted a nut.
And that's what made you come?
And all of a sudden, he busted a nut.
No.
And that's what made you come?
I had him close,
try if you feel like it. No.
I had him close, try
if you feel like it.
So he did, making love to me.
And he pops again.
Two pump chump?
Lucky you.
I asked him if he's a virgin.
He says, yes and starts making love to me again, slowly.
He says, yes and starts making
love to me again, slowly.
Kissing me. He says,
yes and starts making love to me again, slowly.
Kissing me.
Kiss me.
Then this time.
Kissing me.
No, OK, we got it, OK?
No.
But this time...
Marie!
Oh, I got to go.
- Marie!
He needs me.
Marie!
Oh, Jack, yes!
Woo!
It's too much.
- Woo!
Yeah, they're from
another generation.
No respect.
Yeah, they're from another generation.
Want some?
Wouldn't want to be any trouble.
Wouldn't want
to be any trouble.
Maybe a little scrap would be all right.
Wouldn't want to be any trouble.
Maybe a little scrap
would be all right.
There's no dessert because our cash just ran out.
Maybe a little scrap would be all right.
There's no dessert because
our cash just ran out.
Oh, well, that's a bitch.
We'll have to score.
Can't go on like this.
You got a gun?
Who said?
It's $100,000.
It's a cinch.
- It's $100,000.
No risk, you know,
just some old folks.
We prefer to make our own decisions No risk,
you know, just some old folks.
We prefer to make
our own decisions
when it comes to risks.
Yeah, well, you interested?
When it comes to risks.
Yeah, well,
you interested?
I mean, I could do it alone.
I just... I do need a gun.
It's a... it's a work tool.
Well?
I don't give a damn.
You decide.
Fine.
Here you go.
Good luck.
Thank you.
I told you they'd cop out.
Hey, who said anything about copping out?
Hey, who said anything
about copping out?
Hey, man.
Hey, what the fuck's going on?
You know this guy?
Yeah.
Hey.
Look who it is.
Son of a gun.
Yeah. Remember me?
Yeah.
Remember me?
What a surprise.
Yeah. Remember me?
How you doing?
Yeah.
What are you up to?
Same game as before.
Oh, yeah?
What's that?
Jack?
You fucking shot me.
Where's Jack!
He's just standing
there like a statue.
Get in.
He's just standing there like a statue.
He's got the gun.
Get in.
Man, don't cry.
I'm not crying.
- Man, don't cry.
Emotions are for assholes.
Hey, didn't you love him?
I don't know.
- Hey, didn't you love him?
I didn't have time.
I don't know.
He got the job done, OK?
I didn't have time.
But you have to be a dumbass to shoot a cop He got the job done, OK?
But you have to be a
dumbass to shoot a cop
when we could have gone like that.
But you have to be a dumbass to shoot a cop
when we could have
gone like that.
He wasn't a cop.
When we could have gone like that.
He was a prison guard.
He wasn't a cop.
The poor guy had nothing.
He never smiled.
Yes, no, thanks, again, stand up,
sit down, lie down. He never smiled.
Yes, no, thanks, again,
stand up, sit down, lie down.
Just like a fucking gym teacher.
Yes, no, thanks, again, stand up, sit down, lie down.
Maybe he didn't
notice he was free.
Come
under a maple tree with me.
You see I've lost my puppy.
He's oh so small and helpless.
But I must confess.
He seemed like a
nice kind of daddy.
Can you share your money?
He seemed like a nice kind of daddy.
You want me to hold it for you?
Can you share your money?
You want me to
hold it for you?
That's indecent exposure, man.
I know about that shit.
Yeah, man, life is a bitch.
But, still, you have to look on the bright side.
But, still, you have to
look on the bright side.
We got our lady back, eh?
You asleep?
No.
Hey.
You know,
why don't you get up and take a look around? Hey.
You know, why don't you get
up and take a look around?
There's a whole galaxy out here. You know,
why don't you get up and take a look around?
There's a whole galaxy out here.
Mhm.
The Big Dipper right in front of our face.
The Big Dipper right
in front of our face.
Mexico, M-E-X-I-C-O.
Oh, make love
to me, sweet Pete.
Oh, oh, oh. Oh, make love to me,
sweet Pete.
Oh, oh, oh.
Oh, I'm going to be all right.
Oh!
Hey!
Oh, that's so good.
Oh, my god.
Yeah!
Jesus, hurry up.
I'm coming.
Oh!
Oh.
Huh?
Heart-shaped
sunglasses and lips
You have to go.
What's wrong?
You can hitchhike
from here, man.
What did I do?
Nothing.
We are accomplices to
an attempted murder.
It's in the papers.
You're not.
You didn't hurt anyone.
But I'm... I'm in deep with you guys.
But I'm... I'm in
deep with you guys.
No way, man. But I'm...
I'm in deep with you guys.
No way, man.
You have to go.
When I just started coming,
I'm feeling like this.
No fucking way.
Hey!
Don't be crazy, woman.
I can't see you in a cell
with a number on your back.
Stretch your wings and fly, girl.
I can't see you in a cell with a number on your back.
Stretch your wings
and fly, girl.
Listen to my feminine instinct.
Stretch your wings and fly, girl.
Listen to my
feminine instinct.
Sometimes I have vision.
Listen to my feminine instinct.
I'm never wrong.
Sometimes I have vision.
We're not going to jail.
I'm never wrong.
So shut up and make love to me.
I don't know who
chose this car,
but it's worse
than a prison cell.
Ah, it's good for
the environment.
Fuck the environment.
Ah, it's good for the environment.
Man, I can't breathe.
Fuck the environment.
I got to get out of here.
Man, I can't breathe.
Oh, he can't breathe, man.
I got to get out of here.
What about the other people too.
Oh, he can't breathe, man.
There's other people in the car.
It's not just you.
I know, but I...
You know it's always about him, right, Marie?
You know it's always
about him, right, Marie?
I'm getting really squished here.
You know it's always about him, right, Marie?
I'm getting really
squished here.
Yeah, always about him.
I'm getting really squished here.
Always about him, shit, man.
Yeah, always about him.
It's unbelievable, man.
I told you not.
A family picnic and shit.
Ah, no, no, no.
What... what are you doing?
I just have to pee.
Oh, I've got to pee pee.
- I just have to pee.
Eww.
Oh, I've got to pee pee.
Yeah, mira!
Eww.
Holy shit.
Oh, man.
- Holy shit.
What's up, man?
Hi.
Another bank robber special.
Another bank
robber special.
What's happening?
Another bank robber special.
My Uncle Ronaldo had a 1968 red and white top convertible.
What's happening?
My Uncle Ronaldo had a 1968
red and white top convertible.
Nice.
That's a great deal, our
smart car for a muscle car.
Yes! That's a great deal,
our smart car for a muscle car.
Yes!
Yeah, that's it, man.
She's fucking cute, right?
She's
fucking cute, right?
Starsky and Hutch!
- She's fucking cute, right?
Dad, they're
taking the car.
Do something.
- Dad, they're taking the car.
Honey?
My fucking car!
It's a fucking classic.
- My fucking car!
Dad, do something!
It's a fucking classic.
It's our car!
- Dad, do something!
Hey, come back here!
It's our car!
Dad!
Hey, come back here!
You guys did good.
You should be proud, eh?
You've got a real good solid
foundation now, Marie, OK?
Where are we going?
I don't know.
What are they going to do to us,
put a hole in our ass? I don't know.
What are they going to do to
us, put a hole in our ass?
You already got one, man.
Yeah.
What do we do,
just drive around till we run out of gas? Yeah.
What do we do, just drive
around till we run out of gas?
Why not? What do we do,
just drive around till we run out of gas?
Why not?
You're happy?
Yeah.
I am.
We're good together, no?
Yeah.
Thanks, man, peaceful,
on the road, hanging loose.
Oh!
Go on, man.
Come on, bitch. Shake it.
Woo!
Shake it, baby.
- Woo!
All right, come on, shake it.
Shake it, baby.
Ho!
Ahhh!
Ahh!
What's that?
Shit.
The brakes are jammed.
Oh, filthy hairdresser.
I thought this
car looked familiar.
Why didn't
you say anything?
Yeah, it was orange, I remember.
Why didn't you say anything?
Yeah, it was
orange, I remember.
Oh, my poor little balls.
- Yeah, it was orange, I remember.
- It was your idea.
- Oh, my poor little balls.
It was your idea.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
In the rising
sun, we'll drive away.
We'll drive away, hey, hey, to the horizon.
In the rising sun, we'll drive away.
We'll drive away, hey,
hey, to the horizon.
We'll find a way.
We'll drive away, hey, hey, to the horizon.
We'll find a way home.
Always now.
Like a shooting star, we're
fast, alone,
and already gone.
Like a shooting star, we're fast, alone,
Like a number one we'll find a way.
And already gone.
Like a number one
we'll find a way.
We'll find a way home.
Always now.
It's always now.