Girl, you are so lucky.
I know, right?
- I feel so, so lucky, like...
- Aw.
Oh, my goodness.
It's shiny and all bling-bling and--
Oh, talk of the devil.
No, talk of the angel.
Oh, okay. Angel.
Sorry, baby, it's Nana.
- Hey!
- Hi.
Hi!
I know, right?
Is that the way my voice sounds?
Okay, okay.
Okay.
Please leave.
Hello? Um, yeah.
- When are we getting married?
- Hello to you.
Look, I don't even have time
for all of this, Kwame.
I asked you a simple question,
so please answer me.
- When are we getting married?
- What do you mean?
I remember correctly
that I proposed to you.
Oh, fantastic. Fantastic!
Now let me ask you a question.
When did you propose?
No, don't answer that question.
2008, right?
What year are we in? 2018. Come on!
Kwame, you don't have the fear of God.
So please, I ask you again,
when are we getting married?
Is this about your friend getting married?
Look, when you get back to Ghana,
we will discuss it.
Give me 12 months and we will get married.
Same old story. The same old story!
You've turned me
into the Lord of the Rings.
And you keep giving me the same old story.
Let me tell you something, mister.
If you do not do the needful,
I will walk away.
You'll be shocked
at my decision. I will walk away. Try me!
Bring back my towel!
I will kill somebody when I get there!
Look at me.
You three shouldn't have been born.
Are you laughing at me?
Hey, be careful. Be careful!
Guy, take your towel.
Thank you!
God bless you!
But I told you before.
If you want to bathe,
put your towel on the inside.
If I get hold of any of you,
I will deal with you mercilessly.
Indomie!
- Me, Indomie?
- Big head!
You people are nothing
but circumstances and consequences.
I'm sure you don't know anything
about the grammar you're speaking.
Hey, leave it. I will kill you today.
Stop running! Hold on!
Where are you running?
Hold on. Come here.
This guy. Are you normal? What's wrong?
Why are you running?
What's wrong with you?
You, too. Why are you running?
Are you mad? Please go away!
Why he's running
is what I don't understand.
I'm chasing small children.
I'm running after them.
You started running with me.
Everybody followed me, too.
- How does my running concern you?
- Allow me to run.
This idiot is chasing after kids
on the street.
- Hey, bobo, don't talk too much.
- Are you okay?
- Hey! Don't talk too much.
- Okay.
Those kids must not escape. Move!
- Today has to be good.
- It has to be.
Fortune will smile on us.
A miracle will happen soon.
Come here.
Come back here.
- Where are you going?
- I'm off to see a friend.
Honestly, you look like a lunatic.
Kneel down there.
He's talking and you are standing.
Kneel down!
Do you realize you're being weird?
See how you're dressed like a girl?
Tell me, do you want to mislead young boys
out there with your behavior?
You want them to behave like you?
Believe me, you're cursed.
Sir, are you cursing her?
Your life isn't ruined.
- Rather, big things will befall you.
- Are you praying for her?
- Yes, of course.
- Okay, go on.
A big vehicle will crush you to death
for misleading boys
with your weird lifestyle.
You don't know.
I beg you, in God's name, tell me
what made you adopt this lifestyle?
We both grew up in this neighborhood,
until you suddenly changed.
Why did you change suddenly?
What happened to you?
What happened exactly?
Guys,
there's something I don't understand.
I don't know where to start.
Do I address you as a he or a she?
Bobo, what do you call yourself?
What's the meaning of all this?
We need to stop this weird behavior today.
We need to let him know
she's doing the wrong thing.
We have to stop you today.
Today we'll tie you here.
- Ah, no! Forget it.
- We will tie you here!
- Who's this? What happened? Who are you?
- It's me, Isla.
- Stop this.
- Is your face on the 1,000-naira bill?
What do you mean "It's Isla"?
We need to deal with him!
- Sit down, sir.
- Don't come here and misbehave.
Don't say that, please. Forget about it.
- Once he grows up, he becomes your child.
- Isla.
Isla, I don't like this at all.
Isla, this isn't how things are done.
Isla, don't overstep.
- Please be lenient.
- You're getting out of hand.
Please don't be angry. He's one of us.
You're stupid. I will deal with you later.
- Isla, this is unacceptable.
- Please.
- Stand up.
- You just came to ruin things for us.
- So you want him to leave?
- No, you know what?
I promise you guys that, after today,
Bobo will not dress like a girl again.
Am I lying?
Now tell me, how will you dress?
- Like a man.
- The idiot says "like a man."
Like a man.
Isla, this is unacceptable.
- Let's go.
- Go where?
- What's wrong?
- Things aren't done that way.
- We came here to make money.
- He'll give you money.
- Let him give us money.
- Don't come with that.
We can't take money from this freak.
He shouldn't give us any money.
Let her go, please. I said let him go.
- Hey, Isla.
- We don't want it!
Isla, we don't need his money.
Go away with your problems.
Go away. We don't want your money!
We're not taking his money.
Both of you
should leave this place right now!
Isla, you're misbehaving.
We need to teach Isla a lesson or two.
Watch how well I can mimic that guy.
Ask me where I'm going.
- Where are you going?
- To see my friend.
Take a look at that!
I can do it, too.
- Now ask me.
- Where are you going?
I'm going to see my friend.
I'm adverse to losing.
My enemy will lose instead.
So this is where you are?
Eh! You're here!
- This is where you are!
- What's that?
- I've been looking for you!
- Madam, stop!
- I said stop! What's the problem?
- Isla!
It's none of your business.
What's wrong with this one?
- I pity you!
- You and who?
- I'm touching you again.
- Ah!
- Did you tell her who I am?
- I did.
- Madam, see.
- Don't interfere!
- Ah!
- Me and you.
- See her now!
- That's what I'm saying.
- Tell her again.
- It's none of your business.
What do you mean?
I touched you. What are you gonna do?
Please, I beg you in the name of God.
Anybody that tries to separate us
when we're fighting will be unfortunate.
- Where are your people? I pity you!
- I want to kill somebody.
I want to fight you. Yes, I touched you.
- Did you just touch me?
- I touched you. I want to fight you!
- You're touching me?
- Yes! I touched you!
That's it! I told you.
- Talk now!
- She's never lost a fight.
Talk now! I'm not hearing you!
- Talk!
- Please.
♪ Arise, O compatriots ♪
♪ Nigeria's call obey ♪
♪ To serve our father-- ♪
- My friend, answer me. I said talk.
- The slap has changed her.
Auntie, I did not--
It's not like I'm fighting you.
We're friends. We're one family.
Next time, don't interfere
with a married couple's affairs.
- I didn't interfere.
- Don't interfere. This is our business.
- I know.
- Do you hear me? Don't ever do it again.
Next time...
- I'll finish you.
- I'm not--
- I just started today.
- I'm sorry, ma.
- She gets it.
- Go home. Now go home quickly.
I said to the house.
Go!
I'm already going home.
Monkey. Go away! Nonsense.
Dayo, it's okay.
I've told you to stop thanking me.
Ah, let me thank you.
You people should stop!
Isn't that Chioma?
She's the one. It's Chioma.
You people should stop! Stop!
Stop! Let's go!
Stop that car! I said stop that car!
Don't move an inch! Stop!
- Let me go down and beat her!
- Dayo.
- Chioma is tough.
- Dayo, listen to me.
- Get out of the car!
- Get out!
- Let me talk to her.
- Okay. All right.
Get out! Get out!
We don't understand English!
- I don't listen to trash.
- Calm down.
- Chioma--
- Mike, I beg you.
Please stop!
Don't talk to me!
Tell that man to get out. That's all!
What is it?
- Who died?
- Sir, I don't have time for too much talk.
I need to see the idiot
that is inside that car with my man.
I need to see her, disfigure her, disgrace
her and show her I'm a real Igbo girl.
Is she crazy? Why would my man
carry another girl inside this car?
I'm telling him to open the door.
He has refused.
Don't come near me. I'm mad!
Open this door!
Okay.
I'm going to strip naked right here!
- Okay!
- Let him open the door!
- Okay.
- Let us see the girl!
- You want me to take my clothes off?
- No.
Okay, he will open the door.
He will open the door.
Quickly!
- Open it! Open the door!
- I want to see the girl inside.
I want to see who my man
has been sleeping with.
I want to see her!
The girl will die today! Open the door!
Chioma, wait.
It's okay.
- Did you see anybody there?
- Dayo!
- No! It's my turn!
- Dayo.
- Did you see anybody there? Chioma.
- It's okay.
- Stop playing the victim!
- All of you are mad!
What if you dropped her off somewhere?
Dayo!
Dayo, you can't do anything!
Brother Dayo,
we speak the same language. Let's talk.
Dayo, if you kill people--
- Get in!
- Don't test me!
- Beg him!
- Beg him for what? Forget about it!
You don't know
if he dropped the girl off already.
- Do you think you can outsmart me?
- Who's talking about being smart?
- You're trying to--
- We're talking about fairness!
I bought a business.
I want to take 60 %, you 40 %.
What is not fair about it?
- Emeka?
- Obanikoro!
Do you know your problem?
Let me hear you!
Self-centeredness.
And your own is greed!
- Obanikoro, you're too greedy!
- I see.
Be contented with 40!
How do you mean I should be contented?
- After all the things I've done for you!
- What did you do for me?
I brought you to Lagos.
- You brought who?
- You!
Stop lying! I knew the way to Lagos.
I came on my own.
You, a bush boy?
You came to Lagos by yourself?
- You're calling me a bush boy?
- You are a bush boy!
- How do I look? How do you look?
- I'll show you what I'm made of!
- I'm a smart fellow!
- Oh, that's good.
- Trim!
- I will never take that!
- Edible! Eh?
- Okay.
He who lives by the sword
will die by the sword.
- Back to sender.
- See, eh?
- Stop your greed and grow.
- Look, look.
- I'm growing.
- Okay.
Look at the beautiful office
I have here.
I'm growing. Everyone is.
I am growing.
You are not growing because of your greed!
- Have you been to my office recently?
- Which office?
- Where goats are slaughtered?
- You're a fool! A big one!
What is going on here?
Good. Thank goodness your son is here.
Now tell me, do you still want
to display your stupidity?
I'm going to call your own son
and tell him how stupid you are.
You've been idiotic
since your secondary school days.
Let me call your son.
- Please, sir.
- You are done for!
Both of you need to take it easy.
Take what easy?
Take what easy? This man is greedy.
How could I have bought a business
wanting to take 60 %, him 40?
He's insisting on 50-50! Is it done?
I won't stay here
and listen to this rubbish of yours.
He who lives by the sword
will die by the sword.
I'll cut you from the left and right side.
I'll cut your private parts
into several pieces.
- Yellow monkey! Leave me alone!
- So you are running.
- Please...
- Please what?
Oh, you're going?
You see? It's like they say--
"When the fowl messes up,
the land pursues the fowl."
- Do you know, this matches the box...
- You know the fowl?
...you'll use to take your stuff
back to your village.
- Each time the fowl farts.
- I'll force you to walk on your head.
Eat shit
and fill your mouth with it, then vomit.
- Leave me.
- Let him go. Greedy man!
- Hallelujah!
- Vamoose!
Disappear! Look at him walking--
Hey! Come back here!
- Where are you going?
- I'm going after him, of course.
Obinna, you're stupid.
You want to sabotage me.
- You want to stab me from the back.
- Daddy, please stop this talk.
Et tu, Brute? Et tu, Brute?
- I'll be back.
- If you leave--
Who is it?
Oh, Janet.
- Hello.
- Abisola.
- Good to see you.
- How are you?
I'm fine. I'm good.
- How you doing?
- I'm fine.
- What's wrong with your AC?
- Don't mind it.
It stopped working,
- but we'll be fixing it later today.
- Okay.
Is Dora home?
Yes, but I think she's sleeping.
- No, you don't have to wake her.
- Okay.
Please, can you give this to her?
- Thank you.
- So, what is this?
It's a wedding invite.
Okay.
Mike is getting married.
- Mike is getting married?
- Mm-hmm.
- And this is for Dora?
- Yes.
I think you should hold on.
She should be awake.
Are you sure you want to wake her up?
I'm coming, please.
Okay.
Oh, there you are, Dora!
How are you doing? What's up?
What are you doing here?
What right do you think you have
to be here?
Uh... what did I do?
What did you not do?
If you weren't such a bad,
self-centered friend,
wouldn't you ask me what happened
between your brother and me?
Is it a crime to be here?
I just don't want you to hear it
from anyone else.
I wanted to tell you myself.
Please, let's calm down, please.
If Janet is not crazy,
she won't sit there talking to me
about Mike's wedding.
What kind of callous behavior is that?
Wait, what do you mean by crazy?
Huh?
Didn't you tell me
you had gotten over my brother?
Didn't you tell me that?
Really? If you are not crazy,
you and your family used me.
You deceived me!
Used... you?
Wait, can you just take a split second
to listen to what exactly
you just said now? You--
You know what?
It's pointless.
I really shouldn't be here.
I'm sorry I came.
I should take my leave now.
Better. Hey and you know what?
Don't you ever come to my house again.
Ungrateful bunch.
- Can you imagine?
- It's unbelievable.
It's okay.
- See my baby!
- Oshey Baddest!
See my baby!
- You can keep the change.
- Stop giving these bikers money.
- Alausa!
- You want to collect money?
It's okay. Let him be. I gave it to him.
- Stop giving bike riders money.
- I gave it to him.
- Today is a good day.
- Baby, what's going on?
- Don't do that again.
- It's okay.
- Are you guys doing okay?
- Yes, we are.
- You guys are doing good.
- Baby, what's going on?
- You know me now.
- I can see you're happy.
Nkemjika is always latest.
- Always latest.
- That's right!
- Tell me something.
- I bought an iPhone 7.
I said it.
- IPhone 7s.
- IPhone 7s?
- Yes. Latest.
- Can I see it?
- Latest!
- IPhone 7s!
Just flash me.
- Yes!
- Wait.
So, me, I'm gonna shine.
Come over.
You know what?
You're buying me drinks to celebrate.
- No problem. Come. I'm going to the club.
- Okay, let's go there.
Nkemjika bought a new phone!
Let me even take off my slippers.
Nkemjika bought an iPhone 10!
Everybody, Nkemjika bought a new phone!
- Auntie!
- Yes?
Auntie, Ejika has bought iPhone 10.
- Ejika bought what?
- IPhone 10.
- Are you sure?
- Yes!
- Did you see it?
- Are you sure?
- Yes!
- Say "Allah."
- Allah.
Ah! I'm coming!
- Where are you going?
- I want to go and meet Ejika.
- But I said I miss you.
- Forget about love. This is important.
- Ejika has bought iPhone 10!
- Come now.
Ejika has bought iPhone 10!
Alausa, how many will you drink?
Two bottles?
- Yes, I'll drink two.
- Bring two bottles.
How many will you drink?
Eh? Ramotu.
Wait, my friend.
I heard you bought an iPhone 10.
Phone. I'm buying drinks for everyone.
Drink up!
Nkemjika has bought a phone!
Aren't you gonna drink gin
to feel all right?
I'll drink it later. I'm okay for now.
What is it?
- Hey, bartender!
- What?
- Get us some drinks over here!
- I'll get them.
I'll get them,
but we want to see the phone first.
- You want to see the phone?
- I want to see this particular phone.
- 5,005-naira phone!
- Open the phone!
IPhone 10.
- Nkemjika. Let's see.
- Calm down, everybody.
- Drink up! The phone is here!
- Switch the phone on.
Once I switch on this phone,
I'll call Ibrahim.
No, Buhari.
One straight call.
This phone does not need to be charged.
For real!
It doesn't need charging at all. Yes!
- IPhone.
- It cannot die!
Are they seeing you in America?
- I don't understand.
- It isn't switching on?
- Wait!
- No, press it well.
The phone that can call Buhari,
is it going to come on easily?
- No.
- Too much load.
- Let me help you.
- The battery's dead.
- Press it well.
- IPhone 10!
Wait, it's this side.
Okay, that's it.
- Leave it alone!
- Wait!
Wait, you did not put the SIM card in.
- Let me put the SIM in.
- No wonder!
Yeah, that's it.
- Now put the SIM in.
- Gently.
IPhone. Good iPhone.
This is real gold.
- Cassava meal!
- And the thing go skrra!
I'm too stunned to speak.
Don't open the drinks!
- This one?
- Please, let's go!
- Don't open it!
- Don't open what?
- Look what she bought for 5,500 naira.
- She bought it. So what?
- Look what she got for 5,500.
- IPhone 10!
Don't open the drinks!
Don't open what?
- Please leave!
- IPhone!
Hi, Mum.
Mummy, I'm greeting you.
Is that how I taught you to greet?
Is that how I raised you?
Good day, ma.
Welcome.
- Why are you frowning?
- Dora again.
What happened to Dora?
So I went to Dora's house
to invite her to Mike's wedding.
Dora almost beat me up.
I mean, you needed to see the way--
the bad things she said about us!
It just took me the grace, like--
the last strength in me
to just walk away without hitting her.
You know what I think?
I think it was a bad idea.
You shouldn't have gone to invite her.
Clearly, that young woman
is not over your brother.
But I must commend you for not slapping
or abusing or fighting her.
I didn't.
Shows I taught you well.
Sorry. You should go
and talk to your brother about it, okay?
I will.
Mummy, why are you the one cooking?
Where's the housemaid?
House girl. Who's the house girl?
The house girl.
The house girl, she doesn't have a name?
She doesn't have a name? "The housemaid."
Okay, where is Binta?
Better. You should respect people. Hmm?
I sent her down the road
to go and buy me something.
- Sorry, dear, are you going to eat?
- Mummy, I'm so hungry.
Don't worry. It'll be ready soon.
So, tomorrow morning, Jide and Bimpe,
you will go to Abuja for that meeting.
Take everything you need to take.
Don't tell me there's a mistake.
Is that okay?
Chioma, you'll take over
their responsibilities.
You'll do all their work tomorrow.
Any questions?
Are you sure?
Ask your questions now.
Dayo.
- Ah, sorry.
- Are you okay?
I'm sorry. I think away a little.
- Okay, you zoned out?
- Uh, yes.
Before I get zoned out from
a husband-to-be position to a friend zone,
we need to go pick up the girls
for a fitting.
Can we? Have you finished here?
Yes. But I need to tidy up some things.
Let me go and warm up the car.
Hello, babes.
I couldn't even see him.
I am not going to go explain myself
to someone who has refused to see me.
Hold on! You know what?
Allow me to do this in my own way.
I am serious.
You know what? I'm so done.
Like, I'm done.
I've fixed this tire
more than 500 times.
Sir, please attend to us.
Pump up our tire. We need to leave.
I'm sorry for the delay, sir.
Please fix it quickly. You're delaying me.
Are you going to fix my tire?
Leave the road, sir.
What's your problem?
You need to leave the road.
What's going on?
- What do you mean "leave the road?"
- If you're not ready, get out of the way.
I came here before you to get my tire
pumped and you're telling me to leave?
- Who do you think I am?
- Who do you think we are?
- Who are you?
- Do you know who we are?
Who are you?
- What is wrong with this man?
- I'm here. I want to pump my tire.
- You are where?
- You're telling me--
- Look at this man!
- Let's take it easy!
Are you all crazy?
Get in the car. Let's leave!
- You've killed him!
- Dayo!
Hold it!
- You've killed him!
- Come on, Dayo.
- He's dead!
- Dayo! Come on!
Yeah, I love you. It's not that serious.
You don't have to come.
No, I don't know them.
And certainly we didn't hit them.
I mean, I think they just decided
to act like a nuisance.
- Let me call you back.
- Michael, come on! Where is my boyfriend?
And that girl you said
he had an accident with.
- Where are they? I want to see my man now!
- Yes!
I want to see my man right now!
Where's my man and the stupid girl
he's been cruising around town with?
Chioma, which girl?
You're asking me? Don't ask me that!
Didn't you tell me on the phone
that my man was involved in an accident
with another woman?
Chioma, is that what you deducted
from our conversation?
I didn't come here to do mathematics.
I don't know what you're talking about.
I want to see my man!
Chioma, I said someone tried
to hit my head with a plank.
Dayo saved me.
Girls, calm down.
Mr. Mike, explain.
Let me understand, because
I don't understand what you're saying.
I said someone tried
to hit my head with a plank.
Dayo took the hit for me.
Really? Hold on, let me get this clearly.
- So no girl?
- There is no girl anywhere.
Hold on. So someone wanted to hit you,
you got out of the way,
my man became your personal Lord
and Savior and took the hit for you?
Hey! My man is a superhero!
He's a superhero!
You're not cheering me enough.
Yes? Come in.
Hey, brother.
- Janet.
- Husband-to-be in the building.
Oh, I'm sorry, I didn't shut your door.
- How are you?
- I'm fine.
Good, good.
- How are you doing? Can I sit?
- Yeah, sit. It's okay.
- So, how you doing?
- I'm good.
How is Adunni?
Look at you, you're blushing.
She's fine.
Um...
so I came to discuss something with you.
Okay.
I'm not happy.
I'm not happy at all.
What happened?
I went to Dora's house
to invite her to your wedding.
I didn't quite envisage the kind of insult
she rained on me.
It was terrible!
Okay, so, bro, this is me asking you...
...what exactly happened
between the two of you?
Are you kidding me?
No.
That's what happened.
And apparently...
that was not her first time.
Wait.
So, why did she make it look
as if you just dumped her
for practically no reason?
It's okay.
No, it's fine.
At least now I know the truth.
If you're comfortable lying
to the one person
you claim to love so much...
then you're capable of doing so much more.
I said leave me alone.
- Don't leave me like this.
- Leave me alone.
We've started already. Let's finish.
Finish what? I'm not interested.
And I have my reason.
- Oh, God! I'm full. I need to unload.
- Reloaded, my foot.
- I'm going to leave now.
- Please don't go!
Don't you know that Oro is tonight?
- And so?
- There are masquerades outside! Isla!
I've warned you,
women must stay inside tonight.
I've told you! I've told you not to leave!
If you run into any masquerades,
you're on your own!
...the strongest of them
all. There's no bird like the vulture.
Let her be. Don't pursue her.
Let's continue our rites.
Kafila, open the door! What's wrong?
- Open up! The masquerades!
- Where?
Calm down!
- Where did you see the masquerades?
- I ran into them.
This prophet we came to see
is spirit-filled.
All his predictions are accurate.
Believe me.
I'm afraid. But wait. Doesn't the ground
look like it's moving backwards?
- What is going backwards?
- This ground.
It's not going anywhere. It's there.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
May the Lord be with you both.
Amen.
- God be with you.
- Amen.
You see...
Father, leave me alone. Leave me alone.
Yes, I'm speaking.
Young lady, the forces confronting you
are very powerful.
Yes.
Sir, I ran into some masquerades
and I've had nightmares since.
Excuse me, sir.
She didn't just run into the masquerades.
She saw them face-to-face.
The masquerade was looking at her,
- and she was looking at the masquerade.
- Oh, my God!
It was looking at her,
- and she was looking at the masquerade.
- Yes?
Excuse me, sir. It's not a small issue.
Look, I got the revelation
just as you narrated.
It's a bad omen
to see a masquerade face-to-face.
One has to be prayerful
to avoid negative consequences.
Oh!
This is a list of things you need
to get done as soon as possible.
That's what I said.
- Cows? Four cows?
- That's right.
- Ten lizard eyes.
- Red oil, eight gallons.
- Yes. Thus says the Lord.
- Sparrow eggs, 24.
- Thus says the Lord.
White fabric, 45 yards.
Are you planning a birthday?
Not at all.
It's to fight the forces fighting you.
You are insane.
You call this holy ground?
Holy ground, my foot.
- You're not allowed to wear shoes here.
- I don't give a damn. I'm out of here.
Look here! Look here!
Leave me alone, please!
It's dangerous to change your mind
on this holy ground.
Yes, sir.
Tell her the consequences of disobedience.
It's an abomination! That's what I said.
She has to get everything on this list
for her own good.
- Take it.
- Yes, sir.
- Oh, Father!
- Thank you, sir.
Leave me. Leave me, Father.
Excuse me, sir.
- I saw an iPhone 6s on this list.
- Yes.
It's a bad thing if I can't call you
because I don't have a phone.
So sad. There's nothing sadder than that.
The iPhone 6s also has a big screen
that will allow me to see clearly
when I call you.
My glasses are broken.
My associates may not be here
when I need to call you,
and that's not good.
The Lord is waiting for you.
Don't disobey divine instruction.
Please, this is important.
The Lord be with you.
In Jesus' name, amen.
An opportunity to make money has come.
I need to be prayerful.
You are a child of God and fight
like Anthony Joshua. Superhero!
You know what? I love you so much, Dayo.
You're my man. Kiss me.
- I'm not going to kiss you.
- Why?
- You're troublesome. Chioma, what is it?
- What do you mean?
My friend, will you shut up and kiss me?
Please peck me!
Uh-uh. This is not a fight.
We're not fighting.
Do it romantically. It's my right.
Tell me you love me.
- I love--
- I love you, too.
- Yeah.
All right, guys, as much as I would like
Dayo to come home,
we have a wedding to organize.
- Yes.
- May we all fall in love.
You two just want to get married.
I'm sorry, but I'm not sorry.
I can't wait.
I called them.
We have to be at 2207 for our fittings.
- Yeah, yeah.
- So we have to go.
What about me?
Don't worry, I already told him.
He's coming here specially to suit you up.
What do you mean by "What about me?"
So if she didn't tell you,
you wouldn't know you need bed rest?
You need to stay here and rest
so you can recover fully.
And you're saying "What about me?"
Respect yourself. Don't say that again.
- Please.
- What do you mean by that?
Chioma, I know what's good for me
and I know my rights.
I'm sorry.
You don't know what's good for you.
I'm here to teach you what's good for you
because you're my man.
- Mike, please can you just do me a favor?
- What's that?
Help me tell the doctor that I want to be
the only one in this room.
- Yes, with your baby.
- No, no, no. Not with her.
- So you want me to leave?
- Please.
You're dreaming. Your name is Joseph.
You can relax.
- I think that will be our cue to go.
- Yeah.
Congratulations, my dear.
I'm going to join your bridal train.
- Yeah. Okay, fine.
- I will come.
- Thank you very much.
- Get well soon.
- Chioma.
- Thank you very much.
- Take it easy.
- Take care. Later, okay?
My dear, hold onto your man.
Don't let these street girls steal him.
- Stop shouting.
- Let me talk to my fellow woman.
Oh, my God.
Hello? What do you want?
Kill the three.
Kill all three!
Kill the three!
Okay.
Careful. Drive careful.
- Honey, don't go out!
- Oh, my God!
Oh, my God!
- Somebody help!
- Help me!
Call the boss.
Tell him the job's done
and ask him what we should do next.
Call this guy, please.
Call and tell them
we've killed two people.
This guy isn't answering.
Hello, boss.
Something just happened right now.
Yes, we're good to go.
The job is still in motion.
We could only take out just one of them.
Boss, calm down. The place was rowdy.
We're still hunting.
Are you with--
- What happened?
- Guess what. He just ended the call.
What did he say?
- He's angry.
- From day one, I told you how he'd react.
Next one, we'll make it up.
Let's finish it up. Come on!
What is it?
I told you it's all right.
No, you don't understand.
- I need to see my friend.
- No, no, no.
I need to see my friend!
- Mr. Dayo, calm down.
- Ah!
I'm in trouble!
He's my helper, my assistance. He's Mike!
Mike cannot die!
Adunni, what are you going to eat?
I don't want to eat.
Adunni, no, don't be like this.
Please, you have to eat some--
Okay, Adunni, do you want me to leave?
I'm going to prepare
anything that you want.
- Anything at all.
- I don't want to eat.
Please, do you want me to leave?
Don't cry.
Just let me know--
Okay, let me just get you a drink.
I'll be right back.
Yeah, hello?
You have been trying to reach me
since yesterday,
and it hasn't been going through.
Does that make any sense to you?
I didn't ask you to take it this far!
No, I didn't ask you to take it this far!
Look, you know what?
I'll call you much later when I'm done
so I can know how to get you
out of this mess.
'Cause I don't know
what you want me to do.
Okay, fine.
Okay, Jane, thank you very much
for the condolences.
Thank you so much.
- It's lovely to see you. Thank you.
- All right.
- Greet your people.
- Have a lovely evening.
Um, sir, sorry.
Can I just have you for one moment?
There's something
that's been playing on my mind
and I just wanted to talk to you
now I have the chance and it's very quiet.
Basically,
you know my boss isn't aware
- that I understand Yoruba?
- Mm-hmm.
The other day,
I overheard a phone conversation,
and I kept hearing
"pa meta, pa meta, pa meta."
And I know it means three.
I believe I heard there were three people
in that car, sir.
Stop crying, stop.
I know you're only doing your job, DPO.
I'm still in shock
that he accused me of killing his son
that I practically raised.
Ask this foolish man
who brought him to Lagos?
Does it matter? Does it matter?
- Imagine.
- Hmm?
- Do you call that an achievement? Huh?
- Imagine.
Somebody brought you.
People will continue
to bring other people.
So don't make a mountain
out of a molehill.
He who lives by the sword
will die by the sword.
- I will embarrass you.
- You will see.
- I'll discredit you beyond imagination.
- This won't end here.
Chief, please stay out of this for now.
- You will see.
- Continue.
What do I stand to gain from killing Mike?
Mm-hmm.
Were you aware there were
three of them in the car that day?
Yes, I did.
How frequently did you speak to Mike?
What has that got to do with this?
What I'm asking is,
when last did you speak to Mike?
The day of the incident.
- And what did you speak about?
- He was asking about my welfare.
He was asking me how I was faring.
Were you sick?
Do you need to be sick
before you're asked about your welfare?
How you are faring?
- Did he say he was going to the tailor's?
- Yes, he did.
And you knew he was in the car
with his fiancée and her friend?
You obviously have
prior information about this situation.
Could that be what you heard
from my secretary?
Shouldn't we take it seriously?
You called for them
to kill the three of them.
- Nonsense.
- Mm!
Arrant nonsense.
How could someone who is reasonable,
somebody who is sensible,
could have believed that?
Well, I was hoping you'd tell us.
What happened was there was this sacrifice
I needed to do.
I instructed my son
to kill all the three rams.
That was what happened.
He who lives by the sword
will die by the sword.
No longer human beings, but rams now.
He who lives by the sword
will die by the sword.
Yes!
I get it. You want the devil?
I'll show you the devil.
- You'll see. This case is going further.
- You'll see my wrath.
Sir, this ram isn't big.
It's not as big as the other one.
- This one's bigger.
- This one is bigger?
Also, this one is older.
- Can't you see this one?
- What did the boss say?
He instructed us to kill the three rams.
- How can we kill all three?
- Confirm it.
Hello, sir.
Sir, did you say we should kill all three?
All right. Okay. Sorry, sir.
All right, sir. All right, sir.
Mallam, come quick!
And that was exactly what happened.
Okay. I suggest you don't leave town,
because we'll need you
for further questioning.
- Mmm.
- No problem. I am not going anywhere.
- He should not go.
- Constable.
I don't have a hand in Mike's death.
I know nothing about it.
Really? Adunni, really?
After everything?
I left my family, I left my fiancé,
everything back in Ghana,
just to come here to be with you.
And you would think that I would do
something as cruel as killing?
Okay, Miss Nana.
Can you please explain
the conversation you had over the phone?
I was--
I was only rebuking my sister, Efia.
I was on the phone talking to Efia.
I suspected my fiancé of cheating on me,
so I told my sister to find out if my--
I told her to find out
if my thoughts were actually real.
I told her to take a picture of the girl
should she ever see anybody,
but Efia ended up beating the girl
alongside her friends.
- And the girl is in coma today. All the--
- Coma?
All the blogs have carried it.
That's what I was talking to her about
over the phone.
Can you give us your sister's number
- to verify this information?
- Yes I can!
Okay. We will keep investigating.
But, in the meantime, Miss Nana,
you can't leave the country.
And... we will be in touch.
I know you know about this.
You've been watching us all about.
You've been monitoring all our movement.
You know if I'm with Mike
you can never kill him. Never!
That was why you sent those foolish people
to break a plank on my head,
so that I'd be in the hospital
so you could do the nonsense you did.
- You killed Mike!
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- You don't know?
You'll see my wrath!
You killed my helper.
You killed my benefactor.
And you want to live in this world.
Never! It's not possible.
Let me tell you something!
I will not report you to the police.
I will not tell them to take you to court
because that will be a waste of time.
Ah! In Yoruba land, I'll let you know
that we have spiritual power.
- I don't know--
- I'll invoke Mike's spirit.
- What is that?
- Ask me again.
I will invoke the spirit of the dead.
I will invoke the spirit of Mike
to come after you.
He will not only kill you
but all your family.
- Trust me, I'll let you know who I am.
- I don't know what you're talking about.
You want to turn me into a useless person.
If you don't die in the next two days,
call me a bastard.
I seriously don't know
what you're talking about.
Oh, my--
Oh, jeez!
I've always warned you
to stop threatening people.
- Now you're a suspect.
- I didn't do it. Come on! I did not!
Hey, Uncle, please. Good afternoon.
Please, I'm going to Sabitex Hotel.
- I don't know where--
- They said it's a green building,
- and the landmark is--
- Can you see me?
Can I see you? Uh-uh.
I cannot see you. You know that I'm blind.
Or let's just say you're a ghost.
- You can see me!
- Yeah.
You can see me! You can see me! Hi.
My name is Mike. I'm a ghost.
My name is Isla. I'm a tout.
Hold on, okay. What am I doing now?
You're raising your leg up.
Wait. Isla. Isla.
I just told you my name once
and you've turned it into Isla.
I need your help. I need your help.
Some-- Some people just killed me.
Some people just killed me.
- Isla, I need your help.
- Sir, go and sit down, please.
Sir, we have seen it all in Nigeria.
Let me tell you something.
I'm a Naija girl to the core!
I grew up in the ghetto.
That's where I live.
- We've seen it all!
- No, no, no.
Don't touch me!
You want to touch me
and make me lose my body parts.
I have seen where someone gets into water,
the person is drowning.
The person that was there said,
"Why can't you help?"
The person said,
"He doesn't want to come down.
He doesn't want to get in the water
because he doesn't want
to spoil his phone."
So don't think I can be fooled.
I'm a Nigerian.
- Isla, please.
- Please stay away from me!
- I am not as naive as you think.
- Isla.
You're a ghost.
You're a ghost and you're fully dressed.
Isla, some people just killed me.
- Am I the one that killed you?
- I need your help.
- Isla, don't leave me. Please.
I swear to almighty Allah,
if you stress me again, I'll push you
and you'll be crushed by a car
and you'll die.
Please, I need your help.
You can only swindle the rich girls,
not me.
I know it's hard to believe,
but I need your help.
I'll scream if you don't leave me alone.
You're the only one that can see me.
The only one.
You know what?
I accept that you're a ghost.
- Okay.
- I'm a ghost, too.
- You're a ghost?
- Yes.
- You see that ghost and ghost don't work.
- No!
Go away with your ghost stories!
Is something wrong with you?
I've heard you. You're a ghost.
I'm a ghost.
We're both ghosts.
Ghosts don't play. Go!
- Should I explain to you?
- Go ahead.
There are some things going on
in our cabal.
As we're sitting here,
there are spirit beings in people.
Everyone you see has a spirit being
living inside them.
This guy you're looking at is a spirit.
Man.
If I talk more about this,
I'll get emotional.
This guy you're looking at right now.
You know C. Ronaldo?
- Hold on.
- Say no more, sir.
Wait, you mean the Ronaldo
that plays for Madrid?
- The one that plays for Madrid.
- He and this guy are kindred spirits.
- Unbelievable.
- They are kindred spirits.
They're kindred spirits.
You know this guy. You know Messi?
Messi that plays for Barça?
- Bro.
- He and this guy are kindred spirits.
They are kindred spirits. I know.
- They're kindred spirits.
- Bro!
- Forget about that.
- We need to say it.
- He deserves respect. He's my friend.
- Okay, I hear you.
- Now today is today.
- Okay.
- What's happening today?
- I want to tell you something.
I want to do the party today
because the money has been paid.
- Baby, tell them.
- What kind of party is that?
- Tell them!
- You want me to say it?
- What is it?
- I hope they won't start extorting you.
Okay, this guy you're all looking at
says he wants to throw a party.
- Do you know where he built his house?
- Where?
Banana Island.
I'm shocked.
Unbelievable!
Let me tell you all something else.
As this guy is here now...
You know the popular gossip blogger,
Linda Ikeji?
They're neighbors.
Impossible.
I can't be telling lies at my age.
- Let me now tell you the last thing.
- Tell us.
- You heard he wants to throw a party?
- Yes?
It's not because he's a party freak.
He likes music.
He has a mini studio set up in his house
with all the gadgets in it.
He likes music. So the--
Please, leave me.
Let me blow your trumpet.
Linda went to report
to the Banana Island residents association
that his music disturbs her
and he should be evicted.
People are envious.
I'll tell you another thing.
Do you know who this man is?
This man knows Mike Adenuga,
the billionaire.
Let me say the last one.
If I speak again after this...
Damn. This lady has killed me.
- If I talk again, let me die.
- Isla.
Let me just say this last one.
They need to know.
You know the name of Mike's company
is Glo, right?
He named the company after his mother.
Her name was Gloria.
He just removed the "ria"
and named the company Glo.
Allahu Akbar!
Kill me instead.
Don't kill me. I don't have money today.
- Why would I lie?
- I need your help, please.
- What are you doing?
- I need your help.
- Come on.
- What was that?
Who is Isla talking to?
- Hold on.
- Baby.
- Can't you guys see him?
- Who?
He has black shoes
and brown trousers with a--
It looks like she's drunk already.
- Give me one minute.
- Okay.
Don't you see him?
So you're actually a ghost?
- Nobody is here.
- Okay.
You know what? It looks like
Isla drank contaminated water.
- Isla has lost her mind!
- Hey, Isla!
I know what the problem is.
Dayo!
Stop knocking. Let's wait for him.
What nonsense is this?
Wait, wait.
What's up?
I'm here to see Dayo. Is he home?
- What did you say?
- Who?
- Dayo.
- Wait, what did you say Dayo did?
So it is Dayo you came looking for?
You're one of those girls
that follow him around!
Isla, Isla.
- Are you okay?
- I'm okay.
I'm coming from the bank. I'm okay.
- I'm sorry.
- Leave me alone! What is it?
- Please, am I the one that killed you?
"Say no to drugs." You don't listen.
I'll stab you or push you
in front of a moving car and you will die.
- Isla, I'm sorry.
- Oh, he's already dead.
- Help me, please.
- Help you for what? For what?
- Isla, I'm sorry.
- Do you know what I went through there?
Okay, let's go to my fiancée's place.
- Please. Isla, please.
- If these people come--
I said I'm not doing it. Can I go?
- What's this now?
- Isla, help me.
- Help you for what?
- Help me, please.
- I've not heard this before.
- It's like you want to see madness today.
- Isla, please.
I swear, if you follow me,
I'm going to strip naked.
Isla, please.
Ah! Stop following me.
Do I know this person?
Leave me alone.
I said I'm not going again.
You sent me somewhere. I got a beating.
For what? No!
Am I the one that killed you?
No, let's talk!
Am I responsible for your death?
What are you begging me for?
Somebody help me, please.
What is it? Did I know you before?
What is it?
- Good afternoon.
I'm not doing it again.
I'm coming. Please, please. What is it?
Please, I--
Don't beg me. Don't beg me.
I am not interested.
I'm not going. I went somewhere.
Look at the way they beat me.
Am I an armed robber? Did I steal?
Did I sleep with someone's husband?
What is it? Nothing!
- Sorry.
- I'm done helping you.
- Listen to me now. How's it going?
- Fine. Good afternoon.
- I hope you're okay?
- I'm okay.
I believe there's no problem.
There's no problem.
This man is just disturbing me.
- Who?
- He sent me somewhere.
I went there. Look at what they did to me.
I'm just fed up.
- Leave me alone!
- Sorry.
Stop begging me! Stop begging me!
She said you should not beg her anymore.
- Do you know what you're going to do now?
- Don't follow me.
You know what's going to happen?
Do you know Yaba Hospital?
- Yaba.
- Yaba?
- To Yaba.
- Yes?
Let's go there together.
Oh! At the left side of Yaba bus stop?
- Yes. It's not far.
- Have you seen what you've done?
Now they think I'm mad.
They want to take me to Yaba.
- Don't worry.
- Listen, I am not mad.
- I am just trying to help somebody.
- Okay.
If you beg me, thunder will kill you.
I'm trying to help somebody.
Please, let me just go.
I understand you.
I understand you. Yeah.
- We won't be long.
- Let us go to Yaba.
- I'm not mad.
- I know.
I know, you're not mad at all.
Let me explain something to you. You--
- Wait. You see, let me explain.
- Let her be.
Wait.
You see what-- Look at something.
I'm not mad!
- Okay, 1,000.
- 1,000.
- Bye-bye.
- Greetings.
- Greetings to you, too.
- Fine girl.
- I've come to pay my carnival fee.
- Have you paid the sector fee?
- Yes, I have.
- Are you sure?
- I've paid, Auntie.
- I will ask!
- What sector do you belong to?
- Number 33.
- Oh.
- Sector 33?
- Garage side.
Yetunde.
- Please take care of me now, ladies.
- Shut up!
Don't make me break your head.
Who do you think you're talking to?
- Lady, respect yourself, please.
- Where is your sector?
My sector is on that side.
- What's your name?
- Uh...
- Eliazu Texas.
- What did he say?
- Eliazu Texas. Just write "Monkey."
Have you seen what you've done?
- No...
- You've gotten yourself in a mess. Monkey!
- Monkey, M-O-K--
- Stupid monkey!
- No, make it "Stupid."
- Get away from here!
Only you two know what you're doing.
- Respect yourselves.
- I hope you get chicken pox.
Hey! Sit down.
- Carnival money.
How much did we agree on?
2,000.
- 2,000?
- Yes.
- 2,000.
Please can I pay 12 times?
As in 80 naira each time?
But wait, the two--
The 200 naira you collect from us,
what do you use it for?
- It's sector money.
- What?
Do you collect shit?
I said... the 200 naira
that you people collect from us--
- Why are you running?
- Come closer and say it.
You're stupid. Fools.
You're trying to extort me.
Come and sit down.
It's because I don't want
to stain the chair with blood.
God punish you.
- Hey. Isla?
- Did she just ask me that?
- You asked a question?
- You're talking to us?
If you come-- Me, I'm not your husband.
I'll teach you a lesson if you get close.
I dare you to come.
Osondu, have a seat. Forget about it!
There's something wrong with her.
I'll find out.
Something's wrong with you, too!
Something's wrong with you!
There's something wrong with you!
There is-- Both of you are mad.
You think I'm stupid, right?
You want to use me to do training.
God will punish you!
- Look at you.
- Osondu, sit down. This is temptation.
I'm sorry, Isla, please.
We need to go now, please.
I cannot go to any man's house again.
You need to go and see my fiancée, Isla.
- Your fiancée?
- Yes.
You want to spoil everything.
I can't go see any man, over my dead body.
What's making you laugh?
My fiancée is a woman. Fiancée is a woman.
- So, it's a woman?
- Yes.
No problem.
Your constant begging
is making me sympathetic.
Put yourself in my shoes.
- Isla!
- Stop it!
If you don't know how to hail me, stop it.
What's wrong with this rich boy?
But the thing is,
you'll pay me for these jobs.
I'll pay you, Isla.
I'll tell my fiancée to pay you.
That's better.
I have a reputation for being a tough girl
in this neighborhood,
and I was beaten up like a thief.
Thank you. Thank you.
Isla!
Don't do that
in the presence of everybody.
- You make me look like a crazy person.
- I'm sorry.
You talk to me,
knowing fully well nobody sees you.
- I'm sorry.
- Everybody will think I'm crazy.
Thank you. Isla!
Stop it. It doesn't fit you.
"Isla."
- You look like a cartoon.
- Thank you.
Don't follow me.
I want to go and take transport fare. Ah!
But wait, I'm sure you must have been
very stubborn when you were alive.
What's the matter?
No wonder heaven rejected you.
- My name is Adunni. What's yours?
- Isla.
Oh, Isla. Um... would you like to sit?
No, I'm fine. I'm very fine.
But I swear, your house is fine.
- So fine!
- Thank you. Thank you.
- Everything looks really good.
- Thank you very much.
- So you wanted to see me about my fiancé?
- Yes, yes.
- Sorry, I haven't seen your face before.
- No, I've not seen your face.
You have seen so many faces.
But your own face, zero.
- Nice one.
- You're welcome.
So, my late fiancé, what's this about?
Please, excuse me.
- Is she the one? Get out.
- I'm sorry.
Sorry, is she the person?
- You have taste.
- I'm sorry.
Um... hello?
Hi.
Who are you talking to?
I'm soliloquizing.
Uh, okay, um...
So, I haven't seen you before.
What would you like to talk to me about?
Should I tell her everything?
Um... your fiancé sent me to you.
Sorry to interrupt.
You do know that my fiancé is dead?
Of course I know.
But please hold on. Let me ask him
if I should tell you everything.
Your fiancé said I should tell you
what actually happened.
I'm sorry, I have to interrupt.
I don't understand what's going on.
Who are you talking to?
What I'm trying to say
is that he's the one that sent me to you.
Yeah, I heard that.
Who are you talking to right now?
As I said before...
I'm soliloquizing.
Okay, um...
- That's okay.
- Okay.
- He said I should tell you there is...
- Someone--
- Yeah, just a second, please.
Security, please.
Security.
Would you please
make it up to my apartment right now?
Thank you. You are cute.
Sorry to cut your-your...
your little chat there.
- Dehinde?
- Your name is Dehinde?
You're Yoruba? I'm Isla.
Why did you let an insane woman
into my house?
Tell me why. It's wrong.
I asked you a question. Why would you
let a madwoman into my house?
Tell me, are you a mad person?
Ah! I'm a mad person? Come on.
You called me a madwoman?
- You see what you have caused?
- You see what I'm saying?
Let me pass.
You see what you have caused?
No problem.
Just imagine!
Today is my off day. I swear.
If today wasn't my off day,
I'd stab you in many places.
I would do liposuction for you.
There's no point.
- Sorry, ma.
- Touch me and you will regret it.
See, man. I cannot go anywhere again.
What is it?
The first time you sent me, they beat me.
For what?
The second time,
your girl is calling me crazy.
And the gateman called me crazy.
God forbid.
And she's lucky today is my off day.
I'd have beaten her to a pulp.
Please, I don't know about your death.
I've never met you.
I don't have any problem with you.
I'm on my own. Please just go.
Where else do you want me to go?
Go to the graveyard!
You have a resting place. Go there.
You can't be stressing me.
Please, you have to help me.
You have to help me. I'm helpless.
You're the only one that can see me.
I can't go anywhere.
Isla, please.
I can't help you, sir.
Hey! Lord, what an unfortunate day it was
that I ran into masquerades.
I've been seeing spirits since that day.
I know you have a good heart.
I have seen the way you behave
among everyone.
You have to help people.
I know you have good intentions for me.
Isla, if there's anything you can do--
I'm begging you.
I'm begging you. Please.
It's okay. You know how to get me.
When people say I have a good heart,
it makes me melt.
You know just how to make me melt.
You just keep saying
all the right loving words.
You're making somebody feel important.
I don't understand you.
I cannot be going through
all this trouble. Uh-uh.
Why don't you tell me the things
that is just between you and her?
When I get there and tell her,
she'll know that I'm saying the truth.
I will tell you things
that only I and her know. Please.
She will believe you this time.
Wait, wait, wait.
All this job that I'm doing for you,
how much are you going to pay me?
Because I want to be paid.
How much do you want?
I will collect 30,000.
Okay, wait. Give me 25.
You're still frowning.
See, the least I can go is 20.
If you cannot pay me 20-- pshh.
Go. I'm not interested.
I can't go less than 20.
It's not possible.
I can't. I can never.
God forbid. Over my dead body. I can't.
I can't do less than that.
I've lost a lot of jobs--
What's making you laugh?
Isla, I was thinking around...
five million.
- Five million?
- Five million naira.
You want me to charge you five million
so you can run away.
You'll now say
it's because the bill is too much.
No, I'll tell my fiancée
to give you five million naira.
- Swear in God's name.
- I swear to God.
Ah! You said God.
You know that you must not
call the name of God in vain.
And you know that liars go to hellfire.
Maybe you missed heaven
because you are a liar.
You won't rest in peace
if you keep lying as a ghost.
Trust me, I'm not lying.
I'll go anywhere. I will go.
- Isla, you'll go?
- Anywhere you send me.
I am even willing to go
back to where I was beaten up.
Five million is worth getting beaten up.
Let's go.
So, let's see tomorrow. I'll go tomorrow.
- Okay. Yeah.
- You understand.
- Thank you so much. You can go now.
- Thank you.
You can go. I want to undress.
You can go ahead. I'm a ghost.
You're a ghost? So because you're a ghost,
I should let you see me naked?
Or should I help you?
Should you help me? Oh, now I remember
why you're not allowed in heaven.
No womanizer can ever rest in peace.
I've heard you. You've been saying
all along you're a ghost.
Don't worry, sir, just go.
- Isla.
- I'm not joking. Just leave.
Isla, who are you talking to?
I'm not talking to anybody.
Isla, I heard a voice just now.
That's impossible.
I was talking to myself.
Isla, if I didn't come here now, is this
what you'd be doing behind my back?
Not at all. I wasn't talking to anybody.
I was talking alone.
I love you.
So, it's-- it's real.
It's real. Why will I be lying?
Let me tell you my motto.
My motto is "You do not lie.
If you know you want to lie, don't talk."
I can feel his presence.
He's even here.
He's here. He's looking at you.
What's he doing?
- What are you--
- What's he doing?
Tell me, tell me.
What is he-- What is he doing?
I love you so much.
He said that he loves you so much.
You're crying.
Tell him I love him too and I miss him.
He said he loves you too,
that he misses you.
Did he hear you?
He can hear you. He's not deaf.
I wish that I could hold you.
Aw.
He said he misses you, too.
He said you're his world.
Dear Lord, this is genuine love.
If only Hakeem can show me
this kind of love, but that one,
he's a stupid person.
- Anyway, I want to be going.
- Oh, no, don't go. Please stay.
I should stay? Why?
This is not my house. I have my house.
You've become family.
Ah! No, we're not family. I'm so sorry.
We're never family. I'm sorry.
Please, I have to go.
Okay, can I have your number?
You say what?
Can I have your number, please?
- I don't give my number to strangers.
- Please.
- You--
- Isla.
It is because of him.
I'm doing it because I don't want
to do anything to offend a spirit.
Now you're asking for my number.
The other day, you called me a madwoman.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
This is a family house. It's okay.
So can I have it now?
- 0-8-0-5.
- Okay, hold on.
My number. I'm sorry, just let me--
- I don't steal phones.
- I'm sorry.
I'm so excited.
Please don't go.
Tell him to wait,
and I'll be right back with my phone.
What's wrong with this one?
Listen, she's only excited
because you were rich when you were alive.
If you were from a poor home,
she would be different.
I think she loves you.
♪ I remember when I was nobody ♪
♪ When the going was rough and tough ♪
♪ I never thought I'll be somebody ♪
♪ I remember when I was nobody ♪
♪ When the going was rough and tough ♪
♪ I never thought I'll be somebody... ♪
I will punch you in the head!
Go back!
Don't come close to the musician!
I'll punch you in the head.
♪ I remember when I was nobody ♪
♪ I never thought I'll be somebody... ♪
I'm fed up.
I don't know
why this guy keeps following me around.
Saheed Osupa is singing,
and everybody is dancing.
This is what we've been
contributing money for since January.
I'm coming. Hold on.
Madam, I'm tired.
I cannot be stressing myself
because of you people!
Do you know what it means
to see Saheed Osupa and DJ Kano?
And your man came to tell me
he saw his killer on stage
and asked me to come and tell you.
- Calm down, breathe.
- I'm calm.
I've been paying 200 naira every month
just to pay for my carnival money.
Okay, I'm trying to figure this out.
You contribute 200 naira every--
for a carnival?
Yes! It's not like
I'm going to miss the carnival.
We're doing the carnival already,
we're dancing,
and like I just told you,
he wants me to come here.
I can't figure this out.
It's still mind boggling!
- Same here.
- Yes, it's confusing!
He said to tell you to call his friend,
- Da-- I can't--
- Dayo!
Yes, that you should call him.
You should call the police.
You should come to our carnival.
- That the person that killed him is there.
- Okay.
That's not the point! The point is
you're intruding into my privacy
- and it's paining me. I can't--
- I'm sorry.
Leave me alone. Don't touch me.
Stop acting like you're powerful.
Dayo. Yes.
Look, there's a problem.
You have to come over right away.
Now!
Well, she's raving. She's here.
My name is Isla.
I'm not raving.
- Don't go.
- Get out of my way, please!
I said carnival is on.
You're saying don't go.
It seems you haven't been punched before.
- Are you serious?
- Yes!
We need to do something now.
We need to do it quickly!
Do you believe this girl?
'Cause I've never seen anybody
that sees ghosts before.
Dayo, I believe her. I believe her.
If you had seen her,
- you'd have felt what I felt.
- Okay.
She said that after carnival,
we may lose him,
- so we need to do something now, now, now!
- Okay.
Okay, the first thing I will do
is call the police.
Me and the police will go.
Oh, fantastic. Fantastic.
Oh, God.
Hello, sir.
Yes, it's me, Mike's friend, that died.
Yes, sir,
I have very important information for you.
Are you in the office?
Yes, thank you. I'll see you now.
Thank you.
Okay, good.
What's the number of the lady
who sees ghosts?
- Hold on.
- So if we get there, we'll call.
Okay, that's it. 0-7-0, yeah.
All right,
so I'm definitely going with you.
- Right?
- Yes, sure. Wait, wait.
You're a lady. Why don't I go
with the police so you can be safe?
- No, I'm going with you.
- Don't worry.
The person who killed Mike
will not go free.
- No, he can't.
- Not here.
Someone killed my helper, my assistance.
They can't go scot-free!
Don't worry! I will see you.
God bless you!
Yes, yes, yes.
Finally.
What's up?
Ajebo, calm down. Listen.
- Calm down!
- Listen.
First and foremost, that's not my concern.
You've been over-dressing lately.
Lately-- Why are you showing off?
Do you want to expose us in this area?
Why do you act like this?
- Because I'm spending my money?
- Yes.
My share, my percent?
The one we all shared.
Can you believe this?
- I'm a Yoruba man and we like to show off.
- Shut up!
- So I'm jealous of you?
- You're very jealous.
Hey, hey, hey!
Hey! Police! Police!
Hey! Go back.
Stop the music. Stop the music.
Police! Hey, hey, hey!
Hey, police! Stop this!
I'm going home. The show is over!
I'm not performing again. I'm leaving.
I'm leaving. I'm leaving.
No more show!
No more show! I'm going!
I'm going! No more show!
No, no! Okay.
Hey!
Let's go there.
Hey, guys, guys!
No! I'm not here for that.
- Calm down.
- I'm not here for that!
You know you've messed up, right?
One of you has been talking.
- How do you mean?
- Don't ask me questions.
Do we look like Lasisi Elenu?
I said, which one of you has been
running their mouth about the Mike issue?
Mike? Mike is dead.
I've had doubts about you guys
right from the time I gave you this job.
Even now, you're talking
and exposing our dealings.
- Nobody is saying anything.
- Okay. None of you said anything?
Okay, let me ask you a question.
Who is seeing ghosts here?
Ghost?
- Do you see ghosts?
- I don't see ghosts.
- You see ghosts?
- Nobody does.
- Does anyone in your family?
- No.
- Whoever sees ghosts must die today.
- It shall be done.
I'll kill Adunni myself.
You guys will kill the one
who sees ghosts. Take her number.
Is this person crazy?
Relax, boss, we'll do the work for you.
Type the number.
Ajebo, type it quickly.
This is unbelievable.
Wow, Isla?
- Guys, the person is Isla.
- Isla?
Oh! I said it!
I knew you were the informant!
- Relax, boss!
- What's the problem?
- Don't you know Isla?
- Calm down.
- Kafila's friend. She's at the carnival.
Oh! Isla lives in this ghetto?
Okay, whether Isla or no Isla,
Kafila or no Kafila,
- you must kill Isla today.
- We're ready to get it done.
- I'm under a lot of pressure.
- What's wrong with you?
- What's wrong with me?
- Isla is also going to die.
Calm down.
All right. Now, kill Isla today
and I will kill Adunni today.
It shall be done.
Please, I can drive any car. I beg you.
There's no vacancy here.
Please, let me drop off
this application letter for the manager.
Let me tell you something.
That's the boss. Get him before he leaves.
- Is that him?
- That's him!
- Thank you.
- Go and meet him.
Greetings, sir.
- No, get up. Get up.
- No, let me talk like this, please.
- No, get up.
- Let me talk like this, please.
What's the problem? Get up.
Thank you. I'm looking for a job.
Please, any vacancy?
What's your qualification?
Higher National Diploma. I have a HND.
- HND?
- Yes?
- And you want to be a driver?
- What can I do?
There's no white-collar job.
- So if it's blue- or black-collar job--
- It's okay. It's okay.
This is my application letter.
- What did you study?
- Public Admin.
Public Administration!
Yes, I studied Public Administration.
And you want to be a driver!
My brother, sir,
if there is no white-collar job,
- any color job that's available, I'll do.
- Okay.
- Um...
- What is it?
- Okay, I have something for you.
- Thank you very much.
- Huh?
- I have something for you.
- For me?
- For you. Come on.
- I have something for you.
- Thank you.
- No! Don't do that.
- You don't know what you've done for me.
- No, it's fine.
- Take it easy.
- Thank you very much.
- Stop. Can you just stop doing that?
- Okay.
- Can you stop doing that?
- Okay, sir.
- Walk normal.
- Me?
- Yes. Walk normal. Now walk.
- Thank you, sir.
Hello, Dayo? How are you?
Okay, good.
Because of the sensitive nature
of this business,
as discussed and agreed earlier,
I'm writing you a check of 35 million
naira to be paid into your account.
Make sure you see to the transaction
with my client.
And remember,
this is strictly between you and I.
- Did you eat onions before coming here?
- Osas, talk to him.
- Guys.
- Calm down. How are you?
- Welcome, boss.
- How are you doing?
- What's up?
- I'm all right.
- Guys, I don't want any fuck-ups.
- No worries.
- Collect it.
- This is your payment.
- No fuck-ups, please.
- Ajebo, check it.
- No fuck-ups.
- This is the picture of the guy.
- I'll send it to your phone.
- Correct.
You understand. No fuck-ups, please!
- Don't worry. We got you.
- Finish him off quickly.
...you're telling me to leave?
Are you all crazy? Get in the car.
- Aren't you going to see them off?
- Why would I see them off?
Do I look like a guardian angel?
They've left already!
- Shut up!
- They've left! Leave me alone!
- Go! That's what I want.
- I'm not going.
You must do what I want. Go!
I won't cuddle you
because you don't deserve it.
No problem, I'm leaving.
There's no problem.
Hello?
Yes, the three of them are on their way.
Make sure you kill the three of them.
This guy isn't answering.
Hello. What happened?
- Hello, boss.
- Are you stupid?
I said kill the three of them.
Get away from my phone!
- New goods have arrived.
- Shh!
- I have a new phone for you.
- Exactly--
This one is iPhone S2ABC.
The phone was released just this morning.
Nobody's bought the phone yet.
What are the phone's features?
You talk too much.
This is not an ordinary phone.
It dials you by itself.
The phone would dial me itself?
You mean the phone has my number?
If the phone is in one room
and you're in another,
it will call you
to tell you someone called you.
- It's not like other phones.
- Stop shouting. Where is the phone?
Let me tell you its last feature.
If I tell you, you'll buy it on the spot.
The phone won't ask you for your name.
It already knows it.
- It knows my name?
- Yes. It will even sing for you.
Nkemjika?
I've been here since morning.
What's going on?
Can you see how valuable this phone is?
Are you sure you can afford it?
- How much is it?
- Let me see.
Wait. Let me bring it out.
It's a very expensive phone.
What is it again?
- Kill me?
- Yes!
Who are you talking to?
She's crazy.
Are you okay?
Did you drink alcohol?
See you guys later.
Just give me 37,000. Let's do it quickly.
Hello. Something just happened right now.
Where's Isla?
- Where is Isla?
- Who is Isla?
- What is Isla?
- Where is Isla?
- Who is Isla?
- Who?
- Where is Isla?
- Hey, stop shouting. Are you okay?
- Are you mad?
- Where is Isla?
- Are you selling goods?
Do you want to buy a phone?
I have phones for sale.
He drank a lot of gin.
He's drunk and high.
Come on. Let's go.
DJ Kano, let's do it!
There's no point coming here
to fight or shout.
Because right now,
your man just came to meet me,
that they want to kill me.
He said it was his best friend
that killed him.
What?
What is this? Leave me alone!
We're talking about death.
You're talking about hug.
- I guess you're not the cuddly type.
- What's "cuddly type"?
I've been drinking since morning.
There's nothing in my tummy.
I just came to let you know
that I'm stuck with you.
Nobody is going anywhere.
I don't know what I did.
Anyway, he said I should tell you
that it's his best friend that killed him.
And they want to kill me, too.
Wait, wait, wait. Wait, hold on.
What did you just say now?
He said his best friend
is the one that killed him.
No, no. No, he--
- Did somebody follow you?
- Nobody.
- Are you sure?
- I'm dead!
- Calm down.
- I'm calm.
Okay.
Call this number.
It's the police. Just go in there,
call the number. I'll handle it.
Shh. Be strong. Be strong.
He said I should tell you
that there's 35 million naira with him.
Yes, yes. Who's that?
Take a look at this perfume collection.
It smells great.
I'm in trouble!
Just about to get it.
- Dayo!
- I told you.
I told you it's a lie!
That girl seeing ghosts is shady.
She's scheming with some guys
to swindle you.
- I told you, you have to relax.
- What?
They're planning to get to know you,
see what you have and come and--
- What?
- Yes!
Is this a boutique?
This lady has enough clothes and perfume
to kill anyone.
This one is like water.
I'm in trouble!
If I owned this place,
I would die and rise every day.
She said I should...
I'm in trouble! The phone is locked!
I'm in trouble!
The phone is locked. The phone is locked.
Her phone is locked.
Let me go and-- Huh?
Wait. Aha.
Call the police.
That girl is a scammer.
See, Adunni, you need to be very careful.
You need to be very careful.
If you hear anything about Mike's death,
just call me.
Okay? That girl is a scammer.
I need to go because there's
so many things I should do.
I need to go, but just be careful.
She's a scammer.
- Okay.
- Dayo, hold on.
What do you know about 35 million naira?
Did Mike give you any 35 million naira?
No, he didn't give me 35 million naira.
I lent him 35 million naira as a friend.
Because he's dead now,
there's nothing I can do about it.
I let go of the 35 million naira.
- I lent him 35 million naira.
- Dayo.
- Did he tell--
- Dayo?
- Yes?
- What do you know about Mike's death?
Mr. Policeman, pick up your phone.
You're not the only one
that likes Saheed Osupa. What's going on?
I'm dead today. That's for sure.
I'm dead!
Mr. Policeman.
This is Isla. Go to a quiet place.
Get away from the noise. I can't hear you.
Mr. Policeman.
I'm not at the carnival. I left.
I'll tell you everything.
I went somewhere to help someone,
but now my life is in danger.
The lady said that the person outside
has bad intentions towards us.
She asked me to call the police,
but her phone is locked.
We're in Lekki Phase 1.
Bashy Street. Number 5.
Mr. Policeman, I don't understand.
Ijora, Lekki Phase 1.
Mr. Policeman, don't be like this.
You keep saying police is our friend,
but you don't know where we live.
Leave me alone.
I don't want to die. I don't want to die.
I still don't want to die.
I don't want to die.
Adunni, we're all looking for the killer.
Mike, my assistance, my helper,
we're looking for his killer.
Sorry for the interruption.
Your perfume smells nice.
You said I should call the police,
but your phone is locked. So I called--
- Hey! You called the police?
- Oh, my God!
What are you doing with a gun?
Come out here!
So you're the one seeing ghosts?
- I'm not seeing anything.
- You're the one seeing ghosts?
Dayo, calm down! You have a gun?
Okay, yes! Yes!
- Let me tell you.
- Just--
- Ohh!
- Calm down, everybody!
I'm the one holding the gun,
and you're telling me to calm down!
You're very foolish!
Let me tell you something.
You're the one seeing ghosts, right?
Ghost seer!
I've never in my life
seen a ghost.
- Shut up!
- It's the ghost that's seeing me.
Let me tell you something
if you want to hear.
I killed Mike. Yes!
I killed him. Yes, because I envy him.
I'm jealous of Mike!
What is it?
Is Mike the only man in the world?
Mike's father, very rich.
Mike himself, very rich!
- He was your best friend!
- Will you shut up?
- If you say that again, I'll shoot you.
- I'm sorry.
Please let me go. I'm not part of this.
Mike gives me money to pay
whenever he buys something.
He thinks I'm a fool.
He has already told everyone
that I'm spending his money.
Mike! He must die in heaven again.
I'll sit on the 35 million naira!
How could you kill your best friend?
If you say that again, I'll blow your--
See, I will not kill you with gun.
Do you have shaving powder?
I'll put shaving powder
for the two of you.
- Do you have shaving powder?
- She has-- I have.
Let me go get it from my house. I have--
- Come back here!
- I'm dead!
You think I'm a fool?
- We don't think you're a fool.
- No. Don't worry.
You know that I killed Mike.
So you have to die.
The two of you have to die!
Wait!
Yes!
Who called the police?
- She called the police.
- I-- You--
Stop this! Why did you call the police?
It is a toy gun!
I was only kidding with you!
Is this how you behave?
These people are stupid.
I can use the rifle
better than you.
Hey! Hold it there!
I'll punch your eye!
Hey! Shut up!
Back up. Come on, come on.
Come on.
Calm down.
Who's talking?