[Music]
- Good citizensof westerville,
I come to you this dayas our nation is on the
precipice of war.
Now, some of you here ifought with 15 years ago
in the war with Mexico.
I commanded you then, buti come to you today not as
your officer, butas your neighbor,
your friend andfellow patriot.
Our nation is endangeredby the same imperialism as
it was when we marchedthrough Texas.
Will we do no less whenthat danger is on
our very soil.
[Applause]
Ladies and gentlemen,welcome with me now
bishop William hanby.
[Applause]
- As many of you know,prior to my founding the
otterbein college,i traveled over 4,000
miles on thecircuit in one year.
During my travels, I sawmuch injustice and hate.
It has made me a man ofstrong convictions,
and I founded thecollege to serve others,
and it included within itswalls men and women
of all races.
I have made my voice knownand shown my scorn for
injustice, and I willcontinue to stand against
any law that makes it afelony to give food to a
hungry slave or be friendprecious men, women,
and children whodeserve freedom.
The fugitive slave lawof 1850 is inhumane.
It is absurd that givingshelter to a friendless
man, woman, orchild is a crime.
We may be boundby a man made law,
but we are more bound bya lord-given conscience.
Ohio has alwaysbeen a free state.
It was the first statein the union to outlaw
slavery in itsconstitution.
We should stand as boldas the writers
of that constitution!
Today, many of you willjoin the union army,
and you shallbe that bold.
May god bless you as youmake your choice to stand
for the freedom of all!
- How can a christianminister stand on that
platform and support thebreaking of the law!?
- Especially a law thatprotects the property
of a person.
- A human being cannot besomeone's property!
- When a man-made law isin conflict with god's
law, there isno compromise.
We choose oneway or the other.
- You are nothing buta freedom crusader!
- It says injoshua 24:15,
"choose you this daywhom you shall serve.
As for me and my house,we shall serve the lord!"
[Applause]
[Music]
- Good day, dalin.
I understand you havea package for me?
- Yes, from Clay.
Wait here, I'll recordit in my log books,
and you can beon your way.
- Hello, Audrey.
- Hello, Emery. Are you here topick up a package from Clay?
- Yes, I am. He said
he'd be sending afew items home before
he headed off to war.
- I see.
- Which is somethingwe need to talk about.
- No, we cannot talkabout this right now.
- Now, Audrey you know...
- Not now. There are a lot ofpeople here who need you.
- It will be fine.
We can talkabout this later. Audrey?
- You know how I feelabout this, Audrey.
- What do you mean?
- Any day, Clay will get hisgear and head into battle.
- But it's not just aboutyour brother, is it?
What about bishop hanby?
What about theunderground railroad?
- This is about theunderground railroad.
This is for thecause of freedom.
- So Emery is joiningthe war, as well?
- If he does,dalin Wright,
I don't believe that isany of your business.
- Well, with Emery gone,who is to take care of
Clay's responsibilities?
- I will take thepackage to Emery.
Thank you, Mr. Wright.
[Music]
- I would haveanother piece,
if you girls hadn'teaten it all.
[Laughing]
- Thank you, sis.
Is there another piehiding in the kitchen?
- No, no, Jackson,just the one,
which is all you need.
- Thank you, ma'am,it was delicious.
- Well, thankyou, Samuel.
I'm glad you liked it.
Come on, girls, comehelp me in the kitchen.
- Sir, I cannotthank you enough.
You have saved my life.
- You're welcome, god haspurposed me to help those
in bondage reach freedom.
- Ripley, Ohio is alegendary
place among slaves.
Your story's spreadingthroughout the south.
- I wonder if thosestories eclipse reality?
- I am proof they do not.
They say there's a placejust north of the Ohio
river of the it'sthe promised land.
They say if you wantto escape slavery,
head through Kentucky andfollow the north star.
There's a light on top ofa hill that will
lead you to freedom.
- Tell me aboutyourself, Sammy.
- I have come from aplantation where I
was a house slave.
I can read and writeboth english and French.
My master passed away, Andi was left to
his youngest son.
He was a cruelman to my people.
He sold me to hisfriend in Kentucky,
and after crossingthe Kentucky border,
I broke free from mychains and escaped
in the night.
- I am excited that god hasdirected you here. He's good.
- Yes, he is.
- My sister willpack you some food,
and I will explain to youyour next steps in your
journey to Canada, andyou can be on your way.
- Sir, I cannot leave.
- You cannot stay. It'snot safe here at all.
The men who were chasingyou last night regularly
come across theriver into Ohio.
- I have a sister thatwas sold to another man in
Kentucky, as well.
We have promised to meetacross the Ohio river,
and whoever made it firstis to wait on the other.
It is our plan.
- Samuel, do you realizewhat you're saying?
Kentucky is a large state.
Bounty huntersare everywhere.
The border ofohio runs long.
Do you have any ideawhere in Kentucky she is?
And do you have any ideahow long this could take?
- No, I know howabsurd it sounds,
but you yourself saidgod directed me here.
I have faith that he'll dothe same for my sister.
I'll help theothers while I wait.
- Well, I can't verywell argue with that.
- It's all right, little fella.We're here to help you.
We have a boat andeverything is
going to be fine.
You are free.
- Get to the boat.
[Gunshots]
- His name is Abe.
- He's the only one?
- Yes, the othersmust have been caught.
- God will makea way for him.
He'll have a home soon.
- Jackson's at the boat.
We're going backacross for the others.
- So Clay, where's Emery?
- At home.
- Ah, I see. So maybe we'll bein the same company, yeah?
- Yes.
- Cousin, you're going tohave to accept it if
Emery wants to join.
- No, he needsto stay home.
- You boys are withcompany c of the 14th Ohio?
- Yes.
- Well, I'm yourfirst sergeant,
sgt. reicheldeifer.
Let me show you howto wear your traps.
- Traps?
- That's what we callyour equipment
in this army.
Now, take yourcartridge box swing,
put it over your head.
Put the cartridge boxon your right hip.
That's it. Now take your belts.
Make sure that you put iton with the bayonet on
the left and the capbox on the right.
- Like this, sergeant?
- Exactly like that.
You boys are take itjust like veterans.
I think you will bothmake right fine soldiers.
- How can someone keeptrack of all of
this and march?
- Don't worryabout it, son.
We'll make surethat you do.
- Don't be afraid.
My father's stationmaster, William hanby.
I will help you.
- Anna, you startled me.
- Come on, Ruth,we must get home.
- I will not leave untili lead them to the barn.
- Ruth, look at me. Focus.
You can't run away fromme like this again.
I told you, there is abounty hunter in
this area now.
You have to stay with me.
- A bounty hunteraround here?
- Yes, now youknow the danger.
We must go back to dinner.
Father will comeback to help them.
- No, please,don't leave us.
- I will not go until ilead them to the barn.
I will not eat until ihave given them bread.
- Okay, butwe must hurry.
- Come on, we'll helpyou, and you'll be safe.
- Now, you just stay hereuntil my father comes.
You are safe now, andhe'll know what to do.
- Thank you so much.
- You both need to rest.
- Someone will bring youinto the house for food in
the morning.
- Just close youreyes and rest.
Everything will be fine,and you will see
freedom's light soon.
- Where haveyou two been?
You both misseddinner, and Lizzie,
you have strawon your clothes.
- We helped them, jennie.
- Girls, wherehave you been?
Ruth, you have strawon your clothes.
- We helped them, mother.
- Helped who?
- Obviously you've beenout helping runaways again.
- Yes, but I went out andfound her, and she's fine.
She led the runaways tothe barn and give them
food and water.
- Yes, and itwas exciting.
- Was it?
- It was wonderful.
- Yes, but the bountyhunter has made helping
the runaways evenmore dangerous.
- As excitingas it may be,
and as much as we allbelieve in our cause,
it's simply too dangerousfor you to be running
around in the woods.
- Especially with thebounty hunter in the area.
- Besides, that'sfather's job, Ruth.
- And clearly there'stoo much of him in you.
- The Bible says thatruth was born for
such a time as this.
- Lizzie, thatwas Esther.
- But that goesfor me, too. Right?
- What can I say to this?
- Dear Emery,as I write you,
I sit outside my tent in camp.
I am happy to be here with my cousin Reed,
and I am very happy you are at home with Liza.
I have established friendships with several
other men, as well.
Their names are John billings, Daniel Lewis,
Isaac Griffith and Jacob wolf.
I suspect that we shall all remain close
throughout the struggle ahead.
We have made ourselves at home, and as I settled in,
I think of mother and father.
I smile when I remember how excited they were
about the free soil party and how proud I think they
would be that I am fighting for the cause.
I can still hear them arguing with dull faces
that free men on free sale made for a morally and
financially better way than the way of slavery.
I remember when mother called them weak, timid,
half-baked men.
I think being here makes a person sentimental
of fond memories.
I think of how our family once had been as I look
into the faces of these men of courage.
- I can see Liza'sface, as well.
That sweet smile of mysister warms me as I think
of myself and all of thesemen preparing for the
battles thatlie before us.
- We have set up camp near the b and o railroad,
and I have found that the 14th Ohio is
filled with great men.
At this point, we're so confident that we feel we
could single handedly defeat the entire
confederate army.
Stay safe and true to the cause, your brother, Clay.
- Talia, what areyou doing here?
Did you escape onlyto be caught again?
- I will not let mysisters be
taken to Kentucky.Where's Nellie?
- She's in anotherwagon somewhere.
We're going together tonight.Now you must go.
- How can ileave you two?
- Quickly, that's how.
Even if you save me, wemay not reach Nellie.
We can't let her go alone.
She's only a child.
I will stay with Nellie,and you will be free.
Your spiritshall be strong,
and your feetshall be quick.
Your path shall beordered by the lord.
- Yes, estelle,i understand.
- We have our ordersfrom miss Van lew,
Nellie and I willescape into Ohio,
and I will telegraph adinsheridan in westerville.
That is what willhappen, Talia.
- Yes, we willall be free.
[Music]
- Did you understandthe telegraph?
It made no sense to meas I was writing it.
- Yes, I understandit clearly.
I'd like to senda reply, please.
- Yes, of course, bishop.
- Adin Sheridan willarrive in Richmond in
three days.Have package ready.
- I am going to Virginia?
- Yes, i'llexplain outside.
- Are you ready for yourfirst job as a conductor?
- Yes, sir,what's going on?
- This is a codedtelegraph from your friend
Elizabeth vanlew in Richmond.
She has a passenger namedtalia who is to come here.
- Why westervilleand not Philadelphia?
- She is to meet hersister estelle in Ohio.
Miss Van lew believes thatbecause your family is
from Richmond, you shouldbe able to travel with the
run away and not raisetoo many suspicions.
They'll be paying hermaster for a week of
skilled labor.
- How will I getthe passenger here?
- Miss Van lew haspurchased two train
tickets to parkersburg.
The girl will have paperswith her stating you paid
her master for the labor.
No questionsshould be asked.
- How will I gether into westerville?
No one here will believei purchased a slave.
- There is an undergroundrailroad station on the
Ohio river nearparkersburg.
They will put her in acrate and place her on a
freight trainthe next day.
You'll travel fromparkersburg by stage
coach, and the trip forour package should take
about 15 hoursto Columbus.
From there, it will travelby wagon and arrive
here a few hours later.
- I can do this, bishop.- Very good.
You have someone youcan visit in Richmond?
- Yes, I do, and they'recommitted southerners.
- Well, that'sbad for them,
but good for our cover.
- Thank you for having Liza andme over for dinner, Audrey.
- You're very welcome, Emery.I love having Liza.
- Oh, I see, partiality shown toyour little best friend.
- I believe it's prettyclear that
I'm Audrey's favorite.
- Yes, Liza's right.
No more pie untilafter dinner.
- Sometimes I think i'mthe oldest person
in our house.
- Well, I'm oldenough to get the mail,
and we received aletter from Clay today.
- Don't get anyideas, Emery.
With Clay gone, now bishophanby needs you working
the underground railroad.
- I'm just concerned thatclay's joining the Yankees
to persuade youto do the same.
- I believe ihave a say in that.
- Yes, but clayinfluences you.
- What influences me ispresident Lincoln's
call for troops.
- I realize thingsare getting worse,
and obviously I supportthe north and
what we believe in.
I am just concerned aboutthe two of you leaving
Liza here alone.
- She wouldn't be alone.
She has you.
- Yes, Audrey, you'relike a sister to me.
- And you're like asister to me, too, Liza.
And if both of yourbrothers go off to war,
I will take care of you.
- We can makebread every day.
- Yes, Liza,that sounds fun.
- Well, I guessthat settles that.
- Emery, you'vealready had two pieces.
- Dalin, what is this?- A new hat.
- But you haveto return this.
We need food much morethan I need a hat.
- No, you need anew hat, Julianna.
No more people will lookdown on us
because we are poor.
- None of our friendshave ever looked
down on us, dalin.We need food.
- As for food, I havethat covered, as well.
- Where did youget all of this?
- It is my job to get allof this, little sister.
- By doing what?
- It is your job to cook,not to ask
unnecessary questions.
- You promised me thatyou would never steal again.
- Ha, I did notsteal anything.
Quite the opposite,actually.
- Really? well, I must say...
It is a beautiful bonnet.
- It is nice, is it not?
- You know, I never sawmy sister when
we were growing up.
Even though I was a houseslave, and she was a maid.
But soon she'll becrossing the Ohio river,
and we'll bereunited once again.
- I'm looking forward tomeeting Molly very much.
- You'll get along great.
[Children laughing]
- Now young ladies,you haven't fooled me.
[Laughing]
- Lillian, are youexcited about staying with
temperance yetagain tonight?
By the way, temperance,i will be sending your
mother in for these toes.
[Laughing]
- I was next doorto your house,
and I got the girlsall tucked in.
Temperance stillhas your shoes on.
- Ah, not again.
- Yes, and I warned themyou'd be in
for their toes.
Thank you so much, netta.
Lillian loves tostay with temperance.
- Of course, welove having her.
I guess I'll go nextdoor get those toes.
- How did you cometo care for Lillian?
- I was in kentuckyhelping Jackson and John
Parker with runaways.
Jackson had boarded a boatto help the runaways get
on, and I was in the woodhelping a 16 year old girl
and her small sister.
Her sister was Lillian,and she was
three at the time.
Slave catcherswere chasing us,
and I could hear thedogs getting closer.
I was carrying Lillian andrunning ahead to
lead the way.
The dogs caught hersister's dress and pulled
her to the ground.
She shouted atme to keep running.
When we arrivedat the boat,
I could hear hershouting,
"go, Lillian. Live free!"
- Slavery has tornapart so many families,
even my own.
My husband was taken bybounty hunters in an
escape attemptmuch like yours.
It is an abomination thatwill take this country
over a century to recoverfrom, if even then.
I'm thankful for mybrother Jackson.
- I promised that I wouldlook after her for the
rest of my days.
I love her as if she weremy own flesh and blood.
- I'm excited aboutmy letter from Clay.
- Why don'tyou read the letter,
and we will have some pie?
- My dearest Liza, iwanted to take a moment to
write you and tell you ofthe exciting events that
have taken placewith the 14th.
As we marched through the town of Beverly,
we were showered with flowers by the children.
I thought of you, little sister,
and knew you would have loved to be here.
The flowers showered over us like a blessed rain.
Is that not wonderful,miss Audrey?
- It soundsbeautiful, Liza.
What else does it say?
- We have stopped outside of marietta and are now
being showered with pies.
The patriotic hands of the women have treated our
regiment, and the men are cheering loudly.
We are experiencing yet another blessing from the
people of this area.
I must close now so I can finish my pie.
I think of Audrey and her pies at home.
Could these pies compete?
They are certainly close. Your loving brother, Clay.
Mmmmm.
- I see you'rewearing your new hat?
- Yes, I do love it.- You have plans?
- If it's all right, i'dlike to go over to
Ruth's andspend the night?
- That's fine, I haveto work tonight anyway.
- At theshipping company?
- No, I have a few otherthings I'm working on.
- Oh, okay. You have your gun?
- Yes, for safety.
I hear there's a bountyhunter in the area.
- I've heardthat, as well.
- Actually, i'mleaving right now,
so I will see youtomorrow, all right?
- Yes, I will seeyou tomorrow, bye.
- Good bye,julianna, have fun.
- I can't findthem anywhere.
- What are youtalking about Sammy?
- I'm talking aboutkicking someone
in the trousers.
- Now, why wouldyou do that?
- Because my pillow andblanket are missing.
- I'm sure there's areasonable explanation, Sammy.
- Nothing is reasonablewith a boy like me.
- I can surelyagree with that.
- Well?- well what, Sammy?
- My pillow and blanket.
- Samuel, youare ten years old.
That is plenty old enoughto keep track of your
own pillow and blanket.
- I did, I hung them outthe window to air out.
- You did what?
- I put my pillow and myblanket and hung
them out the window.Clearly will
has put his feet on them.They smelled foul.
- Did they fallon the ground?
- I looked on the ground,they weren't there.
Whoever has taken themwill surely regret it.
- There we are- oh, my, Lizzie.
- I gathered every extrapillow and blanket
in the house.
- I would say so.
- And it was thestrangest thing, mother.
- What was?
- I found a pillow andblanket in the backyard,
so I brushed them off andtook them to the barn
for the runaways.
- I believe thosewere Sammy's.
- Getting ready foryour camp in I see.
- Yes, it's so excitingto have all of my
friends here tonight.
- You will all behaving a good time.
- It will be fun.
- Have you or your motherseen Sammy's
pillow and blanket?
He's threatened toput the thief in the stockades.
- There's Liza!
Come with me, Liza.
We'll prepare campand then have apricot biscuits.
- Oh, yum.
- Clarissa bell andjulianna will be here soon.
- Emery, good evening.- Good evening, bishop.
Thank you for allowingliza to spend the night here.
- Of course,you're welcome.
- George stoner's wagonis ready to take a group
of runaways north to thenext station tonight.
I'm going to meet threeof the cargo here in
the woods later on.
- Very good. I will have willand Sammy take food
and water to the barn.
- Can you pleasecalm down, Sammy?
- Sisters are bed bugs.
- You're overreacting, Sam.
- I have my suspicions.
I believe Lizzie has takenmy pillow and blanket and
given them to her friends.
- Well, you did hangthem outside the window.
- That's not an openinvitation for some bed
bug to take them.
- Here, bedbug, take mine.
- Not a chance,they smell all foul.
- Boys, we have a groupof runaways coming in tonight.
I need you to takesupplies to the barn.
- I will go see if ican find the conductor.
You wait here.
- Okay.
- [Both] Lizzie.
- I knew she took mypillow and blanket.
- That's not importantright now, Sam.
Put the suppliesover here.
Go get the blankets.
[Gunshot]
- A gun?- How close was that?
- Close!- I think very close.
- Ruth, take your friendsto the cellar with
your mother and sisters.
Quickly, girls,stay low, stay low!
Ann, get all thegirls to the cellar.
- Girls, girls!
- Gunshots equal danger.
- Gunshots equalsomeone needs help!
[Gunshots]-two gunshots, double danger!
- Someone out thereneeds our help!
Now, are you comingwith me or not?
- I am.- Let's go.
- Get over here!
[Gunshot]
- I said get over here!
- No!
- How many ofyou are there?
- I won't tell you.- How many?
- There are thousandsand thousands of us,
and you can never stop us.
- Yes, but I'll get$150 for stopping you.
And I'm about to getanother $150
for your friend.
- No, you won't.
- We'll see about that.
We will see about that.
*
- Emery, you move up aheadand see what you can find.
I will turn here and gofor the boys in the barn.
- Okay.
- Don't be afraid.I'm your conductor.
You're almost toyour next station.
Walk straight that wayquietly 100 yards.
In the clearing, you'llfind a large barn.
Inside there'sfood and water.
Someone will meetyou there soon.
Go now. Quickly!
- Are you all right?
- Yes.
- We're the sons ofthe station master
and we'll help you.
- Stop right there!
- Okay, okay,that is enough!
- Dalin, Wright?
- Emery?
- What are youdoing out here?
- I heard shots and ithought someone needed her.
What are youdoing out here?
- I heard theshots as well.
You didn't fire them?
They sounded like theycame from a revolver.
- No. I saw a man with arevolver run south
to the woods.
He was shorter than mewith light colored hair.
- Well stay safe then.
- You the same Emery.
- And try not toshoot me next time.
- Oh, I will try.
[Girls giggling]
- I am so excited to behaving this special
tea party with all ofyou for breakfast.
Anyone for tea?
- Yes, please.
- Oh, yes.
- What do you thinkabout last night?
- I think if there's abounty hunter around here,
we should findout who it is.
- You think weshould find out?
- Yes. it is aperfect plan.
A bounty hunter wouldnever expect a
group of girls to belooking for him.
- I would notexpect it either.
- I think itis a great idea.
- We should getstarted right away.
- And I have experiencein this area.
Once I caught johnnytaking an apple from
miss Audrey's orchardbehind her house.
- There's a bigdifference between a boy
taking an apple and a manin the woods with a gun.
- Very good,clarissa-bell.
The first clue.
- The bountyhunter has a gun.
- I think we knew that.
- Yes. what men intown have a gun?
- Seriously?
- Pretty muchall of them.
- Let's go into the woods
and begin lookingfor clues now!
- Yes!
Let us all go runaround the woods in
our nice dresses andlook for clues.
- Any ideas?
- Maybe we should splitup and two of us go
in that direction.
- Maybe you andjulianna head that way.
- So I'll go with Ruth
and Liza will gowith Julianna.
- We need a signal.
- My brothers usuallywhistle loudly.
- Who herewhistles loudly?
- I guess I can.
- Let's hear.
[Screaming]
[Silence]
- Perhaps we should justyell for one another.
- Clarissa-bell,look at this.
- I will bethere shortly.
- Hurry! hurry!
It looks like arope and scarf.
I am sure it's a clue.
- It looks rather dirty.
- Yes, it does.
- Ruth, you're gettingyour drawers dirty.
- How can you careabout drawers
at a time like this?
*
- hello, girls. Didyou find any clues?
- I think we did.
We found thisrope and scarf.
- Where'd you find that?
- It was beside atree in the woods
so I got down andpicked it up.
- So let me guess yougot your drawers dirty.
- Yes, sheabsolutely did.
- Yes, but I thinkwe're much closer to
finding out who thebounty hunter is.
- And I suppose we'regoing to continue
until we find him.
- I know thisis a good thing.
We'll be cautious
and we'll always tell youtwo what we are up to.
- And your brothers too.
Remember that is the deal.
- Yes. our brothers.
- And remember, Liza'sbrother will help too.
- I have no brothers.
- You can have mine!
[Laughing]
- Dear bishop hanby, thank you for showing me
the meaning of faithfulness.
I have watched your uncompromised stand to god
and for what you believe.
Your family has been faithful to Emery,
Liza and me.
I will fight for freedom and above all be faithful
to the lord who is faithful to me.
I want you to know that I intend on being faithful
to this noble cause.
I promise to defend my country against treason
and conspiracies and to vindicate honor to our
glorious stripes and stars.
The last few days have been days
that I'll never forget.
We've been marching without pause toward
philippi, Virginia.
The men were exhausted and in want for water,
food and rest.
Even then, the 14th are ready to fight.
We knew and hoped that we would smell
gunpowder soon.
Scouts were sent out regularly.
My cousin, Reed, and I were honored to be
chosen for such a mission.
- Quietly.
Quiet, quiet, quiet.
Quiet, boys.
Quiet.
Come on, quiet.
Quiet boys.
Quiet!
The enemy could be justdown over there and we
don't want them knowingwe're here, do we?
Okay. Clay, Reed, Jacob,i want you to go down
this road here, easealong the woods,
see if you can seethe enemy down there.
Go ahead and take off yourhaversacks and canteens.
I don't want nothingclanging around.
All right, if you guyssee anything down there,
send one of youback to report.
The other two just keepan eye on them, okay?
Let's go.
Be cautious.
Keep your eyes down.
- We scouted ten miles that night and never saw
any rebels, however we did see
where they had burned Bridges.
There was only the reflection of water where
they had once stood.
I ask that you follow me and my company
with your prayers.
Pray that I am an example of patriotism,
that if we should need reinforcements,
I may inspire others to enroll as faithful
defenders of the union.
We in the 14th Ohio volunteers have pledged
ourselves to a no more noble sacrifice than to
further peace for all men no matter their color
and for our government's enduring honor.
I must now close as my regimen has been told
to remove all that is encombering us.
We're making a large pile of napsacks, haversacks,
blankets and all our articles so we can move
on in double quick time.
We should arrive near philippi at daybreak.
My best to you and your family.
Yours, Clay.
- We need to rememberclay in our prayers.
*
- please, is anyone there?
Is this the station?
Please!
I'm a passenger and i'vebeen sent by an agent.
I've been chased in thenight by slave cathcers
and have lost my conductor.
I've been followingthe north star.
- Come sit down.
I will get you some bread.
My name is Molly.
- I'm estelle.
But I will singof thy power,
yea, I will sing aloud ofthy mercy in the morning,
for thou has been mydefense and refuge
in the days of my trouble.
- You can read?
- I learned to when I wasyoung and lived in Virginia.
- My brother can read.
His name is Samuel and i'mmeeting him in Ohio soon.
He has promisedto teach me how.
- I'm on myway to Ohio too.
I'm going to meet mysister, Talia, there.
- Perhaps wecan go together.
There is to be a boatat the Ohio river
in three nights.
- Yes. yes, iwould love to go.
- I'm really happy tohelp Jackson and the
runaways, but I just keepthinking of my sister.
- You'll have to keepyour focus, Samuel.
Keep focused on yourfreedom and the
freedom of others.
One at a time, we willhelp set them free.
- But I just keepthinking that--
- no, keep your focus.
The promise landis obtainable now.
Israel was caught inslavery for hundreds of
years and walked inthe desert away
from the promise.
Do not let your mindget caught there.
- You're right.
I can't let my focus becontrolled by my emotions.
And I have to keep myfaith that Molly will find
freedom just as I have.
- Free yourself from thephilosophy of slavery.
See yourself as free.
See Molly as free.
With that focus, Samuel,the lord will strengthen
you with his faith.
You will be able to seewith the eye of faith.
- You find any tracks?
- Yeah. I think so.
- Look at this.
- John parkeris a wanted man.
And we who are withhim are just as
valuable to him.
- $1,000 dollars?
Who has that much money?
- I'm sure the localslave owners
have gotten together.
- It doesn'y saywhere to take them.
- The bounty hunterswouldn't know where to
take any of us.
- Then why post flyers?
- To use fear as aweapon to stop us.
[Gunfire in distance]
- Sounds like somebody'sout here besides us.
- Okay. we go togethertowards the shot.
I'll distract thebounty hunters and
you help the runaway.
- Where's the north star?
- It's okay, ma'am.We're here to help you.
We have a boatat the river
and we'll take you across.
- But I was being chased.
- We must get tothe boat quick.
- Here's some water.
This will warm you.
Would you like some bread?
- Do you needanything else?
- Oh, no. Not rightnow, ma'am.
You've done so much.
- Okay. just restfor a moment.
- Happy is he that haththe god of Jacob for his
help whose hope is the inlord his god which made
heaven and earth, the seaand all that therein is.
Which keepeth truthforever, which execute
judgment for theoppressed which give
food to the hungry.
The lord looseththe prisoners.
- I am so thankful.
- We will help you get tothe next station, Isabelle.
Don't worry.
- The lord blessthee and keep thee.
The lord make his faceshine upon thee and be
gracious unto thee.
The lord lift up hiscountenance upon thee
and give thee peace.
- The lord willprotect you,
Isabelle, and getto you Canada.
- My brother Emery, I have just finished
fighting in the battle of philippi.
I could hear your voice encourage me.
After leaving behind much of our gear,
we marched on to philippi in double time.
There was a woman favoring the rebs
that spotted us and fired a pistol at us.
This started our Cannon fire.
As we advanced on the town those rebs
were not ready for us.
It was a site of victory.
The confederates were asleep from the effect of
their whiskey and the convincing tones of
our artillery finally awakened them
to their perilous situation.
The rebs began running from their tents
as they attempted to dress.
- Don't worry aboutyour fancy stuff, boys!
Grab your guns and go!
The Yankees are coming!
- Come on boys, come on!
- The value of the spoil was amazing.
It was quite a contrast, as before this, we had
nothing to eat but hard bread and raw ham.
Now the camp is filled with activity,
food and laughter although we're dealing with picket
fire nightly and ready for more battles ahead.
I'm finding that my time with the 14th Ohio
has changed me.
I know I'm a more noble man.
I know I will stand strong in the next battle
that lies ahead.
Your brother, Clay.
That's it.
What do you think?
- It was a veryinteresting story.
- Yes. it was.
- I'm sure the graybacks won't always
be so foolish.
- There will be strugglesahead without a doubt.
- And you need to go.
- Yes. I do.
I can't sit hereany longer while
Clay is out there.
This is everythingthat Clay and I have.
It will be enough tohelp you take care
of Liza for a long time.
- Emery, youdon't have to.
- Yes. I do.
- How will youget to Clay?
- I know a chaplain whois going to meet
the 14th Ohio tomorrow.
I'm going with him.
- Okay, so we need to goover what we know now.
- Well, we havea rope and scarf.
- I took the scarfto the general store.
Mrs. young said thatit is a fabric
and pattern they sell.
- Did you ask her whoshe had sold it to?
- Yes, and she couldn'tremember exactly.
However they were allpeople she knew from town.
- Did she havereceipts of the sales?
- Oh, yes, but she told Mei shouldn't be so nosey.
- What about the rope?
- Not at thegeneral store.
- I checked at the horsestable in town.
There's nothing like it.
- I checked the Baker andblacksmith and did not
see anything like it.
- You checkedthe blacksmith?
- Yes. he seemed tothink it odd I was so
interested in his work.
- Well, we need tofind this rope in town.
There has to be moreof it somewhere.
- I heard Emery tell willthat the gun that was
fired in the woodswas a revolver.
He said there weren't toomany people in town
who own revolvers.
- That's good to know.
- I think we shouldfollow the money.
- What do you mean?
- Someone in town shouldhave a lot more money.
- That's true.
There are reports of fourrunaways being caught.
Maybe we shouldcheck with the bank.
- I don't think Mr. ripinat the bank will help us.
We need to keep a lookoutfor a man with a new
wagon or clothes orsomething that shows
he's got money.
- Are you okay Julianna?
- Oh, yes. I justhad an idea.
I will look into it later.
- Good day, Anna,will, adin.
- Good day, Mr. Wright.
- I suppose you'rehere for your parcel.
- We were hopingit came today.
- It's much larger thanyour previous deliveries.
- It's a very large order,
but we'reexcited about it.
- So what do you do withall this new fabric?
I never see the hanbygirls in any new dresses.
- We like to collectit when we can.
- I do believe weshould get going.
- Yes, my mother'slooking forward to
receiving the parcel.
- Yes, of course.
Let me give yougentlemen a hand.
- No, no. That won'tbe necessary.
Adin and willcan handle it.
- All right then.If you say so.
- Yes, we'll be fine.Thank you.
- Are you allright in there?
- Yep. I'm okay.
- Can you hurry please.
- Coming.
- Hang on. Onlya moment longer.
Be cautious.Don't hurt her.
- Help her up.
- I don't think I can stand.
- Here you go.
- Thank you, ma'am.
- Adin and I will go tellmother and father
that she's here.
- Very good.
- Oh, no ma'am. Youdon't have to do that.
- Please justcall me Anna.
- Yes, ma'am.I mean miss Anna.
- Are you all right?
- Yes, miss Anna. I am.
To be free.
Thank the lord to be free.
- What's your name?
- My name is Talia.
- As soon asit gets dark,
I'll take youto the house.
My mother has made youthe most beautiful dress.
It will beperfect for you.
- Thank you, miss Anna.
- Please, my friendsjust call me Anna.
- I wonder if anyone'shelped my brother yet.
If anyone can escapefrom slavery to Ohio,
it would be Samuel.
- Go, keep running!
[Dogs barkingin the distance]
- Hey, stop!
- No! no! No! No!
- Get up!
Shut up! Shut up!
- No! no!
- There's the boy.
- Where's the boat?- Shhhh...
- Estelle, the boat.
- Yes, I hear.
The dogs aregetting closer.
- But the boy.
- We have to run, Molly.
Let's go this way.
- Oh, no you don't.
You'll never make itacross that river alive.
- Who are you?
- A man with a boat.
- Is Talia a goodsteamstress, mother?
- Oh, yes.
One of the best i'veseen for her age.
- So she willbe a lot of help.
- Yes.
It will be very nicehaving her here.
- I don't think havingmore girls around the
house is a good idea.
- Sometimes it upsets methat we can't help more
runaways than we do.
- Do you remember thatstory about Amanda,
how she gave her penniesto father to save the
church's telescopenewspaper?
- I do rememberthat story.
- Well those werepennies of faith.
We are helping the runawaysone person at a time.
It may seem as small Asa penny in light of the
whole picture, butevery penny counts.
- So every person is likea penny in a million?
- Every person is likeone penny that
makes up a million.
- Well I know i'mcounting pennies
for a new quilt.
[Piano music]
Will is playing the piano!
Will, piano!
That's my brother,will, in the parlor.
He plays the pianowonderfully!
Can you play itagain so I can sing?
- Sure.
Den away, away...
I can't wait any longer...
Hooray!
I am going home...
Den away, away...
For I can't wait anylonger...
Hooray!
I am going home...
Den away, away...
I can't wait any longer...
Hooray!
I am going home...
Den away, away...
I can't wait anylonger...
Hooray!
For I am going home...
- Will's playingis so beautiful.
What is the song called?
- The song iscalled ole shady.
It was written by myeldest son, Benjamin.
Many union soldiers singit and call it the
song of contraband.
He also wrotedarling Nelly gray.
- Did you like thesong and my singing?
- Oh, yes. Very much.
- Have you given anymorethought to your new name?
- Yes, I think I wouldlike to be called lottie.
It was the name of a verykind woman in Virginia who
helped keep my baby sisterfrom being taken from me
several years ago.
I will never forget her.
- I love that name.
I will go tellmother and Sammy.
Talia's new name is lottie.
- That's abeautiful name.
- Pound them in good,boys. Sergeant
reicheldeifer thinkswe're getting wind tonight.
- Very good corporal.
- Hello boys.
I have returned from homeand everyone sends their
love and prayers to you.
However, someone insistedon coming with me.
- Emery?
- Clay.
I made it to virginiathanks to chaplain Richmond.
- You should behome with Liza.
- Liza's well.She's with Audrey.
But there's a bountyhunter in westerville now.
- Hey, he'll be fine.
He just needs to worksome things through.
- Emery, welcome.
I'm corporal Conrad.
Chaplain Richmond workedwonders for you
to walk into campand join the army.
How'd you getaway with that?
- I spoke with the colonoland all's arranged.
Emery will be placed incompany c along with his
brother and all of you.
- Only a chaplain.
Emery, you're gonnaenjoy army life.
- I look forward to it.
- Good to haveyou, cousin.
Let me introduce youto some of the men.
That's John billings.
Jacob wolf.
Daniel Lewis
and Isaac Griffith.
- Nice to meet you men.
- Now over there, that'ssergeant reicheldeifer.
But don't you call him sir,because nothing will
make a sergeant madderthan being called sir.
- Okay, i'llkeep that in mind.
- You men are alldoing a fine job.
I know how rough it ison your families and the
price you may for thelives of others is high,
but their freedom andthe union's cause is
valuable to life itself.
[Children laughing]
- They're makingso much noise.
- They remind meof Stella and I.
When we were little, weplayed like that everyday.
- And those two loveeach other very much.
- And they will neverhave to let each other go.
The future will bedifferent for them.
- Freeing Stella andsending her to Canada
was the greatest loveyou could give her.
- I know. I justmiss her dearly.
- Perhaps you'llbe reunited with
Stella some day.
*
[knock at door]
- Can I help you?
- Yes, sir. I am lookingfor Jackson cumberland.
- What do you want?
- I need for you tocome out here, sir.
- Who are you?
- I am a runawayreturning from Canada
and I really need yourhelp to get my sister.
- It's toolate today, sir.
Come in the house, eatand stay the night
and we'll go get yoursister tomorrow.
- Sir, please.
She'll be sold inthe early morning.
We must go tonight.
- No one from canadacould possibly know such
detailed information.
Who sent you?
- I must save my sister.
- Who sent you!
- I told you my sister.
- Sir, by cominginside of my house,
you have put my entirefamily and everything
we do in danger.
You tell me the truth or iwill shoot you right now.
- You can't shoot me.
Okay, okay.
Two men from Kentucky,they made me find you.
- Where are they?
- Clear downby the river.
But they don'tknow where I am.
- How can I know that?
- I promise.
I was supposed to leadyou down to the river.
They were gonna take youand make John Parker turn
himself in to save you.
- Here. have some bread.
You realize we can'tlet you go back, right?
- But I have awife in Kentucky.
- Write her name.
- I can't write.
- What's her name?
- Florence Jamison.
But I will neversee her again.
- The only reasonyou found out where
Mr. cumberland livesis because some kind
soul had pity on you.
If we allow you to returnthen they'll beat and
torture you until youtell them where we are.
If you found the strengthto remain silent
then they'd kill you.
Going back isnot an option.
If your wifepasses through,
then we'll sendher to you.
Before the sun rises, i'lltake you to the station at
red oak and you'll beon your way to Canada.
- I understand, sir.
- Do you think we'regoing the wrong
way to the river?
- I think so.
Tonight we should moveback where the bounty
hunter caught the girl.
- We should pray for aclear sky and full moon
so we can see well.
- Yes.
I was taught to trust inthe lord, and that is
what we are gonna do.
- My mama told me a storyabout a runaway named
Liza. Liza came thisway in the cold of winter
with a baby.
She got to the edge of theriver and heard the dogs
barking behind her.
She saw the light at thetop of Liberty hill.
There was no boat.
So she stepped across theice jumping from patch to
patch all the way acrossthe river to freedom.
- That is an amazingstory, Molly.
- She made it acrossthe river estelle,
and so are we.
- Yes.
We're gonna get acrossthat river Molly.
But now we have to sleep.
We have to runagain at dark.
- Go ahead.
I will take first watch.
I am too excited to sleep.
- Very well.
- It's raining butit's still sunny.
How does that happen?
- Well, when the rainclouds aren't big enough
to cover the sun.
- Kind of likehard times, huh?
They aren't bigenough to cover hope.
- Yes, Liza.Just like that.
We received our firstletter from Emery.
Shall we read it?
- Yes.
- Our dear sister Liza and our dear friend Audrey,
I am here with Clay now.
We are both doing well and are healthy.
Earlier today I experienced my first action.
It was a squirmish in the field against some rebs...
[Gunfire]
[Dramattic music]
[Gunfire continues]
- Get your head down!
Reload like thison your back.
- Is this whatit's like corporal?
I thought we'd befighting standing up!
- This is squirmishing.
You're out front, keepingan eye on what the
rebels are getting at.
Now keep your eye onthose cavalry out there.
You see them,get ready to run.
- Okay.
- Get up! Get up!Get up! Come on!
- Let's go.
- ...shortly after the squirmish,
the rains began and have not stopped since.
The close companion to the rain is the mud and
someplaces ankle deep.
Our army issued clothing becomes so heavy with
water, it nearly drags us to the ground.
We can hear cannons in the distance.
It is a small comfort to be safe in our tents but
I cannot help but feel for our comrades who have
pressed on to the battle at Ridge mountain.
- Is it raining whilethe sun shines there too,
miss Audrey?
- I don't think so, Liza.
- Hey!
Fire!
- March!
[Music]
- Fire!
[Gunshots]
[Music]
- Fire!
[Gunshots]
[Music]
- As I write it brings to my attention how much we
miss you, Liza, yet we both know this is where we
are meant to be.
Continue with Audrey to be brave as we stand together
in the savior's love, a love that demands that all
men are created equal on this earth.
- We can do nothing more for this cause, my dear
Liza, than to stand courageously through the
fight for the rights of others.
I know you and miss Audrey are doing the same
as we are away.
Be brave, little sister.
Our love to you both, your brothers, Emery and Clay.
- Am I brave,miss Audrey?
- Yes, Liza. Very brave.
- Look! a rainbow!
[Knock at the door]
- Good afternoon,mr. Wright.
I understand you havea package for me.
- Good afternoon, bishop.
Yes, I do.
And here it is.
It appears to befrom Virginia.
- Very good.
I've been expecting this.
- I must say it's muchsmaller than your last
package from Virginia.
- Yes. indeed it is.
- And the packing slipon your last package said
that the crate wasfull of fabric.
That must have been alarge amount of fabric.
- The hanbyhousehold has five women.
We use a lot of fabric.
- And a veryheavy fabric, yes?
- Contents of the crate werepacked rather tightly.
Good day, Mr. Wright.
- Sir?
- Yes, Mr. Wright.
- I'm concerned.
- Dalin, I have helpedyou and Julianna from
the moment youmoved to this town.
It has never been anyconcern of yours what my
family receives here atthe shipping company.
- Well, I'm actuallyaware there is a matter
here which shouldconcern me.
And I intend onuncovering it.
- Uncovering it?
Your prying is beginningto concern me, Mr. Wright.
- You're notfooling anyone sir.
- The wisdom of theprudent to understand his
way, but that which is inthe midst of fools will be
made known.
- What is hidden willbe made known, bishop.
- I am certain ofthat, dalin Wright.
Truly certain.
[Music]
- I can't begin to thankyou enough for letting me
stay and work here.
- Oh, lottie, it's ablessing to have you.
- Thank you, Mrs. hanby.
- We've gotten so much donesince you've been helping.
The runaways reallyappreciate the new clothes
we're sewing them.
- Sewing has always beena joy for me, but now that
I am free to choose tohelp others with it
I love it even more.
- Hello, father.
- Hello, Anna.
- I am taking thesethings out to the barn for
tonight's guests.
Would you like tocome with me, lottie?
- Oh yes, I wouldlove to help.
- Very well.
We'll return shortly.
- All right, Anna.
- How many runawaysare we expecting tonight?
- We're expecting only two butwe always prepare for more.
Sometimes runawaysmeet in the woods
and stay together.
- I'm excitedto meet them.
- Me too.
Oh, I can takethat inside.
- Here you are.
[Creaking outside]
- Lottie?
Lottie, are you out there?
Lottie?
- Father.
- What is it, Anna?
- Anna, where's lottie?
- She's been taken.
- Will is in the kitchen.
Tell him to get themuskets and meet me on the
front porch.
- Yes, father.
- So you girls think you'reactually close to finding
out who thisbounty hunter is?
- Yes, we're close.
We have a lot of clues.
- We just seem to have aproblem connecting them all.
- That's why we were wonderingif you could help us.
- Yes, we don't knowanyone smarter than you.
- I appreciate yourhigh regards of my
intelligence, girls, buti'm not sure I can connect
the clues any betterthan you already have.
What's wrong, Julianna?
- Dalin.
- What happened to dalin?
- It's him.
- What are youtalking about?
- Dalin is thebounty hunter.
- How do you know?
- Because all ofthis was in his room.
I should have known.
It all makes sense now.
New hat. Nice food.
All the new clothes.
He promised he wasn'tstealing, but I never
thought of this.
- It's not yourfault, Julianna.
- It was right undermy nose the whole time.
- No, Julianna.
You cannot think that way.
Your brother madehis own decisions.
You never couldhave stopped him.
- Wait a minute!
A $500 rewardfor Talia edmondson?
This is lottie!
She's at myhouse right now.
- Does dalin know that?
- If he does,we're in trouble.
- Julianna and I willgo warn my father.
We will take the shortcutthrough the woods.
[Music]
- Make way. Let me pass.
- Please. let the girl go.
- You're in noposition to stop me.
I'm within the law.
- Dalin, whatare you doing?
- Come no closer, bishop.
Let me pass.
- There's no rewardin it if you shoot her.
- I'm merelyobeying the law.
It is you whois breaking it.
- Yes, dalin.
I am breaking the law,
a law that is a stain onthe soul of this nation.
But look at yourself!
You hold within your handthe life of another.
Is that withinyour rights?
- Move out ofmy way, bishop.
I'm turning this fugitiveinto the authorities.
- I will notlet you take her.
- Dalin!
- Julianna?
Julianna, what areyou doing here?
- How could you?
You're my brother.
- Julianna,we needed the money.
- Not that kind of money.
- We had to eat.
- I would eat dirt beforei ate the food of bondage.
- How can you say that?
- You're in bondage toyour own wants, your own
self, your own pride.
- Father --
- father set free everyslaved we owned.
- Yes, and he left us.
He left us with nothing.
- And you're justas greedy as he was.
You're in more bondagethan any slave.
- How can you say that?
- Because the bondage you'rein runs deep to the soul.
I will pray for you,dalin, but if you continue
this, I will neverspeak to you again.
- Julianna!
Julianna!
- Dalin, it is time foryou to stop reproaching
the person of freedom.
- Freedom is no person.
- On the contrary, theperson of freedom is the
light that will set youfree from the bondage of
yourself and thebondage of greed.
- Bishop, idon't understand.
- There was a man whotook men, women and
children into bondage andled them to slaughter.
Oh, he acted within thelaw but it was on the road
to Damascus that he felland saw the light, the
light of freedom.
That was the turningpoint in Paul's life.
This is the thatmoment for you, dalin.
Open your eyes.
See the light.
Walk into that light.
[Music]
- Oh lord, whathave I done?
Forgive me.
[Music]
- It's the river.
- We need to get acrossto the other side.
- Look. I see thelight of freedom.
- Yes, but no boat.
- Remember thestory of Eliza?
She made it.
We will swim.
- Stop! that is enough.
Time to go back to yourmassa before you're beat.
Jump in that river Andi will kill you both.
- Lay downyour gun slowly.
Now leave or iwill shoot you.
- Come with me and i'lltake you to the other side.
- Thank you.
- Are you theone with the boat?
- Yes, I am.
- Just the toptwo steps, netta?
- Yes, Samuel.
Thank you.
I can't get that jacksonto do anything except eat
and save run away slaves.
- I've just put tworunaways the in the cabin.
I told them you'd beout with supplies.
- We'll go now.
[Door creaksopen and closed]
- What are you doing?
- I'm fixing the steps.
What does it look like?
- Now?
- Well, yes.
Netta said she askedyou several times.
- She never asked me.
- Right.
- Take a break andcome here for a minute.
- I just haveone step left.
Can it wait?
- No, I ran into abounty hunter tonight.
I want to tellyou about it.
The stairs can wait.
- That's whatyou told netta.
- What?
- Nothing.
- Thank you.
- You're very welcome.
Eat as much as you'd like.
- Would someone be ableto send a telegram for me?
I'm to send to someonenamed adin Sheridan
in westerville.
I'm going to meet mysister Talia there.
- Oh. lovely.
I'm sure Jackson couldsend one for you tomorrow.
- Thank you.
- And I must find yourbrother right away.
- What is your brother's name?
- His name is Samuel.Samuel libson.
- Are you Molly?
- Yes, I am.
- I'll be right back.
- Samuel.
Can you bring some morefire wood out to the cabin?
- I just haveone more step.
Can it wait?
- No, Samuel.
Just take some firewood to the cabin.
The stairs can wait.
[Music]
- Samuel?
Samuel! I made it!
- I knew you would.
God is good.
- Yes, he is!
[Music]
- What brings youto my home today?
- I've come to tell youthat I have not informed
anyone of the undergroundrailroad which you run
from your home, sir.
- All we do from ourhome, dalin, is as the
lord leads andlove commands.
- I want tothank you, sir.
- Thank me?
In all honesty, it'sbecause of Julianna that
you're evenhere right now.
- It is because ofjulianna and you, sir,
that I have changed.
I know that iam a new man.
- How are we toknow the same?
- Because of a man namedpaul in the book of acts.
Please, let me read.
Then ananias answered,lord, I have heard by many
of this man of theevil that he has done.
He has the authority fromthe chief priests to bind all.
And the lord said unto him, gothy way for he is a chosen
vessel unto me.
I am that man.
- Yes.
- You have taken a riskfor the lives of others.
You know my reputation.
You know what hurti have brought.
Yet you sit here becauseof the lives of so many,
because that is the kindof man that you are.
- Dalin, as someone whopaid for his own freedom
from a wicked man, I knowthe meaning of captivity.
I walked many a mile formy freedom only to walk
back again and spend timein jail until I paid for it.
- Then you understand howgod can get a hold of a
man for a greater purpose.
- I also understand thatthings that appear to be a
risk aren't a risk atall when seen through
the eyes of faith.
- It is my prayer thatyou will trust me
once again, sir.
And if not, I will dowhatever you ask to again
earn that trust.
I want to join theunderground railroad.
Just as the slave traderjohn Newton came to
realize his need,i have also.
- Well --
- excuse us, father.
- No, Anna, lottie. Wait.
It's safe.
- All right, father.
- What is happening here?
- Dalin was just sharingthat he is changed man.
- I would like tosincerely apologize to
you, lottie.
And Mrs. hanby, I'd like tojoin the underground railroad.
- Mrs. hanby?
- It's all right, adin.
What is it?
- I have just received atelegraph from Ripley, Ohio.
It states Elizabeth vanlou has a package ready
for me to pick up fromsomebody named
Jackson cumberland.
- That has tobe my sisters.
- Great. the plan is working.
You will leave right awayto pick up the package.
- Sir, with ripley120 miles away I'm
concerned about travelingso far with them.
I don't know the areasor the bounty hunters.
- Bishop hanby, i'vetraveled the road from
here to Ripley takingfugitive slaves back to
their mastersfrom Kentucky.
I know all the localbounty hunters.
I could be your cover.
If you'd allow meto go with adin.
- Lottie, whatdo you think?
- I think he should go.
No one would expect abounty hunter to be
helping a fugitive.
- Please, sir.
This is somethingi have to do.
- Adin?
- If he can be trusted,sir, it would be
very beneficial.
- I believe you areto do this, dalin.
You told me thatyou are like Paul.
Well, this is yourchance to prove that.
Can you trustyou, dalin Wright?
- Yes, bishop.
You can trust me. I willnot disappoint you.
[Music]
- Well, Jackson receiveda telegram a bit ago.
- How can you beso calm about this?
What did it say?
- It just mentioned thata couple of folks named
adin and dalin will becoming to pick up a
special package to bedelivered to someplace
called westerville.
- It's happening.
I'm so excited.
- Yes, I know.
- Do you mind ifi go tell netta?
- No. not at all. Go.
Estelle has become likea sister to me, and I'm sad
to see her leave.
- Speaking of leaving,molly, I wanted to talk to
you about that.
I have grown a lot sincei've been here helping
Jackson, and I want tostay here and help others
achieve freedom theway that I have.
- Well, did you think iwas going to go to Canada?
- Well, that wasthe plan wasn't it?
- That was our plan but isee that wasn't god's plan.
- Jackson has alreadytold me there's room for
both of us here.
- That settles it then.
- Molly, I know that oncethe war is over you will
have the freedom to go seeestelle whenever you like.
- That wouldbe wonderful.
[Music]
- What are you two doing?
We heard your grumblingclear down the path.
- Sammy has it in hishead that he can climb the
rope to the loft.[Laughter]
- That's it.
Putting up with sisterswho laugh at me is no
longer acceptable.
[Laughing]
- I'm going toget the ladder.
Um, Anna?
- We're working, Sammy.
- Anna?
- You'll have to get theladder on your own, Sam.
- Talia?
- Estelle!
Estelle, you made it.
- Yes, Talia,i'm here now.
- Where's Nellie?
- She's not here.
I couldn't bring her.
They made her house slaveto our master's baby.
There's no way I couldget her away from them.
But she is safe though.
- Bishop hanby willhelp us get her back.
- Come, Sammy.
We'll get estelle's flowerfor the vase and tell
father and motherthat she's here.
- This is Anna.
She's my best friend.
- It is so niceto meet you.
Lottie has told meso much about you.
- Lottie?
- That's my new name.
Do you like it?
- Yes, lottie.
It's perfect.
[Music]
- Hey, Emery, whydon't you come on out?
Boys are telling aboutsergeant reicheldeifer.
- All right.
I'll be out in a minute.
Just let me finish thisletter to bishop hanby.
- Okay.
- Dear bishop hanby, Clay and I have returned to
camp and are now rested from the most intense
battle I have fought since my recruitment. It was the
battle of corrick's Ford.
It all began in the early morning of July 13.
We had marched about 8 miles the night before and
had set up camp in the woods.
We had no tents and had not eaten.
- Get moving. Time to get up.
Conrad, get your men up.
Get them moving. Get them fed.
Come on. Let's go.
Everybody up. Come on.Gotta move out.
Let's go. Time to go. Up.
Come on. Everybody get up.
Get some food in you.We got to go.
Come on, boys. Right now.
Let's get moving.Gotta move out.
- Too early.
- Everybody up. Come on. We gotta move out.
- At 3 o'clock in the morning we were awakened
and given just a moment to quickly eat our hardtack.
- Here.
- Thanks.
- What's going on?
- I have no idea.
- Let's go, boys!
- Has anything likethis happened before?
- Not sincei've been here.
It's going to beall right though.
- I'm worried.
I'm worried.
- It will be fine.
- Better hurry, boys.
We're going to fallin any moment now.
- Already?
- Company c, fall in.
[Music]
- Attention, company.
Shoulder. arms.
Left face.
Forward march.
- Men who moments before were asleep and hungry now
began marching like soldiers with
determination in their faces ready to face
whatever was ahead.
We marched at such a rapid pace that by 1 o'clock
that afternoon we caught up with the gray back's
rear guard.
They were cavalry and after a short exchange of
gunfire, they scattered quicker than my chickens
back home.
By 2 o'clock we had reached the chief river.
After fording the river, we received word from
skirmishers of a line of rebs waiting to ambush us.
We volleyed three rounds in their direction.
- Ready!
Aim.
Fire!
- Fall back!
- Fall back, boys.
Fall back.
[Yelling]
- The rebels took off running for their lives.
After pursuing them for a mile and fording the river
again, we found them formed in a line of battle.
- Company ready?
Aim.
Fire!
[Gunshots]
- Fire!
- Ready.
Aim.
Fire!
[Gunshots]
We were met with musket fire we returned fire and
called out or 6 pound canon to answer them.
The gray backs fled again double quick time led by
their cavalry.
What happened next was unexpected.
- Without warning we were fired upon by the rebs.
[Gunfire]
- Steady, boys.
The almighty has blessed usand the rebel aim was high.
Now we'll giveit back to them.
Ready!
Aim!
Fire!
[Gunshots]
Load.
- By the grace of god the rebs had aimed high
and missed.
We relentlessly fought the rebs for 37 minutes.
We were given the command to advance and the
confederates began retreating.
[Music]
- Come on, boys.
Come on!
[Music]
[Gunfire]
- All that remained were ten rebs and an officer.
- Hold on, boys.
We'll fight them here.
Stand strong, men.
Fire at will!
[Gunfire]
- It's no use.
Surrender, boys.
- Five rebels and the officer were hit.
Five other gray backs surrendered.
The victory was joyous but it did not come without
great loss for both sides.
As we approach the confederate line there was
no celebrating.
Only the stark realization of the great price that
must be paid for this great country.
- Look here, boys.
An officer.
- It's notjust an officer.
It's a general.
- That boys, isgeneral Robert garnett.
I knew him at west point.
We were cadets together.
He's a fine soldier.
It's a shame tosee him gone.
- Our sergeant'sbeen hit!
Our sergeant's been hit!
- Sarge ant reicheldeifer?
- Are you sure?
- Yes, he was hit withartillery fire on the
other side of the river.
- Can they save him?
- There was nothingto be done, Emery.
He's gone.
[Music]
- The men that have fought beside me are
strong and loyal.
I could not have asked for better brothers in this
noble fight.
God is carrying us through, and like them I
will be reenlisting in the army and will not be
coming home after my 90 days of service are over.
I know this comes as no surprise to you.
May we continue together in the cause as we move
forward for the lives of those in bondage.
God bless you all.
Emery.
[Music]
- Would you like to hear this letter from Clay?
- Yes, I would love to, father.
- Dear bishop hanby, after celebrating the
surrender of general johnston's troops the
14th ovi had marched from Richmond, Virginia
to Washington.
News of the war being over has brought to me
mixed emotions.
There has been victory and much loss.
The mixed emotions are made stronger while here
in our nation's capitol after president
Lincoln's death.
- Hey, Emery, haveyou seen my sack?
- No, Reed.
The war is over and nowyou lose your sack?
- It's probably in here.
- I have heard that the 14th will be moving to
louisville, Kentucky in the next few months.
We believe we will be sent home shortly after
arriving to louisville.
I look forward to being home again.
Sharing a tent for four years with Emery has been
an experience.
- Found it.
Goodbye. thanksfor your help.
[Laughter]
- Lives given by those who have fought in battle
will be seeds that produce a great harvest of freedom.
What the future holds for us at home is to continue
to help all men of all colors to experience the
promise of life, hope and a future together just as
god has intended.
We return to a new day.
We have won the fight for the freedom of those who
are enslaved and the underground railroad no
longer needs to exist.
We shall not only see our nation as one again but we
shall see those who have lived by the fruit of
hope live free to pursue happiness as men.
We have written a letter telling Liza and Audrey we
are on our way.
Please be sure they have received it.
We look forward to supporting you in the next
fight, whatever it may be.
We will be back in westerville soon.
Emery and Clay Dalton.
It will be ajoyous home coming.
- There will be so manynew people for them to meet.
[Music]
- What has captivatedyour attention?
- The war isover, father.
It's really over.
I am amazed I'm sittinghere watching estelle and
lottie's little sisternellie freely playing with
other children.
There's no fearor concern.
There's only love.
Seeing Nellie free andwith a future at only
8 years old blesses me.
- The underground railroad hasserved a great purpose.
The lord will continue tobring freedom to all
as long as we stand.
- There's no need forflowers in the vase.
Estelle.
[Music]
- Lottie.
- And Nellie.
[Music]
- They're free now.
Our family hashelped so many.
- God is pleased, and wehave never compromised.
- And I know you, you'llalways have to fight
for something.
- Well, the temperancemovement is beginning.
[Music]
- I think I willgo join them.
- Very well.
Have a good time, Anna.
[Music]