Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
You're the third
emperor of Rome
whom I've served.
First there was Caligula,
then Claudius,
and now you, Nero.
You send General Lucius
Caesennius Paetus
to defend Armenia against
the might of Parthia?
I'm the one who invaded
Armenia in the first place.
I don't goddamn believe it.
I don't fucking believe it!
What's goin' on?
I should be the one
to repel the Parthians,
not that cocksure Paetus.
And you order me
to safeguard what, Syria?
From who?
Parthians are besieging
our legions in Armenia.
And there's a heavy
winter coming.
You better hope, Emperor,
that the power of Rome
rests solely, not in the hands
of your appointed generals,
but in the hearts of those
anonymous soldiers
who make up your legions.
Oh.
Proceed, Marcus.
What is the latest?
A new message
from the Parthians.
They demand we surrender.
They give us three days.
They guarantee we will not
be killed if...
Burn it.
Surrender is not an option.
- General...
- I said no!
Damn it.
The Parthians control
the pass.
The Scythians have cut off
our supply route here.
If we don't get help,
we'll die of starvation.
Do you also think
that this is all my fault,
for making camp
in a place
that can easily be besieged?
That this is all the result
of my incompetence?
This is no time
to look back.
We're in no position
to sustain a prolonged siege.
Our own men remain loyal,
but the mercenaries
- have deserted.
- God damn mercenaries.
Any word from Corbulo?
I sent three of my best men
as emissaries.
They all chose
separate routes.
But the mountains are thick
with enemies familiar
with our plans.
They all failed.
There is one final option.
Take the only route the enemy
will not expect us to take.
A handful
of well-prepared men
could scale the ravine.
Once in the forest,
it's a seven-day
forest march to Syria
and Corbulo's scouts.
Are you telling me, Marcus,
that a few of our men,
exhausted and starving to death,
will be able
to scale a cliff,
walk and run
through the forest,
battle the enemy,
and reach Syria
in just a few days?
Precisely.
I can see that I'm not the
only one who has lost his head.
It's the only route
that will not be crawling
with the enemy.
Meanwhile,
we can make them believe
we're contemplating
the terms of the surrender.
Corbulo, that bastard.
I never imagined that
my greatest political foe
would one day be
my only hope for survival.
And what if,
after all this...
he refuses to come
to our aid?
It's a risk we have to take.
The route is impossible.
Have you already considered
whom to entrust
with this lunacy?
He is a soldier,
raised in the mountains
of North Hispania.
Excellent climber and fighter.
Highly revered
by the auxiliary cohorts.
Auxiliary cohorts?
He might desert.
He is a soldier.
Loyal to Rome.
There are others,
younger, stronger.
But none with his capacity
to endure.
What's his name?
They call him Noreno.
Do you think he will do it?
If it's an order,
he'll obey it to the end.
Yes, an order.
Duty.
A soldier's lot is nothing
but to obey orders,
to fight and sacrifice
one's life
without thinking.
What is hard
is to make decisions.
They must leave tonight.
We are all already dead, Marcus.
Your plan is impossible.
I can already see Corbulo
as he hears the news
of my defeat,
the outcome
of my strategic blunder.
His smile.
We are going to need
great assistance from the gods,
if we are basing our hopes
on a mountain man.
But if the gods
are willing...
so be it.
Sir,
Noreno the soldier is here.
Noreno.
You called for me, sir.
You've been selected
to deliver a message
to General Corbulo.
The others failed
because they chose
a wrong route.
You'll go by one
the enemy does not expect.
Through the ravine.
Sir,
what you ask of me
is impossible.
Impossible or not,
that's our only chance
to survive.
I am aware
of your qualities.
I didn't select you
for your obvious skills.
You were chosen because of
your rare capacity to endure.
If anyone can succeed...
it's you.
We have provisions
for only two more days.
If the enemy doesn't
kill us, then...
the lack of food
or the cold will.
The entire Roman legion
destroyed, disgraced.
You must succeed.
- When do I leave?
- Now.
When you leave the camp,
run straight for the ravine.
Scale its walls.
Once in the forest, head southwest
till you hit Syria
and Corbulo's scouts.
Help me return to Rome.
Help me see my son.
I will do my best.
When you reach Corbulo,
give him this.
That parchment
bears Paetus' seal.
Oh, may the gods
protect you.
Go out from here and run
as if Hades himself
were pursuing you.
For Rome!
I'm sorry, my friend!
Go!
Run!
Come on.
No!
Si?
Another idiotic Roman
who believes he can cross
these terraces to seek help.
What do I do with him, Saka?
Damn proud Romans.
When are they ever
going to stop?
Their pride
is what makes them great.
They can't go far.
Look over there.
Here.
Here's the famous ravine.
Go!
Two of the Romans
are dead.
The other scaled
the cliff face.
That route is impossible.
Nothing is impossible
if you have the will
to survive.
They're just deserters.
They sacrificed themselves
so that he could succeed.
He's making his way
to Corbulo.
The Persians pay us to kill
Romans, not to let them escape.
Madyes, you and Saulio
make your way to the river.
He'll have to cross it
eventually.
I'll send word
to the Persians.
Yeah, for now.
So Claudius, tell me,
how far have you traveled
to arrive at the frontier?
Hibernia.
Hibernia?
That's the edge
of the world.
What's a Celt doing
at the Roman auxiliary?
I heard the pay was good.
Pay.
Like most children...
on the coast of Hibernia,
I was captured
and taken to Britannia
as a slave.
I was a game keeper's
ward but...
they couldn't hold me.
He says do you...
did you ever want to return home?
I was away from home
too long.
I wanted to see the world.
So, I made my way to Gaul
and joined the auxiliary.
They've been the only family
I've ever known.
And for that I'm thankful.
He says you should've gone
to Hispania.
It's his land.
Very beautiful there.
Um, I was raised by
my grandfather in Hispania.
And, uh, when he joined
the auxiliary,
he was stationed
in Britannia.
So I followed him
and fought alongside him.
However, when he died,
I decided I would return
to Hispania.
I carried his body
to the top of the mountain
and there I laid him down
so the vultures could carry
his soul to the afterlife.
However, when I returned
to the auxiliary,
I met Marcus.
He recognized
my ability and...
well he gave me
a purpose.
Oh, oh, I think he means,
uh, for Rome.
- Si? Si?
- Uh, for Rome.
- Yes.
- For Rome?
- For Rome.
- Rome!
For Rome!
Let her go!
Get out.
Do you live here alone?
Where is your family?
Noreno.
Duria.
I wouldn't do it!
Look! Let me go.
I don't have anything
to give you.
I know that you're
a deserter but...
believe me when I say...
I will not tell anyone
where you are.
I will not betray you.
Do you think
I'm actually afraid
you'll tell someone
where I am?
I'm not that important
that in...
they'll need
to send soldiers after me.
I have no interest
in what made you desert.
But let me go.
You will have helped save
an isolated legion
that has no chance
of survival.
I don't care about you
or your damn legion.
Now let's see what
you've got in the bag.
A message with a Roman
general's seal on it.
I should be able to get
something nice for this.
You take what you like,
but you leave me that.
Try to remember
that you were
a legionnaire, too.
Rome and all her glory
can burn in hell,
for all I care.
Thank you.
A soldier's life
is lived outdoors,
in every damn
imaginable weather.
I'm sure that's something
you can't imagine, Nero.
But when you're
a Roman soldier...
you get used
to your hardships...
and what doesn't kill you
only makes you stronger.
Look over there.
Who the hell are you?
Let me go.
Please. I beg of you.
I'm a Roman soldier.
I'm on a mission of mercy.
My men have no food
and no water.
Nobody cares.
Least of all me.
I just wanna sell you.
Scyles.
How the hell did you get all
the way out here with just this?
Scyles!
Shit.
That man belongs to me!
Yeah? Well these
bonds say otherwise!
You're getting old
and slow, Medea.
Turn around.
Go back to your woman,
Solias.
Oh, wait...
You can't.
I killed her.
This world is mine.
Anyone who comes
across this patch
belongs to me.
She wandered too far!
And now,
she paid the price.
This bounty is mine.
And I am claiming my reward!
Take my hand.
Take it!
Steady, soldier.
Stay calm.
You're safe.
Rest.
No, I cannot rest.
Where am I?
How long have I been here?
No one is following you.
Stay still.
You are safe here.
Shh.
You are safe.
"There was
nothing to animate
the drooping spirits
of the army
but the example
of their general,
who endured even more
than the common
soldiers did."
That was written about me,
about my conquests
of Armenia,
whose future Paetus
now holds in the...
in the palm
of his grubby little hand.
When our long
arduous march
took us through
hot, desolate
and rugged countryside,
with food
and water scarce,
and the Armenians
likely to launch
an obstinate defense...
do you know what I did?
I executed Vadandus,
one of the nobles
I had captured,
and I cut off
his fucking head.
And then I took his head
and I put it in
the ballista,
and I sent it catapulting
into the enemy's
fortifications.
And they took it as a...
a portent.
They hastened to surrender.
That's a true story.
Would you have had
the wiles to act as I have?
No.
Only a true soldier
has such an imagination.
Ah.
You are awake.
How long was I out?
Almost a day.
A day?
I really must...
Go. Yes.
I heard a few mumblings.
A name. Duria?
Tell me,
from what do you run?
Bandits?
Other Romans, perhaps?
Did you desert
your legion?
I'm no deserter.
I, too,
was a soldier of Rome.
But that was
a long time ago.
I have a mission
to complete.
We each have
a mission to complete.
Where are you headed,
soldier?
To the Euphrates frontier.
I carry a message
for General Corbulo.
The lives of an entire
legion depend on my success.
I see I am in the presence
of an uncommon man.
Did you come across
the mountains
from Paetus' encampment?
Yes.
And where did you serve Rome?
In another life.
A distant life.
I served under
General Vespasian in Judea.
- Vespasian?
- Mm-hmm.
But, he was the only leader
capable of putting down
the Jewish revolt
against Nero.
And his practice
of rewarding
and releasing his oldest
and most loyal
of soldiers is...
well it's known by all.
He's legendary, sir.
I would have very much
liked to have served under
such a great general.
Now, I serve a great king.
I do not understand.
Come.
Drink and eat.
You need to regain
your strength.
I know this country well.
Your destination
is not far.
The most direct route
is across a span of desert
that lies between here
and the Euphrates River.
I recommend staying out
of the sun,
if you can,
and stick to
the dry river gullies.
Perhaps not the most direct
route across the desert, but...
they will protect you.
Sir, without knowing it,
you've not only
saved my life,
but the lives
of an entire legion.
I am forever in your debt.
Do not thank me.
I would do this
for any man,
Roman, Persian, Scythian.
I'm glad I'm the only one
to hear you say this.
It could be your death sentence
for betrayal against Rome.
In the name of Rome,
I killed many men.
Now in my wildest
nightmares I recall
how sometimes
I even enjoyed it.
But I was the one
who died.
Enemies?
No.
Men.
In truth,
all of them equal.
All of them
children of God.
Equal?
And how, may I ask,
did you return to life
after being dead?
By listening to the words
of a crucified man.
You should not speak
this way to anyone,
least of all
a Roman soldier.
Are you not aware
that Nero has sentenced
all Christians to death?
I no longer fear anything.
Not death.
And, least of all, Nero.
Without fear,
we are free.
Would you still be free
in a prison cell,
condemned to the gallows,
or in the Coliseum
facing wild beasts?
More free than ever.
And you, do you not
want to be free?
Well...
Well, as strange
as it may sound, sir...
these last few days,
I think I felt freedom
for the first time.
Although I was pursued
by my enemies and...
quickly chased down,
and they were ready to kill me,
I've never felt so alive.
I've really reveled in these last few
days, away from the army.
Then it may be that one day
you will know real freedom,
like me,
without killing.
And perhaps someday,
you will explain to me
this truth of yours,
that makes all men equal,
and free.
But for now I must go.
I am very grateful
for your help.
Saul.
My name is Saul.
I am Noreno.
I packed
some provisions for you.
You said that in life,
we all have a mission
to complete.
Have you completed yours?
No.
Wait.
Here.
Take this.
God go with you, soldier.
You are a good man, Saul.
I will not forget you.
I dream that your...
your precious fool
of a general,
Paetus, is close
to surrender.
His men are starving.
His mercenaries
are deserting.
The enemies of Rome
have surrounded him
and have cut off
his supply of lines.
Emperor,
had I led the legion
to reclaim Armenia,
for Rome,
we would've been
victorious by now.
Why hasn't he sent
for me for help?
Too proud?
Too vain?
Too stupid?
Yet I hear nothing.
I hear nothing.
Do you, Emperor?
Nothing.
No galloping hooves.
No... there's no insistent
footsteps.
No one... no one has come.
No one, no one to help,
not a single damn messenger.
You ordered me here to...
not to marshal my forces
unless Paetus himself
sends word that I must
come to his aid.
Three legions are at risk
of annihilation
because of your poor judgment.
And you've condemned your
most able general to wait.
Well, I'm waiting.
Not good enough.
Get up!
That's the spirit.
Show me, Roman!
You've done well,
better than anyone
could've imagined.
But there comes a time
between hunter and prey when
they both know it must end.
You're better than this.
Sand?
I'm not done with you!
Have my fun. Get up!
You're gonna tell me
who taught you how to run.
That's it!
That's the fight
I'm looking for!
We each have
a mission to complete.
Do you not want to be free?
Your mission is over.
I will give you
the sweet release of death.
Now tell me,
what is your name?
I like to know the names of
things I'm going to kill.
Do it!
No.
Your life
is meaningless to me.
Now, you end
this macabre chase...
or I swear,
it'll be your last!
Permission to speak,
General.
Well, what do we have today?
Is it urgent?
Some of the patrolmen found a
legionnaire in the Euphrates.
He claims to be
one of Paetus' men.
Wow.
Paetus.
Well, he must be a deserter.
It doesn't seem
to be the case.
He says he's a messenger.
Paetus dares
to send me a messenger?
Where the fuck is he?
Outside, waiting.
He was armed only
with this.
He insists that he alone
will hand you the message.
Make him come in.
What's your name, soldier?
Legionnaire Quintus
Laberius Surus.
Second cohort,
fourth Scythia Legion, sir.
I carry a message, sir...
from General Paetus
to General Corbulo.
So you're bringing me
a message from Paetus?
Yes, sir.
Oh, I'm sorry,
but you've come here
for nothing.
Valerius, see to it
that this man eats well,
and reward his efforts.
No, no, don't,
please, sir.
You must help us.
I'll not allow that tone,
soldier.
That useless
fucking Paetus...
the situation
is all his fault.
Settling on such
a mountainous area
so goddamned
easy to attack.
But sir,
won't you do it
for the soldiers' sake?
They have no fault
in the poor decisions
- of their general.
- Who do you think you are,
talking to me like that?
You speak insolently.
Yes...
you're right.
The general's bad decisions
are not the men's fault.
That's what war is like.
I'm not gonna help Paetus.
Valerius.
- Come on.
- No.
I'm sorry, soldier.
Why won't he help us?
Thousands of my men
will die.
Oh, what is it, Amariah?
What have I done now?
I gather you've heard
my reply
to the messenger,
didn't you?
I have told you
that business of Rome...
Is not my concern.
Yes, you have.
Especially as I am
your mistress,
not your wife.
Especially as
I'm not Roman-born.
Amariah.
Although
I was not born here,
but this is my country.
Your country,
which is a claim
of the State of Rome.
That should unite us,
not divide us.
Well, all right,
it's true.
I've refused
General Paetus'
plea for help.
And I've sent
his messenger back
on his way, empty-handed.
My orders from Emperor Nero
are clear.
I'm to remain here on
the banks of the Euphrates
to safeground the...
Syria on behalf of Rome.
I do
not understand you, Gnaeus.
For weeks you prowled the halls
of this palace at night...
sleepless, agitated...
awaiting General Paetus
to swallow his pride
and ask for your help.
No.
Beg for your help.
Then, when he finally does so?
There's no glory in arriving
too late, Amariah.
Oh.
The young soldier boy,
he should be admired.
I mean, look at the distance
that he traveled all alone,
through no-man's-land,
wilderness,
amuck with cutthroats
and Parthian assassins...
poor guy
went over mountains,
through forests,
across desert land.
It's astonishing
that he managed
to make it at all.
- He was desperate.
- No.
He's a soldier
in service to Rome.
He fulfilled his duty.
I have been
always impressed
by the willpower
certain men exhibit
when faced
with an impossible mission.
Well, which is why history
will be remembered
such as generals
as great men.
Generals?
I'm talking about
simple soldiers
like that messenger
who you dismissed
without a second thought.
He did his duty.
You have told me many times
of how you, above all
the other generals,
particularly Paetus,
appreciated the value
of good soldiers.
And without them
and their stalwart strength,
even the most...
best military commanders
would have no chance
of victory.
Are you saying
I risk being forgotten
because I didn't come
to the aid of a general
who's no better than a cur?
No, my darling.
Your place in history
is more than guaranteed
in your celebrated single-handed
military victories.
General Paetus
cannot fall further
in esteem
than he already has.
He's humiliated himself
in front of his men
and, most importantly,
in the eyes
of the Roman emperor.
But, if he dies
all alone in mountains
of Armenia...
Then, good riddance.
If he dies holed up
in the barren cold,
under vicious attack,
besieged,
possibly fighting
for his life
with his last breath...
No. That's unlikely.
There's always
the possibility
he will become a martyr,
even a posthumous hero.
Paetus?
- A hero?
- Yes.
A martyr's hero,
who gave his life for Rome.
Legends, my love,
do not necessarily rise
from the facts of an event
but from the most romanticized
version of a story...
the story that people
most wanted to hear...
the hero they wanted
to believe in.
Oh, well,
what would you have me do?
Deny Paetus
his immortality.
March to his aid.
Do not grant him
a martyr's death.
If Paetus returns
to Rome,
he'll continue
his campaign to slander me.
And the fucker
has the emperor's ear.
Slander the man
who rescued him?
- Uh-huh.
- His savior?
The general
who liberated him
from the jaws
of a certain death?
No.
Not even Paetus
is that stupid.
And of me?
What will be whispered
about me behind my back?
They will say...
"There goes...
The great and honorable
General Corbulo,
who was so moved
by the courage
of a single soldier
a messenger
who weathered
an impossible journey
to plead for help."
My advice to you, General,
is to praise this faithful
servant of Rome.
Say nothing of Paetus.
Instead...
speak in complimentary terms
of unsung heroes.
Do this.
The legions will love you.
No one will speak
a bad word against you.
You have condemned
your political rival
in a life sentence
of public gratitude
of singing your praises
through clenched teeth.
Are you sure
you're not secretly
Roman-born, Amariah?
You speak with the wisdom
of one with intimate knowledge
of this political
machinations of the capital.
Politics are the same
everywhere
as is the quest for power,
internal and universal.
The only thing
that ever changes
is the names of those
who wield the scepter
or the sword.
Go.
Valerius!
Summon the tribunes!
I want to see them immediately.
The troops must be ready
to march at dawn.
Congratulations, soldier.
Do you know
what you're going to do now?
Well, I'm going to return
to Armenia.
You're gonna go back?
But your mission
was a success.
Yes.
But when I was
on my way here,
I met a man,
and he said to me
that in life
we all have a mission
that needs to be fulfilled.
And I feel like I still
haven't fulfilled mine.
And I'd like to think
that maybe...
somewhere out there,
there's a woman
waiting for me.
And I can live a life
in peace.
Well...
may the gods help you
in your new life, soldier.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org