Oliver!
I have something for you!
Edge!
A present from Mr. Kane.
-Grid Police Headquarters.
-Yeah. This is Teddy Rex.
What's up?
I got this strange feeling.
Anything weird happen tonight?
Yeah, a murder
down at the carnival graveyard.
It's nothing for you
public-relation guys, Teddy.
Yeah.
They're keeping it real quiet.
Got it. I'm on my way.
Put my little rubber duckies
Three and four in the water
Mmm, yeah, a wiggle push
And a wiggle push,
they go, they're off
Ooh, that's cold!
Cold! Cold! Cold!
Warm. Ah, perfect.
Don’t flush, please.
OK, freshen up here, Teddy.
Here we go. Hmm, let's see.
No stubble as usual.
A little toothbrush action,
and...
Like a summer breeze.
You can forget this thing.
Looking good.
Well, dreamer.
OK, Zippy, Teddy's going out.
Wish me luck.
Hmm, little kissie. Oh, sweet.
Back at you.
OK, I'm off.
Oop. Almost forgot.
Cookie!
Macadamia. Yes!
Open sesame.
Here we go.
And swish!
I got a strong tail.
OK, my first case.
Don't cook your circuits again,
Coltrane.
I'm sick of always dragging you
in for repair.
Downloading
outlaw combustion vehicles.
Attention, shoppers.
In-store special at aisle nine.
Naughty boy clones
are half-off.
Seriously, Coltrane...
you sure your CPUs
are ready for action?
Oh, yeah.
At midnight tomorrow,
it's all over!
We're doomed!
Somebody, help me! Help!
Got you!
Gentlemen,
it's so good to see you!
I'm from the Grid Police.
Are you collecting
for the Policeman’s Ball?
Humor! Humor!
Put that thing away.
It could go off.
Somebody could get hurt.
Well, then I suggest
you not move, huh?
Grid Police!
Now, gentlemen,
you've been observed.
You've been seen,
spotted, caught...
committing a crime,
so you're under arrest.
Well, thank you.
Upsadaisy!
I thought you said
you had the front.
you had the back.
-Oh, like you had the front?
-Like you had the back.
Nothing like
a welcome-back party.
These were not
engine scavengers.
-Body hunters?
-Probably.
DNA-encrypted clone.
I.D. unknown.
Serial number unknown.
Manufacturer unknown.
Recommend Medevac for final I.D.
It's as if he didn't exist.
But that doesn't make any sense.
Coltrane downloading.
I need Medevac.
Yeah. Headquarters. Medevac.
Yeah. I need an I.D.
on a murder victim.
Have Knife contact me as soon
as he's got the information.
Thank you.
You two call yourselves cops?
You're a circus act.
Modem Katie's performance test
to my terminal.
If the numbers check out...
you'll be street-legal again,
Coltrane.
Welcome back to the Grid, Katie.
Check your circuits, Coltrane.
If any...
I love when he does that. I do.
This is a precedent-setting
crime site.
We are
at the carnival graveyard...
where the body of a dinosaur
has just been discovered...
and from the looks of it,
the victim of foul play.
Grid Police are investigating--
-Hey, hey, move it along.
-Hey, what are you doing?
-This is a secured crime scene.
-Excuse me! Since when?
-Behind the barrier.
-Hey, Teddy, how you doing?
Hey, Sarah. What's going on?
It looks like somebody
had a sensitivity attack...
and wants to keep
this incident under wraps...
which, you know,
I don't blame 'em...
because if this got out...
Could be trouble, I know.
Yeah. So, what are you doing
out in the jungle tonight, huh?
Funny thing.
I was home asleep, right?
And all of a sudden,
I had this flash.
Deep down,
I knew something was wrong.
Wait, are you telling me
that all you dinos...
are on the same wavelength?
Well, it's kind of like
we feel for each other.
It's hard to explain.
Look at this, would you?
Dinocide.
This is terrible.
Yeah. That's a first.
Got any clues?
No suspects, no evidence,
no clues, no nothing...
unless you got something for me.
No. I wish.
All right, buddy. You take care.
You, too.
Oh, boy.
Poor guy.
Body bag coming through.
Coming in. Coming in. OK.
Yeah. Teddy Rex.
Where's Commissioner Lynch?
The commissioner is at
the New Eden fund-raiser, Teddy.
I'm on my way.
Our Zapheads
have come through...
compliments of Adam.
Where's the body?
Uh, we lost it
when the guns jumped us.
Guns?
Mr. Edge, we shook them off.
We're lucky
we're still breathing.
I agree.
Mr. Edge, now, we wouldn’t want
to make Mr. Kane angry.
Look him in the eye...
convince the commissioner
I'm his man--dino.
That's right, dino.
Walk tall.
-Hey, hey, watch it, tubby!
-Sign back there. Sorry.
Can I help you a minute?
Yeah. Wash, no wax, please.
Official business.
As you were, gentlemen.
Can you believe that?
Just in, a dead dinosaur
has been found...
in the carnival graveyard.
DNA pioneer EIizar Kane...
announced the revival
of the now-extinct raccoon...
will begin
at midnight tomorrow...
using the same revolutionary
cloning techniques...
Elephants, lions, whales,
now raccoons?
Katie,
what's happening to the world?
I ask myself that same question
all the time.
What are you doing up so late?
Dad said I could help him out
tonight.
He should be here any minute.
You know,
it's about time you two meet.
You’re just relentless,
aren’t you?
Coltrane,
report to New Eden Foundation...
Grid 2120, priority one.
Forget it. I'm off, remember?
Yeah. Priority one.
Your car's on the way.
All right. Thanks.
Do me a favor--catch up
with my little buddy...
take him up to my apartment
and give him something to eat.
Sure. Can you swing by
the playground tomorrow?
It's a surprise.
I'm not real good
with surprises.
Aw, Katie!
All right. I'll try.
-Katie...
-I'll be there if I can.
Tomorrow!
I'll try really hard.
OK. See you.
See you.
Why not bring back bald eagles
and then raccoons?
Kane's bringing back
all the extinct species.
Thank you.
Well, good evening.
-Rex, T. Rex.
-I'm sorry.
This is
an invitation-only affair.
Really?
How's this invitation, Frenchy?
Teddy! What a surprise.
You here to work the room?
I'm looking
for Commissioner Lynch.
Whoop, there he is. Nice
talking to you, Mr. Summers.
Excuse me. Pardon me.
God!
Something smells good here.
Well!
Commissioner Lynch,
sorry to barge in.
Excuse me.
Teddy?
There's been a murder
at the carnival graveyard, sir.
-And?
-Commissioner.
EIizar Kane, I'd like you
to meet Teddy Rex...
Assistant Press Liaison Officer
with the Grid Police Department.
But, of course,
you must know each other.
Teddy and myself go back a ways.
This is Dr. Shade,
my personal doctor.
-How do you do?
-Good evening.
Not many people get
to meet their maker...
at a fund-raiser, huh?
Teddy's my crowning achievement.
Wow. Thank you, Mr. Kane.
-Please excuse me.
-Oh, of course.
Very nice to have you here,
but tell me why you are here.
Well, it's kind
of a police matter, and...
It is now my great honor
to present EIizar Kane--
DNA research pioneer...
and, of course, the founder of
the New Eden ecology movement.
Thank you. Thank you.
Years ago,
I re-created dinosaurs...
to show how science could
change the world, and I did.
My friends, the ark is ready.
Mankind will step aside
for our new destiny.
-My dream is...
-Sir, this was a dinocide.
-A dinocide?
-Yes.
Excuse me, sir.
Is something wrong?
Yes. Yes.
There's been a dinocide.
I beg your pardon, sir...
but I'd like to be assigned
to the case.
Teddy, you have a great future
in the department--
Sir, I'm just a publicity stunt.
-I want to be a real detective.
-Now, now, now, Teddy...
we all have our paths to follow.
I understand,
but dinos and humans are here...
to rise above our limitations--
you know,
make our dreams come true.
What?
Teddy, you sound like
you're running for office.
Please, sir,
just give me a chance.
At ease, Teddy. At ease.
Sir, a minute, if you would.
Please?
You may help yourself.
So, what do we have, Frenchy?
Meat, meat, meat, and meat.
You know,
I'm a recovering carnivore.
Sweets.
Ah! Yes! Cookies!
One per customer!
Toodle-oo.
Now, our tall and shiny
reptile freak over there--
he could be the key.
We could make him
our first dino detective.
What? Are you out of your mind?
Just track with me, sir.
Look, Teddy solves the dinocide.
Inter species relations are
smoothed over. Who's the hero?
-Teddy Rex.
-No! Lynch--
the commissioner
who had the vision...
to look beyond species
to tame our town.
Six of these.
Cheers.
Oh, Teddy...
Yes, sir?
You have the case.
Undercover. No press. No fuss.
Just results
by prime time tomorrow.
Let me go! Put me down!
-I can't believe it!
-That big pig!
I won't let you down.
I got to call my mom.
I don't have a mom.
-There is one condition.
-There is?
Yes. We're teaming you up
for your own good.
-Great.
-With a veteran, a pro--
Colstein.
Well, well, well.
Hey! Coltrane!
What?
Yes, I do,
but that's not the point.
-Commissioner.
-Coltrane.
-Summers.
-Coltrane...
there's been a homicide,
and your name came up.
Am I a suspect?
Actually, it was a dinocide.
A dinosaur is dead.
Teddy Rex, meet Katie Coltrane.
You two solve this case
together.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What? What?
Teddy's in public relations...
but I'm field promoting him
temporarily.
-He's a dinosaur.
-Come on, Coltrane...
he graduated from the academy
just like you did.
-He's a dinosaur!
-You're not a specist, are you?
Give me results
by prime time tomorrow...
and I'll double
your regular commissions.
He's a dinosaur! Come on!
Hey, Coltrane,
straighten up and fly right.
This is your chance
for a comeback. Don't blow it.
He's a dinosaur!
Look, as long as
we're partners...
why don't we
make the best of it, huh?
You're a dinosaur.
Yes, technically.
I have this dream.
I've always wanted
to be a detective.
If Oliver Rex would’ve squealed
about your master plan...
nobody would’ve believed him...
but with the nose job
Edge gave him...
we don't have to worry
about that anymore, do we?
You little squid.
You're supposed to make certain
your police pals stay clear.
That is your job.
And for which you will
follow us into the next world.
For your information...
I have used
my own powers of persuasion...
to convince the commissioner
to assign...
the department's token dino
to your messy dinocide.
-Theodore Rex?
-Yes.
I've also teamed him up
with a burnt-out gun.
This is going to be trouble,
I can feel it.
Hey, Coltrane and Teddy Rex
will blow this case.
I guarantee it.
And we will just sail away.
Ah, my stop.
Well, midnight tomorrow.
Ta-ta.
This is from Adam.
Edge.
You do realize...
the missile launch
is midnight tomorrow?
-That's your problem.
-There's no leeway.
All right, don't get
your knickers in a twist.
My people are working on it.
Don't call Zapheads people.
They belong in cages.
Well, then clone me
some better ones.
You know how I feel
about failure.
Yes, sir.
It reeks of imperfection!
What do you want me to do?
Just have them followed.
I don't want anyone
to sense our concern.
Spinner...
Spinner, over here.
Psst. Hey, wake up.
Get your finger
out of your nose.
Spinner!
Yes, Mr. Edge?
Listen, I'm going to give
you toads a shot at redemption.
Redemp...
You, shut up!
Listen, I want you to keep
your beady eye...
on that gun and the rex.
Look but don’t touch.
Whatever you say, sir.
Good.
All aboard.
One seat. No waiting.
-Seat guards.
-What?
Safety first.
Safety...
Driving defensively...
Listen, I can raise your seat.
No, thanks. No, no, no!
Get me down--now!
I'll lower it.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Listen, uh, I just...
I just wanted to say
that it's a real pleasure...
working with a professional
like yourself.
What do you have on the case?
We got a dead dino,
which is a first.
No suspects, no clues,
no motives.
So we need to determine
a cause of death, right?
Where would you have
a dino autopsy?
Yes!
The Museum of Natural History!
Of course! We're off!
Sorry, ma'am.
Pharaoh or whatever you are,
sorry.
Oh, holy shoot.
Back to traffic school.
Coming, coming.
Everything's fine.
Just got to glue its head
back on.
You going to a fire?
Slow down.
No.
It's just fossils creep me out.
Why is that?
I can feel my ancestors,
you know?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Your ancestors?
Yeah--staring at me,
talking to me.
Yeah, right.
What are they saying?
Well, they want me
to follow my heart...
do the right thing--the usual.
Please.
Well, don't you have
a guardian angel?
-Yeah. Me.
-Right.
-Wow!
-What now?
I mean, look at this!
You know,
it just makes me wonder.
I mean, these bones
have so many untold stories.
If dinos weren't extinct,
we'd be running the world...
and you soft-skins
would be fossils.
-Can it, OK?
-Whatever.
Poor little guy.
-You knew him?
-Well, yes and no.
What do you mean? You either
knew him, or you didn't.
Well, I've see him around, but
I didn't know him personally.
-Can I help you?
-Yeah.
Grid Police. Who are you?
Dr. Armitraj,
head dinosaurologist.
He's a detective?
-For now.
-Katie!
-Let's cut to the chase.
-Be nice.
What do you have on the victim?
He died of an explosion
close to his snout.
I really have not had
a chance to look at him.
-Oh, excuse me.
-Doctor, may I?
-Help yourself.
-Thank you.
May you what?
Religion.
There you go.
Send this to Captain Alaric
at headquarters.
See, he can reconstruct
whatever killed our friend here.
Then we'll have our lead.
-What about prints?
-Ah, prints.
You see, the scale patterns
on our tails...
are all different and distinct.
Headquarters computer, I need
a tail print I.D., please.
Stand by for a holofax,
will you?
Oh, and I need you to do this
as quickly as you can for me.
Tail print I.D. confirmed.
T. Rex I.D.--Oliver Rex.
Cloned at New Eden.
Lives at Prehistoric Place
with Molly Rex.
Molly Rex?
-Is that somebody you know?
-Don't I wish?
She sings at a nightclub
on Prehistoric Place.
Get down, yeah.
Get back up again.
Groovin'.
What is that smell?
Clean, unfiltered air.
Everything in here
is good for you.
-Hey, Teddy!
-Hey, Tina.
-How are you?
-I'm fine. You?
I'm fine. Soft-skin, I see.
Her name's Katie Coltrane.
Could we get the tour, please?
Walk with me. Welcome
to the Extinct Species Club.
If a species shows up here,
it's history.
Yeah, well, you must be
running out of space.
Yeah, well, more species
are vanishing every day.
Maybe Mr. Kane
will bring these species back...
just like he did with dinosaurs.
You said a mouthful.
OK. Let's talk liquids here.
We've got glacier, natural,
or fizzy water--that's H2O.
I'll just take some tap,
thank you.
Sorry. I don't dance.
Oh, I'm kidding.
Listen, find yourself a table.
Make yourself comfy. I love you.
That thing at the table
just clacked at me.
That's just Grok.
He likes soft-skins.
He thinks you're kinda cute.
-What is this?
-Ah, now, this is great.
This is hydroponic seaweed
and krill.
No toxins, chemicals, or dyes.
-You gotta try some.
-No, thank you.
-Come on.
-No, no, no.
-I don't want any. Put it down.
-All right.
Can I ask you
a personal question?
-Sure.
-I thought you people...
you know, ate meat.
Um, I'm kind of on the wagon.
You know, it's not like
the old days, Katie...
with herds of duck-bills
roaming through the plains.
Yeah, and you guys
were eating them all.
Oh, and you humans
are such a deal, huh?
The only time you soft-skins...
seem to pay attention
to other creatures...
is to shoot them, eat them,
or wear them.
Am I right?
Are you listening to me?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
You just don't--
What is he doing?
I mean, it's a whole thing.
-We don't get out much, do we?
-No, I don't.
-Great.
-I'm just going to see...
what I can find
out in the rest of the room.
I gotta get out of his eyesight.
He's making me nervous.
-Fine.
-Check her out.
-Go freshen up.
-All right.
Oh, man.
Molly.
And now,
my reptilian relations...
clack your claws
for the bodacious cretaceous...
mesozoic mama...
Miss Molly Rex!
Come on, let me cling on,
feel like I'm dying
Make that low-down music
tickle up your spine
Baby, I could warm you
with this heart of mine
I'm no angel
I'll take your blues
Stomp down your troubles
Rock you with a steady roll
Use your connection
to win my affection
You're my little
ace in the hole
Let me hug you now
before the night is gone
Come on, flag this joint,
so we can carry on
I can make you heaven
while the shades are drawn
I'm no angel
Come on, honey, thrill me
like a midnight breeze
Don't care how you do it, babe
Just so you please
Take my kisses
till your weary heart's at ease
I'm no angel
I'll take your blues
And stomp down your troubles
Love you with heart and soul
I love her!
You're my little
ace in the hole
How's about it?
And you think
you're going to get somebody?
-Not tonight, baby.
-Hey, come here.
-Let's go.
-No! Police business, right?
-Yeah. Let's go.
-Dressing room. I'm coming.
-Flowers from a fan.
-Whoa. Thank you.
Have we met?
Well, uh, I've seen you around.
-We're the Grid Police.
-I knew it.
Last night, I'm dead asleep...
and all of a sudden,
I get this flash.
I know. Me, too.
Dinosaurs feel for each other.
Oh, yeah. They sure do.
-Excuse me.
-Certainly.
Don't bruise the taffeta.
Wide load coming through.
Ooh, shouldn't have said that.
Sorry.
Hey, come on.
We're looking for a killer here.
-Whoa. Killer?
-Yeah, well...
Mrs. Rex, I'm sorry to say
that your husband Oliver...
was murdered last night.
Did he have any enemies
that you knew of?
Murdered--oh, wait.
Wait a second--
Ollie wasn't my husband.
-He was my roommate.
-Great!
No, that's bad.
I mean, uh, I feel for you.
What exactly was he?
A pussycat.
No, no, I mean, what did he do?
He was an entertainer.
A song and dance dino.
Worked kiddie parties
and conventions.
Did he have any hobbies?
You know, outside interests.
He worked at New Eden.
It was in his heart--
-Did you say New Eden?
-Mm-hmm.
Well, thank you, Miss Rex.
You are so beautiful.
I mean, you were so helpful.
Say, won’t you come to Oliver's
recycling here tomorrow?
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
You said you didn't know
he was dead...
and suddenly now
you're having the funeral?
I find that a bit odd.
Nope. Speedy funerals
are a dino custom.
Yeah. Can you ix-nay
on the funeral-ay, please?
Yeah. Get the breath-ay
out of my face-ay.
I'll be outside. Excuse me.
Like I said,
if you think of anything...
I will definitely
get a hold of you.
-Listen, just call me Teddy.
-Teddy.
I'll see you at the funeral.
I got to get some air.
Excuse me.
I really got to go.
I'll call you. See you.
-That was inexcusable.
-What? What was?
Your glandoism.
-I am not glando.
-You are glando.
Your mind has shut down,
and your glands have taken over.
Hey, I am not lovesick, OK?
I know I haven't been
a detective long...
but I'm fully in control--
We have I.D. on
your murder victim from tonight.
I'll be there.
We'll pick up
where we left off tomorrow.
I'll see you then.
OK, I'll just gas up
and go home.
-Straight home.
-Right.
Look, boys,
they're splitting up...
and there goes our little witch
with the gun.
Wait a minute.
Now, you remember
what Edge said. Just watch.
I suppose we could
tweak his tail a smidge.
The police
My first case.
Let's see what I got so far.
I have the victim's I.D.,
and his roommate is Molly Rex.
Oh, Molly Rex.
Molly, Molly,
Molly, Molly, Molly.
Oh, I love the sound of that.
Ah, some trick-or-treaters
out for an early Halloween.
Knife.
Coltrane.
So, how did your rewiring go?
-What's it to you?
-Very good.
They kept
your aggression level up.
I must say, the dead clone
you sent me tonight...
was quite a puzzle...
but I finally got his I.D.
by breaking the code.
-The code?
-The genetic code.
The map of our destiny,
and we're all slaves to our DNA.
Zapheads! It's Zapheads!
Hey, what are you doing?
That's not nice.
Get off of there!
This is T. Rex.
This is an emergency.
Mayday, mayday, mayday!
This is
an official police vehicle.
Code red! Code red!
Katie! Where are you?
Look at these cloning patterns.
Very precise, very regular...
each one bearing
the proprietary imprint...
of the creating corporation.
It gets better.
Look at this.
New Eden.
The foundation was built
on the cloning patterns.
All registered to Kane.
According to the I.D. numbers
on those molecules...
his name was Adam.
Adam.
Hey, I just had a new tune-up!
I mean it, you guys!
Get off of there! Mayday!
Hey! Katie!
-Katie! Katie!
-Yeah.
-Help me, Katie!
-See you.
Get out of here! Come on! Get!
You think you're scary.
Scary red eyes.
Come on! Don't get me mad.
I hit the fire extinguisher,
and my whole world went white.
Katie, my door is stuck.
What is going on? Why didn't
you go home like I told you to?
I did. I was.
I--I ran into some Zapheads.
-Did you pull your gun?
-My--my gun?
Yeah, your gun.
Don't you have a gun?
Well, actually, I--
I don't believe in violence.
You don't believe
in violence...
and yet you want to be
a police person?
You must lead
a charmed life, then.
Yeah. Don't I just?
Night on the town, huh, boys?
We have made
some very hot credits...
selling the dino's
tour car parts...
on the old black market.
I thought I made myself
crystal-clear.
Look, but don't touch.
Well, of course I warned them...
but do you think that they
would listen to me? Oh, no.
When you can't
control yourselves...
you make it harder for us all.
Well, it seems to--
Well, you know, I mean,
everyone has their own agenda.
Mercy.
This is your last chance.
You keep your eye
on the rex and the gun...
or I'll stick you
in the blender.
Slick partner, Coltrane.
Pick on a dino. That's easy.
-Beauty and the beast.
-Yeah. Who's who?
I need another
rex-friendly vehicle.
You promise to take care of it?
The word around here is
you're in the doghouse.
Look, you--
I told you about that.
Don't piss him off, OK?
OK. Actually, you're in luck.
I happen to have
the perfect vehicle for you.
Well, get it outside right now!
-Excuse me. I have to go.
-Let's go.
People, people, people,
what has the world come to...
when cop cars get stripped
with the cop still in them?
I don't know, Katie. Why would
those Zapheads go after me?
-Can it.
-Teddy! Coltrane!
Your tour car was bought
with taxpayers' money.
You've been on this case
for twelve hours...
and you've got zip
to show for it.
Teddy, look, we cut a deal.
You wanted this case, and
I wanted a boost in my polls.
-Yeah.
-Not more trouble!
I didn't want this case
to begin with.
What?
Where the hell were you
when the car was stripped?
-I was at Medevac.
-Medevac?
Your orders
were to stick with Teddy!
You embarrassed the department.
What do you mean, I--
Sir, if anyone let
the department down, it's me.
-Yes!
-Yeah.
Yeah. Look at you.
You don't even
look like a detective.
Oh, sir, please.
You cannot judge a dino
by his scales.
What?
Never mind.
Coltrane,
you stay out of this...
or I'll transfer you
back to drug duty.
A gun and a dinosaur detective.
Wait till I get my hands
on Summers.
Summers?
Do me a favor.
Meet me up at supply.
-OK.
-Open your mouth.
Minty fresh.
Commissioner.
Are you telling me
Summers set this up?
You heard me. He said
you still have the magic.
Remember, this case
better be gift-wrapped...
by prime time tonight, or else.
-Coltrane.
-Sir.
Any I.D. on that murder victim
from last night?
Yes. It turns out he's
a clone registered to New Eden.
Interesting. I'm working
on those weapon fragments...
they sent me from the museum.
Nice bit of sleuthing, Coltrane.
Thank you, sir.
-Hey, Ella.
-Hey, Teddy.
What happened to you?
Oh, don't ask.
Hey, I'm here for a new look.
-Oh, really?
-Oh, yeah, yeah.
I'm on my first case.
How about that?
-That's wonderful. Good luck.
-Thank you, thank you.
-Undercover dinosaur, huh?
-Yeah, right. That's right.
Look, I've got to blend in, OK?
-Oh. Go to the zoo.
-Ella!
Step right up. Go ahead.
All right. Here I go.
Turn around
-Ready?
-OK, Ella. Dress me up.
Now, make me look nice, OK?
I got this very picky partner.
Besides being loud, obnoxious,
and very pushy...
she's a joy to work with.
Oh, that's no good.
Kill all the wabbits
Ella, this is not undercover.
Push the button!
Ella, undercover.
Porfavor. Please!
Not bad.
Undercover now!
He's a cop. You got to
make him look like a real cop.
Ella.
I'm getting a wee bit of
breeze in my lowlands, lassie.
Work with me, will you?
All right.
I think this will do fine.
Yeah. You look good.
You look like a real cop.
I'm too sexy for my clothes.
Where are we going?
-Whoa. Slow down a minute.
-What?
-New Eden?
-Yeah. What's the matter?
It's just that Dr. Kane...
you know, he's my creator
and a father figure--
-Come on, Teddy.
-What?
You sound like
we're going to arrest the guy.
We're just going to ask him
questions.
That's what we do.
We're police officers.
If you want to play
with the big guys...
you got to behave
like a big guy.
-New wheels, Coltrane.
-Thank you.
-You ready?
-Yeah.
-That's our new van.
-What?
Hey, kind of cute.
And it's leaving.
Why is it leaving? Hello?
Guess we're hoofing it.
I, uh...what?
That guy at the desk--
look at that thing!
Calm down. Calm down.
Breathe. Breathe.
Zen. Zen.
Now let's go.
-How am I going to get in?
-Through the back.
Get in the back.
In the back
of the garbage truck?
Oh, fine. I'll sit in the back
of the garbage truck...
where it smells like cheese
and fish and boogers.
Oh, it stinks in here.
Ohh. I get my first case
and here I am...
in the back of a garbage truck
with the goosh and the mush.
Are you driving or what?
No. I'm waiting for you
to sit down.
I can't sit down, because
if I sit down, I'll get gushy...
and I'm not going
to get gushy...
because I just got
my new clothes.
OK, sorry, you're right.
You know how
to drive this thing?
-Shut up. Shut up!
-Well, then close the door.
Hey, you don't mind
if we make a stop, do you?
Ooh! Fine.
I'll just be in the back.
What am I stepping in?
Ugh! Guano!
Are you sure you can drive?
Whoa! Don't hit the cadets!
Don't hit the cadets!
I'll get you back for this.
My snout!
Pass it to Joey. Joey's open.
Pass it to Joey!
Cool! A dinosaur.
Hey, kids, what's going on?
-What's your name?
-What's up?
-How you doing?
-Hey, look at the dinosaur.
-Nice blading, guys.
-You look good.
Thanks for coming. Don't worry.
My dad's not here.
-Oh, good.
-He's at work.
I wanted to give you this.
-What? This is for me?
-Yeah.
-That's nice.
-It is nice.
It's a badge case,
now that you're a gun again.
I finished it this morning.
Yeah. Thanks.
That is so sweet.
You know, this looks like fun.
Can I play?
-Sure!
-Meet Teddy Rex.
-Do you blade?
-Oh, yeah. I'm amazing.
What, are you kidding?
I got a room full of trophies
at home.
They retired my jersey.
I even have a candy bar
named after me.
-Hey, hey, stop that.
-What?
-Candy bar too much?
-A little.
May I have three balls
at the same time, please?
Watch the master at work.
Face the wind.
A-one, two, three!
I'm the baddest dino in town,
doo da, doo da
I had Spinner
follow the rex and the gun.
Take a look.
The kid's the handle on them
in case they get too close.
Leave it to me.
Wow, Sebastian.
I just, uh...
It's a badge case,
now that you're a gun again.
Well, here we are.
The New Eden compound, Katie.
Get me out. It stinks.
Can you believe this? This guy
has got his own personal zoo.
Yeah. Incredible.
It's the only place in the Grid
that still has live animals.
A pair of every animal on earth.
Yeah. I think this is--ow!
-Sorry.
-No problem.
Sorry.
Can you just slide your butt...
-Yeah. That's great.
-Like that?
-All right.
-All right, buddy, let's go.
Oh, boy.
It's like coming home for me,
Katie.
This is where I grew up.
And here's Mr. Kane's lab,
where I was cloned.
Ah.
Memories, memories, memories.
Freeze the elephants first.
Midnight
is only five hours away.
May I help you?
-Welcome to New Eden, Mr. Rex.
-Well, thank you very much.
We're here to see Kane.
-And you are?
-Coltrane. Grid Police.
And you are?
Dr. Shade, Kane's
personal physician. Follow.
-Come, Teddy. Follow.
-Hmm. Follow.
I hope he has a moment to spare.
This is highly unusual.
Mr. Kane, you have visitors--
Teddy Rex and, um...
-Coltrane.
-Yes. Coltrane.
Yes. Welcome, Theodore. Hello.
Hi, Mr. Kane.
I'm sorry to barge in, sir...
but I'd like you to meet
my partner...
Detective Katie Coltrane.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to...meet you.
We have something wonderful
to show you.
Guppies?
Ice fish.
They're remarkable creatures.
They live in our polar oceans...
in water so cold,
no other organism can survive.
They possess an enzyme which
I've isolated and reproduced.
Because of it,
ice fish can be trapped...
and frozen in ice for years.
Brought back to life again.
After injecting a serum
from the ice fish...
into a subject's blood...
they can be frozen and
reanimated whenever you like.
That's just peachy, but we are
not here for a social call.
-I liked the fish.
-Come on.
No need to take an attitude.
I'll try to remember that.
We're here because
someone gave Oliver Rex...
and a clone named Adam
a new cosmic address.
Is there--is there something
we can do to help?
Well, according to his roommate,
Oliver worked here...
and the dead clone
was registered to you.
Adam worked in species data
with Oliver.
-Species data?
-I collect endangered species.
We try to rescue
the last specimen when we can...
and keep them here
at my compound.
Thank you for letting us know.
You're so very welcome, but
I do have one more thing to ask.
Isn't it a little strange
to you...
that both these guys were made
extinct on the same night...
and they both
just happened to work for you?
It strikes me as tragic.
I'm sorry, officers.
I'm sorry I can't be
of more help to you.
-Thank you.
-Thank you for your time.
Thank you. Good-bye.
Good-bye, and I really
enjoyed seeing the fishes.
-Let's go.
-Excuse me. Coming!
Goal!
Brothers and sisters...
we are gathered here this day
to recycle Oliver Rex...
who, from the beginning
to the end...
was our friend.
Listen, where's the body?
He was liquefied.
What do you mean, he was
liquefied--like a smoothie?
You see those tubes over there?
His essence
fertilizes the flowers...
so that each guest
can take some home.
Farewell, sweet Ollie.
Oliver! Oliver!
Oliver is compost!
It couldn't have been a dino--
Oh, yes! She speaketh the truth!
Go on, baby doll! You testify!
Maybe it was the soft-skins,
Oliver!
-What?
-Who's next?
Please.
A word from your creator.
My children, my children.
I am to blame
for Oliver's murder...
because it was I who brought
dinosaurs back to life.
But I give you my solemn oath...
we'll find
who's responsible for this.
A better world is coming.
I promise. I promise.
My favorite part.
-I'm going after Kane.
-What?
I'm going after Kane.
Good funeral.
Thanks so much for coming,
Teddy.
Oh, uh, Molly, my pleasure.
If there's anything else
I can do...
Well, a walk home
would be a lifesaver.
Yeah.
Let me ask my partner.
Excuse me. Oh, boy.
Oh, boy.
Molly wants you
to walk her home...
and it's purely
police business?
What was I, hatched yesterday?
-No, no, no.
-Come on. What are you doing?
We have work to do here.
Yeah, I know, but
think of it as a police escort.
Please?
Don't do the eyes.
You know the eyes kill me.
-OK, I'll tell you what.
-I'm sorry.
You have one hour. We'll finish
the interrogations inside.
You be back here in an hour.
And do me a favor.
-What?
-Do you have a breath mint?
-Nothing. One hour.
-Nice ceremony.
-Thank you.
-Theodore.
-Yes, Century?
I advise you to give up
your dream of being a detective.
No. I can't do that.
-Are you ready, Teddy?
-Ah, Molly. You bet.
-Right this way.
-They never listen.
Ah, youth.
Mr. Kane, I have something
that might interest you.
My best friend’s a cop!
She's going to kick your butt!
Get me out of here right now!
Hey, man, what are you doing?
Get off me!
Hey, help! Hey! Let me go, man!
Get your--get off of me!
Meet Sebastian--
Coltrane's pet, our insurance.
How do you do, young man?
Stuff it, pantload!
Hey, mind your manners, kid.
Get your hands off me,
you scarecrow!
Well, what do you know?
It's--it's my house.
You want a...
a little snack--
maybe some milk and cookies?
I'm a fool for milk and cookies.
Milk and cookies!
Cookies, cookies, cookies,
cookies, cookies!
Milk and cookies for my tummy
Here we are--home, sweet home.
I'm just going
to straighten up a little.
Oh, well. It's a mess.
-Oh, say, it's so cozy.
-You really think so?
-I know.
-I decorated myself.
-Nice--nice kick.
-Yeah. I started in the chorus.
No kidding. Really? Wow.
Well, gee, Molly,
I'd like you to meet my dog.
This is Zippy the dog.
Oh, doggies.
Zippy. Zippy, talk nice.
Zip--Zippy!
No, no, no! Don't...
Sorry. He's a little mad.
I left him alone so much.
Coltrane, Teddy Rex, report
to Captain Alaric A.S.A.P.
Do you want to see
my car collection, Molly?
I've got some really nice ones.
A gray one and a big silver one
with mag wheels--
a whole pile of them.
-Oh, Molly...
-Step out, boy.
I'm not such a good--
such a good dancer, Molly.
One, two, three.
Two, two, three.
Hold me tight!
Twirling and whirling...
The dinos are, uh...
well...
dancing.
I got it, Molly! I got it!
You got some stuff in you.
Watch your tail there.
Look out!
Watch it, Zippy!
Oh, Molly, Molly, Molly, Molly.
Whoo! I'm getting chills
on my scales.
Teddy, I know you're up there,
and I know you can hear me.
You don't know
what's going to happen to you...
if you don't get your tail
down here right now.
Look, I know it's not much.
It'll probably
turn your finger green--
turn your finger greener.
Teddy, it's perfect.
Wow.
Listen, I'll be back soon.
-Oh, you have to go?
-Duty calls. Toodle-oo!
Take care.
Oh, you...
So long.
It's a badge case,
now that you're a gun again.
Molly, Molly, Molly.
Ooh, you got it bad, don't you?
My, my, my, aren’t we
just a tad glando this evening?
Come on! I'm not glando, OK?
Oh, I see you dancing out
in the street under the stars...
and flinging your tail around
like you're a free guy.
Oh, Katie, you act like
only humans fall in love.
I can't understand you.
Why do you keep your feelings
all bottled up inside, huh?
You Yoknapatawpha are? You are
the classic ankylosaurus type.
That's right. Tough exterior...
but soft and gushy
on the inside.
Get into the truck, Teddy.
They want us at headquarters.
It sure looked like you cared
for Sebastian back there.
Am I right or wrong?
Right? Wrong? Right.
Do me a favor.
Don’t tip. Don’t twirl.
Don't swirl.
Just walk--like a man!
Well, do your best.
Get in the truck.
I reconstructed
the little gizmo myself.
-It's a butterfly?
-It's a replica.
It carries an explosive device
in its body.
It explodes on contact
with the victim--
-the work of a real artiste.
-Nasty.
Now, where would our killer
get a weapon like this?
Only one name comes to mind.
In technokill circles,
he's known as the Toymaker.
-Toymaker.
-So, where do we find him?
He runs a dead storage company
as a cover.
It's called Dragontail
Dead Storage Company--
somewhere in the Ninja Grid.
-Good luck, Coltrane.
-Thanks. Come on.
Time for a house call,
eh, Katie?
Brake, brake, brake!
I thought you said
you could drive!
Can it.
So, this is
Dragontail Dead Storage.
Yep. Download ambush avoidance.
What?
I didn't know you were bioware.
Yeah. All guns are.
We're implanted with biochips.
You see this badge?
It's like a union label.
We're more human than human.
Let's go.
Hey, that must be
classified information.
Yes, it is,
so let's keep it that way.
Oh, right. Ahem.
So, you're a human
computer terminal, right?
Yeah. After you.
-Door. Let's go.
-Right.
-Didn't I tell you to be quiet?
-No minimum tail clearance.
So, people keep
dead relatives here...
until medical science
can reanimate them?
Well, they brought
you guys back...
so why should that
be a surprise?
Well, that's true.
-Walk like me.
-Right--like you.
Tip..toe...
Stop with the tip-tip.
Don't tip-tip. Just tiptoe.
What is that smell?
Is that you?
It's not me.
How could it be me?
-Did you--
-Look, I didn't butt-trumpet.
One of these things is leaking.
Fine, fine. Let's go.
-Doo doo--
-Don't "Doo doo doo."
-What?
What,
am I waking these mummies up?
Come on. Come on.
All right, there's a bell.
I'm going to ring it.
All right, ring the bell.
Yeah.
Maybe we should look around.
Welcome to Dead Storage.
Who's going to die?
Nobody's dying.
We're looking for the Toymaker.
Never heard of him.
What do you mean? Come on.
We know he's here. Where is he?
Who wants to know?
Who are you?
I'm the guy from the bag.
You want me to get
in that bag with you...
and snatch you to pieces?
Ooh, I'd love it, baby.
Come and get it.
Come here. Come here.
Don't be going in my bag,
you understand?
Listen, zit...
I want to know
where the Toymaker is...
or my friend here is going
to bite your pea head off.
Food.
-Ha!
-What do you mean, ha?
You're four inches tall,
and you're giving us "Ha"?
Hey, nightmare hair, take
lizard lips and get out of here.
Take that.
Fuzzy! We got trouble!
What's he talking about Fuzzy?
What is Fuzzy?
I don't know.
It's a hairy hot dog.
-Cops!
-Cops? I'm out of here.
What?
Follow me.
Let's go. Come on.
Up, up, up, and away.
We're going now.
This is us moving. Elevator up.
-I'm going.
-Get me out of here.
-Let's go.
-Follow me.
I'll take your blues,
stomp down your troubles
Love you with heart and soul
I'll take your blues,
stomp down your troubles
Rock you with a steady roll
Here's your connection,
take my affection
Then you're my--aah!
All right,
you're coming with us.
Not in this life, dream boy.
Miss Molly Rex, I presume?
I can't believe
you'd do that in the elevator.
I didn't pump gas.
-Katie, I have an idea.
-What?
I'll play a tough guy--
you know, from the old movies?
-Yeah. What about it?
-Check it out. Watch this.
Is anybody home, sweetheart?
-I believe this is our host.
-Watch my attitude here.
A bioware...and a dragon.
That's tyrannosaurus rex,
girlie-boy.
Welcome.
Have some tea.
Are you the Toymaker?
I've been called many things.
What's this, Kung Fu? I don't
want to play games with you.
-We're here because--
-We need a gun.
What, headquarters
doesn't supply you with weapons?
Yeah, they'll give us weapons,
but they're too bleeping small.
We got a problem with that?
What are you doing?
-I'm here to buy a gun, OK?
-You don't need to buy a gun.
-Katie, I'm undercover here.
-What, what, what?
Work with me!
Oh, is this a ruse?
You need a gun.
-I need a gun.
-He needs a gun--
a big gun, because he's a big...
guy.
I almost thought you meant that.
Could you stay here, please?
I'll finish the act.
Oh, sure.
That's more like it.
Very nice.
You do very professional work.
Oh, and by the way...
last night, one of your
butterflies killed a dino...
and we can connect you
to the murder.
Suck eggs, cops!
-What is that?
-It's a bug, and it's beeping.
It's beeping,
and I don't feel good about it.
-Let's backtrack.
-Easy, steady.
Don't shake the platform.
You know what? Little tiny
baby steps to the left is good.
Now to the right.
-I'm out of here.
-Right, right, right.
Go on. Right, right, right.
Hey, I ain't cleaning this up.
I'm going to hit him, Katie,
I swear.
What do you mean? What are you
going to hit him with?
-With my breath.
-Oh, no, not that.
No. Don't do it, don't do it.
Oh, come on--oh...
That breath didn't bother you?
Last chance.
Who bought the butterfly?
That's it!
I'm going to eat this guy!
You cannot eat our only suspect.
Watch me.
You want to know? I'll tell you
anything you want to know!
Aah! It's Edge.
Edge bought the butterfly!
He works for Kane!
-Kane? Where is he?
-At the compound.
Wait till I get my claws on him.
-Forget it. He's got hostages.
-What?
Yeah. A little boy who works
at the mystery meat stand...
and some dino singer!
Molly and Sebastian.
It's chow time!
Aah! You want Kane?
-Yeah.
-Talk to the Zapheads.
I got some payback
for the Zapheads.
But the compound's a fort.
You'll never get in!
Never, never, never, never--
-Ah, so what? Come on.
-OK.
Boss, I quit!
Oh, no! Let me go!
No! You're messing
with the wrong guy!
Let go!
What are you looking at?
Well, doc, when do I get
my seat on the ark?
Excuse me?
Tonight,
Kane takes down mankind.
I mean, that is what this whole
freak show is about, isn't it?
So, Kane kills
all the soft-skins...
and gets to play God, right?
Tell me, Mr. Summers.
What diseases
run in your family?
Very big feet.
-How delightful.
-What? Was it something I said?
Sweet dreams, Summers.
You weren't really gonna bite
that guy's head off, were you?
It crossed my mind.
-Gun command.
-On-line, on-line bioware.
Gun command.
-Man.
-What's the matter?
I can't get anybody on my comp.
I think that explosion
blew it out...
and that means
we're out here all alone.
Yeah. Listen. For what it's
worth, I've got you covered.
-Why, thank you, Teddy.
-Sure.
And look, we have company.
I'm going to get me
a Zappy meal.
What do you mean, you're
going to get a Zappy meal?
You're a vegetarian.
What are you talking about?
Hey, I binge once in a while.
Let's go.
At midnight,
the world turns into a pumpkin!
Or an ice cube!
-Coltrane and Teddy bear...
-And everybody else!
Hey, girls.
So, hey, guys, how y’all doing?
This broad keeps popping up!
Don't I, though?
Did you miss me?
I bet you did. I missed you.
We had such a good time.
You know, I was thinking
about it the other day.
We had such a good time
when I was shooting at you.
You were shooting at me--
trying to kill me, remember?
And I thought, "Where do I go
if I have a problem?"
Where did I come? To you.
I'm looking for Kane,
and I need your help.
Now, why would you do that?
I'm really crushed!
I mean, I came here because
I thought you could help.
I'm so emotional
I don't know what to do...
and my partner is just really
going to be put out by this.
Your partner?
You thought I was going to come
here by myself, didn't you?
-Yeah, I know you did!
-Yeah, she knows we did!
Silly man. Look.
Hey, I want you to read
this message into the holocam.
We'll send it
to your gun girlfriend.
She'll get a hologram.
Then she'll see the light, and
we'll live happily ever after.
I can't read your writing.
Well, then, sound it out!
Dangle my toes in the air
Look at me, Katie!
I'm a pterodactyl!
Hey, look, stop that.
Stop moving around!
I thought you said
you could fly this thing.
Excuse me.
I'm not used to flying...
three thousand pounds
of dino-flab every day.
Ooh!
I think I'm going to be sick.
If you let that go,
I swear to God...
I'm going to turn you
into a pocketbook.
Take us down! There's
Kane's compound right there.
Look at me! I'm flying!
Come on. Quit that.
Quit it!
You're making the copter move.
Great, great. Lower us down.
I think my--
here comes my lunch!
-Don't let it go--fly off!
-No, no, no, no!
Watch out for the trees!
Get the hell out!
-What are you, nuts?
-Oh, I'm going to shoot you!
Where are all the animals?
Where are all of Kane's animals?
Stop that! Stop that!
-Not that fast!
-Hey, hey! Not so fast!
-I'm a passenger down here!
-Stop that! Stop moving!
He's going to make
tyranno-sore-ass soup out of us!
Gee, I'm gonna make
an hors d'oeuvre out of you...
and quit flapping down there!
Oh, dear! Help me, Katie!
You've got to bail out!
-Somebody's got to bail out!
-You go!
We're going down!
Help me! Help me!
My God!
Please, your creatorship...
if you would give me
just one moment here.
I just want to say one thing.
None of this is my fault!
They made me bring them here!
He is the one!
Shoot him! Shoot him!
Oh, look, EIizar.
It's...
What was your name again?
Coltrane.
Where's Sebastian?
In a cage,
where all bad children belong.
Get rid of them.
Get rid of them!
Excuse me.
-Why, Teddy!
-Molly!
-Teddy!
-Molly! Oh, my head!
-What happened?
-Teddy, are you OK?
Teddy, you are safe now.
Wait a minute.
You killed Oliver and Adam,
didn't you?
The sacrifice was necessary,
unfortunately.
Well, at headquarters,
we call that murder.
Teddy!
I'm sorry. You're under arrest.
Look around. It's the future.
-Yeah? What?
-Life has changed, Teddy...
and in one minute,
I'll change the world.
What are you talking about?
What the...
You see, mankind is
a failed species, and look--
-New Eden will finish them off.
-Oh, no.
I will block out the sun...
and create a new ice age!
-Katie!
-Sebastian.
Over here, Katie! I'm here!
Come and get me!
Katie, watch behind you!
Move out of the way!
Katie, turn around!
Wait!
This time, I run evolution...
not God.
Here is my ark.
It contains the seeds
of the New Eden.
I brought here
breeding pairs of all plants...
insects, mammals...
amphibians, birds, bacteria...
et cetera, et cetera,
et cetera...
the ingredients for paradise.
That's my paradise.
It's...
My paradise! It's my breed!
Detonation, minus one hundred.
My destiny.
So you froze them here
just to save them.
Oh, no. It's a small price
to give them immortality.
Don't you agree?
We call it
survival of the fittest.
-We should go.
-Yeah.
Wait!
What have you done with Molly?
Oh, she's safe.
I'm pleased
that you care for each other.
Detonation, minus ninety.
A pair of rexes--
at last, my ark is complete.
Yes. Prepare him for sleep.
Of course.
Molly, my love.
Molly,
what have they done to you?
Detonation, minus eighty-five.
Hey, hold your horses.
Needles creep me out, you know.
Oh, one little prick,
and you'll wake up in paradise.
Oh, terrific.
So, tell me, why did you guys
kill Oliver and Adam, huh?
They threatened to expose
Mr. Kane's master plan.
Don't you realize?
Something wonderful has begun...
and you, Teddy,
are invited to join the party.
Yeah, well, do me a favor.
You seem like a nice, mean lady.
Please help me stop your boss!
EIizar has the remote control.
He's the only one
who can abort the plan, so...
I'd like to have
a little chat with Kane!
He's on his way up
to one of his sleep chambers.
Now, shh.
Teddy, close your eyes.
The best is yet to come.
Yeah, maybe you're right, doc.
I'll cooperate.
Teddy? Teddy!
Sorry, doc. Got other plans.
Teddy!
Detonation, minus eighty.
Katie!
Oh, Katie, am I glad to see you!
Oh, Katie!
You all right? Good.
Who's your friend?
I just met him over there.
Can I keep him?
-All right. Let's go.
-All right!
-Hey! Get out of here.
-Grenade! Grenade!
Get out of here!
Let's go.
Detonation, minus seventy.
-Access denied.
-What's the code? Come on.
-Come on!
Access denied. Access denied.
-Access denied.
-Please, come on!
I'm sorry, Molly. I'm sorry.
Ouch.
Molly, Molly.
-Teddy!
-Molly? Molly?
-Oh, Molly!
Oh, Teddy!
Oh! I thought
I'd never see you again.
Oh, I missed you so much.
-I was so worried about you.
-Stay right here.
-You're so cold.
-You're so warm.
And I'm so ill.
Detonation, minus sixty.
Katie! Come here, you!
You're squishing me right now.
Oh, my goodness!
And you're just
a little gregarious.
Yeah. I'm so happy.
What is this place?
Where are we?
This is Kane's ark,
a frozen zoo.
He's mad. He wants
to play God or something.
Katie!
-Katie!
-Katie! No!
Why?
Teddy, I told you,
we'll create a better world.
Come with me! I forgive you!
Teddy, come with me!
I can't!
Teddy, you are not a cop.
You can't be what you are not.
-Come with me.
-No!
You drop the gun!
You hear me?
It's a pity.
-Teddy?
-What? What?
Are you hit?
No, I'm--I'm just playing.
I'm not exactly hit.
I'm off-line, and I'm down,
so I think you're on your own.
All right, give me your gun.
I can't.
-What?
-I can't.
Katie, give me your gun.
This is no time to play around.
-Give me it.
-You might've been right.
It kills me to say this,
but you might've been right.
Use something
a little better than a gun.
No, Katie, look,
all this time...
you've been telling me
a good cop uses a gun, right?
So, what are you
telling me now?
I was wrong.
-Your brain.
-What?
Use your brain.
All right. Brains over bullets.
-Yeah.
-Let's do it.
Hey, partner?
Wait a minute.
You said the "P" word.
Yeah, I did. Good luck, OK?
Yeah. You, too, partner.
I'm going after Kane. Hang on.
-Scram then.
-Right.
I'll see you.
Detonation, minus fifty.
Come on!
Hey, come--come back here!
OK. Where are they?
Wait. Brains over bullets.
OK. Get the rope. Here.
Detonation, minus forty.
Yeah. Come here.
Come here!
OK. All right.
They went to the right. Yeah.
Detonation, minus thirty-five.
I'm going to get you guys.
Head them off at the pass.
Detonation, minus twenty.
Geronimo!
Teddy...
Teddy, the remote.
Detonation, minus fifteen.
-Teddy!
-Hand over the remote.
You're under arrest, Kane.
I'll stop your missile myself.
-Ten...
-Take that!
-Nine, eight...
-Don't do it!
-Seven, six...
-Don't do it! My breed! Teddy!
-Five, four...
-Oh, please!
Three, two, one.
We're here today
to honor Theodore Rex.
Teddy, we owe you an apology.
Soft-skin, scale--
you've shown us
that they’re only words...
words that keep us apart.
Our survival rests on all
species treating each other...
with compassion, kindness,
and respect.
-Teddy...
-Go on.
It is my honor to promote you
to detective first class.
Wow! Thank you, sir.
-Teddy, you were right.
-Yes, sir.
We can all realize our dreams.
Teddy, I'm so proud of you.
Thank you!
Hey, Molly.
You the man!
Congratulations, detective.
Hey, thanks, Katie.
I couldn't have done it
without you.
-Oh, yes, you could.
-You think?
Oh, yeah. I believe
you could do anything...
you put your mind to, Teddy.
Aw, please!
Anytime you need me,
you know how to find me.
You know,
it's funny you should say that.
As a gold badge,
I get to pick my new partner.
What?
So, what are you doing
the next twenty years?
Oh, you mean that soon?
Katie, I think
this is the beginning...
of a beautiful friendship.