Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Hey, what's up?
How you doing'?
Hey, could you pick me up,
please?
Like, now?
How was the movie?
I'm sorry, okay?
Yeah, get in.
Hey.
You know, when I was your age,
I barfed all over
Grandma's favorite shag carpet
in the guest bathroom.
I told her
it was bad shellfish.
But actually,
I downed half a bottle
of peppermint schnapps
behind Sweetie Pie's
with my friends.
So, come on.
No judgment. Just tell me
what happened tonight.
Zach and I broke up.
Oh, my God.
Sweetie, I'm so sorry.
No, don't... Don't...
Don't do any of that.
It's just...
He started talking about Japan
and how it's too far,
and that I shouldn't
do the program next year.
That's not cool.
What?
Like, Mom,
you just have no idea
what I'm going through, ever.
- Maybe he's right.
- Actually...
Maybe I shouldn't go. It's not
like I speak the language.
I don't know anyone else
who's going.
Why am I even going?
Listen, when I was
in high school...
No, Mom, this isn't
the Sweetie Pie's, okay?
Things are, like,
a lot more stressful now.
Yeah, you'd be surprised.
Why don't you sit down,
and I'll tell you a story.
Because I'm gonna go to bed.
I'm tired.
Aw. Well, you're probably
just gonna
stare at your phone all night.
So, then why can't you
just text me?
Sit your butt down!
It was the early '80s...
No, please, not the '80s.
Yes, the '80s
in the San Fernando Valley.
And me and my friends...
Were valley girls.
I know, you've told me
a thousand times.
You guys were all like,
"Oh, my God.
Like, where's my brain?"
Yup. And we actually used
words like "tripendicular,"
and we wore teal eyeliner
and popped collars.
And we hung out
at the mall every night.
Wow. Deep.
Okay, so we weren't exactly
solving world hunger.
But at the time,
it seemed perfect.
♪ Life was
Like a pop song ♪
♪ And we knew all the words ♪
♪ See the people
Walking down the street ♪
♪ Fall in line
Just watching all their feet ♪
- ♪ They don't know ♪
- ♪ Where they wanna go ♪
♪ But they're walking in time ♪
♪ They got the beat ♪
♪ They got the beat
They got the beat ♪
♪ Yeah
♪ All the kids
Are getting out of school ♪
♪ They can't wait to hang out
And be cool ♪
♪ Hang around
Till quarter after twelve ♪
♪ That's when
They fall in line ♪
♪ They got the beat
They got the beat ♪
♪ Kids got the beat ♪
♪ Yeah
Kids got the beat ♪
♪ Go-go music
Really makes us dance ♪
♪ Do the pony
Puts us in a trance ♪
♪ Do the Watusi
Just give us a chance ♪
♪ That's when we fall in line ♪
♪ 'Cause we got the beat
They got the beat ♪
♪ Kids got the beat ♪
♪ Yeah
Kids got the beat ♪
♪ We got the beat ♪
♪ We know you
can dance To the beat ♪
♪ We got the beat
Jump back ♪
♪ Get down ♪
♪ Round and round and round ♪
♪ We got the beat ♪
♪ We got the beat
We got the beat ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We got the beat
We got the beat ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We got the beat ♪
♪ Yeah
We got it ♪
Nope. Stop.
You were singing
and dancing on a fountain.
That's how I remember it.
That's what it felt like.
God, that's so cringy.
We lived in a total bubble.
We never left the valley.
We barely left the mall.
We were warned
to never go over the hill
where all the weirdos lived.
Punks and runaways.
It was just
a few zip codes over,
but seemed like
a million miles away.
♪ I don't give a damn
'Bout my reputation ♪
♪ You're living in the past
It's a new generation ♪
♪ A girl can do
What she wants to do ♪
♪ And that's what
I'm gonna do ♪
♪ And I don't give a
damn About my bad reputation ♪
- ♪ Oh, no ♪
- ♪ No, no, no, no, no, no ♪
♪ Me, me, me, me, me, me ♪
♪ I don't give a damn
About my reputation ♪
♪ Never said I wanted
To improve my station ♪
♪ And I'm only doin' good
When I'm havin' fun ♪
♪ And I don't wanna please
No one ♪
♪ And I'm never gonna care
About my bad reputation ♪
- ♪ Oh, no ♪
- ♪ No, no, no, no, no, no ♪
- ♪ Not me ♪
- ♪ Me, me, me, me, me, me ♪
- ♪ Oh, no ♪
- ♪ No, no, no, no, no, no ♪
Damn it!
Stupid thing ate our demo.
See? It, too, is sick of
playing our five shitty songs.
Pigs!
♪ Oh, I don't give a damn
About my bad reputation ♪
♪ Oh, no, not me ♪
And he was, "Totally."
And then he was all like,
"Uh, call me, babe."
And I was like, "Rob!"
- Oh, my God!
- I'm so sure.
Oh, my God.
But you said
you wanted to call him.
Duh. Like, she totally does,
but she can't act like
she does.
See, that's why Julie has the
most bitchin' dude in school.
- Yeah.
- Whatever.
Ugh. I'm gonna barf.
Where should we go now?
- Esprit or Limited?
- Limited.
Esprit.
I... Esprit.
Well, I've got a radical idea.
Let's blow. I mean,
we could go anywhere.
Like another mall?
No. Like,
get on the first bus we see.
We could, like,
go over the hill
to Hollywood or something.
Or we could just, like,
see where it takes us.
You're freaking me out!
Oh, my God.
Like, freak me out.
It sounds, like,
way dangerous.
- Hollywood is so groady!
- Let's go.
Thank God.
Julie, like,
here comes your man.
- Damn, he's so fresh.
- Stop.
Hey, hot stuff.
Catch you at the pep rally?
Yeah. It's, like, mandatory.
Hey, Mickey.
♪ Oh, Mickey, you're so fine ♪
♪ You're so fine
You blow my mind ♪
♪ Hey, Mickey ♪
♪ Hey, Mickey
Hey, Mickey ♪
Whoo!
Yeah!
Mickey Bowen!
Check out that bod.
All right.
It's fine. It's fine.
It's fine.
Hey, everybody.
And to think that some members
of the faculty
suggested
that we shouldn't have
a pep rally for one person.
Boo!
And need I remind you?
Senior prom is just
one month away!
And, uh, I have
some great news for you.
Let's get a drumroll, please.
Our high school
has been selected
to have our prom
broadcast live
on the greatest radio station
in LA, KROQ!
Oh, my God!
And,
everybody, remember,
no more spiking the punch.
Okay? Last year, I got a DUI.
Mickey, I'm not...
Mickey, I'm not supposed
to come in here.
Okay.
Mickey,
we could get in trouble.
We're gonna get
in trouble together.
- We can't...
- Hey, it's just us. Okay?
Now!
What do you say, Jules?
Me, you? That?
Just say yes. Just say yes.
- Okay.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
- Yeah!
Excellent!
♪ Janet
Jackson Janet Jackson ♪
♪ Just like Janet
Just like Janet ♪
Hmm.
I, like,
totally have to practice
if we're gonna be live
on KROQ.
KROQ is a radio station,
Loryn.
I need UVs, like, now.
- Tell me.
- What happened?
I just got asked to prom
by five assholes.
I just can't decide who I want
to take me, Mike or Danny.
Danny has the bod,
but his brains are bad news.
I mean, he's going
to Cal State Northridge.
Like, we're going
to Northridge?
Yeah, but we're not gonna
actually date the guys
who go there.
But, I mean,
you don't have to worry.
You're set for life
with Mickey.
Oh, my God, you guys
are so getting married.
- Totally.
- I'm so sure.
I mean, people are
waiting now, you know?
Some girls don't even
get married
until they're, like,
23 and stuff.
If I'm not married by 23,
I'll kill myself.
But I'm not even sure
what I wanna do with my life.
Yeah, that's why
you get married.
So you don't
have to do anything.
Yeah, like,
once the divorce is final,
my mom has to,
like, get a job.
Well, what does
she like to do?
Be married.
Don't bring up
your mom's divorce, Stacey,
it makes me really sad.
Sorry.
Does anyone want a Diet Coke?
- Okay.
- One for me.
- No ice, Stacey.
- Okay.
But what if you got
a bitchin' job?
You know,
like designing clothes?
Or, Loryn, dancing?
Why would you want to?
To have a life.
To, like, be independent.
Ew! Bummer!
But it's the 1980s, guys.
Girls can do anything.
♪ Oh, girls just
Wanna have fun ♪
♪ I come home
In the morning light ♪
♪ My mother says ♪
♪ "When you gonna
Live your life right?" ♪
♪ Oh, Mother, dear,
We're not the fortunate ones ♪
♪ But girls
They wanna have fun ♪
♪ Oh, girls just
Wanna have fun ♪
Sorry!
♪ The phone rings
In the middle of the night ♪
♪ My father yells, "What you
Gonna do with your life?" ♪
♪ Oh, Daddy, dear, you know
You're still number one ♪
♪ But girls
They want to have fun ♪
♪ Oh, girls just want to have ♪
♪ That's all they really want ♪
♪ Some fun ♪
♪ When the working day
Is done ♪
♪ Oh, no
Girls, they wanna have fun ♪
♪ Oh, girls just
Wanna have fun ♪
♪ Girls, they wanna ♪
♪ Girls
Girls just wanna have fun ♪
♪ They just
wanna They just wanna ♪
♪ They just wanna
They just wanna ♪
- ♪ Girls ♪
- ♪ Wanna ♪
- ♪ Fun, fun ♪
♪ They just wanna
They just wanna ♪
Girls just wanna have ♪
♪ They just wanna
They just wanna ♪
♪ Girls just wanna
Girls just wanna have fun ♪
♪ Some boys
Take a beautiful girl ♪
♪ And hide her away
From the rest of the world ♪
♪ I want to be the one
To walk in the sun ♪
So, I totally stole
my mom's Joy of Sex book!
Did you see
those illustrations?
It was so gross.
Yeah, I'd like to hear more
about this book.
Wasn't on
my summer reading list.
Like, I could totally give you
a full report tonight
at my friend's party.
1807 Sierra Vista Heights.
No. Get out. Like, go.
No. Ugh.
Sorry about my buddy there.
He can be a real dick.
Yeah. He's, like, way rude.
He does this all the time.
Hi. We were all just leaving.
Like, now.
Yeah, um... I mean...
Hey, wait! What's your name?
Hook me up with those 'chos
and I'll tell you where the
Val chicks are going tonight.
Dude, a bird was just
all over those.
Wicked.
Wait, back up.
You just left?
Well, I had a boyfriend.
Who was a total tool.
And he had all those tattoos.
I mean, he was actually
considered pretty,
you know, edgy back then.
You have instant chemistry
with this crazy hot guy
and you just bailed?
Well, if you'll
let me finish...
Because you were
afraid of his tattoos?
Ugh. You know, I'm so tired.
Maybe you should just go
text all your friends.
No.
I mean, you can keep going.
If you talk more about him
and not about,
like, leg warmers.
Okay. No leg warmers.
I promise.
Now, take it forward, take it,
one, two, three...
- Mom?
- Huh?
Have you ever, like, thought
something was totally right
that it should, like,
fit just perfectly
but then
it just totally doesn't?
Ooh, well...
I guess,
that kind of depends
on what you're trying
to fit where, you know.
I mean, sometimes,
things aren't meant to...
- be put in certain...
- Oh, my, God!
Experimenting is fun.
- Ew! Mom!
- It's exciting.
- Hello, ladies.
- Oh, my God!
Look at what I got.
What is that?
Look at this new technology.
- Look at how sleek it is.
- Whoa!
There's a whole VCR in here.
Look how small that is.
It's burning hot to the touch
but I think that's normal.
We could make
our own workout video.
Honey, we can make
all kinds of videos.
- Ooh!
- No, stop, guys.
Oh, Julie Richman.
American teenage girl...
- Stop, Dad.
- ...of the Valley variety.
But what is she
working on right now?
Is it another world-famous
fashion project?
Um, my outfit
for Mickey's costume party.
For what party?
No. I mean, are his
parents gonna be there?
- No Risky Business.
- Yes.
His parents will be there.
They even got it catered.
Well, that sounds classy.
Kamikazes!
It's very important
to stay hydrated.
I know this because I'm a mom.
Yeah. I'm a mother.
Do you think Dolly
Parton stuffs her bra, too?
Totally.
Oh, my God.
Do you remember the Halloween
that we made those
Houdini costumes?
Yeah, with the handcuffs.
You guys are so lucky
I rescued you
in middle school.
- Especially you, Stacey.
- Oh.
Hey, yo! Adrian!
Ah, it's Rob!
Oh, what happened
to your hands?
No pain, no gain!
Unbelievable.
You are, like, so lucky.
Seriously,
that was a perfect cannonball.
Oh.
Oh, you're soaking.
Hell, yeah.
You're smokin' too, babe.
What are you, anyway?
Oh, wait. Uh, Chip!
Chip!
Dukes of Hazzard!
Yo, Mickey!
Check this out!
Oh, hell, yeah!
Chair launch!
Drop, drop, drop...
Three,
two,
one!
♪ Friday night
And everyone's moving ♪
♪ I can feel the heat but
It's soothing, heading down ♪
♪ I search for the beat
In this dirty town ♪
♪ Downtown the young ones
Are going ♪
Are growing ♪
♪ We're the kids in America ♪
♪ Everybody live
For the music-go-round ♪
♪ Bright lights
The music gets faster ♪
♪ Look, boy,
Don't check on your watch ♪
♪ Not another glance ♪
♪ I'm not leaving now, honey,
Not a chance ♪
♪ Hot-shot
Give me no problems ♪
♪ Much later, baby
You'll be saying never mind ♪
♪ You know life is cruel
Life is never kind ♪
- ♪ Kind hearts ♪
- ♪ Don't make a new story ♪
- ♪ Don't grab any glory ♪
♪ We're the kids
in America Whoa-oh ♪
♪ We're the kids in America
Whoa-oh ♪
♪ Everybody live
For the music-go-round ♪
Hey, guys,
they're giving out
free polos back there!
Dweebs!
Whoo!
♪ We're the kids
Hey ♪
♪ We're the kids in America ♪
♪ We're the kids
Hey ♪
♪ We're the kids in America ♪
() Whoa!
Radical costumes.
But who are you?
We're young.
We're still figuring that out.
Good evening, my liege.
- Hey, Casper.
- Hey.
Oh, are you
Elliott from E.T.?
I am.
I love that movie!
I know. I mean, uh...
Is it attached to your butt?
No. It's more of,
I'd say, the groin area.
Oh.
I mean, not...
It wasn't...
I'm Princess Diana!
- You look great.
- Thanks.
You know, I really like her.
I know she's not
a blood princess.
I know that it's by marriage,
but I still...
Hey!
- Are you a fish?
- Uh...
'Cause, son,
you're going for a swim!
That was amazing.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm... I'm fine.
Uh, I... Do you wanna come in?
I can't.
I borrowed my nana's wig.
Jules, you won't believe
what just happened!
Danny was all bragging
about his new Porsche.
And I was, like,
ribbin' him hard
sayin' he wouldn't take
that thing over 90
and he was, like,
"I'm so sure."
So, I'm, like,
"Okay, prove it, dude."
So, we take this thing
out to the street.
He gets it to, like, 50,
wimps out.
So, he starts doing donuts
and then he throws up.
And then I was, like,
"There's no way you're getting
that puke
out of the glove box."
- You're not even listening.
- What?
- Are you listening to me?
- Yeah.
Uh... You puked
in his glove box?
Who's that douchebag?
I don't know.
Okay, well,
I think you really need
to see this for yourself.
Man, these
high school guys blow.
Oh, my God, totally.
Pretty good with that pump.
Maybe you can show me
what else you're good at.
Oh, gee. You're not
really my type, cro-mag.
I'm every girl's type, babe.
Let's just say you don't
have the right equipment.
Shut up, dude.
Dyke alert!
What?
Say that again.
Say that again!
- Frankie says relax.
- Hey, hey, hey!
Back up!
- Do you want this?
- Hey, hey!
Yo, get these guys
out of here, man.
I just got clocked
by Daisy Duke.
Damn!
Jock douchebag.
- Who cares?
- She's a val, man.
Come on.
I stole
all the remotes.
Looks like you lost the
War on Drugs, Mr. President.
Dude!
Yo, dude.
Nice recovery, Manny.
I thought you were
down-and-out
after you hurled
in the Jacuzzi.
Okay. This is your party, too.
You belong and your
camp friends were wrong.
Oh.
Just... Okay.
You looking
for someone out there?
Are you crazy?
Yeah.
Uh, we met at the beach.
I'm Randy.
I'm Julie.
Hey, open up!
So, do you, like,
live around here?
Not exactly.
Come on, man.
Hurry up in there.
Wanna get outta here?
I'm so sure.
- Kill. Let's motor.
- Wait. As if!
Like, I just met you.
And this is Mickey's party.
The Mickey?
- This is Mickey's party?
- Shh.
Well, I mean,
where would you wanna go?
Anywhere.
What would you wanna do?
Anything.
Oh, God. I don't know.
Mickey, all of my friends,
like, everybody would probably
have a total cow if I left.
Forget them.
What do you wanna do?
You are crazy.
♪ You might think I'm crazy ♪
♪ To hang around with you ♪
Where are you going?
♪ Maybe you think I'm lucky ♪
- ♪ To have something to do ♪
- Shh.
♪ But I think
That you're wild ♪
♪ Inside me is some child ♪
♪ You might think I'm foolish ♪
♪ Maybe it's untrue ♪
♪ You might think I'm crazy ♪
♪ But all I want is you ♪
Come on.
You can't leave
your boyfriend's party.
I mean, Karen will...
These are the kids they warn
us about in life skills class!
Come on.
Jules...
♪ You might think
It's hysterical ♪
♪ But I know when you're weak ♪
♪ You think
You're in the movies ♪
♪ And everything's so deep ♪
- Hey!
- ♪ But I think that you're wild ♪
♪ When you flash
That fragile smile ♪
♪ You might think I'm foolish ♪
♪ What you put me through ♪
♪ You might think I'm crazy
But all I want is you ♪
Absolutely not!
♪ And it's hard
So hard to take ♪
♪ There's no escape
Without a scrape ♪
♪ You kept it going
Till the sun fell down ♪
♪ You kept it going! ♪
Hey, Speedy, you got my money?
- Come on. Come on.
- I'm so not getting out here.
Okay, but when they attack
the car, save the radio.
Jules!
Whoa!
♪ You might think I'm delirious
The way I run you down ♪
♪ But somewhere sometimes
When you're curious ♪
♪ I'll be back around ♪
♪ You might think it's foolish
This chancy rendezvous ♪
♪ You might think I'm crazy ♪
♪ All I want is you ♪
You guys are cutting it close.
Well, we ended up
in a bad part of town.
♪ To bring me back
I'm a million miles away ♪
♪ A million miles away ♪
Sorry.
Wait, shouldn't somebody
stop that fight?
It's called dancing!
Hardly.
Like, what's the point?
Pointlessness!
Amazing, right?
I don't know.
It's kinda weird.
It's just authentic.
But I guess you don't
get that in the valley.
I like the valley.
You think you like the valley,
but it's empty.
You dress alike,
you talk the same.
Oh, my God! You guys
totally dress the same!
Maybe you need
to get out of Hollywood.
So, when can I see you again?
Aren't you supposed to, like,
wait until
the end of the night
- to ask me that?
- Why?
Julie! What about Mickey?
Like, I think you're having a
mental breakdown or something.
Oh, my God.
Just a little bit longer,
please?
Look around us.
People have holes
where they're not supposed to.
Please?
I got stabbed
with that kid's hair.
Obviously, you, like,
wanna be here, but I don't.
I'm calling a cab!
Are you gonna be
able to get home okay?
I got a 1420 on my SAT, Jules!
I think I can get myself
back to Encino!
Hello, you Hollywood urchins!
Safety Recall!
We are Safety Recall!
I got a special guest here
this evening.
And I just want to
try something new.
You guys on board?
♪ I see you
Through the smoky air ♪
Sellout!
♪ Can't you feel
The weight of my stare ♪
Boo!
♪ You're so close
But still a world away ♪
♪ What I'm dying to say is ♪
♪ I'm crazy for you ♪
♪ Touch me once
And you'll know it's true ♪
♪ I never wanted
Anyone like this ♪
♪ It's all brand new ♪
♪ You'll feel it in my kiss ♪
♪ I'm crazy for you ♪
♪ Crazy for you ♪
♪ Trying hard
To control my heart ♪
♪ I walk over to
Where you are ♪
♪ Eye to eye we meet
No words at all ♪
♪ Slowly now we begin to move ♪
♪ Every breath
I'm deeper into you ♪
♪ Soon we two
Are standing still in time ♪
♪ If you read my mind
You'll see I'm crazy for you ♪
♪ Touch me once
And you'll know it's true ♪
♪ I never wanted
Anyone like this ♪
♪ It's all brand new ♪
♪ You'll feel it in my kiss
I'm crazy for you ♪
♪ I'm crazy, I'm crazy
I'm crazy, I'm crazy for you ♪
So, you go to school.
What else?
You know, like, hang out.
Yeah.
But what are you into?
Um, I don't know.
Like, my friends and shopping
and, like...
I can't believe
that this is happening.
This is, like...
It's wild.
I really have to go.
People just leave
their stuff out?
Yeah. It's, like, the valley.
Nobody steals things.
That's what you think.
I'm shoving that bike
in my trunk.
- Jules?
- Uh, yeah?
You up?
Yeah, I am now.
Mickey's on his way.
I'll go fix you some Tang.
Thanks.
Mickey!
So, are you going to win us
another championship?
Oh, yes, ma'am.
We're gonna cream Tarzana.
You don't have
to call me ma'am.
I'm barely old enough
to be a cool babysitter
that you used
to have a thing for.
Hey, there's my girl!
You go get 'em,
you little McEnroe.
I'm gonna win it for you, all right?
Okay. Let's hit it.
Mickey.
We need to talk.
Come on, babe,
it's the championship.
Mickey, I can't
do this anymore.
Look, we all had
too much fun last night.
I got mega drunk, you left
without saying goodbye.
Yeah?
It's all good. We both
feel terrible.
No, no. I just think we, like,
don't want the same things.
Oh! Mmm.
Is this about...
prom night?
Hey. It's normal
to be nervous, okay?
But I promise,
it's gonna be special.
Mickey...
Now, come on, let's roll.
Mickey, that's not what
I was talking about.
Mickey, I need to talk to you.
You wanna talk to me
in the car? Let's go.
What's going on with you?
I'm trying to figure it out.
But I don't wanna, like,
be your cheering squad.
You're not even a cheerleader.
We're over.
Big mistake, Julie.
Big mistake!
And way to get me outta
my zone for the match!
Not cool at all!
Big mistake!
You do know
if you cared about our band
half as much as you
care about that ramen,
we'd be, like,
really rich right now.
Oh, I'm sorry.
You don't want some?
No, I want the ramen.
We're still gonna practice,
though, later, right?
The office
of Randall J. Phillips.
Well, hello.
This is Julie Richman
returning his call.
I'd like to schedule
an appointment, like, ASAP.
Well, I'm just looking
at his schedule right now
and it would appear
he's free forever.
- No!
- Yes.
And she just, like,
dumped Mickey?
Yes.
But don't worry.
Stacey's on it.
Oh, my God, Jules.
Are you okay?
- Hey, welcome!
- I am amazing, guys.
I think I'm really
into that guy.
Randy. He's, like,
totally tripendicular.
- Knees up.
- We don't date guys like that.
Does he even, like,
know how to play tennis?
No, but, guys,
it's just like...
Here we go.
...the way he makes me feel,
it's like...
To the right!
♪ When I'm with you, baby ♪
♪ I go out of my head ♪
♪ I just can't get enough ♪
♪ All the things you do to me
And everything you said ♪
♪ I just can't get enough ♪
♪ Some boys kiss me
Some boys hug me ♪
♪ I think they're okay ♪
♪ If they don't give me
Proper credit ♪
♪ I just walk away ♪
♪♪ They can beg
And they can plead ♪
♪ But they can't
See the light ♪
♪ That's right ♪
♪ 'Cause the boy
with the cold hard cash ♪
♪ Is always Mister Right ♪
- ♪ I can't go for that, no, no ♪
- ♪ No can do ♪
♪ I can't go for that, no, no ♪
- Wow.
- ♪ No can do ♪
♪ I can't go for that, no, no ♪
♪ No can do ♪
♪ Take my tears
And that's not nearly all ♪
♪ Oh, tainted love ♪
- ♪ I can't go for that ♪
- ♪ No can do ♪
♪ Tainted love ♪
- ♪ I can't go for that ♪
- ♪ No can do ♪
♪ It's getting hotter ♪
♪ It's a burning love ♪
♪ And I just can't seem
To get enough of ♪
♪ Oh, tainted love ♪
♪ No can do ♪
♪ Tainted love ♪
♪ 'Cause everybody's living
In a material world ♪
♪ It's getting hotter
It's a burning love ♪
♪ You know that we are living
In a material world ♪
♪ And I am a material girl ♪
Guys, can we just, like,
talk about this later?
Come on,
let's go to Sweetie Pie's.
Totally.
Where's Stace?
Oh, my God!
Like, what's he doing here?
We got him to give you
another chance, Jules.
Come on. He's our ride.
Are you guys joking?
It's okay. Some people
totally freak out senior year.
Just like in that book,
Go Ask Alice.
Oh, my God.
I'm not freaking out.
You so are.
I mean,
this is just like my, um...
The divorce.
Come on.
No!
Fine. Be a skank.
Is she coming?
Screw her.
To the max.
- Come on.
- It's over.
Looks good, dweeb.
Julie thinks she's, like,
way too cool for us now.
- No.
- You think?
What, she likes this guy
because he's different?
Different from who?
Hey, can we not
talk about Julie?
Yeah, you're right.
Let's just have fun tonight.
What?
Mickey and Karen hooked up?
I know. Crazy, right?
I mean, I get that you didn't,
like, want him anymore,
- but still.
- Right? Thank you.
Okay, first of all,
she's the skank.
Well, I'm ambivalent
about that word.
But, yes.
Okay, well, were you
freaking out about it?
Well, at the time,
I was a little preoccupied.
Ooh, la, la.
French restaurant? Fancy.
At least we know
he has good taste.
Mom, what do you even know
about France?
Nothing, I guess.
I just always wanted to go.
Okay. Bye.
So, you're just going to dinner
and a movie with this boy?
- Yes.
- Okay.
And, um,
you'll be home by midnight?
Yes, Mom.
Sorry. It's important
to your father.
Okay.
- Love you.
- I love you, too.
Bye.
Just say no.
- To what?
- Everything.
They have these
secret shows every month.
- X even played once.
- X?
- Yeah, the band.
Oh, sorry, did you not know
anything at all about music?
Not punk music.
- So, why don't you tell me?
- Oh.
Okay, well, for starters,
punk is dead.
Well, I'm sure the dead band
is gonna be totally bitchin',
but I have curfew.
But you're gonna miss
your one-week anniversary.
I mean, that's a big record
for this guy.
- Hey, shut up.
- Ow!
Well, we can celebrate
another time,
but I have to get home.
My parents are, like,
gonna kill me.
Okay, I'll take you home.
I'm not gonna make you leave.
That's crazy.
I'm not putting you on a bus
on Hollywood Boulevard.
A bus?
Not. I'll totally cab it.
Like, why stop there?
Why not a stretch limo?
We'll hang tomorrow?
Oh, yeah,
that's what I like.
Randy.
Yeah, I like it.
Oh, Randy.
Honey?
How was the date?
Fine.
Sweetheart, come in
here and tell us about it.
Okay.
- So?
- Hey, ya.
- Hi.
- So what did you guys see?
Return of the Jedi.
Ooh.
Is Darth Vader Luke's father?
Tell me. Tell me.
No, don't tell me.
Don't tell me. Okay, tell me.
- Yeah, he's...
- No, don't tell me!
- Okay, tell me.
- Yeah, he's the dad.
Wait.
Who's whose dad?
Well, the Jedi.
Are you lying to us?
I can tell you're lying
'cause your mouth is open.
Close your mouth.
We try to be so chill
and you're lying to us?
Our... Our plans changed
and I didn't have a dime,
and it's not like I have some
kind of satellite phone device
I can keep in my pocket and
just transmit to outer space
and call you guys
whenever I want to.
You're grounded, young lady.
Thank you for turning me
into a typical mother.
I'd like you
to go wash your face
and go to bed.
Wash it.
Is that how you ground
a child? I don't even know.
I think you did it the best
you could have done it.
What are you doing here?
I figured we could be
grounded together.
Shh.
I'm sorry.
Oh. Nice top hat.
I may have gone through
a brief magician stage
in fifth grade.
Yeah, that's the day
that Karen got her car.
Nice.
Oh, yeah, that's just, like,
a thing that Stacey and I do.
I've been making clothes
since I was, like, seven.
So, what's this guy's story?
- Well, this is Shaun.
- Shaun?
I named him
after Shaun Cassidy,
who was, like,
my first true love.
Here, I'll show you.
See, I was, like,
kind of obsessed.
- Oh, wow. Hot.
- Shut up!
Wow.
It's like...
It's like art.
The way
you put clothes together.
I just think it's, like,
why be boring?
You know?
Yeah.
My guidance counselor
told me there's this college,
Fashion Institute
of Technology.
Yeah, where is it?
- New York City.
- Ooh!
Yeah.
- But I mean, I don't know.
- Well, let's do it. Let's go.
I mean, some day.
But, like, I have to finish
senior year and...
Oh, my God,
did I tell you that,
like, KROQ is
throwing our prom?
No, no, no.
I know what you're thinking.
But it's gonna be awesome.
- Is it?
- No. It is. I promise.
Especially if I have
the right date.
What, you mean, like,
Shaun Cassidy over here?
I hear he's got a lock
on prom king.
♪ Talking away ♪
♪ I don't know
What I'm to say ♪
♪ I'll say it anyway ♪
♪ Today's another day
To find you ♪
♪ Shying away ♪
♪ I'll be coming
For your love, okay? ♪
♪ Take on me ♪
♪ Take me on ♪
♪ I'll be gone ♪
♪ In a day or two ♪
♪ So needless to say ♪
♪ I'm odds and ends ♪
♪ But I'll be stumbling away ♪
♪ Slowly learning
That life is okay ♪
- ♪ Life is okay ♪
- ♪ Say after me ♪
♪ It's no better
To be safe than sorry ♪
♪ Take on me ♪
♪ Take me on ♪
♪ I'll be gone ♪
♪ In a day or two ♪
♪ Things that you say
Yeah ♪
♪ Is it life or just to play
my worries away? ♪
♪ You're all the things
I've got to remember ♪
♪♪ You're shying away ♪
- ♪ I'll be coming for you anyway ♪
- ♪ I'll be coming ♪
♪ Take on me ♪
♪ Take me on ♪
♪ I'll be gone ♪
♪ In a day or two ♪
♪ Take on me ♪
So,
are you sick of me yet?
No.
But you know
what would be rad?
If you, like, hung out in
the valley a little bit more?
Do you really want me to?
No, come on, my friends,
they're not, like, contagious.
- I did some research.
- Research?
About New York.
The scene there is exploding.
The East Village.
We could rent a railroad flat
on Avenue A.
We'd be so broke,
we'd have to eat
Chef Boyardee 24/7.
And you'd be
in fashion school.
Mmm-hmm.
I'd write you songs and play
them for you on stage at CBGB.
8I don't know. I mean, I...
No, I'm supposed to, like,
go to Northridge in the fall
and, you know,
my parents would, like...
I mean, what do yours think?
Look, I don't have that.
It's just me and you.
That's all I want.
♪ I'll stop the world ♪
♪ And melt with you ♪
♪ You've seen the changes ♪
♪ It's getting better
All the time ♪
♪ There's nothing
You and I won't do ♪
♪ I'll stop the world
And melt with you ♪
Hey, you okay?
Did I tell you guys that
Randy's writing me a song?
Oh, he's in a band?
I didn't know that.
Let me guess, a punk band.
Technically speaking,
punk is dead.
You know, uh, honey...
I was thinking that, uh...
I, uh...
I'm not so sure
that he's the guy for you.
You know?
You know, Dad,
you don't even know him.
Well, I think that
he's too old for ya.
And I think he drives too fast
and I think he does
too many drugs.
Which is any amount of drugs,
in my book.
And also, I...
He's never once come
to the front door
to pick you up. He's never
knocked on the door,
and introduced himself...
Yeah, who doesn't
introduce themselves?
- Like Mickey used to do?
- Yes.
- Sure, like Mickey.
- Yes. Like Mickey.
By the way,
Barry said that Mickey
is torn up without you.
Torn up.
Well, that doesn't
surprise me at all.
Wait, you talked to his dad?
Honey, it was
an investment thing, okay?
Oh, my God.
By the way, we're not
investing in, uh, Macintosh.
We're gonna go with Commodore.
You're the boss.
Point is, honey,
Mickey, he's got a future.
Mickey is the kind of person
who will take care of you.
He's reliable.
He's going places.
- He'll take care of your kids.
- And he can take care of you.
Oh, my God. What are
you guys even talking about?
I mean, honey,
you know, next year, you're
gonna be at Northridge
and you're gonna have to make
a lot of big decisions.
And your mom and I
wanna help prepare you.
I might not even go
to Northridge.
There's some
really rad fashion stuff
happening in New York.
New York City?
Yeah, and Randy said that...
Honey, you're not moving
across the country
with a guy we've never met.
Dad. It's not...
Especially not
to New York City, okay?
No.
That's the crime capital
of the world.
Okay, the crime statistics...
So, basically,
it's a giant...
- Oh, it's a murder capital.
- ...jail!
You walk down the
street and it's just stabbings.
- Stabbing!
- Whoa, whoa, guys.
Okay. What if I just
invite him over? For dinner?
That way, you guys could
get to know him.
Could we start there?
What?
I mean, I know I haven't
seen you in a while,
but pretty sure
the guy I remember
didn't dress
like Kenny Loggins
and go hang out with
a bunch of old yuppies.
Gimme a break.
Like you haven't done
some warped stuff for chicks.
Remember Mad Dog Marie?
Oh, yes, who went off
to Marie-hab.
Yeah, I mean, this is, sort of,
the first phase of our plan.
She wants her folks to know
the guy who's taking
their girl away.
She's not moving in here.
- That's not happening.
- No, no, no.
NYC, man.
What do you mean, "NYC, man"?
Going to New York now?
So, that's just it, then?
No more band.
I mean... Okay.
Cool. Well, thanks
for letting me know.
You and Sticky should come.
Look, I've got some new songs.
And a new scene
gives us freedom...
Why are you doing this?
We have people here
who like our music,
and they actually, like,
come to our shows.
That's everything
that we've been working for.
You really wanna spend
the rest of your life
playing the same five songs
to the same 50 people
- in the same club?
- Man!
This girl is Nancy.
You're Sid and she's Nancy!
And not in a good way.
What, you think
that's gonna work?
Those rich assholes,
they're gonna hate you, man.
They already hate you.
She digs me and her parents
are gonna dig me, too.
News flash. Parents don't
dig you, all right?
Not even your own.
Damn it, I'm late!
And don't grill him
about his parents.
He doesn't like
to talk about them.
- Honey.
- Or is grades or whatever.
He's totally smart.
Sweetheart, I am gonna keep
an open mind.
There's so many cul-de-sacs
in the neighborhood.
It's easy to
drive around in circles.
Hello? Julie?
Julie.
I'm wondering if we need
to buy Randy a Timex.
Ha-ha.
Okay, I'm gonna start.
- Dad, no.
- No, I am.
It's rude. Your mother made
a lot of food.
And I don't like someone
treating you like this.
We've been waiting
for a long time.
I bet you guys are thrilled
he's not here.
- Don't say that, dear.
- We're not thrilled, okay?
But we are validated.
The truth is,
it is better
to just find out now
what kind of a person he is.
You can find someone
who can take care of you.
Not everybody is as needy
and scared of the world
as you are.
Jesus, guys can suck.
- Yeah.
- You must've been so pissed.
Yeah, pissed.
Embarrassed.
Mostly just sad.
So, I mean, was that it?
It was just over?
Well, I didn't know.
I called
and there was no answer.
I thought maybe it was.
But then...
I'm sorry.
Well, then why didn't
you show up?
Parents are hard for me, okay?
That's your big excuse?
You know what,
trigonometry is hard for me,
but I still show up.
What do you want me
to say, Julie?
You want my whole
pathetic life story?
How my dad bailed on me
before I was even born?
How my mom kicked me
outta the house
because she wanted
to start a real family?
Look, you have this life.
This shiny, bright, perfect...
I... I saw it. I...
I don't know how
to fit into this.
You could start by showing up.
I will.
Cool.
I need to work
on my dance moves
if I'm ever gonna be on MTV.
You're so good at dancing.
Who has time for that?
Like,
I totally was watching
the "Thriller" video today...
Happy birthday.
Is it...
Oh, my God.
Oh, I love it.
Oh, thank you.
Hey, I'm kind of having a
birthday party this Saturday.
Oh. I didn't know.
I mean, it was, like,
totally last minute.
But you're totally invited
as long as you're okay
with, you know...
Oh, my God, stop.
You're, like, totally
putting me in the middle
- just like my mom does.
- Spaz down, Stacey.
God.
Mickey will be there with me.
Yeah. I heard about you two.
Oh, yeah, what'd you hear?
Was it something like,
"Oh! Mickey!
Oh, my God, Mickey!"
We used to say that exes
were off-limits.
Yeah, well, we used to say
a lot of stuff.
What do you care now?
You have Randy.
God, this is so stupid.
I think you guys
would actually
just really like him
if you got to know him.
Well, why don't you bring him
to my birthday party?
Okay.
Whoo! Keep on wheelin'!
Hey, that's for you.
Oh, my God, thank you so much.
It's a book.
Oh, my God, Karen.
I have tiny cars on my feet.
This is really good practice.
- For what?
- Prom.
Oh, my God, you guys came!
Oh, happy birthday.
- Thanks for coming.
- Yeah, totally.
Hey, Randy.
Right on. Happy birthday.
Oh, it's a scratch-off
lottery ticket
that's already
been scratched off.
You take that
to any gas station,
they'll give you
three bucks. Cash.
Oh! Thank you.
I'm here
with the birthday girl,
and it is time
for "The Safety Dance".
You know the dance.
Time to grab your partner
and show me what you got!
But if you hear the whistle,
baby, you out!
Stacey. Hey, hey!
Stacey.
Oh! Are you okay?
Yeah, I take karate sometimes.
We're not liable for this.
♪ We can dance, we can dance
We're doing it From wall to wall ♪
Everybody look At your hands ♪
I think I'll take a timeout.
What? You sure?
Really, it's okay.
♪ Safe to dance ♪
Whoop! And this is why
we always wear underwear
at the roller rink, people.
Ugh. The things we do
for girls!
Ooh, you're out, bitch.
Go get a chili dog.
Come on.
- Okay.
- Okay?
Yeah!
Whoo!
- What?
We're down
to our final three couples.
Ooh! Show me your best moves.
Ha-ha! This is not where I saw
my life going.
♪ S-A-F-E-T-Y ♪
And we have our winners!
Whoo!
- That was amazing, right?
- Yep.
Uh-oh!
If you lost a tooth,
it's over
at the lost and found.
That was awesome.
- With so many spins.
- Yeah, for sure, Karen.
What're you doing here, freak?
I don't want any beef, dude.
Where's the beef, huh?
I'm cool.
Just making sure
you're okay, buddy.
I mean, your girl was
kind of all over me.
You look angry. You need
to cool off a little bit?
Yeah, she's really something,
isn't she?
Oh, my God.
- Oh, my God!
- Fight! Fight!
Guys, stop!
Stop!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Get him off me!
Yeah, he's crazy, man.
Get off of me! Get off of me!
You think I wanna be here with
these trust fund jerk-offs?
I'm happy to get the hell out!
- Get off me!
- You're done.
Come on, Julie, let's go!
Wow. Classy.
Stacey, I am so sorry.
I think that you should
probably just go.
- But, Stacey...
- Just go, please.
Thank God.
I think
he's actually psychotic.
What was that?
What is wrong with you?
You realize that everything
my friends
ever thought about you
you just proved them right?
Why do you even care
what they think?
Because they're my friends.
What, these vapid, stupid,
rich, shitty people?
I am one of
those people, Randy.
You know what, all we ever do
is hang out with your friends,
listen to your band,
do your stuff,
but the moment I even try
to show you my world,
you, like,
totally sabotage it.
I'm sorry, okay?
Wait, come here. Come on.
I'm sorry.
All those amazing things that
we said we were gonna do,
let's just go and do that.
None of this stuff matters!
You see, that's the problem,
it's that nothing
matters to you.
But I have things in my life
that I care about,
that are important to me.
Don't tell me you're gonna
bring up prom again.
Seriously, Julie?
It's like we're
from different planets.
If you want a prom king,
maybe I'm not your guy.
You know what,
maybe you're not.
You don't mean that.
Does this look like
it's working to you?
I have given up
everything for you.
- You don't even show up.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
Your fake friends
aren't gonna call you back?
You know what,
I'm sorry that I have people
in my life that care
about me. Okay?
Right.
It's not working.
You know what?
Forget it.
For sure.
Like, totally!
Those tots
look awfully lonely.
I know how they feel.
You think, uh,
one of them might like to be
my date to prom?
What about Karen?
Mmm.
No, I broke up with Karen.
It's never been about her.
Only us.
So, what do you say?
Yeah. Okay.
Let's do prom.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah. Prom could be fun.
It will be fun.
But it doesn't mean
we're back together.
Okay?
All right, sweet. Yes, ma'am.
But seriously, are you
gonna finish those tots?
♪ I would say I'm sorry ♪
♪ If I thought that
It would change your mind ♪
♪ But I know that this time ♪
♪ I have said too much
Been too unkind ♪
♪ I try to laugh about it ♪
♪ Cover it all up with lies ♪
♪ Hiding the tears in my eyes ♪
♪ Because ♪
♪ Boys don't cry ♪
♪ I would break down
At your feet ♪
♪ And beg forgiveness
Plead with you ♪
♪ But I know
That it's too late ♪
♪ Now there's nothing
I can do ♪
♪ So I try to laugh about it ♪
♪ Cover it all up with lies ♪
♪ I try to laugh about it
Hiding the tears in my eyes ♪
♪ 'Cause boys don't cry ♪
♪ Boys don't cry ♪
♪ I would tell you
That I loved you ♪
♪ If I thought that
You would stay ♪
♪ But I know that it's no use ♪
♪ 'Cause you've already
Gone away ♪
♪ Misjudged your limit ♪
♪ Pushed you too far ♪
♪ I took you for granted ♪
♪ Thought that you
Needed me more ♪
♪ Now I would do
Most anything ♪
♪ To get you
Back by my side ♪
♪ But I just keep on laughing
Hiding the tears in my eyes ♪
♪ 'Cause boys don't cry ♪
♪ Boys don't cry ♪
So, I...
I saw that song
that you wrote for her.
It's good.
You'll get her back.
No. I'm pretty sure
she's done.
Damn.
Maybe we should
go to New York anyway.
You know? I mean,
a change could be good.
Check out a new scene?
Plus, we're getting evicted,
so...
What do you think?
You know what, let's do it.
Yeah?
Let's get the hell outta town.
Yeah!
Stace?
Will you hear me out?
Like, I don't really
have a choice.
Look, I am so, so sorry about
your birthday party, okay?
And, I'm...
And I'm not with him anymore.
And, I know, it's not...
Are you okay?
I've been, like,
the worst friend recently...
No, I said stuff, too.
But it's just...
I mean, everything
at home is so...
I just want everything
to stay the same.
Yeah, totally.
- I'm sorry.
Um...
I kinda got into Dartmouth.
Wait, what?
- You got into Dartmouth?
- Uh-huh.
Stace, that's amazing!
I know.
But you all are going
to Northridge,
and Karen will, like,
freak out at me...
No, no, no. Screw Karen!
You have to go.
That's Ivy League!
Oh, my God!
I'm going
to an Ivy League school.
You got in! You're a genius!
You're going to Dartmouth!
Oh, my God!
I really have to pee, though.
Oh. Okay. Sorry.
Mom's letting me
get a waterbed.
Whoo! Yep.
Oh, my God.
Wow. Four years
of silent treatment.
Northridge is gonna be
a blast.
Karen? She lied.
Didn't even get
into Northridge. Idiot.
But I got in?
Maybe that's why
she went nuclear on us.
Hey. Don't forget
that pink dress, right?
The one that goes
with my cummerbund.
Well, I was actually thinking
it might be super rad
if I did something...
Don't you wanna match, babe?
Right. Julie.
Yeah.
Not babe.
I want a hotdog.
Let's go.
You look bitchin'.
Thanks.
Uh, I remember my prom.
It's a lot of pressure, right?
Totally.
Oh, my God!
I know!
Oh, wait.
This is gonna make it,
like, mega.
Oh, my God. Totally!
Ah.
So, like, what happened
with Karen?
Ugh. She called you
a backstabber
for hanging out with him.
And I was like,
"Wait, you totally did
the same thing
but, like, way worse."
And she freaked out,
totally stopped the car right
in the middle of Ventura
and told me to get out.
Yeah, and then she told me not
to get out, but I did anyway.
Julie! Come quick,
I want you to see this.
Put our fight on hold
for a second.
Look, look.
T-minus ten, nine...
You know what that is?
That's the first
female astronaut.
That's Sally Ride.
Go for main engine start
and we have ignition.
There she goes.
And now, lift-off
for America's
first woman astronaut.
The launchpad is clear
and STS-7 is free...
There she goes.
Pretty cool.
Yeah.
You know, I bet...
I bet her parents
had some scary times.
You know,
a daughter like that?
Always wanting to blaze
her own trail, you know?
But, damn,
I bet they're proud today.
You know, Sally Ride,
she's from Encino.
She's a valley girl.
♪ Pressure ♪
♪ Pushing down on me
Pressing down on you ♪
♪ No man ask for ♪
♪ Under pressure
That burns a building down ♪
♪ Splits a family in two ♪
♪ Puts people on streets ♪
♪ That's the terror of knowing
What this world is about ♪
♪ Watching some
Good friends screaming ♪
♪ "Let me out!" ♪
♪ Pray tomorrow
Gets me higher ♪
♪ Pressure on people
People on streets ♪
♪ Okay ♪
♪ Chipping around, kick my
Brains 'round the floor ♪
♪ These are the days
It never rains but it pours ♪
Yeah!
♪ It's the terror of knowing
What this world is about ♪
♪ Watching some
Good friends screaming ♪
♪ "Let me out" ♪
♪ Pray tomorrow
Gets me higher ♪
♪ Pressure on people
People on streets ♪
♪ Turned away from it all
Like a blind man ♪
♪ Sat on a fence ♪
♪ But it don't work ♪
♪ Keep coming up with love
But it's so slashed and torn ♪
♪ Why, why, why? ♪
♪ Why? ♪
♪ Love, love, love,
love, Love, love, love ♪
♪ Insanity laughs
Under pressure we're breaking ♪
♪ Can't we give ourselves
One more chance? ♪
♪ Why can't we give love
That one more chance? ♪
♪ Why can't we give love ♪
♪ Give love, give love
Give love ♪
Give love, give love ♪
♪ 'Cause love's such
An old-fashioned word ♪
♪ And love dares you to ♪
♪ Care for the people ♪
♪ On the edge of the night
And ♪
♪ Love dares you
To change our way of ♪
♪ Caring about ourselves ♪
♪ This is our last dance ♪
♪ This is ourselves ♪
♪ Under pressure ♪
♪ Pressure ♪
Honey?
- Oh, this is great!
- Hello, prom night!
Sweetheart?
And now, we wait
for the young female human...
- Now I can't see anything.
- ...to emerge from her lair.
Honey? Sweetheart?
Fully groomed for the prom.
Stunning.
All right. Can we get
a picture of you two?
Mickey,
give her that corsage.
- What happened to the dress?
- You said pink.
- Just a few more photos.
- Just a couple more shots.
- Mom, we really have to go.
- I'm coming in close.
We're gonna be late.
We have to go.
Guys,
this is important.
- Please be careful.
- We won't be back too late.
Julie?
Au revoir.
Bye, Mom.
Coming to you live
from the most bitchin',
awesomest prom in America,
it's Rodney on the ROQ,
KROQ, and...
Raechel Donahue.
Happy to be here
on my day off.
Oh.
Yeah!
Come on, Valley High,
show us how rad you are.
I wonder if there's a KROQ
prom king and queen
out there somewhere. Huh?
There for sure is,
there for sure is.
Because we gotta
pick somebody.
Congrats on the big news,
Stacey.
Oh, hey, thanks, Mr. G.
Just don't forget
about us here in LA.
I won't.
- End of an era, huh?
- Hmm?
Oh, yeah.
It's, like, so sad.
Are you kidding?
High school
hates people like me.
I'm sure you don't understand.
You're so cool and confident,
and always
at the best parties.
I hated those parties.
I'm going
to Dartmouth
for computer science.
I'll be at MIT.
It's only a swift a 111 miles
as the crow flies.
Do you want some punch?
You have some.
♪ Oh, oh, dancing with myself ♪
♪ If I had the chance
I'd ask the world to dance ♪
Come on, kids, too close.
♪ Dancing with myself ♪
♪ Dance, dance, dance, dance ♪
♪ Dancing
Dancing with myself ♪
This is the longest
I've ever been in a gym.
Rad.
Wow, wasn't that amazing?
And now, the moment that
you've all been waiting for.
Time to announce the KROQ
most bitchenest,
awesome prom king and queen.
You!
And the winning couple is...
This is totally fun, right?
Totally.
Do you think we can, like,
go together again?
Mickey Bowen
and Julie Richman!
Number one!
Awesome.
You're so awesome, Mickey!
Yeah!
Hey, do you guys have anything
you wanna say
to young America?
Congratulations, Sally Ride.
Women!
Balls to the wall!
Yeah, Mickey!
Hmm.
So, are we
back together again?
Because I got us
a room at the Sheraton.
No.
Like, no, we're not back
together or no Sheraton?
Do you really wanna
do this right now?
Damn it, Julie, are you, like,
wasting my prom night?
Not anymore.
Ladies, I'm single!
Yeah!
Not exactly how we thought
prom would go, huh?
Our last hurrah.
Yeah.
I heard about Northridge.
What are you gonna do?
No clue.
Maybe that's good
for a change.
Yeah.
♪ Moving forward
Using all my breath ♪
♪ Making love to you
Was never second best ♪
♪ I saw the world
Crashing all around your face ♪
♪ Never really knowing
It was always ♪
♪ Mesh and lace ♪
♪ I'll stop the world
And melt with you ♪
♪ Let's stop the world ♪
♪ You've seen the difference ♪
♪ And it's getting better
All the time ♪
♪ There's nothing
You and I won't do ♪
Who are these guys?
♪ Let's stop the world ♪
♪ I'll stop the world... ♪
♪ I'll stop the world ♪
♪ And melt with you ♪
♪ You've seen the difference ♪
♪ And it's getting better ♪
♪ All the time ♪
♪ There's nothing
You and I won't do ♪
♪ I'll stop the
world And melt with you ♪
I couldn't miss prom.
♪ Dream of better lives ♪
♪ The kind which never hates ♪
♪ Trapped in the state... ♪
These high school dudes blow.
Totally.
♪ I'll stop the world
And melt with you ♪
Hey. You should call this gal.
She does choreography
for music videos.
Oh, my God!
♪ Let's stop the world ♪
♪ I'll stop the world
And melt with you ♪
♪ I'll stop the
world And melt with you ♪
♪ Let's stop the world ♪
♪ I'll stop the
world And melt with you ♪
So, wait, this song that
they play on KROQ
all the time,
- is about you?
- Mmm-hmm.
It was also in a terrible
fast food commercial.
Oh, my God. You were,
like, actually cool once.
Mmm. I'm gonna take that
as a compliment.
But then you left him for Dad?
Not exactly.
We moved to New York
and they got a record deal
right when I was
finishing fashion school.
And I did the looks
for their first tour.
Tell me you went on that tour.
Yes.
Wait, so,
what happened with Randy?
Well, life happened.
First loves don't always last,
but they change everything.
You could have been
with a rock star.
You could have had,
like, a sick life.
I do have a really sick life.
I have you,
and my company.
I actually get to design
clothes for a living.
And I love your dad
more than anything.
And Randy,
being with him
and seeing the world,
that made me who I am.
What are you gonna do
about Zach?
I don't know.
Guess I'm just gonna have to
figure it out,
on my way to Japan.
You know, blaze my own trail.
Like, totally.
Where do you want to go?
Everywhere.
What do you want to do?
Everything.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org