Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
There are all sorts of ways
to hit a cue ball.
The thing you're trying to do
is send it
in a particular direction,
to hit another ball and drop
that ball into a pocket,
but it's where you send
the cue ball next
that separates you
from the others.
When you first start playing,
you think it's only
about that one ball.
You can put backspins,
sidespin or topspin on a ball,
or you can make it stop
on a dime, bounce off a rail.
You can hit a ball soft, hard,
or just give it a little kiss.
You can send a ball
behind another ball
to make it hard for
your opponent to make a shot.
Once you have the skills,
you can do any of these things.
Some dads take their kids
to church or to the ball game.
That's what some dads do.
My dad?
He took me to pool halls,
and he taught me how to play
a game called 9-ball.
- Are you ready?
- Yeah.
Mm!
Alright, fellas.
I tell you what.
We'll put my watch
against your $50.
It's worth three...
five times more than that.
Wait, hold on.
What are you doing?
What do you say?
Me and my sentimental,
watch-loving son
against you two fellows,
and I tell you what
because we... we are...
No, Dad. Dad, come on.
That's your grandpa's watch.
- Zip it. Zip it.
- It costs...
Sorry.
Why don't you run and get me
a pack of cigarettes?
That shirt really brings
out your eyes.
Here is to your grandpa.
Nice watch.
Nine-ball, succession pool...
where you got to
knock them down in order.
This is truly a sport.
It takes skill,
and, more importantly...
it takes foresight.
Ah, come on!
I love $50.
Nine-ball... sport of kings.
What do you say, fellas?
Double or nothing?
- Yeah, not this time.
- I don't think so.
Well, thank you so much
for your patronage.
Could have at least
saved me a shot.
Well, I tell you what,
next game, you shoot first.
Now, how about you get us
a couple drinks?
My treat.
Hey, kiddo, I didn't realize
how late it was.
Your mom is gonna have my hide.
Let's skedaddle.
Come on, let's just stay
a little bit longer?
I'll let you drive.
Awesome.
Chip?
Yeah.
Ah, damn it, go!
Go, Dallas!
Aah!
Jesus, easy, boy!
Dallas, I ain't
telling you again.
Get up.
You're not staying home
from school,
so you get that out
of your head right now.
Hey, I need your help cleaning
out the shed after dinner.
- Can't.
- Is that so?
Dad has got a game
with some guys from Kentwood.
- Forget it.
- He wants me there.
Dad, tell her what
the deal is tonight.
You're not going,
and that's the end of it.
We'll see.
Yeah, we will see,
won't we?
Did you even hear that?
Hey!
That's trouble, you know.
You never help me
discipline him.
He is barely squeaking
by in school!
He's fine.
By your standards, maybe.
Did it ever occur to you
to be his parent
instead of his playmate?
Just one cup of coffee.
He's doing fine.
What do you mean by that?
Well, what I mean is
he's doing fine, Gina.
I thought you'd had enough
of this shit when you was a kid.
Damn it, Gina, don't.
I know the road you're going
down. Don't do it.
Shit!
I'm gonna be late again.
We need to talk.
I mean it.
I'm not worried, Gina.
I can't just leave work
like that
every time you cause
a problem at school.
I'm gonna lose my job
over your little stunts!
Oh, God.
Mom?
Mom, let me see.
- Dallas.
- Mom, let me see!
Dallas!
Honey...
You know how your daddy can get!
Your daddy around?
No.
- He say when he'll be back?
- No.
Well, why don't
that surprise me?
Well, tell him Earl stopped by.
He'll know why.
I always thought I was gonna
have a big life...
nice house,
two cars, three kids.
Just like on the TV.
- This is it.
- Let's face it.
He hasn't been good
to you in forever.
Only part of my dream
that come true is Dallas.
You know how you know
when it's over, Sandy?
They stop kissing you.
Better no man
than a worthless one.
Who you calling worthless,
Sandy?
Dallas.
I see the way
you flirt with him.
Oh, please.
And you... you...
you wonder why he takes off!
You're bad-mouthing him
all the time.
That is not fair!
It's true.
You drove him away!
Go to your room.
Go!
I don't want to hear
another word out of you, go!
Get!
Well, look at what
the cat drug in.
She's a beaut.
Yeah.
You seen Cal around, Jackie?
Earlier.
You two aren't together?
Can I get a drink?
So if you're not
with your dad,
how'd you get here anyway?
Yo, Dallas!
You're up.
Coming.
Be right back.
Good because I'm not done
with you yet.
Wait, you're Dallas?
Last time I checked, and, uh,
you must be Wayne.
No, kid.
No, this isn't Toys "R" Us.
We're playing for money here.
Nine-ball, it's the bottom
of the break.
Call your last shot.
Let's rack them.
Oh.
Believe you just lost all that
paper-route money, kid.
Oh!
I... I do believe this is
what they call "ball in hand."
so, uh, let's see.
If I were a cue ball,
where would I want to be?
I don't know, Wayne.
What do you think?
Because, you know, I got a lot
of different options here.
You know, I could take a shot
on that side pocket right there.
Maybe I could spice some things
up and try and do a bank.
Ooh!
I'm not gonna feel so bad
about whooping your narrow hide.
Well, uh, you want
to make it $40,
so you can take me
a real good lesson?
Done.
Oh, my, the heat is on.
Ahh.
Excuse me.
Nine-ball,
one rail, corner back here.
Never happen.
- Oh!
Never is a long time.
Afraid not.
You didn't call a pocket.
Yes, I did.
I... I pointed to the...
He didn't call it,
did he, Seth?
Anybody else hear him call it?
Seems like we all
on the same page.
You're a dick.
You know what I said.
Bar ain't no place
for a kid, nohow.
The boy called it right.
This old man talking to me?
Uh, no disrespect,
but I did hear him.
I don't see how this is
any of your concern.
Well, you asked everyone,
and I believe I qualify.
Consider yourself
disqualified.
Is that right?
This boy beat you
fair and square.
Hey, boy, that's enough.
Jackie's right.
- Ooh!
Come on, get back.
Mnh-mnh.
Take your money, son.
Oh, damn it.
What was that?
Why don't you just mind
your own business?
Yeah, okay.
Uh, listen, why don't you just
tell me you live
within a reasonable distance,
and I'll take you home
to your mama?
I don't have a mama.
I... I mean...
I mean, she died.
So who... who do you stay
with then, boy?
My dad, but, uh, you know,
he... he had to go somewhere.
You know, he left me
with a buddy of his.
You know, he didn't realize
what a drunk the guy was.
You know, he... he beat the crap
out of me earlier.
Can't go back there,
or he'll kill me.
Uh, is there anywhere
I can take you,
or anyone
I can drop you off with?
Or wh-what about a neighbor
or a...
My dad is at a pool hall
called Fatty's in Baton Rouge.
You know, if you could just,
you know, drop me off there,
everything would be cool.
You know, my dad is actually
a professional pool player.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah, big time.
So wh-what's happening?
Is he on a circuit or something?
- Yeah, sort of.
- Hmm.
Well, what you do mean
"sort of" or something?
I don't know.
He just, you know, plays around.
Yeah.
Yeah, so basically he just plays
in bars for money, right?
Well, n-not just bars,
you know, tournaments, too.
He's actually making a real
big name for himself.
Yeah, I mean, you know,
people actually compare him
to Willie Mosconi.
Ah, is that right now?
Heh, Willie Mosconi?
You'll see when you meet him.
This is your last warning.
Get up.
Dallas?
What time is it?
About 7:30.
Come here.
Lie down here.
Go lie down.
You know, uh, you should
show me some moves.
- I-I don't think so.
- Why not?
I'm-a let you answer
that question.
How far away from Baton Rouge?
It's down the road that way.
Okay. Later.
- Hey, wait, hold on!
- That's okay.
Wouldn't want to end up
on Amber Alert.
You still might, smart-ass.
Okay, fine.
Suit yourself.
- I will!
- Have a nice walk.
I can't tell you how sorry
I am about your father.
Well, thank you for taking
care of everything, Merle.
You bet, Joe.
He'd have done
the same thing for me.
Mm.
Now, what are my chances
on talking you
into joining the 21st century
and buying a cellphone?
No, I'm...
I could have called you
a week ago.
Well, I'm just not gonna put a
microwave up against my ears.
It's not gonna happen.
I'd settle for
a mailing address.
Mm.
Well, as executor
of your father's estate,
and I use that term loosely,
I need your signature
on a couple of things
to finalize his will.
His years in assisted living
pretty much took care
of any assets he had left,
but there were a few items
he wanted you to have.
That's 9 grand the IRS
didn't know about.
Well, he never did cease
to amaze me
how he could
turn a nickel into $5.
Gave me his Winchester rifle.
Said it wouldn't fit in the box.
I'll give you a minute.
There is something else, Joe.
The nursing home
forwarded his mail to me.
Didn't know what you wanted me
to do with this.
It's from Christopher.
It's addressed to your father,
but I think it's meant for you.
So, uh, you're not, like,
on vacation or anything?
You actually live in here?
That's right.
Who are they?
Uh, sit back and mind
your own business
before you make me
have an accident.
Oh, I'm just messing.
I got you.
Well, where are they?
Well, what have we here?
We stopping?
Yeah, I got to make a living.
Hurry up.
It's hot in here.
Well, it was a lot hotter
on that road, wasn't it?
Could have
walked there faster.
- What seems to be the problem?
- How you doing?
Are you with, uh,
roadside assistance?
Uh, no. No, I'm not.
I just kind of do freelance.
I might be able to get you
on the road a lot sooner.
Okay, good, good.
Well, how much do you,
uh, you cost?
Well, I can guarantee you
I charge a lot less than...
Um, we were, like,
a couple miles down,
and it started, uh...
Alright.
Cut the act, slick.
I know you're not sleeping.
I was trying to.
Is everything in there?
Yeah, you know, of...
of course.
I didn't take nothing, you know.
Just dropped my pencil.
Oh, yeah, where's your pencil?
You know what would
make more money?
Yeah, I saw you work
your marks
in the pool hall, remember?
He was trying to get over
on me first.
Oh, and that's all
that matters, right?
- Cal teaches me plenty.
- Yeah, it shows.
Come on.
You're not staying in here.
Hey.
Here.
Stop scribbling
on all my crap.
Why we stopping?
Now, you just stay put.
I don't want you going anywhere.
If the air works.
Why wouldn't it?
Now, don't touch anything.
If you do, I'm gonna break
one of your skinny fingers.
Joe.
What in the name of God
are you doing here?
You've, uh, you've kept the
place looking real nice, Maggie.
- Law says you can't be here.
- I know.
I know, I...
I, uh, you know,
I don't want any trouble.
I just, um, I just wanted
to tell Christopher
that his granddaddy passed away.
I'm sorry about that.
I'll let him know.
And would you give this
to him, please?
Chris isn't here.
- Yes, I know he's moved on!
- Yes.
Who's there, Maggie?
Nobody.
I'll be right in.
Mm.
You just stay away from him.
It's the least you could do.
Why'd the woman snub you
like that?
I mean, personally, I...
I think it's kind of whacked.
Why can't you give
your kid a gift?
You know the nice thing
about a personal life?
- It's personal.
- Hey, man, I'm on your side.
There are no sides.
Hmm, didn't like your
breakfast, honey?
Well, uh, he's having
some lady problems.
Lost his appetite.
Everything was fine.
Just the check, please.
Hey, uh, you know,
I think I figured out
the problem with your kid.
Yeah, well,
I don't remember asking.
Just show up to the wedding
and give him
the money in person.
I mean, she can't stop
you then, right?
It's more complicated
than that.
Then, stop complicating it.
What day is it?
Sunday?
Well, you know
I saw the invitation.
We're still going to Fatty's,
right?
Hell, if he ain't
pissing people off,
he's ripping them off.
You know them chains and watches
he sells ain't real?
You know, I'm glad you won't
let him play in here.
He's more trouble
than he's worth.
- This place is skanky anyway.
- Okay, enough.
Well, the apple don't fall too
far from the tree, does it?
I can't imagine why
your daddy ain't home.
- Fuck you, fat man.
- Okay.
You know, it might be
in your best interest
to keep your mouth shut
once in a while.
You know, Cal's talented,
and that makes people jealous.
Yeah, he may be talented,
but the truth of the matter
is that your dad...
What would you know
about my dad?
You live in a camper with a dog.
And what does that make me?
Someone whose own family
don't want him around.
You're Cal McCarthy's kid,
right?
Yeah, yeah.
You were at the house, right?
Uh-huh.
- Where is he?
- I don't know.
Come look for him with us?
Dallas, we should probably
be going.
Hold on, cowboy.
The three of us are talking.
I don't want to go anywhere
with you.
Hey, hear that?
The boy don't want to go.
Maybe you would like to stay and
hang out with us for a spell.
Do you know, your daddy and me,
we go way back.
Yeah, well, that's all well
and good, but, uh,
the boy is in my charge,
so if you don't mind.
Oh, we mind.
Might be best if you hop back
in your time machine
and made yourself scarce.
That's just not
gonna happen.
That's not a request.
You know what?
I... I changed my mind.
- I'm... I'm gonna go.
- No, kid.
You want my advice?
Save yourself
a little bit of pain
and suffering and walk away.
Alright, old man.
Dallas, you get
in the RV right now.
Come on.
Aah! God.
It's a good thing
you aren't gonna live
long enough to reproduce.
Oh, what?
A cat's got your tongue now?
Okay, that was stupid.
No, that was 85 miles
past stupid.
Yeah, I'm sorry. Okay?
Can you just get off my back?
I got a better idea.
I'm gonna get you
off my back.
Stay, girl!
- Where we going?
- We're not going anywhere.
You're going home.
You're gonna call someone
to come get you.
- I already told you.
- I don't care.
- Call anyone.
- What?
I'm not your fricking problem,
okay?
Just leave me alone.
You don't understand.
I know where he's headed.
Look, listen, there's a poster
back at Fatty's, okay?
There's a big pool tournament
this weekend in New Orleans,
and he's gonna be there.
That couldn't matter
less to me.
Either you start dialing
or I'm gonna call a cop.
This is your choice.
You know what? Fine.
Go ahead.
Then I'll never see him again.
I fricking lied, okay?
He's not coming back for me.
You coming?!
I screwed up
on the hands a bit.
Well, that's not half bad.
I think you ought to do
something with that.
- With what?
- That.
You mean like a job
or something?
Yeah, like a job or something.
Who's gonna pay me
to do this?
A lot of people.
Kind of just figured
I would play pool.
Yeah, well, I'm sure Cal
will be proud of you
no matter what you do.
Alright.
Come on, Story, go get it.
Bring it here.
You're the first person she's
let throw a ball besides me.
Really?
Yeah, she must have guessed
you had a good arm.
My dad taught me.
He was a pitcher in high school.
Is that right?
You know, um,
I actually played for a bit.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
You know, my mom worked a lot
and my dad couldn't always
get me to practice,
so had to quit.
Had to quit.
Well, we couldn't get enough
of baseball in our house.
Yeah, we... we ate it.
We drank it.
We slept with it.
Whenever there was a game on,
we'd go out on the porch
and listen to the play-by-play
on the radio,
ask each other about players'
stats, you know, and all.
We could not stump my youngest.
What's his name?
You got any favorite memories?
I mean, I don't know.
I got lots of them.
Any one of them
stick out in your mind?
Well, this one time when I was
about 7 or something,
I remember my dad bought
this really bitching
Triumph motorcycle,
and we took a ride
out to the country,
to one of his buddies' houses.
You know, a whole bunch of guys
hanging out.
They didn't mind me.
They even let me play
a few hands of cards with them.
I remember when it came time
to leave,
my dad sat me in front of him
and wrapped me up
in his big old leather jacket.
I still remember
what it smelled like.
Pretty stupid, huh?
No, no. That's...
that's not stupid at all.
You know, my dad's not
a bad person.
Yeah, well,
I'm not here to judge.
Ugh.
Do you know you have
a taillight out?
Uh, yes, I do.
I do apologize.
License, registration,
proof of insurance.
Okay, Houdini,
you can come out now.
This might be the time
for you to come clean.
Not really.
Well, let me rephrase
that then.
This is the time that you are
gonna come clean.
Okay, fine, I'll tell you
when she leaves.
No, you're gonna
tell me now
or you're gonna be
leaving with her.
Okay, okay.
Fine, fine.
This cop might be
looking for me.
For any particular reason?
Because my mom has probably
got half of Louisiana
out hunting for me by now.
Hmm, and that would be
your dead mom?
You wouldn't have helped me
find him
if I told you the truth.
She know where you are
and what you are doing?
No.
So you gonna turn me in?
I don't know yet.
The day's not over.
I know there's one thing
you're gonna do for me.
- Hello?
- Mom?
Dallas.
What are you doing, baby?
Are you okay?
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
I'm with a friend.
What friend?
Doesn't matter.
He's taking me to Dad.
No, no.
Tell me where you are.
- I'll come get you.
- Not yet.
- Mom, I'm gonna bring him back.
- What?
- I'm gonna bring Dad home.
Dally, honey,
this ain't got nothing
to do with you, okay?
I'll be home in a day or two.
A day...
Don't do this to me.
Dallas, please, don't.
- Dallas.
- I... I got to go.
Dallas.
You feel better now?
It's overrated.
What are these for?
You earned those.
You did right by your mama.
Besides, you don't want to smell
like old cheese
when you meet with your father.
Oh, Ricky.
Did you hear that?
I think that is the sound of you
going to the poor house.
I bet you're gonna go there
before I do.
Oh, shit.
That's alright.
I'm gonna be over here
with my little private
cheering section while you clear
the table for me.
Hey, Dad.
Miss me?
Dallas, what are you
doing here?
Came to find you.
Uh, is your mama here?
No, and good thing she ain't.
She the reason you left?
No, hell, no.
I'm not an idiot.
No, no, some fellow is
bothering her, so, you know,
I was just pretending
to be her boyfriend is all.
Don't bust my balls.
That's all it was?
'Course that's all it was.
Then why did you leave?
Well, Dallas, you know, it...
Hey, how did you
get here anyway?
My friend Joe Haley
gave me a ride.
That so?
Joe Haley.
Hey, Dallas, why don't you,
uh, why don't you go get us
a couple of drinks?
Okay.
Want anything?
Nope, no, thanks.
I suppose you know what's
going through my head right now,
so why don't you tell me
how a grown man knows
my 14-year-old boy?
He was on the side
of the road.
His bike had broke down,
and I just offered him a ride.
He said he was looking
for his dad.
Well, you found me.
Where you from?
Uh, mostly here.
Yourself?
Here and there, I guess.
Mm. You guess, yeah.
What do you mean by that?
Uh, nothing.
No, really, not...
nothing at all.
You know, Joe, uh,
there ain't no road map
to being a daddy, you know?
We just do the best we can.
Yeah, you got that right.
Thank you, boy.
Well, it was nice
talking to you.
- Yeah.
- Um, I-I'm gonna go.
Come on, Joe. Come on.
You don't want to hang
for a little?
No.
Hey, Joe.
I just...
I wanted to say thank you.
Uh, you bet.
I'll put your backpack and
your bike in your daddy's truck.
Okay.
Oh, hey, and Joe,
don't worry about the wedding.
Your buddy is leaving, huh?
Yeah.
I'm sorry about that.
How about we do what we do
and get down
to some serious matters, okay?
We've got some fish to fry.
Alright, folks.
I've got 50 bucks says this boy
can beat anybody in this room.
$20, $40, $60, $80, $81.
Easy money, huh?
That sure as hell beats 9-5,
barely alive.
Why do you do it?
Why do I do it?
It's in my blood, just like
it was in your grandpa Gus'
and just like it's in yours.
You're making me
lose count here.
Alright.
Why you so moody?
Look, you just made
some money.
Can we just go home now?
Dallas, tournament
is tomorrow.
I didn't come all this way
not to play.
Fine, after the tournament.
We'll talk about it later.
No, why can't we
talk about it now?
Stop riding me, boy.
Okay.
Why don't you take this,
go get us a couple of sodas?
I'm gonna take a shower.
Afterwards, we'll go
grab a burger.
Does that sound alright?
Dallas.
You okay?
It's okay.
It's alright.
I know these guys.
Cal, why did you make us
chase you
halfway across the state?
It's $1,000.
$1,000. Take it.
You're five short,
son of a bitch.
No!
Please don't hurt him.
Don't do it.
Dad.
What are you doing?
No, wait, please.
How am I supposed to pay
you back if I can't play?
No, wait, please.
I... I... I know where
we can get the money.
Dad, just promise me
you'll come home?
Okay.
There's a dog.
Just get the box.
I'll distract it.
Go.
Hey.
Shh.
- Get out of here!
- Oh!
Ah!
Get the money.
Hey, kiddo.
Are you okay?
I just want to go home.
Yeah.
I'm sorry about your friend.
You know, to be honest with you,
I sometimes forget
you're just 14.
I know you want to go home,
and I don't want you to worry,
so first thing in the morning,
we're gonna put you on a bus.
Okay?
But you said you were
coming with me.
I'm not, Dallas.
You promised.
I know.
I know I did.
Listen...
I am not good...
As a matter of fact, I am
horrible at playing pretend,
and I've been doing it too long,
and it's not fair to your mama,
and it's certainly
not fair to you.
The fact of the matter is I...
I can't do it anymore.
But...
Just hear me out, please.
See, me, I am who I am.
And I'm gonna have to live
with that forever,
but that does not mean that I
have to put you through it, too.
I mean, look at us, Dallas.
I'm supposed to be your daddy,
and you're the one
that's taking care of me.
Look, the best thing I can do
for everyone
is to not go back.
But mom needs you.
No.
No, your mama doesn't need me.
The only one mama needs is you.
You lie.
- You lie about everything.
- Yeah.
Yeah, I know.
The thing is, though, I'm not
lying about this,
and some day you're going
to realize very soon
that I was really never there.
- Get out of here, kid.
- Joe, I...
- You're a little prick.
- I...
What, what, what?
You're sorry, right?
I didn't have a choice.
You always have a choice.
They were gonna cut off
my dad's finger.
Well, none of that matters
anymore.
Joe, wh-what can I do?
I'll do anything.
You can leave.
Come on, girl.
You got to eat.
Come on, Story.
Can I help you?
I want to sign up.
Dallas?
I'm not here for you.
I'm here to beat you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to the one and only
Lacy's Cue 9-Ball Open.
Alright.
Let's hear it.
Let's get this party started.
Somebody should have
warned me.
Tell you what,
you're impressing me today.
I did notice you were
a little tight on the breaks,
maybe just loosen up
that backstroke a little bit.
Or just do it your own way.
Dallas McCarthy.
I tell you, folks, this boy
is only 14 years old.
I don't know for sure,
but I think we could be making
some history here tonight.
Let's hear it for all
the players we've had
in this tournament.
You've got to be kidding me.
Is this kid not something,
people?
This is one of
the best tournaments
I think we've ever had.
You all give me
a little space here.
Come over here, boy.
How you feeling?
- Okay.
- Okay?
Son, you're about to be playing
your daddy in the finals
of a winner-take-all
pro-am qualifying tournament
and the best you can tell me
is you feel okay?
Oh, hell, he's just a little
bit nervous is all.
He's never beaten me more than
a game in a row in his whole life.
Oh, let's hear it
for our two finalists.
Now let's shoot some 9-ball.
Make it good, Dally, might be
the only shot you get.
There's your one.
Ball in hand.
That was your first mistake.
May as well start unscrewing
that thing now.
Let's rack them.
I think that makes us even.
You know, I'm gonna be
flat-out honest
with you here, Dallas.
I do believe that your chances
are dwindling.
Oh, talk about keeping it
in the family.
Let's hear it
for these McCarthy boys.
Looks like I may shoot again.
That was beyond impressive,
Dallas.
Hey, Cal, can you
come over here a minute?
Cal, you proud of your boy?
I am always proud of my boy.
Spoken like a real papa.
No, it's... it's all right.
Hell, I deserve it.
Dallas, no matter how much
you hate me,
I am so proud of you.
I will always love you.
You need to know that.
In three seconds,
I'm calling security.
Where did you get that?
From the 9-ball tournament.
Just wanted to give it to you.
That's all.
Hold on.
I believe you still owe me
one favor.
Joe?
Joe.
Hi.
Just let... let me rest.
Sorry. Just rest.
I'll talk to you later.
It's okay.
Just... Just rest.
Damn it!
Give me those damn keys.
Now!
You could have killed
the both of us.
Relax. I drive my dad's truck
all the time.
You had no right.
Figured I was
doing you a favor.
Yeah, well, you figured wrong.
Now give me those damn keys.
Get dressed.
You're gonna be late.
You look good.
Know what you're gonna say?
Don't worry.
It's gonna be great.
Oh, no, no, no.
You're coming, too.
You got me into this.
Come on.
You want to get closer?
No, I'm fine.
Okay. Here you go.
No, I... I got this.
Just take care of the guests.
Okay.
- Hey.
What are you doing here, Joe?
I already know about grandpa.
I just wanted to
congratulate you...
in person.
This is a big day.
Yeah, just surprising.
It's been a while, you know?
Chris, you have every right to
be angry about a lot of things.
I just wanted you to know
that I'm a different person now.
Yeah?
You don't look that different.
Still fighting those demons?
Some of them.
Um, I want you
to have this money,
just to help you get started.
We're fine.
I know it hurts, Chris.
Yes.
Yes, it does.
17 years' worth.
It hurts me, too.
What do you want from me, Joe?
I... I... I just...
Nothing more than to tell you
how sorry I am, okay,
and that I...
hope some day
you could come to forgive me.
I don't know.
You had two sons.
You cared more about
losing Danny
than you did about saving me.
Excuse me, but I'm going
to go do this right.
Mom.
I shouldn't have
brought you here.
It's alright.
Don't worry about it.
What was that about?
I blinked.
I, uh, I took my eyes
off the prize.
After one of Danny's
Little League games,
he and I went out
with some of his teammates
and their parents
for drinks and whatnot.
I think Christopher was...
Well, he had a cold,
and he had stayed home
with his mother that day.
And we were already late.
I don't know why I...
I thought I could
beat the light.
My judgment was impaired.
I didn't realize that
Danny wasn't...
...that Danny wasn't buckled in.
Dallas, there's some things
in your life
you just can't run away from.
So, uh, let's get you home.
It's over there.
It's gonna be weird
without my dad around.
Dallas, you know,
whether he comes back
or even if he doesn't,
that's something
you can't control,
and you can't let it derail
your own life, you know?
It's... it's time for you
to get on
with your own life
however best you can.
Uh, could I see that drawing
you did of me earlier?
- Sign it.
- Why?
Because I want it.
Okay.
Off you go.
Think God ever makes mistakes
when he assigns children
to their parents?
I don't know.
He should have put us together.
He did, son.
He did.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org