(MultiCom Jingle)
(upbeat rock music)
(gun shot)
♪ You tell me that the world is sinking ♪
♪ If you let it die tonight ♪
♪ Compared to this my
brain stops my heart ♪
♪ And so this dagger's mine ♪
♪ Sometimes I wonder what escapes more ♪
♪ And that's that heightened shout ♪
♪ Don't tell me what I know is true ♪
♪ Cause I never want
to see her face again ♪
♪ I never want to feel this so much more ♪
♪ I never want to feel like mine again ♪
♪ I don't care ♪
♪ If I don't even know at all ♪
(woman yelps)
♪ No heights, fear of falling ♪
(gun shot)
♪ Distraction's just so hard to find ♪
♪ Wearing masks that heighten show ♪
♪ Don't tell me what I know is true ♪
- C'mon, lets go!
♪ Because I never want
to see her face again ♪
♪ I never want to feel this so much more ♪
♪ 'Cause I never want
to see her face again ♪
♪ I don't care ♪
(crashing)
(splashing)
♪ Oh help me gain my freedom ♪
(thunking)
- As I was saying, Father,
this is what we can sell with our
new development in Australia.
Sun, beaches, lifeguards, pretty girls.
Mullet Beach has everything that we need.
I really think we should
move on this, Father.
- Do you know what this is, Son?
- Mud.
- Right, do you know what
you can make with it?
- [Bobby] A mess?
- Bricks, mud bricks.
- [Bobby] Bricks?
- One day, we could build a whole resort
out of mud, organic natural materials,
like an extension of the earth.
- Yes, sure.
Now Australia and Mullet Beach,
I really think that we--
- I think you'd better leave, Bobby.
Mike looks a little bit tired.
I'll look after him.
- Yes, sure, okay.
I'll get back to you
later on this, Father,
when you're done playing
with your mud.
(whimsical music)
- Time for a little drinky.
Feeling any younger?
- All the time.
- I know a lot of fun things that we
can do in the mud.
♪ Oh say does that star-spangled ♪
♪ Banner yet wave ♪
♪ For the land of the free ♪
♪ And the home of the brave ♪
(clapping)
(group chatting)
- Bobby.
Have you seen your father?
- [Bobby] Yes, he seems
a little preoccupied.
- I know.
There's no way we can let
him address this crowd.
God knows what he'd say,
you'll have to do it.
And by the way, have you told your father
you're going to Australia?
- No, not yet.
- I'll take care of your father.
Mr. McCain,
let's sit down,
you look tired.
- Whatever you say.
- I hope you're keeping up
Mr. McCain's medication.
- Religiously, Richard, religiously.
- Ever think of the sun, Richard?
- You mean Bobby, Mr. McCain?
- No, not my son,
the sun, up there.
You ever think about it?
- Uh, no, can't say I do.
- A lot of energy up there, Richard.
All the energy we'll ever need.
- Excuse me, please.
If there's any shit off those greenies,
you know what to do.
Welcome, distinguished guests,
ladies and gentlemen, to the opening of
McCain World Resort here in Los Angeles.
(audience applause)
Now as you can see, the award-winning
McCain architects are in tune with
today's requirements.
(group laughs)
(heckling)
McCain architects have blended the
oblique lines of this resort into
the surrounding habitat.
- Yeah, who'd you bribe?
- I would now like you all to
join me and put your hands together
for the son of the developer of this
magnificent complex, Mr. Bobby McCain.
(audience applause)
- Go back home.
- I'd like to welcome you
all, ladies and gentlemen,
on behalf of my father to the latest
McCain's World resort.
We at McCain's believe
that developments like
this one are an asset to the community.
- Yeah, and wreck them.
- There are those who disagree with
what we do,
- [Man] Hey, back off, buddy.
- But we feel that it is our duty
to realize the world's
potential beauty spots.
That's why we're about to break ground
on two new resorts, one
at North Beach, Hawaii,
and the other one in Australia.
So I'd like you all to
take out your checkbooks,
and let's invest in the future.
(audience applause)
To you all, I would like to say
aloha, and good day, thank you.
(applause)
(group chatting)
- Your speech was good,
I didn't think you had it in you.
- There's of me that
you don't know about.
- Like being an exchange
lifeguard, for instance?
- I can pull it off,
have you arranged everything, the trials?
- It's done, Bobby, you'll win.
- Good.
- You will be the exchange lifeguard
on that plane to Australia,
even if you can't swim a stroke.
- I can swim.
- I heard.
- Excuse me, I'm going to
go check on my father.
- Stop annoying him, we need him.
- For now.
That little jerk bugs me.
You taking care of the old man?
- Don't you worry about big Mike McCain.
- Energy!
- Little Donna has got him
right where she wants him.
- He keeps acting this crazy,
we'll get control of the company before
those pills of yours finish him off.
(giggling)
(whimsical music)
(air whooshing)
- Father,
- Bobby, take a look at this.
If we incorporated a few wind generators
on the Australian site,
we could save up to--
- That's what I want to talk to you about.
- Good, wind could be the whole key.
- No, not wind, Australia.
- Australia, great place,
can't wait to get back there.
- I think I should go instead of you.
I can lock up the Mullet Beach deal while
you stay here and play with your mud and
your wind, or work with them, and stuff.
I know how much you like Australia,
- Good idea.
- But I really feel that I can, what?
- Good idea, you go to Australia,
it's just what you need, a trip down under
will do you good.
- It's not a vacation.
- I realize you'll be working,
but Australia's a funny place.
It changes people, and I figure,
you need a change.
- What, there's nothing wrong with me.
- I know that,
I love those people, love 'em so much,
I married one.
- Not that we ever hear from her.
- Hey kid, don't go blaming your mother,
it was my fault that we broke up.
I figure if I had stayed in Australia,
your mother and I might still be together.
But, that's the way the wind blows.
- [Announcer] Good day,
Australia, Flight 115
now ready for boarding,
- Time for your candy, Mike.
- Oh, thank you.
You know, I think Bobby
going is a great idea,
but I don't like this
pretend lifeguard business.
If the people at Mullet Beach figure out
they're being had?
- Don't worry, they're just a
bunch of dumb hicks.
- I don't think so.
- Mike, it is a legitimate
business tactic.
You used to do the same thing yourself.
Remember the time on our riviera deal?
You pretended to be a movie star.
- I don't do that anymore,
that was a long time ago.
- Now your contacts are
Al and Clint Eastman.
- Contacts, Al and Clint Eastman.
- From Red Beach.
- Now, the Mullet Beach Surf Club
don't know your real name, to them you're
Bobby Carter, okay?
- Don't know my real
name, I am Bobby Carter.
Bobby Carter.
- They don't know who you are,
so try and keep it that way,
and if you have any problems, call me,
and do try and call your mother,
I know she'd love to hear from you.
- And did you pack my
teddy bear to protect me?
- No, I packed these.
- Rubbers?
- Yes, if you're going to lay anything,
lay rubber first.
- I want the community to work with us.
- They will, they will,
leave it to me.
Leave it to Bobby.
- Goodbye.
- Good luck.
- Thank you very much.
Keep an eye on the old man, will you?
- Oh, we will, we will.
- Here's a little Aussie good luck charm.
- Oh, thanks.
- Oh, and me and the little lady
want you to have this.
For protection, here,
here's another one.
- Thanks.
Goodbye, goodbye, goodbye,
goodbye Helen, thank you very much.
Goodbye father.
- Bye bye, Bobby.
- Bye, Bobby.
(clapping)
- [Announcer] All right
boys, and the final
check this afternoon for the beach race,
the exchange lifeguard field race final,
kindly sponsored by our
Prince Slop of Slappers Cancer Council,
the competitors are
competing for these trophies.
They have been donated by our friends
at the Red Beach council.
- I don't get it, Clint.
Why am I dressing up as a shark?
- So that all the victims in the
beltways will think that
you're a real shark,
and they'll swim in.
- Why?
- So that they'll get disqualified.
Well, except the chap from Mullet Beach,
he wouldn't know a shark if he met one.
- What?
- And of course, the winners of this will
spend three months at Malibu as an
exchange lifeguard at Malibu,
and let's hear it now for our finalists
here this afternoon, ladies and gentlemen.
(scattered applause)
- Look, Tim, Tim,
just act like a shark.
That way, Mullet Beach will win,
even though they're the worst team.
- Oh, we want Mullet Beach to win?
- That's right.
- Uh, why?
- Tim, Tim.
Just act like a shark,
that's all you have to do.
I've got to be in the race, remember?
Just act like a shark.
- And of course, the Red Beach team
with my nephew Clint Eastman,
being the champion of
last year's challenge,
where are you, Clint?
(scattered applause)
Hey, it doesn't matter, he'll be here
for the start.
(splash)
And of course, we have Rusty Mullet
from Milton Beach.
Rusty Milton from Mullet,
I beg your pardon.
I beg your pardon, slip
of the tongue there.
Let's have a round of applause for them.
All right, that's more like.
(mumbling)
I'd like you to take now to the beautiful
pride of the owner there,
the Mullet Beach Surf Club club
and here are some of the competitors,
Hammerhead Hogan from the Gulf Coast,
and Butch Parson from Lyle Beach,
who will be up there to relieve him,
go boys!
(upbeat music)
- C'mon Kylie, go!
(crowd cheering)
- And the Red Beach team
way, way, way out in front,
by five or six meters.
- [Man] Shark!
It's a shark, everybody!
(splashing)
Swim, there's a shark!
- What's this, the victims are coming in,
that's got to be a disqualification,
the victims are coming
in, there's gotta be.
(splashing)
- [Man] Shark!
- Shark!
- What's that?
That's a shark, look!
(splashing)
(crowd reacting in surprise)
(siren wailing)
(Al yelling)
(splashing)
(cheering)
- [Al] The only ones
that can win the race!
(crowd cheering)
- Okay, ladies and gentleman,
put your hands together for our own
Mullet Beach champ, Mr. Rusty Milton!
(crowd cheering)
(cheerful rock music)
- Congratulations, Mick.
Who would have thought old Rusty
had it in him, eh?
- Strange world, isn't it?
- But it's not gonna make any difference,
you and your club are past chance.
Rusty might have dragged the group to
the states, but you're
still a very distant last
in the championships.
In fact, one more result like that,
and you're out of the
Certified Surfing Association for good.
That would be a pity.
- Is this you or your
uncle speaking, Clint?
- You're wasting your time, Mick.
- You had your chance.
Watch your back.
- Watch my back, will you?
(radio chatter)
(crowd chatting)
- Mullet Beach?
- [Driver] Mullet?
- Mullet Beach, yeah.
- [Driver] Mullet, yeah, sure, sure.
- Do you know where it is?
- Yeah, yeah.
First time in Australia, mate?
- Yeah, why?
- Fine, no, no worries,
no worries, Mullet Beach, here we come.
Please, hop in.
- I think we're here.
Yeah.
- Oh, right.
- I told you mate, it's off the coast, eh?
- How much do I owe you?
- On the meter.
- Six hundred and twenty-three bucks?
- All right, we'll make
it an even 850, eh?
- Excuse me?
Oh, bridge toll.
Besides, I thought you guys were
supposed to be big tippers?
- Oh, you sure 850's enough?
- Eh?
- Look, I'll tell you what,
how about this?
I'm a bit of a gambling man.
- Oh, yeah?
- Look, one of yours, okay?
What do you say we flip this coin,
and we go for double or nothing?
Tails, I don't pay anything,
and heads, I'll pay
you 17 hundred dollars.
Come on, American.
- American?
- Yeah.
- You're on.
- All right, that's my kind of guy.
Ready?
- Yeah.
- Ooh, ouch, looks like tails, it's me.
I'm sorry, man.
But thanks for the ride,
I really appreciate it.
It's a nice country you got here.
Have a nice trip back.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Memo: my father reckons they're the
greatest people in the world,
so far I've found Australians to be
nothing but a bunch of
cheap incompetent hustlers.
(engine roaring)
(snoring)
(clanking)
Good day.
- What can I do for you, mate?
- I'm Bobby Carter,
the exchange lifeguard?
Looks like you were expecting me.
- Mick, sorry you missed the party.
Follow me.
(cheerful instrumental rock music)
(gasps)
- Watch it.
- Mullets, Max,
this is Bobby.
Tishi.
- Tishi.
- Bobby.
- Kylie.
- Hi.
- [Mick] Terry over there on the camera.
- [Bobby] Terry.
- How are you, mate?
- [Bobby] Good, good.
Where's the tower?
- [Mick] What's that?
- You know, the thing
the lifeguards sit on,
I mean the lifeguard station.
- We don't need them.
When the sharks attack,
we can tell where they are
just by the screams.
See, look over there.
Couple of white pointers.
- Keep it clean, Mick.
You're giving Bobby the wrong impression.
(crowd cheering)
- [Bobby] Beautiful beach you've got here.
- [Mick] Wait till you see your room.
- [Bobby] Oh, no thanks.
I'll stay at a hotel.
- [Mick] Nah, that'll cost you money.
I've never known a life
saver to have any money,
especially an American one.
- [Bobby] Oh, right, right, yeah.
(ominous music)
- This is much better than a hotel.
You don't get accommodations
like this every day.
The world famous Mullet Cave.
So what do you reckon?
Listen, mate.
I'm going out later on, you wanna come?
- Uh, no, thanks.
I think I'll just stay here
and try and get some sleep.
You know, cab lag and all of that?
- Sure, sure, no problem.
(squeaking)
- I feel like I'm in a '60s time warp,
this place is a dump.
Our reports about the
Mullet Beach Lifesaving Club
were accurate.
How these bunch of nerds
ever survived at all
is beyond me.
McCain's bulldozing this clubhouse
will be a community service.
As far as Mullet Beach goes,
well, this place is a paradise.
The company is gonna make a killing.
- [Mick] Who you talking to, Bobby?
- [Man] Quick, tell him to put
his clothes on.
- [Mick] Where is she, mate?
- Who?
- [Mick] Come on, bring her out.
- Oh, I was just talking to myself.
- You bastard, you've cleaned the cave.
This place was a bloody tradition.
Told you the Yank was gay.
- No, it's okay, the
place needed a good tug.
You can do my car later.
- You find any money laying around?
- No, but I did find enough bikini bottoms
to start a boutique.
- Here we go, I think this
was a trophy of yours,
isn't it, Max?
(laughing)
Tough bit of training, you ready?
- Yeah, sure.
- Boat training.
- Great, with or without trunks?
- Trunks?
Oh yeah, good one.
(laughing)
- Hey, hey, pal!
Hey, that's the second time
you tried to run me off the road.
- Love the swimmers.
You must be the Yank.
- Yeah, Bobby Carter.
- McCarter?
- No, Carter.
Just Carter.
- Yeah, well you should
watch where you're walking,
Bobby Carter, right?
- Don't worry mate,
guys always forget their names when
they're talking to Charlene.
(thud)
- Look.
(suspenseful music)
(clunking)
(splash)
- Where's the Yank?
Anyone seen the Yank?
(coughing)
- Doesn't look like much a of a lifeguard.
- Tell me about it.
- What's the story?
- Mate, it was just a bit of routine
boat training, you know how it is.
- Routine Mullet Beach boat capsize,
no story there.
- Yeah, except for there was a shark.
- Shark?
What sort of a shark?
- Oh mate, it's hard to tell, you know.
Close up, it could have been a hammerhead.
- Did you see the shark?
- It was a great white.
- [Reporter] And how would you know that?
- Well, I'm an LA lifeguard.
- Oh really, how big was it?
- Oh, four feet.
- Eight meters.
See,
it's hard to tell, you know.
But I sort of just hit him, you know?
Whacked him on the nose a couple of times.
- Yeah, he hit him,
and there was two of them, they came.
- Yeah, a couple of them there, yeah.
- You came at them, and you,
- Sure, a couple almost.
- Punched him in the, it was amazing.
- I'd say hairy snappers, you want a peek?
Hairy snappers.
- Sharp teeth, yeah, pointy sharp teeth.
- All right.
(cheerful country music)
♪ Let's make a move ♪
♪ Let's get started ♪
♪ Don't leave me cold, broken-hearted ♪
♪ Let's make a move ♪
♪ Let's get started, ♪
♪ Don't leave me cold and broken-hearted ♪
♪ Let's make a move ♪
♪ Let's get started on us tonight ♪
♪ Hey baby ♪
- Hi, would you like to dance?
- No thanks.
♪ Don't walk away ♪
- You from around here?
- No, I'm from another planet.
- My name's Bobby Carter
and I'm from America.
- Same difference.
- You don't like Americans?
- Jeez, you're quick of the mind.
- So why don't you like us?
- American, just like that McCain bastard.
- McCain, who's McCain?
- One of your mob.
He's bought up half the land around here,
so can bung up some ugly resort
for rich folks and kick all of us out.
- Can't stop progress.
Who knows, maybe this
McCain's got the right idea.
- Don't you just love
telling us what's right?
♪ Sometimes I get so lonely ♪
♪ Thinking about you ♪
♪ Sometimes it hurt so bad ♪
♪ What can I do ♪
♪ I wanna love you till my heart stops ♪
♪ Till the suns stops shining down ♪
♪ Until the stars fall
right out of the sky ♪
- How about it, babe?
- With you?
Are you serious?
Ever tried to sit on a skeg and twist?
- With you, you bitch.
You'd love it with a twist.
- I like a man who likes it rough.
You wanna play rough?
- Any time, baby, just let's go.
(crack)
(thud)
♪ Let's make a move ♪
♪ Let's get started ♪
- Well done, Charlene.
♪ Let's make a move, let's get started ♪
- That girlfriend of Mick sure
does know how to take care of herself.
- Charlene?
I taught her everything she knows.
♪ Let's make a move ♪
- Come on, let's dance.
♪ Let's get started on us tonight ♪
♪ Let's make a move ♪
- Ladies and gentlemen,
let's hear it for the
legendary Bag on Beauties
(crowd cheering)
And now, and now it's
official welcoming time
for our newest and best friend,
and here to welcome is the one and only,
the beautiful Karen Weist.
(whoops)
(crowd cheers)
- Okay, it gives me the greatest
pleasure of pleasures to introduce to
all of us here and to
welcome to our very own
Mullet Beach, our visiting
exchange lifeguard,
direct from USA, and maybe Hollywood,
Mr. Bobby Carter.
(group cheers)
(cheerful soft rock music)
- What can I say, welcome to Australia.
- Thanks.
Did you have a party like
this last Sunday, too?
- Yeah, a bit wilder.
Hey, you wanna swap?
- Yeah, okay.
- Karen, this is Bobby,
Bobby, Karen.
- Hi Bobby, I'm Karen.
I do TV, the Big Wheel,
have you seen it?
You're the first American I've ever met,
have you been to Hollywood,
do you know Steven
Spielberg's phone number?
- 'Scuse me buddy, you've got my girl.
- Oh, sorry.
- Thanks, Karen.
- Julie, excuse me, Julie?
I think we started off on the wrong foot,
and I just wanted to let you know that
I'm not here to teach anybody anything,
I'm here to learn, really.
Listen, can I get you a cup of coffee?
(giggling)
You're not gonna believe what you see.
Are you ready?
Oh, I think I'm out of coffee.
Let's take a walk on the beach.
- Got him a beauty.
(giggling)
- It looks like the club's going to
have to close at the end of summer.
- Why?
- It's Red Beach, they wanna combine
the two clubs, sort of like a surfing
corporate takeover.
They'll get our funds and better members.
- How are you involved?
- I own the club.
- You do?
- My parents bought it
when they retired.
It was just a beach house.
They've gone now, and I lease it
to the surf club.
- The club house is right on the beach.
The land must be worth a fortune.
- Yeah, I supposed so.
Al Eastman's always making me
offers I can't refuse.
- But you do.
- Sure, the guy's a creep.
Besides, I reckon he's in it
with this McCain bastard.
- Maybe McCain is not so bad.
Maybe it's--
- Bullshit.
Bullshit, the guy comes here,
tries to take our land--
- All right, all right,
all right, I'm sorry,
I'm sorry, you're right.
I just don't want this place to change.
- But you could make
an absolute fortune.
- You don't get it, do you?
I don't care about the money.
I care about this.
(somber music)
I'm sorry, what do you care about?
Family?
Tell me about you.
- Well, my dad's a bit sick back
in LA, and my mom, she
lives here in Brisbane.
She and my dad married when
she was really young,
and they were separated
when I was really young.
And I don't remember much about her.
- Are you gonna try and get in touch?
- I don't know, I haven't seen her
in about 18 years.
- So you're half an Aussie.
- Yeah, I suppose I am.
- I suppose that is why you're half okay.
- You think I'm okay?
- Yeah, but don't wet yourself.
(rustling)
(giggling)
(background moaning)
(thumping)
- Julie Thomas.
One hard-headed lady.
Arrogant, self-righteous,
hates Americans.
I think I'm in love.
(urgent music)
(dog barking)
- You sure can run.
- Thanks, you're not so bad yourself.
- Now listen, Bobby,
one thing.
- What?
- If you really want to
look like a lifesaver?
- Yeah?
- We gotta get you a
new pair of those, mate.
(laughs)
- What's wrong with these?
What, these, come on.
(dog barking)
(farting)
- Look at this, Mr. Surf Hero.
- Oh, hey, you're a good-looking fellow.
- Morning, Bobby.
- Good morning, Kylie.
It's not what it seems.
(farting)
- Good day, Bobby.
- Morning, Tishi.
It's definitely not what it seems,
I slept on the couch.
- Sure.
(ominous music)
(growling)
- What is it, boy?
(barking)
- You!
- [Mick] Get him, now!
- [Clint] Get that bastard off me!
Get him off.
Get the bastard off me.
(growling)
Hey, just a joke.
I'm sorry, okay?
- How's the bike?
- I can flush the tank,
but if I'd started it...
(growling)
- Just call the bastard away.
- Killer, you know what to do.
(farting)
(splashing)
(barking)
(screaming)
(whimsical music)
(barking)
- Have a nice day, Asswipe.
- Yuck, Captain Marvel'd be embarrassed
to wear these.
Mullet Beach green.
- Try 'em on.
- Oh, look a bit tight for
the wedding tackle, hm?
- You're in the hands
of a professional, now.
- That should do it.
You going to the
demonstration against McCain
this afternoon?
- That bastard.
I'd forgotten all about it,
thanks for reminding me.
- Good, we'll see you there.
Come too, if you like.
We'll need all the help we can get.
- Thanks.
(cheerful music)
This coastline is just sensational.
- Don't worry, we won't
let McCain bastards
take it off us.
- You'd have to be crazy.
- Yeah.
- Well, well, well, look who's
come to check out the meeting.
(sniffing)
Jeez, Clint, you ought
to take a bath, mate.
You smell like dog piss.
- [Man] Are here now to say a few words.
- Want you to woof him,
I told you to woof him in the car,
just woof him.
- Developers are paying big bucks
to our own council to get these
building applications through.
Now, are we just gonna
sit back, and let these
foreign consortiums ruin our
- Sarah.
- Public parks and beaches?
Well, are we?
- [Group In Unison] No, no way.
- I don't think we'll have any trouble
with this bunch of boofheads.
Which one's the Yank?
- That's him.
- Oh.
- So what are we going to do about it?
- Al Eastman, nice to meet you.
- You better count your fingers, mate.
- I'll see you in the title, Dooley,
say hello to your mother for me.
What's going on, McCain?
Gray said you'd be in touch.
- I've been busy.
- Well I can't talk to you here,
my office in the boat
shed across the road,
but I wanna talk to you, now.
Nice to meet you, Mr. Carter.
Very nice.
- So what about our American friend,
Mr. Bobby Carter, exchange lifeguard.
Yeah, I'm talking to you, mate.
What would you do about it?
- Uh, we have the same problems at home,
I don't know what to say.
- Oh, thanks mate,
that was a big help.
- All right, well,
get off your butts, organize.
- So where do you stand, for or against?
- It's not my town,
if you wanna keep it, you do it.
- I thought we were working
on this deal together.
What's the idea of going down there
and stirring up all this trouble?
- I had to say something.
- Well, they're a bunch
of boofheads anyway.
Is that girl gonna sell the clubhouse yet?
- I've tried everything,
and she's staying put.
She's not interested in the money.
- Stupid bitch.
- Hey watch it, pal.
- We struck a nerve.
We sampling a few of the local delicacies,
are we?
She's a very attractive girl.
- She's not gonna sell, and that's it.
I'm reporting to Gray that I
think we should consider
canceling the whole thing.
- Now you wait a minute, Bobby.
I've sunk a lot of money into this.
You've been down here for five minutes,
and already you're making
negative decisions.
Now you give this girl time
and she'll sell, right?
- Negative?
And my friends call me Bobby.
You two better call me Mr. McCain.
- We two better call
you Mr. Carter, right?
Otherwise Julie will
be disappointed in you,
won't she?
- She's not gonna sell.
- You lot are bloody hopeless.
There's zone championships
are starting in a week.
We might as well pack it in now.
- So what's new, we always lose anyway.
- Yeah.
- Well, why do we bother?
- Because we must.
- That's right, if you don't,
you'll lose the club.
I mean, that's what you said, right?
- Yeah.
- You lose everything?
- That's if those developers don't
get it first.
- Well, I have a confession to make.
- Jason!
Jason!
- There's a kid caught
in the rip, come on.
(dramatic music)
- All right, Terry, Tishi, get the reel.
Julie, look after the mother.
- It'll be all right.
- [Kylie] Down.
- You've got the bell?
That's all right, I'll take it.
(sobbing)
- Pull him over.
- [Tishi] Cough it up.
Come on, you're okay.
- [Terry] Yeah, he's gonna be all right.
- [Tishi] Good boy.
- Fellas.
What's this, mate?
Christmas shopping list?
- I saw you out there yesterday,
I know you can do it.
- When it's important.
- If you wanna save this club,
it's important now.
- So what's this?
- [Bobby] It's a training program.
(scoffs)
- [Mick] Fifty pushups?
- And that's just to start.
Look, I'll never be as good a lifeguard
as you guys.
But the one thing I can
do is, I can organize.
I can organize people
into getting things done.
Now, do you wanna keep this place?
Do you?
- Yeah.
We just don't go for all
the parades and shit.
- Well you're gonna have to,
if you want to survive.
That's why I made this program.
I just believe that if
we all work together,
that we'll give those titles a run
for their money.
- Hey man, there's a
five kilometer beach run.
- Yeah.
- What's in it for you, Carter?
- Let's just say that I owe you one.
- All righty, let's give it a burl.
(cheering)
- Now I have some good
news, I have some good news.
Charlene has offered to help us.
- [Max] Yo, Charlene.
(lightning crashing)
- [Tishi] Can somebody
explain to me why this
good news sounds like bad news?
(cheerful music)
- Go!
Go!
Oh come on, you're just racing.
Pull!
Row!
Okay, row.
Four, three, two, that's it!
Four, three, two, switch legs.
Come on, don't quit, four, three, two,
pick it up!
Come on, pick it up!
Make the boat slide.
Put your back into it.
Move it, what are you two,
men or mice?
- Meece, girl meeces.
(smack)
(groans)
Cute, now 10 more.
Now for the big test, number one group,
here, through water.
(blows whistle)
Through, through!
Remember the timing.
- [Bobby] Well?
- I don't believe it.
A week ago I thought we
didn't have a chance,
but I was wrong about you, Bobby.
- Thanks.
Well, we've only got one problem now.
- What?
- Me, I'm nowhere near
as good as you guys.
- You're just as good
as Rusty was, better.
- [Bobby] Thanks.
- [Charlene] Okay, Mullets,
that's getting better.
Through, through.
Come on, through.
- Julie, there's something
I have to tell you.
- That's it, okay you two,
swim training begins now,
two laps fro the skinnies to the cliffs.
Go.
(whistling)
- I don't think so, Donna.
- Aw, come on, baby,
it's good for you.
- No, thank you.
- Honey, honey, the
doctor said you should.
- I hate quack doctors.
- Honey, what are you doing?
- Packing.
- Oh, where are we going?
- We're not going anywhere, I'm going.
- You?
Where?
- Australia.
- I've never seen him
act like this before.
- Well, maybe we can
use it to our advantage.
- How?
- I'll call a general meeting.
We'll say he's flipped out,
gone bananas.
- So?
- You get a letter from the doctor
who gave you the pills.
(giggling)
- That's it.
Big Mike McCain has
finally lost his marbles.
His son's off, womanizing in Australia.
So it's up to his senior vice president,
- Richard Gray.
And Mrs. McCain.
- Oh, and Mrs. McCain.
To take over the running of the company,
the board will buy it.
- What about Mullet Beach?
- I'll tell Eastman to turn up the heat,
whether Bobby likes it or not.
Donna?
- Oh, Richard.
- I think we've done it.
- Richard, I think this
calls for a celebration.
- Oh, I'll second that.
You know, I've got this feeling
this is gonna be a
highly productive merger.
- Oh, Richard, Richard.
(laughing)
- So, that's about the size of it.
Our founder and managing director is
sadly unable to function
competently in his position.
(crying)
- Therefore, with the blessing of
Mr. McCain's wife,
and power of attorney,
it is my melancholy duty
to assume control of McCain World Resorts.
Now, Mrs. McCain and I
feel it would be the best
thing, the only thing,
to carry out Big Mike's plans as if he
were still here with us.
(chatting in agreement)
Now you've all seen the
computer projection.
Oh, that coastline is
some of the prettiest
on earth, and the easiest to develop.
Flat land, not much forestation,
and it's a steal, as long as
we make the decision today.
Those hillbilly Aussies won't know it
until it's too late!
Carried unanimously, good.
Big Mike would be proud of you.
- [Bob] One thing worries me.
- [Richard] And what's that, Bob?
- Our people in Australia, that soft cock
Eastman and his son, can they handle this?
- Probably not, but
don't you worry about it.
We have somebody down there as well,
and he is keeping an eye on Bobby McCain,
and Mullet Beach.
- Does Bobby know?
- No, Bob, our man is in disguise.
- [Mick] Left right,
left right, left, right,
left, left foot, left foot!
- Right wheel.
- Left, left foot, left foot.
(Scottish bagpipe music)
- Killer, you want some?
- [Mick] Left foot, left
foot, left foot, left, left!
Left foot.
- And step two three, halt.
Mullet Beach crew, you have two more days
until the zone championships.
As a team, you're
beginning to work together.
The improvement is beyond expectation.
However, let's not rest on our laurels.
Training for the afternoon will be
what the hell, have the
day off, you've earned it.
- Oh!
Thank God.
(thudding)
(groaning)
(splash)
(serene music)
(splashing)
(laughing)
- Come on, Killer,
hurry up, or we'll miss the party.
(ominous music)
(barking)
What is it, mate?
(sniffing)
Petrol.
(barking)
(clanging)
- Here you go, guys, marshmallows.
- Oh yeah, did you remember the forks?
- Oh, get out of here,
use a dirty stick like everyone else.
Hey mate, not the thongs, jeez.
- Instead of prawns, it's a little piece.
- That's not a joke, buddy.
Yeah, go and laugh.
- I've got to hand to to you, mate.
You surprise me, you're really fitting in.
- Well, thank you very much.
You're a great bunch of guys.
- Yeah, 'cause people around here
can be a bit funny when
it comes to foreigners
- Oh, you've had some problems?
- No, I said foreigners.
- Excuse me everybody, it's only
two days until the championships.
Mick would like to say something.
(laughs)
- Even though there's
still two days to go,
I reckon for the first time,
we're in with a chance.
(clapping)
(cheering)
Even though I wanna kill
you two slave drivers,
I would like to propose a toast to Bobby,
and to Charlene.
- [Bobby] Yeah, Charlene.
(cheering)
(ominous music)
- You bastard!
You two-faced lying bastard!
- Terry you idiot, what's
this dickhead doing here?
- [Terry] I caught him
trying to torch the club.
- [Julie] What?
- Don't worry, Killer and I
convinced him it wasn't such a good idea.
- Well what's that got to do with Bobby?
- Plenty, he's in it with them.
You wanna tell them, Carter?
Or should I say Mr. McCain!
- Hey, hey, hey, Terry, you drunk or what?
- Ask him!
- He's in it, all right,
he's the bloody big boss's kid.
- Shut up, pencil neck.
Bobby?
- [Tishi] Well?
- My name's Bobby McCain.
(ominous music)
- What?
- I tried to tell you, I really did,
I tried to tell you a couple of times.
- I found this in his stuff.
Have a listen.
- [Bobby On Recording] So
far, I find Australians
to be nothing but a bunch of
cheap incompetent hustlers.
(tape screeching)
How these bunch of nerds ever survived
at all is beyond me.
McCain's bulldozing this clubhouse will be
a community service.
- There's more.
- [Bobby On Recording] Julie Thomas,
one hard-headed lady.
Arrogant, self-righteous.
(smack)
Hates Americans.
- We trusted you.
- Go on, thump the prick.
- Shut up.
- Mick.
- [Terry] You're friggin' a spy.
- I tried to stop that development,
you gotta believe me.
- A Yankee land developer spy!
(barking)
(thud)
- Terry!
(hissing)
(screams)
Hey, hey, hey!
Terry, Terry, Terry!
Watch it, mate, watch it.
(crash)
(groaning)
- Give it a break!
Terry, give it a break!
- Let go of me!
(barking)
- Oh, shit.
- So the whole thing was a setup.
- Yeah.
- Well, at least that explains how
Rusty won the trip to Malibu.
- Yeah, never could figure that.
- Listen, I don't want
that development to happen,
you gotta believe me.
- I believe you?
- All those things I said
on the tape recorder
when I first got here.
- Sure.
- I tried talking to Eastman--
- Listen, Bobby, will you just shut up?
You know,
you won't be able to stay here
at the club anymore.
(peaceful music)
(engine revving)
Hey, Mrs. B.
This is Bobby McCain,
the fellow I called you about.
- McCain, McCain, another one.
Bloody McCains all over the shop.
- What is she talking about?
- Don't worry mate, she's
stark raving bonkers.
Aren't you, Mrs. B?
- No guests after eight PM,
no animals, breakfast is
served at seven sharp.
- [Mick] Did you get my dog dry cleaned?
- Yup.
She's also deaf as a post.
- I heard that, I heard that.
What did he say?
- He's just a son of a
bitch with no friends.
She'll look after you.
- Thanks.
- Got McCains coming
out of the bloody walls.
- Excuse me?
It's 11:35, you must know.
- Thank you, does that phone work?
- Yeah.
It'll be 20 dollars in advance.
- For the phone?
- Yeah, room 2D, down the hall.
- Oh, okay, for the room.
Here.
- Bloody McCains.
- Thank you!
Operator, yes.
I'd like to place a collect call
to the United States to Mr. Mike McCain
from Bobby, area code 310,
three, four, one, four, five, three, four.
- Hi.
- [Bobby] Father.
- Eastman's got no right, I never gave
the go-ahead!
- Well somebody did!
- Richard Gray.
Well, it doesn't matter.
I'm here now, we'll do things right.
- Listen, McCain is a
dirty word at Mullet Beach.
Believe me, they don't want a high rise.
- I don't blame them, I
wouldn't want one either.
- So what are you doing here?
- I've been designing the right kind of
resort for Mullet Beach.
Here, take a look at this.
Take a look at it.
Low rise, okay, no more than two stories.
Mud brick, solar and wind power
set back from the beach, they won't even
know it's there.
- This is good, this is really good.
And I thought you were,
- Nuts?
- Well.
- That's okay, I was acting a
little loopy there for a while,
I think it was those stupid pills.
Been feeling a lot better, though,
since I left LA.
- It must be Australia.
- It must be.
- I'll tell you something, kid.
There's a lot of hungry sharks out there.
- Where, at the beach?
- No, driving taxi cabs.
(laughing)
- You gonna see Mom?
- I don't think so.
It's been a long time, Bobby.
I'm sure she's married
some Aussie cattle man,
or newspaper owner, or something.
- Dad?
- Why don't you go and find her,
my hands are tied up, right here.
- They're not gonna buy it.
- Leave it to me.
Hey, I hear you found yourself an angel.
- Found and lost.
(somber music)
Julie, wait, please.
- Oh, let's not do this, Bobby.
I don't wanna talk, okay?
- Please, from the first time
that I saw you, Julie.
- What, you knew I was a sucker?
- No.
Look, I know you're angry with me,
and I know I deserve it.
But at least give me
the chance to explain.
- No, I won't.
Don't you remember?
I'm arrogant, hard-headed,
and self-righteous,
get out of my life.
- Will you shut up!
- Shut up, everybody!
- Thank you.
Now there's a bloke here that's got
something to say to us.
He reckons he's got something interesting
to say about the McCains' development,
so here he is, what was your name, mate?
- Mike McCain.
- [Terry] What's he doing here?
(group heckling)
- Well the last time I was in Australia,
I was told that you always gave a guy
a, how do you put it?
A fair go?
(group heckling)
Yeah, a fair go, that's all I ask for.
Is a fair go.
- All right, shut up everybody,
and give the bloke a go.
- Look, I don't blame you for not
wanting a high rise building slapped in
the middle of your best beach.
I think that's a dumb idea,
I don't want that.
What I want for us is this.
- [Terry] Hey, we don't
need any resort, mate.
- This is not a resort, this is a
community-owned project.
(group heckling)
Look, I don't mean to get personal,
but do you have a job?
- No.
No.
- Does anybody else here not have a job?
Come on people, I did the research myself.
Twenty-eight percent
unemployment on this coastline.
What you need is an
environmentally-friendly
eco-center, powered by natural resources.
(group grumbling)
Look, look, look.
We can't for you, if you don't want it,
we won't do it.
But give it a chance,
look for for yourself.
You decide.
(group arguing)
(slam)
- [Donna] Well?
- Your husband is at Mullet Beach!
- [Donna] And?
- Eastman says he's stirring up trouble.
He's talking about a cooperative venture.
- A what?
- Big Mike has told the people of
Mullet Beach that he'll give them back
all their land, if they
go into partnership
with McCain's.
- You're kidding.
- He wants to build some
kind of resort commune.
- Didn't anyone tell
him, communism is dead?
- Well don't you worry about it, baby.
Because he can't do it.
Big Mike doesn't know it yet,
but he does not run McCain's anymore.
- Richard?
It's time you and I did something to
finish this, once and for all.
- Mr. Eastman, I've heard a lot about you.
- And me about you.
- And this must be your
nephew, Clint Eastwood.
- It's Eastman.
- Of course.
My kid's just about the same age as you.
- Yeah, we've met.
- That was very unusual speech
you gave this morning, Mr. McCain.
- You heard it, good.
Then you can appreciate the purpose
of my visit.
I want the deeds to all
the Mullet Beach properties
you purchased on behalf of McCain's.
We're giving them back.
- No can do.
- What's the problem, they're in the bank?
- No, they're right here in the safe.
But my boss told me to leave them
where they are.
- Al, I'm your boss.
- I'm afraid not, you were relieved
of command yesterday.
Richard Gray is now the general manager
of McCain's.
They reckon you're a few shrimp short
of the full barbie.
- So you won't give me the deeds, then?
- Clint and I are the only ones
who know the combination, Mr. McCain.
And I'm afraid they're
no longer your property.
So if you don't mind, we have work to do.
- Good day, gentlemen.
(creak)
- Mick, have you seen Bobby anywhere?
- Have you tried skinnies?
- Mick, I've been up and down the coast,
we've got to find him.
- Mrs. B's?
- I've been there, Mick.
His bags are gone.
- Look, he figures everybody hate him,
he's probably going back to the States.
- Mick, please, I wanna see him again.
- All right, there is one place
he could be.
(huffs)
(optimistic instrumental music)
Where are you off to?
Trying to skip out on the team
before the titles, huh?
- Bobby, I don't want you to go back
to the States.
- We need you, mate.
Let me put it this way,
either you come with us now,
or I'll let Killer here
rearrange your features.
(barking)
- Unless we can get a hold of those deeds,
McCain's will force Julie here to sell up
and push ahead with the old development.
- But it's your company,
why don't you stop them?
- I've been squeezed out, son.
They say I'm not sane.
- Gray?
- Yeah, and my good wife is in there
somewhere, as well.
- [Julie] So what do we do?
- Stall them, I'll get the company back.
If we can just get our
hand on those deeds.
(suspenseful music)
- Bobcat to Mullet Beach,
we've got ourselves
a right dickhead.
- Take the car, it's not mine,
it's my uncle's.
- We don't want the car.
- You, I'll get you for this, you prick.
- And me too, I hope.
- Oh, Christ, the daily double,
piss off, Yank.
- Did you say Yank?
(screams)
- You bastards, you'll pay for this.
- He's right, you know,
he can identify us.
- You bet I can, you're gonna
rot in jail.
- Oh, jail, I don't wanna rot in jail,
do you?
- Certainly not.
- I guess we'll have
to do him in after all.
- What?
You mean?
- Unless, unless he tells us
what we wanna know.
- What are you talking about?
- The safe in your uncle's office.
- All we want are the numbers to open it.
(spits)
- Oh, man.
(laughs)
- If that's the way you
wanna play it, Kylie.
- What's this, dog food?
You gonna make me eat it?
Man, I'd eat dog shit before
I told you anything.
What are you doing?
(gasping)
- Oh, man.
Oh.
- Right, rub it in.
- You rub it in.
- Uh uh, don't look at me.
(squishing)
(groans)
- Oh god, don't look,
I think he's enjoying it.
- For the last time, the combination.
- Frig you, all of you.
(crying)
- It's time.
- Dinner time.
(barking)
Killer.
(growling)
(screaming)
(laughing)
- He still back here.
Okay, where should we hide the deeds?
- Oh, right in here.
(chuckling)
- Is it gonna be all right in there?
- Oh yeah, sure, no worries.
- Sure.
- Taxi, taxi, Mullet Beach!
- Mullet Beach, you've gotta be kidding.
- What's he doing?
- Ah, don't worry about him,
we'll get the sea plane,
it will be quicker.
- Mr. Eastman.
- Mrs. McCain.
- Where's McCain?
- Oh, the big one's gone to ground,
and the little one's down the beach.
You see, we have these
surf lifesaving titles.
- Is everything under control?
- No worries, he tried to get the
deeds off me, but I told him to,
disappear.
- Are the deeds safe?
- No worries, we're set like jellies.
- We're set like what?
- We're set like,
ah, doesn't matter, it's an expression.
- Have you purchased the clubhouse yet?
- Ah, there's the problem.
You see, the lady who
owns it won't sell it.
- And what are you doing about it?
- Well like I was saying before,
we have this surf lifesaving competition,
teams from all over the country
will be here.
- I'm sure it's great, but what does
it have to do with the clubhouse?
- Mullet Beach will lose
like they do every year,
and then the association
will throw them out.
- So?
- So that means that there will be
no more funds, which means no more money
for the clubhouse,
no more money for Miss Julie Thomas,
she can't pay her mortgage,
she'll have to sell, no risk.
- There better not be.
- Would you like to watch Mullet Beach
go down the dunny?
- Go down the what?
- It's an expression.
♪ Now it's Christmas,
everybody's having fun ♪
♪ Santa's coming round
with gifts for everyone ♪
♪ And it's all because of Christmas ♪
- So what about the iron man, Terry?
- Sorry, I'm out.
- But that's your event.
- Yeah, I know, I think we can do
better than second last.
- Yeah, last.
- McCain's chance now,
you've seen his times.
- Wait, wait a minute,
I'm not taking anybody's place.
- Hey, my event, my call.
You're our best chance.
♪ Now it's Christmas, everybody's having ♪
- Well?
- Will you do it?
♪ Santa's coming now with
gifts for everyone, ♪
♪ And it's all because of ♪
- Great, mate.
- Good luck.
- Ho, ho, ho!
(children yelling)
Ho, ho, ho!
(children cheering)
- Welcome, to the pillow
fighting championships,
and introducing the
champion of all champions,
the one, the only, Griller
Mark from Red Beach
the team, (hooting),
the Griller!
And of course, his
challenger from Mullet Beach,
Max Foisen.
(upbeat music)
(crowd cheering)
- [Man] Come on, Max!
(whistling)
(thwacking)
(thud)
(crowd cheering)
- You said they'd come last, you idiot!
- And they will, we still got tomorrow.
- Hey, if they do as well today,
they'll win the damn thing!
I don't like this.
I don't like this at all.
- You do realize, we're going to
get the title deeds to her property,
and that way we can piss the bitch off
out of the clubhouse, keep
smiling, keep smiling.
- Fourth and tenth, they've got a punt.
- What?
- That is an expression.
- [Julie] Hi.
- [Bobby] Who's this?
- Bobby, I've got a surprise for you.
Anne Marie, your mother.
- Bobby.
Hi, welcome home.
- I don't believe it.
- Go on, you really do--
- Thanks.
- [Anne Marie] Look wonderful, oh.
- He would have never
have done it by himself.
- I'm so happy to see you.
- Eastman, I am worried about the deeds,
go get the deeds.
- No worries, Clint and I are
the only ones who know the combination
of the safe.
- Eastman.
- Clinton!
- You idiot!
- I'll kill him!
- Three cheers for Mullet Beach, guys.
- Hip hooray.
- We haven't saved the club yet.
- So, long time, Anne Marie.
- You're looking good, Mike.
- Bull, I look terrible.
If I'd stayed in LA one more week,
I'd be dead by now.
- You should have never gone back there
in the first place.
- Haven't changed, have you?
Still tell me what's good for me.
- And you're still not listening?
- You two taking up where
you left off?
- Yeah, me being a jerk again.
Sorry, Annie.
What?
- Oh, I just haven't been called Annie
in a long time.
Shouldn't you go and talk
to your wife?
- The little darling's been trying
to poison me, she and her friend.
It's over.
I hope the two of them
live happily ever after.
- So did they take over
the business, I mean?
- Nah, we've got them, haven't we, Son?
- Well, if you can hold on to those deeds
until you can sort things out in LA.
- Yeah, and prove that I'm not a psycho.
- That may not be so easy.
- You know, I might just go over and see
if I can find anything out.
Excuse me.
- You did a good job, Mike.
I like him.
- Chalk it up to genes.
On his mother's side.
- Hello Richard,
hi Mommy.
- Two mothers in the same bar,
pretty confusing, aye?
- Oh, not really,
only one of them is a real mother.
- What do you want, junior?
- Oh, just wanted to know
how it went with the deeds.
- We'll get them.
- Sure you will.
- Bobby, your father's no longer in
control of the company,
now he can pass out
all the deeds he wants to,
it doesn't mean a thing.
- Poor Mikey is gaga.
- There's nothing wrong with him,
you can see that.
- Now, maybe.
But you saw how he was acting in LA,
crazy as a loon.
- He was fine.
- He was nuts, staring at the sun,
playing in the mud, I drove him nuts.
- Donna.
- Oh, what the hell?
Who's gonna believe Bobby boy?
Big Mike McCain's son and heir?
I kept him drugged out
of his brains with these.
He was crazy, all right.
- That's enough.
(giggling)
And no point in telling anyone,
the pills leave no trace.
No one will ever believe you, come on.
- You know, there's
never been anyone else.
- No?
Three wives, several constant companions,
not to mention girlfriends.
- Are you keeping score?
- That would be a full-time occupation.
And looking at the lovely Donna,
I don't really think I could be bothered.
- Me neither.
- Aren't you supposed to be mad?
- Totally crazy.
(laughs)
(woman screaming)
- What's that?
(ominous music)
(groans)
(groaning)
- Oh my god, Kylie, are you okay?
- [Bobby] I've got her feet.
Easy.
You're all right.
- Some crazy guy in roller blades.
- He took the deeds.
- Gray.
- Don't worry, everything's under control.
(laughing)
- We've got the deeds.
(shrieking)
We've got Big Mike.
- And I've got Big Richard.
- [Announcer] Welcome again, folks,
to the North Coast championships,
and what a splendid day,
and a special hi to Mrs--
- It's only a slight concussion,
she's gonna be okay, but that leaves us
without a suite for the boat race.
- [Tishi] What about Bobby?
- Nah, it's too close to the iron man,
we might have to pull out.
Unless?
- No way, Jose.
- Ladies and gentlemen,
I'd like to announce
the finals of the surf boat race,
sponsored by Skyland
Drive Ins at click clack
from the back.
I'd like the competitors to please stand
by their clubs.
- Okay.
- How's your head?
- Oh, I'm all right.
- Ladies and gentleman, I'd just like
to announce that Johnny
Jake from Woodbaum,
his wife has just given
birth to Joshua John,
just last night, a big round of applause
for Johnny Jake and his wife Anna,
are you right, Reg, Reg?
(pistol fires)
(suspenseful music)
What a beautiful day, Christmas day
on the beach, folks.
While our lifeguards are fighting for the
biggest range, and his part of the world,
the snow keeps falling down.
Now, for the rest of this course,
for the moment, are you ready, lads?
In first place, Red Beach,
85 points and leading by a
(crowd cheering)
- Go guys!
- [Al] Let's hear it for the fans.
(clacking)
Next, the dark horse with
83 points, Bar Beach,
next, with 80 points are,
who should have been disqualified,
with 75 points,
(splashing)
(crowd cheering)
- [Man] Keep it straight!
Clint, you idiot!
(cheering)
(screaming)
- Go.
(cheering)
(bells ringing)
- Bobby McCain, the great surf hero.
It's not gonna work, you know.
We've got the deeds back,
won't be hard to convince the board
your father's still mad.
- You may as well forget it, Bobby.
- Listen, Bobby boy,
Donna and I play for keeps.
You're way in over your head.
- Do you always talk in cliches?
- Well, unlike you I'm not here
under false pretenses.
- They know how I am.
And I know exactly what you two are.
Dad!
- Hello, Richard.
And how's my faithful little wife?
Pumping me full of those ugly little pills
wasn't very nice, darling.
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- Really?
When I got Bobby this little toy,
I thought it might come in handy some day.
- [Bobby] It did.
- [Donna on Recording] I kept him drugged
out of his brain with these.
He was crazy, all right.
(laughs)
- I want both your resignations
from the board of my company, immediately.
My lawyer is drawing up the papers.
(thud)
(crash)
And I suggest you return the deeds.
This is virtually a confession
to an attempted murder.
- I can walk.
- Bye!
(pistol fires)
(crowd cheering)
(suspenseful music)
- With my nephew, Clint Eastman,
way out in front, let's hear it
for my nephew, give it right here,
I got fifty to one on him, go Clint, go!
Go, Clint go!
(splashing)
- Go, go!
- Come on, Bobby!
Bobby!
- Bobby, go!
- All right, he's way ahead now!
(crowd cheering)
- [Al] It's Clint Eastman!
(splashing)
- We're gonna win!
Go, baby, yeah!
- Bobby, Bobby!
- Go, yeah, we're winning!
- No, get up!
- Get him!
(crowd cheering)
- No!
- Let's get out of here.
(cheering)
- I'm sorry, Uncle Alfie.
(thud)
- And it's Al, you idiot.
(group cheering)
(gasping)
(screaming)
(splash)
- Distinguished guests,
ladies and gentlemen,
(bird squawks)
ladies and gentlemen, I'd like to announce
the winners of the Surf
Lifesaving Club Title,
- Mullet Beach!
(crowd cheering)
- Ladies and gentlemen,
the Mullet Beach captain,
Mick Dooley!
- Come on,
- Come on, lady.
(thud)
- Oh, sorry, Mr. Eastman.
- Thank you.
Thanks very much, I'd like to thank
our supporters, and of course,
the club members, thank you club members.
(cheering)
(applause)
Al Eastman, you're a wonderful man.
- Get up, get up.
You're pathetic, just get away.
Now I think you should all know,
this could never have been possible
without the help of one man, Bobby McCain.
Bobby, up here.
(crowd cheering)
(applause)
- Well I'd like to take all the credit
for it, but I can't, it
was a team effort, huh?
Let's give another hand
for the Mullets, yeah!
(applauding)
(cheering)
- (whoops) Mullets!
- I know you're all waiting to
hear about the tourist development,
and I'm pleased to announce that it will
be going ahead,
but not as first planned.
The community has passed
my father's designs
for an environmentally-friendly
cooperative development.
We can't stop progress,
but we sure can plan the
impact for our futures.
(crowd cheering)
(applause)
- This is crazy, I can't believe you!
- [Richard] No, you are
an idiot, Al Eastman!
(thud)
(groans)
- Thank you.
- Sorry excuse for an American!
- Don't hit me!
- You're disgusting, and I hate you!
I hate you, I hate you!
(booing)
- Give her a real one.
- Hey, come on you two.
Come on.
(group cheering)
(optimistic music)
♪ I know you wanna be loved ♪
♪ No word passes from your lips ♪
♪ I know you wanna be seen ♪
♪ No touch comes from your fingertips ♪
♪ If there is a way to send a message ♪
♪ Better do it before I go ♪
♪ Let me help you out
'cause I can tell you ♪
♪ Everything and you should know that ♪
♪ If you wanna be the only one ♪
♪ You better say it ♪
♪ Just say it ♪
♪ They are standing waiting
to sound the drums ♪
♪ I'm gonna pray that ♪
♪ You will tell me tomorrow ♪
♪ Know that nothing is sure
in this crazy world of ours ♪
♪ Maybe there is no cure ♪
♪ To the silence that surrounds us ♪
♪ If there is a time
to take your chances ♪
♪ This is the time to show ♪
♪ Let me help you out ♪
♪ Cause I can tell you ♪
♪ Everything and you know that ♪
♪ If you want to be the only one ♪
♪ You better say it, just say it ♪
♪ They are standing waiting
to sound the drums ♪
♪ I gonna pray that ♪
♪ You will tell me tomorrow ♪
♪ Tell me tonight ♪
♪ Maybe tonight ♪
♪ Know that nothing is sure ♪
♪ In this crazy world of ours ♪
♪ Maybe there is no cure ♪
(MultiCom Jingle)