It's dinner. Hope you don't catch up, but I've already tasted.
I look forward to showing you the rest.
-Hello. -Hello.
-Have you booked? -No. I might come another time.
No danger. Come in. Follow me up.
I feel very dizzy.
I have exactly what you need.
-A stick? -Sugar. It makes the world sweeter.
How much is left?
You are actually done.
-Already? -Yes.
And because you did so well, I would like to invite you for food.
If you have not eaten measured on that.
I have a partner.
Can't a man and woman go out and have dinner anymore?
As long as it's just dinner.
I told you not to take crème brûlée.
You've known me for five minutes and already say what to do.
-I like that. -I have ordered a taxi.
Hang with me. -It is too late.
Is it?
Okay then.
Come on! I could have gotten a taxi at this price.
-Why did you seat the seats. -I want to keep everything hygienic.
First of all, thank you for helping me achieve 500 followers.
It's a small step for man, though.
We have something very special for you today
or tomorrow, or next week. You get to see the core itself.
You know me as the guy who opens game consoles, mobiles.
Things you can buy for yourself
and get the same tickle off as I do when I open the box.
The only difference is that you do not have to buy anything.
If you order something from an unknown source, you do so at your own risk.
This is a mystery box
from Darknet.
It cost about 200 pounds and you get a black box like this.
The rest is a mystery.
I know you're here to see "the old man in the box".
This speaks for itself.
We have some dolls here
as someone placed on hands, feet and head.
So ... yeah.
Here is a family photo.
We have a family photo here.
Someone has ripped their faces off.
The only thing I can read from this is that the person is a lunatic.
A playing card.
It was like a fan!
I can't point out where things went wrong.
One thing I realized is that
an addict never remembers why it really became as it became.
Out of here, whore.
What do you think happens when they run out of items or people to sell?
It's just a matter of time.
-Nathan? -Yes, and you are?
-Noah. - Noah ... Sit down.
-How do you fix this? - Do like everyone else.
You spend your time and leave as fast as you can.
-I mean the tattoos. -Ah, stupid of me.
The equipment is made of different items from the dining room.
I ask for extras pay.
I made the syringe out of a pen and a metal spoon.
It's hard currency in here.
They are joined together with a motor from a shaver.
I empty at least three pens a day for my ink collection.
I mix it with mouthwash to make it flow better.
Then finally there are the needles and the batteries and then you come in.
-I didn't know it was so hot. -I'm really handy.
So ... now comes the fun. What do you want?
-Noah's ark? -Are you a comedian too?
-I work freely otherwise. - It's just running.
-What are you for? -Oh ... A big question.
A big answer, then? No?
Spray holes, tattoos.
No problem. Can I talk?
I'm worried that you're not in the shape to participate in this.
Then I would not sit here?
Nine girls have disappeared in the last nine months on a 25 km radius.
This young lady, Sophie Roberts ...
I have access to all her accounts and internet history.
It will put some momentum on you.
This is skin.
This is ... scarification.
It is an old custom to label the body
by cutting and grooving skin ...
Pretty inside, actually.
A youngster reported a mysterious box from Darknet a few days ago.
He found it there and some other random things.
I looked at some of these box openings. You should look at them.
-What else do you have? -The other clues we have ...
... are their families and friends who claim they planned to tattoo themselves.
We've been watching surveillance videos and bank statements.
But to be honest, it has not yielded anything.
The source of the skin, then?
It's a needle in a haystack.
The boxes are bought with bitcoin currency. That makes it impossible to track.
And the sites where he advertised are mirrored around the world.
It also makes it impossible to track.
We get to work on what we have.
I'll start tonight.
Rehab?
Give me a few weeks.
If we continue to feel as if we are not accepted
our bodies, our minds and souls will collapse
in front of those who made us feel this way.
There is a great opportunity for us out there.
But the road to it is expensive.
But we must try to succeed and live up to expectations.
It is important to know that if your father's approval is not enough for you
you have no value to us here.
Eve ... it's been three weeks.
-How are you? -Not so bad.
-How's the fall? -I'm working on it.
-Russian again? -You know me.
People ask questions. The families are becoming more and more upset.
I'm doing my best.
- I'll call you back. -You don't hang up.
Hello everybody.
My name is Eva.
My dad was a surgeon.
And ... like most dads ...
... especially those in medicine ...
... he felt a disgust for art.
I claimed that ...
...my profession...
... was artistically medical.
I help people transform themselves into something ... new.
I like it.
So ... take a look in the mirror.
- What a strange feeling. -It's a scarification.
-Why give people scars? - Their wish.
60?
-Thanks. -Thanks.
-I like your type of places.
I don't go out that often, but I try to be a little adventurous.
A drink? - Two shots, please.
-Are you alone? -With a friend.
Allow me.
What a soft skin.
Bowl!
-What's your name? Lucy.
-Do you want a receipt? -Thanks.
That's no danger, I said.
Wait a minute ... I recognize you.
Oh right.
Don't you remember me?
You don't seem so convincing.
I see a lot of faces these days, but not many such scars.
How does it heal?
As good as a self-inflicted scar can heal.
What a pleasure to hear.
The world is small. Be sure to treat the wound, as I said ... and have fun.
You, wait!
You're the expert. Don't you want to show me around?
-In one condition. -And what are the conditions?
That I should not waste it on something stupid.
So you bought a tattoo studio in response to:
"Don't spend it on something silly."
Try telling these guys that some of this is silly.
A friend said that ink in the skin makes a man crazy.
Do you agree?
If my personalities mean I'm crazy ... then I can stay that way.
What are you doing here?
The same as you.
I admire the art at its best.
I saw that you have no tattoos.
A tattooist without tattoos.
It confuses me.
Want to take something to eat?
I've eaten, but thanks for the offer.
Something to drink, then?
-I don't say no to that. -Good.
-Where are you from? -Moscow. Nostrovia.
-Why did you move here? - Look at something different.
Different temperature too, huh?
-Cold hands. - Warm heart.
So why don't you have any tattoos?
-Are you afraid of the pain? - I'm too greedy.
-What do you mean? -I want my skin to be clean.
If I started, I couldn't stop.
When a customer asks me to do what I want, I become selfish.
- Then I'll give them what I want. -Good answer.
What does that mean...?
That which reaches me, consumes me.
You said you admire the art here.
You are a good listener.
But what are you doing in London?
I am a Russian spy with orders to poison the Prime Minister with Novichok.
I hadn't expected that.
I'm glad you appreciate my humor.
Thanks for the chat.
You know where I am.
-Eva. -Nathanial. Kalla mig Nathan.
Nathan ... Nice to meet.
Mia, Mia, Mia ...
Someone should have called you a taxi home.
Now let's have some fun.
What?
I thought you would say something.
Mia, Mia.
You taste good.
Hi, Terry.
Hi, Sssssusan.
Hi, Stanley.
How are you?
It's dinner.
Hope you don't catch up, but I have already tasted.
It is good.
You will like it.
But ... before you eat ...
... I want your advice.
What do you think about it?
Good good.
I'm glad you like it. I look forward to showing you the rest.
-It became more difficult to feed my pet. -That is when you have reached the bottom.
-What's his name? -Stanley.
My nephew is Stanley. -He's great in the food.
He ended up with baby food when he was four. Animals in operation.
- Did you let him starve? -Never. he was my responsibility.
And I also have to eat.
-How is it going? -It's fine.
Be quiet and no interruptions up there or here.
-You can continue as you please. - Don't worry, Nigel, I can handle it.
Do you want?
It's done.
-Why is this design? -My girl was the same.
She's gone.
Sad to hear.
I think you did the ... tattoo.
Have you thought about trying something different?
What do you mean?
It's called scarification. It decorates the skin in a more surgical way.
Trust me.
Do you have a taxi number?
Do not worry. Give me two minutes and I'll drive you home later.
-Are you sure? -It is quiet.
-Do you live far from here? -Not so far from here.
-Why are the seats wrapped? - Aesthetic reasons.
Can you bring it to me?
What the hell?
You can scream as loud as you can ... no one will hear you.
You're screwed!
I prefer distorted, but thanks for the compliment.
-What are you gonna do to me? -Do not worry. You notice.
You know in Hebrew, my name means: "He who gives".
The ironic side of it: "He who takes".
-Your sick bastard! -You just wasted good meat.
He who gives.
-Hello Eva. It's been a while. -It really was.
-I'm a busy guy. -And I'm a busy lady.
But tonight I'm free ... if you are.
Aren't you free if I'm not?
You are so fun.
Can I come over to you? I cook and bring dinner.
-I'm a vegetarian. -Noterat.
Hi, the world, I'm the guy in the box and welcome to today's video.
I want to begin by expressing my gratitude, sharing
and love I received since the last box opening.
Thanks to you, I now have over 10,000 followers. Crazy.
For those of you who missed my last broadcast you get the chance now.
In the last video ... I got this leather wallet.
Quite cruel, as you can see.
It looks like a human tattoo.
I'm sorry I haven't posted anything in awhile.
Things like that fuck up a lot.
But I do it again today. Now let's go outside the box.
What you see is that this box is bigger than the previous one.
The cost was significantly higher as well.
But hope the content makes it worth it.
Now we check. Predictable...
... and nervous, but as you can see ...
... we have got more dolls.
Dog food.
Don't think I want to give it to the pussy, but it looks well sealed.
Is it that I spend so much on boxes that I can't feed the cat.
I have no words for this.
This is strange. Very strange.
We put it away.
You know from last time
that I can see everything after I open it.
But this I have to open twice.
We give it a try.
It is very soft.
It also smells.
Hey ...
Oh my God.
Hörni, I don't know if you can see it ...
It's a heart.
Should you
Oh, my God, no.
It is a USB flash drive.
What the hell.
Then I try.
There is only one file.
It is called "Cornucopia".
Hörni, I'm sorry, but we have to let it go.
Specialbud.
- Nice place. -I rent it.
-Do you drink red? -Yes thank you.
The blind leads the blind.
Today's lecture is a demonstration
of a classic proverb.
The blind leads the blind.
If you change it to the deaf, the blind shows say it is complicated.
Just like now. Only half of you can see me.
Don't you think that if the Father had the ability to see us?
and see all the actions we perform
our punishment would lead us to a more perfect place.
I'll leave you with that thought.
Remember to...
... communication is vital to the issue
and will make you realize how important communication is in your future choices.
When you return home you will not disappoint yourself.
When the Father returns to this land, we shall not disappoint him.
We will meet Him.
Can you send the cross stitch kit to your friend with blindfold.
The deaf person opposite can only see the pattern you are going to sew.
The blind can only sew on the instructions given to them.
Something to start.
How does it taste?
-It means perfect in Russian. -I should have guessed.
That which reaches me, consumes me.
-Excuse me? -Tatueringen.
Why should one come close to something so innocent.
Not only do I destroy a life without a voice, but ...
... myself too.
Close, but also devour.
-How long? - I've never eaten meat.
- Have you never thought about it? -Not directly.
-Can I persuade you to try? -No, that's fine, thank you.
-You can smell anyway? -I feel the smell from here.
-Take a scent of aroma. -I said no!
-I apologize. -No, leave it.
I go up and change.
- It was not necessary ... - It was my mother's.
-Hello! -Follow me.
Why are the seats wrapped?
It sounds weird. I have donated most, but this one was my favorite.
Don't you think your mother had had something against it?
Not at all.
This is very strange.
But ... okay, then.
I want this.
You can get it.
What the hell are you doing here? How did you get in?
You left the key in the door.
Well ...
Good timing.
IVANOV EVA UK CITIZENS
COHEN DRAWING British Citizens
-Reach? -We have a mountain to climb.
Tell me about Nathan.
Yes, he is making a distinction. Yes, he is a tattoo artist.
He also happens to be very odd.
But it doesn't click anywhere.
-Click with you? -Excuse?
-Your methods are effective, but dangerous. -Look at the results.
In the end, you have to give me more to work with. You can't do it yourself.
When I have something to give, you can have it.
I have understood.
-Hello. - Sorry, we're fully booked.
I'm friends with Nathan. Can I wed him?
-Oh, Nathan resigned this morning. -I do not understand.
He came here before me.
But is that his studio? He bought it from her mother's legacy.
No, it's my studio.
- But ... he said it. - He was probably just trying to impress.
Nathan was just an apprentice.
No, I quit.
- They didn't know anything ... and you just quit. - It wasn't the right place for me anymore.
-Don't you enjoy the pain? -I did it before, not now.
-Don't you tattoo yourself? -Not directly.
-Do you know where he is now? -No clue.
Okay thanks.
Nathan?
- There is no distribution. -Do you blame me?
-We need more people. - More help?
No, to review and fill the drawers.
We use the weak to feed ...
Stick with you, whore.
What does it mean?
What gives birth to me kills me.
-Eva, how are you? -You were right.
-About what? - I'll tell you when we see you.
No, you have to tell me now.
Eva?
Hello everybody.
Be good pipes towards the end.
And Merry Christmas to you all.
Nathan?
The game is over.
You found the keys.
It's time to leave now.
Stop faking the accent. What do you think?
Have you taken the girls?
Here we go.
Tell them where they are
then you will not sit as deep down in the crap as you do now.
Now I'll tell you.
I tattooed the girls.
I made them feel good.
And then ... when I finished ...
... I cut off their skin ...
... and then I ate them.
What I can't handle ...
... I share with this gang.
How do you stand up for yourself?
Someone is hungry.
Eva?
Eva!
We had been a couple to count on.
Against all odds.
I wonder it would have been different now.
But it can't be.
Sophie?
-Who are you? The police. I'll get you out.
She doesn't wake up.
Why are you doing this?
I was about to finish it before I met you.
Complete what?
I haven't been much to sports.
Didn't understand me on that.
But now I'm the bat
and you are the ball.
It sounds much more enticing.
-You disgust me. -Now.
Now now!
You and I...
... has covered all the bases.
Now it's time to make a home run.
The thing with my job is ...
I give...
... and I take.
- Hi, Nathanial? -Yes. Can I help you?
District Prosecutor, Janice Jordan. Can I come in?
- May I ask why you are here? -We have several cases of missing persons.
We usually search through these areas before we start asking questions.
What do you think?
About what? Instead?
-It was probably fun in the 90s. - I remember.
- Are you sleeping here? -It's better than in a store.
It has been locked for years. I never got any key.
Public toilets. You are welcome.
I want to keep it simple.
I am very busy and now I have been accommodating enough.
I'm looking for Eva.
What do you mean?
It's time for you to go.
-I can get a search warrant. -Do it.
Good luck with the renovation. I look forward to seeing it.
Eva?
Do you know why my name is Eva?
It means "to live".
To live a life.
My gift to you is dead.
Do you know what you did to her?
That's life.
We live and we die.
Calm down. You are going nowhere.
I ...
...need you.
I have something very special for you today.
Do you know why? 1,000,000 followers.
This is a new mystery box. It cost £ 2,000.
I've already opened it, but I have to share it with you.
It looks like a piece of clothing. As you see...
... it has many details.
The problem is that it feels like human skin.
But it's probably pig skin.
Then you were ready.
Thanks friend.
I did not get hold of batteries.
These are not good for health.
As you wish.
-It does not matter. I'm going out today. -It's not true?
-Yes, you're my last customer. -So you're released earlier?
Four years. Death by careless driving.
Eva?
Hello!
I was stuck there for 15 hours.
Come on! When is the trial?
There will be no trial.
Yes, but everything is there.
- The forensics found nothing. - But he will be sentenced?
- Four years for causing another's death. -He's a very smart man.
And I'm a patient woman.
The only blood they found was mine.
Don't forget that crowbars get a rod.
I saw what you were doing.
Take it easy.
-It was a long time ago. -I had a full up. Good to see you.
Good work.
We are family. But this ...
... it is entirely you.
Thank you for coming to this ceremonial event.
Please stand up.
What you all succeeded in has helped us get to the next step ...
... to make the world a better place ...
... for our children, ourselves ...
... and the Father.
The rulers have confirmed that the Father is with us in the end.
That which reaches me, consumes me.
Translation: Mika Wainonen www.ordiovision.com