Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Come on, come on,
they're gaining on us.
I'll lose 'em.
Yeah, that's right.
- Look out!
- Ahhh!
Oh, gee. Sorry,
I didn't mean to scare you.
Huh?
Stop.
That tickles.
Oh, wow!
Still getting used
to that strength thing.
- Everybody okay?
- Huh?
Good. Now hand me
those weapons.
Where are my manners?
Please hand me those weapons.
Can't believe
I forgot the "please."
Wow.
Okay, I hope you learned
your lesson.
Crime doesn't pay.
Adios.
Who is that guy?
A new superhero?
Yeah, a super polite hero.
Come on.
Are you ready
to do this deal?
As long as you don't get
cold flippers
like last time, Penguin.
Hah, cold flippers.
Ahem!
What? Who was that?
Up here.
I didn't wanna be rude
and interrupt
but, well,
then I did because,
you know, criminal activity.
Get him, boys.
I've had enough of being
tickled today, thank you.
Now, how about everyone
comes along quietly?
Hah, not likely, Red.
Lasers don't hurt me,
so you think that chains will?
Come on, guys, I was trying
not to prejudge you.
So... quietly then?
Mitzi. Mitzi girl.
Is there a problem, miss?
Mitzi, she's stuck
in the tree.
Don't worry, I'll get her.
Come on, little kitten.
Whoa!
Ho-ho! Look at you.
Wow, how did you get up here?
Oh.
Come here. Here you go.
Try to keep her
on a leash from now on.
Not only is it practical,
it's the law.
So long.
Wow, that's the nicest
superhero ever.
Okay, no one around, so...
Shazam!
Best day ever!
Well, well, well,
little boy Batson
has finally returned.
Oh, hey, Terrance,
Corey, Brian.
How are you guys today?
Great. In fact,
better than great.
I don't know where
you went off to today,
but you missed out on a
nice couple from Metropolis
looking for a well-behaved
little boy.
And since you were gone,
they picked me.
I'm really happy
for you, Terrance.
Oh, I bet you are, Billy,
you're always selfless
and that's why you'll always
end up alone.
Later, little Billy.
Better luck next time.
Come on, guys.
Did I say "best"?
I meant worst day ever.
Take a look at these.
"Lightning guy stops robbery."
"Big cheese foils Falcone."
"Hero saves dog in tree."
He saved a dog from a tree?
I mean, even Superman
doesn't do that.
I'm sure Superman would
save a dog from a tree
if he ever saw one.
Maybe if we were paying
attention instead of talking,
we'd know, wouldn't we, Kent?
Sorry, Mr. White.
I don't want sorry,
I want answers.
Who is he?
Where is he from?
What's his name?
I mean, look at that profile.
His chin looks like
it was made of marble.
That's it. We'll call him
"Captain Marble."
Already taken, Chief.
Is it? It doesn't matter.
Point is, what does he want?
Why is he so polite?
This is the story
of the century.
And I want a Daily Planet
exclusive yesterday.
Well, what are you all
standing around for?
Go, go!
I'm sorry. Excuse me.
- No, it's okay...
- This is...
Yeesh.
- Kent.
- Yeah, I was just
about to go out
and get you that interview,
Mr. White.
Ah, don't worry
about that, son,
superheroes have never
been your strong suit.
Well, I don't know about that.
I have another assignment
for you.
Something important,
something meaningful,
something that
only you can do.
I won't let you down,
Mr. White. What is it?
I need 1,000 words about the
Metropolis Farmer's Market by tomorrow.
They have this amazing
fertilizer exhibit
and if there's one person
that knows
how to write about manure,
it's you, Kent.
Sure thing, Mr. White.
Like, is this radish organic?
Absolutely, grew it myself.
Well, how can
I be sure, dude?
Well, uh...
So good.
Organic.
Told you.
Dang juicer.
I can't seem
to get this down.
Oh. Thanks, stranger.
Gather all the food
for the master,
he must be appeased.
Master will be pleased.
I mean, I was a farmer.
So, of course I guess I should
report on the farmer's market.
And, by golly,
I'm gonna give Mr. White
the best article on perennial
produce he's ever seen.
Help! Monsters!
Someone's in trouble.
Looks like Clark Kent
isn't the only one with
an assignment today.
Huh? Grr.
Don't you know?
Stealing is never part
of a healthy diet.
Puny Kryptonian.
Well, then.
All right, what do you have?
Sister Eye!
No.
Oh, well, how about...
Cousin Eye?
Trouble alert.
Uh, excuse me. Did... Did...
I didn't hear what you said.
- Did you say something?
- I gotta go.
Uh, Mr. Wayne, I didn't...
I didn't even get to tell you
about Grandpa Eye.
- Uh-oh.
- Need a hand?
That'd be super.
Take care of these guys,
I've got a train to catch.
Oh, come on, you have
to do better than that.
By the authority
of the Green Lantern Corps,
I command you to surrender.
Bah! The mighty Oom
doesn't answer to
your puny Lantern Corps.
Huh?
Oh, no, the bridge is out.
Hey, look, it's Superman.
Save us, Superman.
Oh!
Huh?
Next stop, Metropolis Central.
Yes, Superman.
Just because you're evil
doesn't mean
your breath should be.
Go brush your teeth.
You're the Dummy,
right?
Yeesh, way to set
the bar low.
Ha-hah! Too slow, Dummy.
I got this.
Huh?
Uh, like, thanks, man.
- How did you...
- Speed of Mercury, isn't it cool?
Oh, hey, one sec.
No, wait, who are you?
Okay, yeah, that's good.
I'm sure this thing has
a weight limit, so...
I've got it.
Strength of Hercules.
I could do this all day,
but who has the time?
- Pardon me.
- Huh?
I think you misplaced these.
Well, that takes care of that.
Hi. I'm...
By the arm hairs of Atlas,
are you okay?
You know Atlas?
That's so cool.
I've got the stamina of Atlas,
isn't that rad?
I barely even felt
getting hit.
But I bet he will.
Thanks.
Don't mention it.
- There's only room for one bat person around here.
- Huh?
Don't you think?
The master
must be satisfied.
But not today.
Retreat!
We have to go after them.
Later.
Right now, we have to stop
that building from collapsing.
I don't know if sunbathing on
the roof was such a great idea.
Whoa!
All right, everybody,
now shake your body.
Loosen those limbs.
This is fun.
Come on, you can do it.
It should feel like
you're climbing
up the side of
a mountain. Yeah!
Your turn, Flash.
I'm on it.
You're safe here, ma'am.
Gotta run.
Wow.
I'm here to offer
some support.
And jump, two, three.
Two, three, four.
- And one.
- Wow, what a workout.
What in
the blue blazes?
I think you can let go now.
Oh. Uh, heh, right.
Oh, my gosh,
I can't believe it,
Flash, you just ran up
those bricks like "zoom."
And Wonder Woman
with the lasso,
you were all...
And Superman,
with the heat vision,
you secured the base
with a "pssh."
Batman swung in
and caught that guy
while Green Lantern
was putting the wall
back together.
You guys are incredible!
It is such an amazing
pleasure to meet you.
You have been my hero
since I was just a kid.
Oop, sorry.
Since you were a kid?
By my observations,
you're approximately
the same age as Superman.
Same age? Oh, no, uh...
I just meant that
watching you makes me
feel like a kid.
Hmm.
Anyway, what a thrill
to meet you guys,
I hope I didn't get in the way.
Not at all.
In fact, we're grateful.
Mister...
Oh, uh, sorry.
I'm Shazam.
Uh... Shaz-what now?
Well, Shaz-bot.
- Shazam.
- Excuse me.
Shazam, it was pretty courageous
of you to leap into danger like that.
I know, that's one
of my powers too.
Courage of Achilles.
I used it just the other day
to eat some anchovies.
How can we be sure
you're one of the good guys?
Totally understandable.
But even if I wasn't,
a great philosopher
once said,
"Keep your friends close,
and your enemies closer."
So, really what
do you have to lose?
Yep, I know quotes.
Wisdom of Solomon.
Sweet, am I right?
Why does he keep mentioning
Solomon, Atlas and the others?
- Well, I...
- His powers obviously derive
from each of the ancient heroes
he's described,
that makes up
the name "Shazam."
S for the wisdom of Solomon.
H for the strength of Hercules.
A for the stamina of Atlas.
Another A for
the courage of Achilles.
And M for
the speed of Mercury.
That means that
Z must stand for...
The power of Zeus.
Still haven't figure out
what that is myself.
Well, whoever you are,
we really appreciate
your help.
My pleasure. I mean,
helping the Justice League,
so awesome!
You should tag along.
Come to the Hall of Justice,
see where the magic happens.
- I don't think...
- Seriously?
The Hall of Justice?
Like, the Hall of Justice?
Oh, man, I... I...
Be cool.
This is the greatest thing
that's ever happened to you
but just... be cool.
I mean, I guess so.
I don't have
anything going on,
so, uh, yeah, whatever.
It's not our fault.
Jeepers is right.
We would've had your food
but the Justice League
showed up
and ruined everything.
Enough!
I'm tired of excuses.
What I need is food.
And if you can't get it,
then I, Mr. Mind,
will find others who can.
Yes.
So powerful, so hungry.
So hungry.
Yes, food,
I need more food.
Excuse me. Sivana,
how goes our small experiment?
It's done.
This magically infused chemical
should do what you wanted.
Now, can you stop
mind-controlling me and let me go?
Hmm, nope.
Now jump like a kangaroo.
Mind control is the best.
Eat. Eat. Hunger.
Food.
Bring me more food.
I must have more before
the Justice League arrives.
The Justice League?
Here? But how?
Call it intuition.
And over here, we have
our trouble alert system.
If there's a problem
anywhere in the world,
we'll know about it.
This is incredible!
I...
I think I might cry.
Hall of Justice branded tissue?
Can I keep this?
Highly unsanitary.
Totally going
in my scrapbook.
You guys, I really can't
thank you enough for the tour.
You all mean so much to me.
The Justice League has always
been a beacon of hope.
In the darkest of times,
I've always said,
"What would
the Justice League do?"
I mean...
It depends on your roster,
that Plastic Man
is kind of different,
but, uh, that doesn't matter.
You guys have
helped me a lot.
I might need one
of those hankies, Batman.
Well, I better get going.
I hope we do some superhero-ing
stuff together soon.
No, wait.
I call
a Justice League meeting.
Is a meeting necessary?
We should be out
finding these monsters.
I have their location
via the Bat-Tracer, and...
You know the rules, Batman.
If one of us
calls a meeting...
Then we all must attend.
Should I go or...
No, stay right there.
Krypto will keep you company.
It's an ultrasonic whistle.
One sec.
A super-dog.
Ah, hi, Krypto.
Aren't you cute?
Yes, you are. Yes, you are.
I think we should let him join.
The League?
But we just met him.
Not everyone is as reluctant to
join the League as you were, Batman.
I like him.
And not just because
he has a lightning bolt
on his chest,
though that doesn't hurt.
I'm with Flash,
there's something
so innocent about him.
You can't catch me.
Or juvenile.
I saw we take a vote.
All in favor,
raise your hand.
Shazam,
we have an offer for you.
An offer?
We'd like to invite you
to become a member of...
the Justice League.
What? Is this for real?
I... I... This isn't some
hidden camera show, is it?
There are 24 cameras
in this room,
none of which you could find
even with Superman's abilities.
No, this isn't a prank.
The reality is you fit all of
our Justice League criteria.
- You have superpowers.
- Check.
- Fight for good.
- Double check.
And not a kid.
Check-aroni.
So, Shazam, what do you say?
I... will be
the best Leaguer ever!
I promise, seriously,
you'll never regret this.
Shazam, the Justice League
is more than a
well-tuned crime fighting unit.
It's a family.
A... family?
And families
are built on trust.
Shazam, we think that
you could be a great
addition to the team.
But in order for us
to fully trust you,
we need to know
who you really are.
Not the superhero.
But, you.
My, uh... Oh, no.
Don't worry,
we'll go first.
Well, except for Batman,
he kind of gets an exception
because he's so grumpy.
I'm not grumpy.
Yeah,
I don't know you.
No idea.
I mean, that's not
even really a disguise.
Well, sure it is.
The star draws your view
from my face.
Not really.
Clark Kent?
Oh, wow! You did
that amazing exposé
on building
without instructions.
That was fantastic.
Oh, thanks,
I worked really hard
on that piece.
- Ahem.
- Oh, right.
So, are you ready
to be part of the family?
I...
I can't.
I'm sorry, I... I really am.
I have to go.
Just as I surmised,
Shazam has something to hide,
and this proves
he is not to be trusted.
But you hide everything.
- Bat exemption.
- No, but I...
Bat exemption.
Now, come on.
We have monsters to catch.
Huh? Oh!
Hmm. Mm.
I can't believe I didn't just
join the Justice League.
But if they knew that
I was just a kid...
- Whoa, is that guy flying? Oh, man!
- Nice cape.
I've never seen a superhero.
Wow.
Look, Mommy,
Superman got a new costume.
Bye, Red Superman.
Stay still.
How did you even get in here,
you pesky beast?
Oh, hello, Billy.
How was your day?
Oh, you know.
It doesn't take a wizard
to know something's
bothering you.
But I'm a wizard,
so maybe it does.
Billy, you can tell me
anything.
I had
this great day, you know?
Fighting bad guys,
meeting my heroes, but then...
But then the Justice League
wanted me to join their team.
That sounds wonderful.
It was, except,
in order to join,
they said
they needed to trust me.
Which means I would have
to reveal my secret identity.
And you were afraid
they would reject you
when they found out
you weren't an adult?
Exactly.
I know that, in your heart,
all you've ever wanted
was a family, Billy.
Somewhere to belong.
I've tried to give you
that place,
but my time is running out.
Soon, you'll need
to find your own way.
And you'll discover
that being in a family
doesn't come without
its own risks.
Risks?
Like what?
Trust, my son,
trust to share a part
of yourself with others.
And hope that those you
share it with will accept it.
You're talking about
you sharing
the power of Zeus
with me, right?
The first guy you chose
to be the Wizard's champion?
Well, I wouldn't say first.
There was another.
His name was Teth Adam.
Shazam!
But he would become
Mighty Adam.
He started out as
the hero I hoped he would be.
But I was blind not
to see his growing ambition.
Soon, he was corrupted by
his power and turned to evil.
He tried to enslave the world,
but after a long
and trying battle,
I defeated him.
No!
And thus, he became
Black Adam.
What did you do?
I locked him away
where he can never harm
anyone again.
The point is, Billy,
that even I,
the wise and powerful Wizard,
risked something
and continue to risk
by giving that power to you.
My true champion.
Aw, shucks.
What is it?
The League?
I sense a trap. Go.
And remember, Billy,
nothing creates trust
like helping those in need.
Wisdom of Solomon?
No, common sense.
Now go.
There you are.
Now just hold still.
I hate moths.
Fan out.
No sign of anything
out of the ordinary.
Strange. The Bat Radar
indicates the tracer should be right...
where that box is.
- Oh, I got it.
- No, it's a trap.
Right as always, Batman.
The Monster Society
welcomes you.
Is that a talking worm? I mean,
come on, we fight worms now?
I'm no mere worm, Flash.
I'm the powerful Mr. Mind,
the greatest villain
in the galaxy.
Wanted in over three quadrants
of the universe
for my evil evilness.
And now I can add defeating the
Justice League to my accomplishments.
Sivana, if you please?
Huh?
Though my powers of
mental persuasion are strong,
I know they could never tame the
superheroic minds of the Justice League.
Well, maybe the Flash.
Thanks... a lot.
You'll never...
get away with this.
I already have.
The adult mind
is hard to manipulate,
but the mind of a child...
Sivana, fans.
- Huh?
- What?
- It worked!
- Of course it worked.
Dr. Sivana is no slouch.
I'm a kid?
Well, I'll be
butter-churned in July.
But I don't wanna be a kid.
What are you talking about?
I don't feel any different.
Turn us back, Sivana,
this instant.
Sivana can do
nothing and neither can you.
Ah, so easy.
I have all of you now.
Wait! I don't see Batman.
He's gone!
Go, my monsters.
Find the Batman
and bring him to me.
And now, Junior Justice League,
are you ready to do my bidding?
Well, as Pa used to say,
"Does a cow moo when you pull its udder?"
What?
I'll assume
that's a yes,
so welcome to
the Monster Society of Evil!
There.
There is the false Bat.
Get him for the master.
Uh-oh.
Ha-ha!
Got you.
Come out, Batsy.
There is no place to go.
Huh?
Ha! Got you, got you.
Now you're stuck in Bat Glue.
No place to go, Batman?
Or should I say "Batboy"?
Are you okay, kid?
I saw those bad guys and
thought you might need some help.
- I...
- I mean, I appreciate the amount of work
you put into your cosplay,
but superhero-ing
is kind of dangerous.
- I...
- How about I drop you off to your mom?
Maybe she'll take you out for a milkshake
or something. Those always cheer me up.
I am Batman.
Sheesh.
Mr. Mind transformed us
into children
in order to control our young
impressionable minds.
But because I'm awesome, I was able to
get away before his powers affected me.
- Wow, you really are Batman.
- Duh.
I guess that's a no
on super-hearing.
Okay, okay. Digesting.
Well, listen, Batman,
how about you stay here
while I take care of...
No. Mr. Mind controls
the monsters
and the preadolescent
Justice League.
There's a chance
he can get you, too.
I don't want you jumping in
there and causing more trouble.
- But I can help.
- Yeah.
I don't work with people
I can't trust.
And after your quick exit
at the Hall of Justice,
I can't trust you.
- What are you gonna do, then?
- It doesn't matter what I'm going to do.
I'm Batman...
...and everything I do
is incredible.
The Batmobile.
My diary is never
gonna believe this.
Well, okay.
Good luck, Batman.
I know there's no obstacle you can't overcome.
- I have complete faith in you.
- Come on.
You're a real hero.
Change of plan.
Do you really wanna help?
Uh-huh.
In my youthful state,
I'm unable to reach the pedals.
- So, you'll need to drive.
- Drive?
You can drive a stick,
can't you?
Okay, no...
Stop. Wait, no. Not that way.
I thought you said you'd done this.
Of course I have.
I'm an adult.
Just a little rusty. Oh!
Rusty? And why are you in third gear?
Okay, let's just
stay off the freeway.
Hello! Welcome!
Have a great day.
Well, what do we have here?
It's not even Halloween
but, my, you look wonderful.
What brings you in today?
The master needs food
like a pig needs a pile of mud.
Ooh, isn't that nice?
Brick O's! My favorite!
Looks like I have the last one.
- I'll take that. Thanks.
- Huh?
- It looks like it's ripe...
...for the picking.
Look what I found. Guess who's
going to be master's favorite now?
As my ma used to say,
"You can't win a pig kissing contest
without getting
a little dirty."
That doesn't
even make sense.
- Does, too.
- Does not.
- Does not, infinity plus one!
Ow!
I'm telling the master.
Have a nice day.
Mmm.
Ugh. Gross.
Oh, good. Mmm, you're back.
Just place the food anywhere.
Mmm, I'll get to it eventually.
I know it's me saying this but
shouldn't you, I don't know, slow down?
Eat more faster.
Slow down? No.
If anything, I need to...
speed up.
Mmm.
Peas? What are peas
doing here?
What's the rule?
No peas, please.
Exactly.
Anything else is fine.
Broccoli, arugula, whatever,
just no peas.
Sheesh. Now go!
Give me more.
I must have more!
Oh!
Whoa. Wow!
This place is amazing!
I thought the Rock of Eternity
was cool, but this place...
Rock of Eternity?
Nexus of magic
in another dimension.
Uh, it's a long story.
What are you doing?
My Bat Computer is the most
sophisticated computer on the planet.
High-def with over
a billion mega-brixels,
state of the art.
It also streams Brickflix.
And it has the ability to find
anyone at anytime in the world.
- Pretty cool, huh?
- Way cool.
There.
They're stealing food from
everywhere. We have to stop them!
I have to stop them.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You don't trust me. But,
I mean, come on.
I helped you with the monsters,
the Batmobile... sort of.
I know it's hard to believe,
but I don't trust people very easily.
No, that's not hard to believe
at all. You live in a cave.
In our line of work,
we have to be careful.
I mean, what if
you were a bad guy?
I've already revealed
too much to you.
You're lucky I don't
take you out right now.
I could, you know?
'Cause I'm Batman.
And Batman is totally
the best hero.
O... kay?
Point is, it pays
to keep people at a distance.
- So you...
- Never get hurt.
Hemingway once said,
"The best way to find out
if you can trust someone
is to trust them."
Fine. Shazam!
- Billy Batson.
- Hey.
I don't understand.
How did you...
It all started when I helped you
during that Two-Face situation.
Oh, no. Which one?
Which one?
The red wire, Billy.
I don't know who
the voice belonged to.
I just knew it saved our lives.
After that, I went about
my usual routine.
Well, Billy, that's the last of the
money you got from recycling.
Hope this sandwich is worth it
'cause I'm starving.
Spare some food.
Have a great day.
You're a nice boy,
Billy Batson.
Hey, how do you know my name?
That wasn't the only weird thing that
happened to me over the next couple of days.
Excuse me, ma'am,
let me give you a hand.
You're
a nice boy, Billy Batson.
I just kept running
into the strangest people.
Hey, mister, you dropped this.
- Huh?
- You're a nice boy.
Here. For your trouble.
Free subway token?
Thanks, mister.
Little did I know
that small token
would lead me
on an incredible journey.
Billy Batson, you have
been found... worthy.
That voice.
Climb aboard for
the adventure of a lifetime.
What is this place?
"The seven deadly enemies
of man."
Whoa, what a scary bunch.
Billy Batson!
I've been expecting you.
You? That old man
I gave the food to.
That woman I helped
to cross the street.
And that guy I returned
his money to.
- They were all you.
- Yes.
I did that to test you, Billy.
Test me? Test me for what?
To see if you're worthy
of great power.
And you are, Billy.
Never have I seen
a heart so pure.
The world is a dangerous place.
It needs heroes.
Heroes like you.
All you need to do
is say my name.
Your name?
Shazam!
Sha... zam?
No, no, no.
You can't just say it timidly.
Otherwise, how would you
ever introduce yourself to people?
That'd be ridiculous.
Say it with meaning,
with purpose.
Shazam!
After getting the power
of Shazam, I went to work,
helping the city
as best I could.
It was awesome.
Not just because I had
these incredible powers
but, you know,
because I was a grownup.
Sorry, kid.
Maybe next time.
Next.
- Whoa!
- One, please.
But even with
all that power,
it didn't really matter.
I just wanted to belong.
To not be alone.
You wouldn't understand.
You're the Batman.
You've got friends, a family.
But being a kid,
an orphan,
it's the worst.
I totally understand if you
don't want to work with me,
now that you know.
Uh... I'm sorry.
I know this is supposed to be,
like, an important moment,
but I don't really
recognize you.
Maybe in your adult form?
I'm Bruce Wayne.
Bruce Wayne?
Like, the Bruce Wayne?
Billionaire Bruce Wayne?
The Bruce Wayne with all those
super expensive sports cars?
The Bruce Wayne with the private
jet that has its own arcade in it?
Holy moly! What's that like?
It's okay. I mean,
I only have, like,
500 games onboard.
No big whoop.
Awesome!
Listen, Billy,
when I was a kid about your age,
I lost my parents, too.
So I know what it is
to be alone.
I took that fear and loneliness and
decided to do something good with it.
Just like you're doing.
Be proud of who you are, Billy.
Kids can be heroes too.
My three former Robins
are a testament to that.
What you did? That's brave.
Showing me really who you are?
That's trust.
I don't know what the others would say,
but you're all right with me.
Now, back to business.
We have to figure out why the
Justice League is gathering all that food,
and how to stop that telepathic tyrant,
Mr. Mind.
Speaking of food, I'm starving.
Ooh, me too.
Hey, wanna see something cool?
Alfred, can I get two glasses
of milk and cookies?
And not the oatmeal kind.
Maybe... Ooh, something
with chocolate chips in it?
As you wish, Master Damian.
Uh, Damian? I'm...
Oh, oh, yes.
- Faster, old man.
- Old man...
- You have your own butler?
- Not bad, right?
He'll make me whatever I want.
Unless I make him mad,
which happens more than...
Wait a minute. That's it!
Mr. Mind said that
in order to control us,
he had to make sure our minds
were young and impressionable.
But that also means
he has limits.
And if I'm right,
which I always am,
the more active the brains
of our friends are,
the more difficult they are
to control.
So we have to make them
angry or stressed.
- And that will break his hold on them.
- Exactly.
Once the hold is broken, we toss one of
these disrupters onto them, and presto!
No more mind control.
- Got it.
- And, Shazam?
Good luck.
The most powerful ring
in the galaxy,
and here I am trolling
the ocean for stinky fish?
Ugh.
Say,
that ring is pretty cool.
Oh, hey. Yeah. It can
make anything I can think of.
- Really?
- Really.
Even... I don't know,
a boat?
Please.
Wow. What about a whale?
Like I told you,
anything.
Not bad.
So you can make anything?
A jet?
Two jets?
What about a dog piloting
a jet while drinking a shake
and wearing sunglasses
while wearing a large hat?
And barking out the ABCs.
Yeah. All right.
Oh, also a knight
in shining armor
with a sword, riding a bicycle,
handcuffed to a T-Rex,
- standing behind a pony...
- Slow down.
...on top
of an armored car.
Oh, and can you get
a sports car in there, too?
Anything... else?
Just this.
One down.
Mmm, prime rib.
Mr. Mind is totes
gonna love this.
Ah, Wonder Woman, I see you're
still flying that invisible clunker.
Clunker? Why, you...
My mom gave me this jet!
It can run circles
around your rodent mobile!
No. No, it can't.
- Can, too.
- Cannot.
- Can, too!
- Prove it, then.
First one to the end
of the canyon wins.
You're on!
Looks like there's room
for only one of us, hotshot.
Ha! That did it.
Huh?
No way!
I totally would have won if I'd
had a more aerodynamic cow.
You never did like to lose.
Argh! Just wait
till I get my hands on you.
Now, now, Wonder Woman,
no one likes a sore loser.
Two down.
Whoo-hoo!
Pardon me.
Flash coming through.
Wow. That's quite
a pile of food you have there.
- Yeah, so?
- Well, I mean, uh,
how are you gonna get it
all to your master?
I'll just run it over
to him, duh.
Oh, just, uh,
one by one, then?
Mm-hm.
Huh.
I just thought
because you're so fast,
you could do something a bit,
I don't know, flashier?
- Hey, I can be flashy.
- Oh, I'm sure you can.
Superman said he could do it faster, but,
I mean, you know, what does he know, right?
Superman said that?
Ooh. After all the times
I beat him in a race...
Whatevs. I'll show him.
- You better step back.
- Oh. Sure.
Ha-ha! See? Nothing to it.
Hmm.
Is that the best you can do?
No.
Watch this.
Where am I?
Mmm, nice.
Master's gonna love
this Kent Farm's corn.
Superman, save me.
Oh, hi, Clark.
Well, I'll be a tadpole
on a lily pad.
What are you doing here?
I've come to help you.
Help me? I'm Superman.
You're the one
that's gonna need help.
Somebody needs a nap.
You know
I have X-ray vision, right?
Who's the hide-and-seek
champ now?
More like chump.
A Boy Scout like you
is no real threat
to an awesome superhero
like Batman.
I hear a lot
of gums flappin'...
but not a lot of wind.
You may have muscles, Clarky,
but when it comes to
strategy or planning, you...
You're just lucky
I'm pulling my punches.
Ooh,
I'm shaking in my Bat Boots.
You're not even wearing
any boots.
Ah!
You got any more insults
now, dingbat?
Just one.
I liked you better when
you wore your underwear...
on the outside.
Huh?
Oh, boy.
I'm glad to see everyone
back to normal.
Well, relatively.
Can we, like,
get this over with
so I go back to being an adult?
Being a kid is the worst.
Huh. I haven't really noticed
a difference at all.
That's because you've always
been a kid.
But I'm dying. The mood swings,
the hunger pains.
How can you even
trust kids at all?
All these hormones,
no life experience.
I feel like I'm going to cry
at any given moment.
Hey, being a kid
isn't that bad.
Kids, back to business.
What we know,
Mr. Mind has been hoarding a massive
amount of food here at this warehouse.
The League will take myself and Shazam as
pretend prisoners in order to get into the base.
Once we are in his inner sanctum,
we'll use these mental dampeners
to protect us from
Mr. Mind's control,
and stop this Monster
Society of Evil once and for all.
That door does open, you know.
No food?
Why did you come back
empty-handed?
We brought something better
than food, Jeepers.
We brought prisoners.
That's right. Batman is here.
You better take me
to Mr. Mind right now.
Please.
We don't take orders from you.
No one can see the master
right now.
Children, leave the prisoners
and continue gathering food.
Uh, Batman, what's plan B?
Well, what are you waiting for?
Batman?
Uh, sorry. At this age,
I wasn't all that good at thinking ahead.
Creatures, get them!
Jig's up. Attack, now!
Excuse me.
For a doll,
why'd you have to be
such a...
you know, Dummy?
Let go, imposter!
Imposter?
I called this name first.
Kryptonian, I've defeated
your kind before.
You're no match for Oom.
This would be beneath
adult Superman.
Me? Not so much.
Come on, it's not funny.
I didn't want to leave
the swamp, you know?
But he didn't care.
No one understands me.
It's over, Sivana.
I hope so.
I'm tired of being
mind-controlled. We all are.
All I want to do is go home and work
on my own plans for world domination.
Great! I mean, good.
Not good. It's...
It's good that you wanna stop,
but not...
- Where is Mr. Mind?
- He's there.
What do you think
we'll find in there?
Whatever it is,
we'll face it together.
By Hades' heatstroke,
what is that?
It appears to be
some sort of chry-sal-lis.
Everyone knows
it's pronounced chrysalis.
Can we just call it a cocoon?
Well, whatever we're
calling it, what's it for?
For Mr. Mind.
Uh, guys, I think
we need to get out of here.
Now!
Seconded.
We're gonna need
some serious moth balls.
We can do this, team.
Let's get him.
Fools!
You have served your purpose.
You gathered the sustenance I
needed to complete my transformation.
Now nothing on Earth
can stop me from ruling
over you small-minded mortals.
Nothing on Earth?
That's it.
Follow me!
You won't get away
from me that easily, Junior League.
Whatever it is you're hoping
to do, Shazam, do it fast.
Follow them.
He's coming!
Hold on!
Oh, this ride better end quick.
Is this supposed to slow down?
Uh, yeah?
The Wizard who gave me
my powers lives here.
He'll know what to do.
Come on.
Do you see
the power of eternity?
Yes. The power,
I must have it.
Wizard. Wizard!
What? Huh?
Oh, Billy!
It's good to see you.
- "Billy"?
- Uh...
I said...
"Silly." Silly Shazam.
So good of you to come.
And you brought
some young friends
to trick or treat
at the Rock of Eternity.
Lovely costumes.
The star on that tiara
really draws your eyes
away from your face.
Told you guys.
I think I have some candy corn
in the back.
- Wizard...
- Mm, but that was 100 years ago.
Uh, Wizard?
Does candy corn go bad?
Ugh. No. Wizard,
this is the Justice League.
They've been transformed
by a malevolent worm
that just transformed
into a giant moth
who is floating around outside
waiting to destroy us!
A giant moth?
I... hate... moths.
This building, it tastes...
It tastes like eternity.
Yes. More. More!
The power,
it's intoxicating!
What is happening?
That giant moth is
feeding off the Rock of Eternity.
This place is the nexus
of limitless magical power!
If he eats much more,
he may be unstoppable.
Not to mention...
Oh, no!
What is it?
Hurry! The more
the rock is destroyed,
the more it weakens
the defenses of the building.
Shazam,
if what is inside
this prison is released,
an unspeakable terror
will be unleashed upon us all.
You must use the power of Zeus,
and together,
you can defeat this evil.
The power of Zeus?
But I don't know what that is!
You must completely trust them.
You have to be willing to let
them see you as you really are.
Yes. Yes, that's great.
But can you just
be more specific...
Free! Free!
By Poseidon's pits,
who is that?
I am Black Adam.
Earth's mightiest mortal.
Holy moly.
The power of eternity,
it is mine!
Ah.
My unwitting pawn.
You? The voice.
The voice inside my head.
But how?
Centuries of isolation
strengthens the mind.
I just needed
to harness my powers,
and use the Rock of Eternity
as an antenna
to find a weak-minded being
that would be open
to suggestion.
Weak mind?
I'm Mr. Mind.
And now, I'm all-powerful.
Let me show you power, worm!
Shazam!
Oh, dear.
Oh, no.
Oh, this doesn't look good
at all. Huh?
Shazam!
His costume,
he looks just like you.
Who is he?
The Wizard's first champion.
Evidently, he went crazy
and took over the world.
We're in trouble.
Oh, must go faster.
Must go... Oh!
Hello.
Perhaps we could come
to some sort of arrang...
Heh.
Wizard.
It is time we finish this.
If you want the Wizard,
you'll have to get through me!
You'll have to get
through all of us.
Sorry, kids,
you need to be
this high to fight me.
Aw, man!
He's joking, Flash.
Oh! I knew that.
What I'm not joking about
is your doom!
Hyah!
- Whoa! Hey, let go of me. I'm Batman.
- Hey, hands off!
Yeah. Hey, not the cape. This is silly.
Whoa!
Leave my friends alone!
You.
So, the Wizard found
a new errand boy.
Come. Come show me
what you have.
You amateur,
you're making this too easy.
Ha-ha.
Pathetic.
You're not capable
of wielding the power
that that suit represents.
You're nothing but a boy.
Say good night
forever.
Stop!
This is between us, Adam.
Leave the boy alone.
Fine.
Whoa!
Got him.
Thanks, Wonder Woman.
All right, League,
it's time to stop this madman
once and for all.
But how?
He's more powerful than we are,
especially as kids.
We have to try.
We can't leave the Wizard
to face him alone.
Agreed! Come on, guys!
It's some kind of energy field.
Wizard!
Billy, you mustn't interfere.
I will hold Black Adam off
as long as I can.
I've created a portal
back to Earth.
Go! Now!
I'm not leaving you.
Never mind about me.
Black Adam is too dangerous
for you and the others
to face right now.
But what about you?
You must go now.
If I don't stop him,
you will be
the last line of defense.
Remember, the power of Zeus.
Wizard!
Your time
is finally up, Wizard.
No!
I'm coming for you, Shazam!
- Oh, no.
- No, no, no, no.
I'm coming for all of you!
Let's go home.
I've got a plan.
When I was first turned
into a child,
I found our vehicles
were ineffective
because of our height.
In fact, Shazam had to drive
the Batmobile.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You got to drive the Batmobile?
- Oh, sweet!
- Are you kidding me?
Yeah, it's definitely
stick shift.
For our
vehicles to be effective,
they need to be our size.
It's time to build
something new.
Well,
butter my bricks and call me a biscuit!
These look amazing!
The trouble alert.
Lois Lane reporting live
from the League of Nations
building in Metropolis,
where a man has appeared
floating down through the air.
He is hovering
toward the main assembly now.
Maybe there's
a new hero in town.
No. Not a hero.
Definitely not a hero.
Black Adam is here.
And I thought I was fast.
Sheesh.
What now?
Now we do
what we were born to do.
We save the day.
Nothing on Earth
can stop this party. Whoo!
Bad feeling about this.
Maybe he's here
to install the disco light.
Excuse me. You can't
just barge in here
and ruin our party...
Party over.
People of...
Sorry.
People of Earth,
I, Black Adam,
am your rightful ruler.
You will obey me
without question.
Those who don't will be
crushed beneath my...
Feet?
What?
Who dares?
The Justice League,
that's who!
Execute plan Playtime.
Foolish children.
Your games won't stop me.
You must think
you're pretty slick.
What?
Need help getting cleaned up?
How about this spin cycle?
Tag! You're it.
Batter up!
All right, Flash,
let's wrap this up.
What kind of games
are these, children?
The kind you'll lose.
Now, Princess!
Huh. Enough!
Not quite.
Every game should end
with a little fireworks.
- Did we do it?
- We must have.
He is flatter than a flapjack
on the griddle.
Hah!
Kneel before me.
Kneel before
the great Black Adam.
What?
Say, leave the kid alone!
You are a horrible human being.
Pick on somebody your own size.
Get out of here!
Stop it!
- Leave us alone!
- I am Black Adam.
We know.
I am all-powerful!
We'd never bow
to the likes of you.
Coward!
What now? We need,
like, three more Shazams
to even put a dent in that guy.
Three more?
Shazam!
Remember, the power of Zeus.
The power of Zeus!
Guys, I know what I have to do.
But, to do it,
I have to show you
who I really am.
Remember, Shazam,
the only way to trust someone
is to trust them.
This might tickle.
Shazam!
This is amazing!
We're adults again.
I feel...
More powerful
than a locomotive.
Way more powerful.
Hi.
I'm Billy Batson.
You're a...
Kid.
Now you know
why I didn't want to tell you.
I didn't want you
to think less of me.
Billy, being a hero
isn't about your age
or having flashy superpowers.
Part of being a hero
is trying to make the world
a better place,
no matter what age you are.
Yeah. That
and an awesome costume.
By the way,
why didn't my costume change?
You've already got
a lightning bolt.
Billy, you're going to make
one incredible member
of the Justice League.
Ha-ha!
Sentimental fools!
Even by using
the power of Zeus,
you will not defeat me.
I am Black Adam!
As my ma used to say,
"There's nothing worse than a
rooster that hollers before sunrise."
Well, Terrance,
your mother and I
are both school teachers,
so I hope you like
studying every day.
Oh, and we almost never eat at
those fun fast-food burger places.
Your father makes
wonderful salads.
And, we have a rule.
No more than 20 minutes
of TV a day.
You're safe here, folks.
And remember,
there's no better insurance
than a safe driver.
Billy?
Billy! You have to help me.
Hey, Terrance, what's up?
My new family...
I have to do homework,
eat my vegetables.
There's even a time limit on how
much I can watch TV.
Maybe we should get out
of the city right now.
Let's go to your mom's.
Terrance can help her
clean up the basement
and organize
her coin collection.
You're gonna love it, buddy.
No!
I'm really happy
for you, Terrance!
Whoo-hoo!
Pardon me.
Hyah!
Shazam!
We're back!
Oh, man,
if I had to hear one more
of Superman's farm sayings,
I might have quit the League.
Oh, that's for sure.
- You can say that again.
- Yeah.
- It was awful.
- Yes, I couldn't agree more.
They're not that bad.
What did you do?
No.
No!
The powers are mine!
Shazam!
Shazam.
Looks like I might've
hijacked your magic.
Sorry, not sorry.
I'll get you, Shazam.
Once I have my powers back,
you will be destr-
Destroyed!
Well, Shazam, you did it.
No, we did it.
But how did you know the lightning
would take away his powers?
Or change us back to adults?
Well,
let's just say...
I had a hunch.
Hmm.
So, now that we beat
the bad guy
and everything
is back to normal,
how should we celebrate?
I know just the thing.
Remember how I told you
that Bat Computer could find
anyone anywhere?
After you revealed
your identity to me,
I had it search for any living
relatives you might have.
You have two.
Your uncle and...
Billy?
My sister.
Billy!
I'm Mary.
And this is our Uncle Dudley.
Hello, Billy.
That's what I'd call
a happy ending.
I'm okay.
All I have to do
is find that Salvaxion warlord,
and I'll be knee-deep
in targman moolah
from now until next week.
What is this?
Let go!
Well, what do we have here?
What's your name, little fella?
Mind, Mr. Mind.
The greatest villain
in the galaxy.
Wanted in over three quadrants
of the universe for my evil evilness.
"Wanted," eh?
This day just keeps
getting better.
Huh?
Oh, my.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org