Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Stop being a baby.
It wasn't that heavy.
You're breathing harder than I am.
I'm just faking it.
To make you feel better.
I'm just dropping it.
- I forgot something.
- What?
It's for my hypertension.
Whoa. What's that?
Amlodipine.
What do you take for your arthritis?
- Ibuprofen.
- I'm taking Fosamax.
And I haven't noticed
any real improvement.
I'll tell you something.
I'll tell you
what's a real revelation. Diclofenac.
- For your sciatica.
- My sciatica. I highly recommend it.
Now, tell me.
What do you take for your cholesterol?
- Crestor.
- I told you! Take Lipitor!
Mine was sky-rocketing
and it came right down.
You don't remember me telling you?
- No.
- I'm telling you again. Try Lipitor.
Or get a new doctor.
And while you're at it,
get yourself some Exelon.
Now, what the hell is that for?
Your memory.
You're questioning my memory?
Don't ever question my memory.
So, your daughter and your granddaughter
are gonna sleep here?
In theory, yeah.
The two of them together?
It's not the Ritz,
but it is a spare bedroom
and the only one I got.
Well, wouldn't it be more appropriate
if your son-in-law were to leave?
- I mean, after all...
- After all, he behaved very poorly.
And they have newspaper people
all over his house,
which they should have,
to find out what he really did.
So I thought the girls would
have a little more privacy here.
And what about you?
What about your peace?
True. However, it gives me
a chance to be with my girls.
Hmm.
And what about these girls, hm?
I mean, you know,
it's kind of sad to chuck 'em.
I mean, they're such classics.
Oh, I can never let
my girls know about my girls.
No. What are you doing?
Take one, for Christ's sake.
Be a man. Grow up.
You mean you haven't dicked around
since you've been divorced?
I'm afraid those days are over for me.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Nexium.
It's good for my stomach.
All right, buddy. I got a family
waiting for a portrait.
The old "in the cellar" extra buck.
Love it.
You bet.
Tell me when the girls arrive.
- I'll stop by for a visit.
- You got it.
Later.
Prostitutes paid
with taxpayers' money?
Let's go live to the press conference
with California's
Lieutenant Governor, David Addison.
I am deeply sorry
that I did not live up
to what was expected of me,
and I must take full responsibility
for my misconduct.
I am therefore resigning
as Lieutenant Governor.
I now want to devote all my time
toward earning back
the trust of my family.
Words cannot express
how sorry I feel for the terrible hurt
that I have caused them
and how blessed I am
that they have found it
in their hearts to forgive me.
Thank you very much.
How many prostitutes
have you slept with?
Did your wife
find naked pics in your phone?
What message
are you sending young women?
How long have we worked together?
Eight, ten years?
Twelve.
This man taught me everything I know.
Come over here.
His reviews were
a major cultural reference.
It's a pleasure.
But the industry's changing, Claude.
I mean, with a constant stream
of multi-platform readership,
our consumers are now more interested
than ever in what's happening.
They're "woke," as they say.
I really don't want to take advantage
of the special relationship
that you have with this newspaper,
but I really can't look the other way
as far as your family is...
Stop.
Don't go there.
Okay. I'll tell you what.
Why don't we turn this around
in your favor, huh?
You enlighten us on the situation
of your son-in-law, more or less,
so then you can call the shots before
any of those sleazy gossipmongers.
So we keep the focus on him,
instead of on your daughter and family,
who are already weathering
a pretty nasty storm.
I can guarantee fair treatment
and no mention whatsoever
of intimate family issues.
You can trust me on that, really.
What about the article I sent you?
Oh, the one on Pina Bausch?
Heiner Muller.
Oh, Heiner Mueller.
- Muller. East German.
- Yes.
Modernist playwright.
Known all over the world.
Oh, right. Mark?
Uh, we found it super interesting,
like everything you send us.
A little bit difficult
to put into the print edition,
but it might be perfect for our brand-new
cultural digital supplement.
What the hell is he talking about?
It's our online edition.
It allows us to print
ancillary cultural news.
- We even have an app.
- Take a look.
Yeah.
Wait a sec.
- Can you bring that one back down?
- Yeah, sure.
It sounds like this is something
you're interested in?
Well, Henry Muller was
an important figure in European culture.
I'm sure we can find a way
to fit him into the front page
of the digital edition.
That is, of course,
if we all do our part, huh?
- Of course.
- Send me the article, please.
- Sure.
Jesus Christ!
I really loved you.
Still do.
We also have
an impressive recreational room
with light exercise equipment.
We also have activities...
Now, our dining room serves
three well-balanced delicious meals.
Everything is freshly made here.
And right this way,
I'll take you out to our gardens.
Now, of course,
this is our outpatient facility,
which is separate
from the rest of the facilities.
It's so beautiful.
And you'll notice
that is very intimate, very secure.
I love this garden.
Mrs. Blanche, it's this way.
Sir? You all right?
- Huh?
- Are you all right? Are you lost?
No.
Would you like me
to take you back to your room?
No. I can find my room.
Oh, I'm so sorry. I'm new here,
so I still don't know everybody yet.
I'm working on it.
I am new here.
I'm Zephyr.
So I'll be here. Just let me know
if you need anything, okay?
All right. I'll see you around.
Are you out of your mind?
You'll get caught!
If you don't kill yourself first.
These places can be very depressing.
It's a very nice place.
And I can think of absolutely nothing
that I want to do more
than be next to her.
She needs me.
She may not even remember you,
for Christ's sake.
Alzheimer's? No memory.
- Really?
- Hmm.
She'll remember me. Trust me.
What makes you so sure?
Because what she and I
shared together and lived together
can never be forgotten.
Oh.
Yeah. Yeah.
There was this girl in Ronda.
That's a little place in southern Spain
where the family used
to go for a summer vacation.
She was petite. A little cross-eyed.
- Hmm.
- But she had a gorgeous smile.
And, oh, the most contagious laugh.
Incredible.
But, of course, you know,
I had to go back to the States.
But we promised we'd write to one another
and we did, we did for a time, but...
I lost contact.
Never even kissed her.
So you do understand me?
A little. Hmm.
Is she now...
available?
What about her husband?
Dead.
You're the only person on this planet
who would willingly
check himself in to an old folks' home.
- Yeah?
- Hey, Dad.
Sorry I didn't call sooner
but, with all the new allegations
and talking to Tania
about everything, it's been a lot.
- Well, how is she doing?
- She's pretty upset.
And you? I know you're mad at me.
I don't know how many times
I have to say this.
You're making a colossal mistake.
I don't know what promises
this asshole has given you
or how he did it,
but he's a son of a bitch, he's ignorant,
and whatever he's up to doesn't hold water
and in the future, you're gonna
find out very quickly, madam.
Yeah, well, you always told me
that I should take my chances,
so that's what I'm gonna do.
Any time you and Tania get bored
with all the crap
that's going on at your house,
I got two beds upstairs
in my spare room waiting for you.
Thanks, Daddy.
It's not gonna come to that.
Well, it'll be okay 'cause you called.
And that's the best thing
that happened today.
But also I have something to tell you.
- Really? What?
- Well...
I'm going on a trip with Shane.
- No.
- Really? Where?
Well, we're just doing
some Golden Years traveling, that's all.
Maybe Spain. Maybe winging it.
I don't really know what he thinks
going on a trip like this is.
Wait. What do you mean "winging it"?
Well, you know, what old people do.
We're old people. Um...
Having a good time.
Not caring about
keeping in touch
with folks or anything else.
Dad, are you okay?
I'm okay. My stew is burning.
- I got to go.
- Okay.
Something wrong?
It's Dad. He says he and Shane
are going on a trip.
To Spain. Winging it.
Winging it?
Yeah, that's what he said.
Until they get tired.
So what's the problem?
Well, they're old.
Who's gonna take care of 'em?
Oh, Selma!
Grandpa's a grown-up
who can look after himself.
- Yeah.
- And he's going with Shane,
who's, like, the responsible one.
I can totally see those two hooligans
scouring Spain for Spanish widows.
- Um...
- Not everyone is like you, Dad.
Please, just don't misinterpret my words.
- It's not what I meant.
- Are you gonna say something?
- Honey, it was a joke.
- A joke.
- It was a joke, Tania.
- A joke. Yeah. Okay.
It was a joke!
- It was just a joke.
- Yeah.
- Look.
- What?
- Is that...
- Yes, sir. That's her.
There's no cure, is there?
Not for either of us, but for her,
there's a chance to slow it down.
But microscopically or through
all kind of scans and everything,
you can't detect it.
You can only detect it after you're dead.
The only way they can really diagnose it
is through behavioral patterns.
What's so beautiful about that, you moron?
What are you talking about?
They won't catch me!
Oh, beyond brain circuits
and neuron connections, huh?
You don't wanna do it?
You don't wanna help me?
I'll tell you what to do it for.
Do it for your cross-eyed girlfriend.
Do it for every goddamn girl
that never accepted any plea from us.
Don't push it, buddy.
You got me to be your alibi for Selma
and that's all you're getting from me.
Now, don't tell me there's more.
You just got an Uber license!
An Uber driver?
- How do you know it's gonna work?
- I don't. It's a chance.
I'm taking a chance.
Something you ought
to think about doing more often.
And you also have to remember
that I don't remember
a goddamn thing, okay?
But I need them
to put me in the dementia unit...
Yeah, I'm your neighbor and friend.
I tried to get in touch
with your family, but no luck,
so I decided to pay for your care
myself until I can reach them.
Bingo!
Well, I doubt you'll be playing bingo
in the dementia unit.
Oh, don't be such an asshole.
I already put the money
in your account. Here's your receipt.
- Ah...
- No, wait a second.
You make lists about every goddamn thing.
So I know you would worry about a receipt.
I also have the GP report here.
How did you get that?
A little thing called acting.
Yeah. I forgot you were
in the drama business.
Well, it's the first time
I'm gonna be on the other side.
Do you think they're gonna
put me in the slammer
for assisting an insane person?
I'm not insane.
I've got Alzheimer's.
Give me a break.
I will get in the home.
They will accept me in the home
because we're paying.
And paying works.
I can imagine this has been
a very painful decision for you.
Oh, you can't imagine
how painful it is for me.
His memory loss has been significant?
Yes. Particularly since
his wife died two years ago.
He's deteriorated fast.
We're talking... downward spiral.
I'm so sorry to hear
about your wife, Mr. Berenson.
Oh, here's the GP report.
This is a bank transfer receipt from...
Oh! Uh...
- Sorry.
- Housekeeping.
Do you have the neurological test results?
I'm afraid not. The tests were
scheduled for two months from now.
But he can't afford to wait that long.
He can't sit at home pissing
and shitting his pants the whole time.
Hm-hm.
And does he recognize people?
Well, he recognizes me
because I'm his next-door neighbor
and I see him every day.
But I guess
he doesn't recognize anyone else.
And what are his hobbies?
What does he like to do?
He likes to drink a lot.
- Anything else?
- Play chess.
He plays chess?
But I always beat him
'cause he thinks he's playing checkers.
Sometimes I suck my thumb.
Yeah, he also has
some kind of childhood regression.
Totally immature.
Mr. Berenson, where do you live?
I live at, um...
one, six, zero, zero...
Uh...
Pennsyl... Pennsylvania Avenue.
Washington, DC.
And I can't remember
the numbers after that.
That's the White House.
Why would you, suddenly,
wanna go to the White House?
Let me explain
our community to you, Mr. McDowell.
We have three units
distributed on two different floors.
The general unit and the dementia unit
are both on the ground floor.
Patients with Alzheimer's
and other non-aggressive dementia
are on the second floor.
Claude, for the time being,
he'll be in our general unit.
Uh, no.
He really needs to be
in the dementia unit, not the general one.
I mean, he's ill. He's very ill.
He babbles incoherently
and shits his pants the whole time.
Babbles, shits, babbles, shits,
babbles, shits.
That's all he does.
- Can I speak now?
- Yeah.
I'd like to have Alzheimer's.
Why?
Wanna play a game?
- Yes.
- Okay.
If I show you my wiener,
you got to take your pants off.
Okay.
You nodded at first. She wanted to do it.
I'll leave you to unpack.
A nurse will be coming in a minute
to help you settle in.
Anything you need,
don't hesitate to get in touch with me.
- Thank you.
- Okay.
What the heck are you doing?
Richard Burton, Peter O'Toole
had this stuff in their dressing rooms
every day of their life.
Maybe it's time to forget all this.
Go home.
Oh, sure, I get it.
Claude, please, listen to me.
I appreciate your nobleness, but I'm fine.
It's not Guantanamo. I can do it.
You got your pills?
- Your cellphone?
- Yeah, I got my cell.
Anything you need, just call.
Hm? And break a leg.
How about a hip?
Oh.
Here are your little blue pills.
- For what?
- Take them.
If opportunity knocks,
you'll want to rise to the occasion.
And inspirational cat posters
sure ain't gonna do the trick.
You and me?
Not gonna happen.
Now take a good look
at these four items on the screen.
Good morning, everyone.
I'd like to introduce
our newest resident, Mr. Claude Berenson.
Hi, Claude. I'm Alicia.
You can have a seat right there.
- There?
- No, in front.
Right.
So, Claude, we were just looking
at these four objects on the screen.
Did everyone get a good look?
Now, let's turn this off.
There we go.
How are we supposed
to remember them if we can't see them?
That's the whole point of the game.
It's a memory game.
So, Sarah, can you tell me
what object you saw on the screen?
A tennis racket.
- A bottle.
- Yeah.
Um...
- A TV set.
- Very good.
Claude.
Hm?
Do you remember
what the fourth object was?
Jell-O.
No, it wasn't Jell-O.
A clown
with a Richard Nixon false face on.
No.
Any other idea?
Yeah. A comb.
Very good, Claude. It was a comb!
You okay, Lillian?
Yes.
Can you pass me the salt?
One, two.
You're having way too much salt.
Hm-hm.
Mine.
This salt is mine.
Can you pass me the salt?
What, are you a record?
How are we doing here, hm?
Everything good?
He's had a third of the salt shaker.
Tom! You're not supposed to have the salt.
It doesn't work with your heart condition.
Heartbeat, heartbeat.
Not for long.
Everything okay, otherwise? Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Good.
"Good, my Lord.
I have remembrances for you."
"The fair Ophelia!
Nymph in thy orisons.
"Be all my sins remembered."
"How does your honor for this many a day?"
That was really good. Really, really good.
Lucy, I think we actually dropped a line.
It's like he had no idea I even existed
before this whole thing
with my douchebag dad.
That's because he didn't.
- Thanks.
- I'm just being honest.
You're not in his little theater gang.
I could be.
What are you gonna do?
Suddenly be the lead
in the school play with all of them?
Why is that so hard to imagine?
Oh, just face it. You and I have
been dorks since we were kids.
We're not popular. We're not losers.
We're just in the middle.
Yeah, well, maybe I'm sick
of being average.
Well, your parents' televised scandal
is certainly taking care of that.
She's a spy.
Don sent that bitch
to make sure I don't talk to anybody
about how he got that rezoning.
- She's not a real nurse, you know.
- Who?
Her!
Zephyr. But I won't be signing
that affidavit.
How are you doing, Miss Lillian?
Do you happen to know
what a breath mint is?
Hi.
Might I sit?
I'm Claude.
You don't remember me?
Claude Berenson.
I'm a theater critic.
I reviewed so many
of your fabulous performances.
I saw your Medea. That was magnificent.
Pure. Honest.
Your Blanche DuBois,
certainly the best I ever saw.
A lot of people think
it's the greatest Blanche
that anybody ever played.
Lily, it's me.
Claude.
See?
Are they your children?
No, that's you and me.
In 1978.
Shakespeare. Winter's Tale.
At the Palace Theater. In New York!
You don't remember that?
You remember who took the picture?
Sir John Gielgud was kind enough.
And then he invited
the whole cast to dinner.
You and I started talking.
And we really kind of
got into a conversation deep,
kind of started getting into each other
and, suddenly, we noticed
we were all by ourselves.
Everybody had gone home.
And then you and I went
to the Park Central Hotel
and we stayed all night.
We spent every night together.
Every night for weeks and weeks.
You don't remember that?
Yeah, it's me.
Oh, please, keep looking at me.
No, I'm the same guy.
I haven't changed.
I'm a little grumpier and more
of an asshole than I was before probably.
But I still have all the same passion.
And I care about you, Lily, still.
Hello.
I'm Claude. I have Alzheimer's.
Do you two know each other?
I don't remember things very well.
- Shane.
- Haven't you killed yourself?
Get over that, will you, please?
I have not killed myself.
- But I do need a couple of things.
- Okay.
- Get a pen.
Write it down. I need some lilies
and I need two Gershwin CDs.
Well, why? Why?
Because that's
her favorite music, okay?
Gershwin. Two of those CDs
and six bunches of flowers.
Does she remember you?
No, she doesn't remember me yet,
but I'm getting there.
I got to go.
Mr. Berenson, it's shower time.
What's a shower?
Claude, let's not play this game.
All right, get back there.
Get around the front.
I can do this.
I don't mind, sir. It's my job.
Come on, it's not your job. It's my job.
No, it's no trouble at all.
Just give me the brush.
- Okay.
- Out.
- All right.
- O-U-T means out.
I'll be back to check on you
in five minutes, sir.
Oh, my darling
Oh, my darling, Clementine
You were lost and gone forever
Dreaded sorrow, Clementine
Oh, my darling
Oh, my darling, Clementine
You were lost and gone forever
Precious darling, Clementine
You all sang so beautifully!
And, you, Donahue, you played marvelously.
Thank you!
And remember, next week,
there will be a magician coming!
I love magicians. They're so magical!
Wow, Lillian!
- Oh.
- These are so beautiful.
- What's that?
- They're lilies.
Peter really outdid himself.
Lily Blanche.
It's for me.
Is it a note?
A CD. I'll play this.
"Doubt thou the stars are fire."
Embrace me
My sweet embraceable you
You irreplaceable you
Just one look at you
My heart grew tipsy in me
You and you alone
Bring out the gypsy in me
I love all the many charms about you...
Are these your children?
Lily, no. They're, um...
They look happy.
They are.
They were.
They still can be.
They never really had
a lot of time together
because he was only near her
when her shows would come to New York.
And every night, they would stay together,
and he would take her
to the jazz clubs in the Village,
he would take her to nice restaurants.
She liked to go up to
the tall buildings, the skyscrapers.
And one night, they went to a club.
And the band leader knew him.
And all of a sudden,
they started playing
her favorite Gershwin song.
"Embraceable You."
And she was ecstatic.
And then she went back
to be with her husband.
Every now and then,
he would just... Couldn't stand the fact
that he couldn't see her,
be with her, touch her.
One day, he summoned up enough courage
to ask her to run away with him.
And she wasn't surprised.
She wasn't surprised.
It was almost as if she expected it.
She said, "Give me some time.
"I have to go and explain to my husband.
I can't just tell him."
And then, she stopped writing.
Stopped taking his calls.
And he...
flew over to Paris
to see her.
To try to see her.
And so finally
he just threw in the towel.
He met another woman.
Another woman?
Yeah.
Just moved on.
Then, one day, came a letter.
And in the letter,
the key phrase was, "Doubt thou
"the stars are fire."
Shakespeare's most beautiful words.
Soon after that, the only stuff
he ever heard about her anymore
was what he read in the newspaper.
They seem happy.
Embrace me, you irreplaceable you
You, too, Rosie?
I cannot shake this damn song.
She can't stop playing it
in her room.
You're not getting paid to sing. Go. Work.
- Thank you. Bye.
- Don't be a naughty baby.
Are you sure you wanna do this?
What choice do I have?
It's either this or kill myself.
Why don't you just give it a minute?
The scandal will die down
and everyone at school will forget it.
I'm not waiting for this to blow over.
What am I supposed
to say when your parents call me?
Tell them what I told you.
I took a bus to New York.
I don't want you to go.
I'll be fine.
This place. Okay?
Yeah, it's better than okay. I like it.
It's much better than I thought.
Everybody's kind of...
There's no egos around.
And everybody's...
kind of laid back and calm.
- It makes me feel young.
- Hm.
They don't get on your nerves?
No.
Actually, it's the opposite.
We have kind of a...
I don't know, a camaraderie.
And it's kind of touching, actually.
Well, I guess you're all in the same boat.
We're certainly all in the same diapers.
Miss the family?
Not really.
I mean, I haven't heard from them
since I've been in so-called Spain.
You remember one day,
well, you were there several days,
when my daughter yells out at me,
"Don't forget, Daddy,
to carry your cellphone with you
"in case I need you."
Didn't mean shit. She never called.
Did you bring me something?
Yeah. Booze.
And some seasonings and spices.
You know, the food here sucks.
They make us eat a soup every day.
Tastes like the back of a stamp.
Well, that's what you get
for being a masochist.
So, any progress with Lillian?
Is she still not remembering
your resistible charms?
Not yet.
I'm working on her hard.
It is harder than I thought,
but we're getting more time together
and there is still a chemistry, trust me.
Is she here?
It's so good to see you
looking so much happier.
- Who's the fella?
- Her brother.
I love you.
- Oh. They must be close.
- Hmm.
- Well, yes.
- Hi, Peter.
How did you find her today?
A little more cheerful
than usual, actually.
Isn't she? It must be the flowers
you've been sending her.
Flowers? What flowers?
The lilies. That isn't you?
- Maybe your wife has a secret admirer.
- Well, she has plenty of fans.
Some of them even write
to our home address.
Those awful tabloid newspapers
are to blame.
- Well, I'll see you next week.
- Yes.
Bye, Peter.
"Your wife." She said, "Your wife."
I heard her perfectly.
I don't think I know you.
Stop! Did you know?
Why did you tell me he was dead?
How could you lie to me like that?
How could I tell you?
Every time you run a yellow light,
you go rushing
for a goddamn priest to confess it.
You would have never helped me,
would you have?
- Of course not.
I insist you leave this place right away!
Can't you see what you're doing
is immoral, intrusive
and probably illegal?
I love her. Her husband does not love her.
Not like I do.
How the hell do you know
how much he loves her?
Because no husband
who really loves his wife
is gonna leave her in a dump like this
and only come see her twice a month!
I'm not going anywhere. I'm staying here.
Suit yourself.
But don't expect any more booze
or any more favors from me.
And I won't be making
any more monthly payments!
You're on your own.
I cannot be an accomplice
to this felony any longer.
You keep bragging about
your cross-eyed girlfriend, you know,
that had the wonderful laugh or smile
or I don't know what the hell it was.
I know now why she didn't ever kiss you.
Sorry about that, ma'am.
Ugh.
Are you sure?
I called the senior living place
and they confirmed it.
What were you doing at his house?
And why did you take your travel bags?
It doesn't matter.
I tried to call Shane,
but I didn't have his number.
How could he not tell me?
Maybe he didn't wanna upset you.
He's always like that.
He's always keeping things to himself.
But I don't understand. Alzheimer's?
He's always so sharp.
I realize
that this may sound a little harsh.
- But it kind of makes sense now.
- What?
Yeah, we all said he was getting
a little more ornery after Helen died,
but the truth is
he was being very obnoxious,
at least with me, and I mean before the...
It doesn't matter.
He blamed me for global warming,
Selma, for Christ's sake.
But I guess it wasn't his fault,
you know? Poor guy.
That's it.
- Very good. I'll take one.
- Uh-huh.
It might be a bit of a shock
for him to see you,
so try to be not too disruptive.
Claude?
Look who's here.
Hey, Daddy.
You see? He's happy to see you.
You...
You're doing a jigsaw?
Are you sure you're okay here?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
- Why?
- Well...
Are they treating you well?
- Yes.
- Okay.
Aren't you bothered by the other patients?
I mean, we know how you like your space.
No, they're fine.
You got to miss your home.
- Your library.
- Huh?
Your books. Don't you miss 'em?
What books?
We miss your cooking.
Okay, we're gonna come and we're
gonna bust you out of here one day,
take you back to our house
and you can destroy the kitchen.
- Huh, Tania?
- Yeah.
How's the food here?
- Good.
- Good?
Are you sure? You used
to badmouth five-star restaurants.
Stars? It's daytime.
You guys...
I'm gonna go see the supervisor.
Come on, Grandpa.
I don't understand.
A few weeks ago, he was lucid enough
to give me advice, just as he always did,
and he tells me that he's going on a trip
with his friend and they're winging it.
So now he's here with Alzheimer's.
Perhaps he was simply telling you
about a trip he made
with a friend many years ago.
Truth be told,
I've had some problems at home.
But it's not an excuse.
I hope you have the time
for your father now, Mrs. Addison,
because he's going to need
your attention and your affection
more than ever.
Nice and relaxing here, huh, Grandpa?
So what movies do you watch?
No Country for Old Men?
So what games do they have?
Not spin the bottle, I guess.
Card games? Dominoes?
Yeah?
You don't get half of what I say, do you?
What about books? Anything interesting?
God! No wonder you lose neurons here!
Don't worry, Grandpa.
I'm gonna smuggle in the good stuff.
Cognac?
There's the old Grandpa I know.
You want some cognac?
Old-time cognac.
Vintage.
You know, you kind of
ruined my plan to run away.
He barely recognized me.
He couldn't even name Tania.
Oh, no. What did the doctors say?
That it's Alzheimer's
and some sort of childhood regression.
Wow.
You know how he is about his books.
Yeah.
I remember one time I didn't return a book
and he put a rotten shrimp in my glovebox.
He probably doesn't even
remember them now.
Really?
He might not even remember me.
Or how much he hates me.
This is very nice. Very nice.
Hm-hm.
Our residents are very comfortable here.
Almost as if they were
in their own living room.
Well, a lot of us would kill to have
a living room like this, Mrs. Marcos.
- Oh, thank you.
- Look at this natural light.
- This is beautiful. You think so?
- Yeah, absolutely.
Hey, cutie.
Who are you?
Well, I'm David. And who are you?
You know damn well who I am.
Don sent you to spy on me, didn't he?
Sarah, please.
I know there's a camera in that thing.
I'm sorry. Who?
Don! Tell him
to stick the affidavit up his ass.
Come on, Sarah. Leave Mr. Addison alone.
He came to see his father-in-law.
Claude?
It's... Hey, whoa! Where are you going?
Remember me? How are you?
How are you doing in here, buddy?
Your son-in-law. David.
With a "D"?
David with a "D," yeah.
So you don't recognize me at all?
You always hated my guts.
You remember that?
I wanted to say that I'm very sorry
for what's happened to you.
You were a real pain in my ass,
but I never wanted to beat you this way.
I don't want your illness
to wipe my slate clean.
I want us to pick up
right where we left off.
Turn this whole thing around.
I want us to be a real family this time.
Selma's gonna forgive me, too.
Hello?
Worse comes to worst, I'll take Florida.
At the desk is a guy who's asking for you
and he looks very suspicious
and a bit dangerous.
God!
Thank you for the warning. Oh, God!
At my request he would not.
Hermione, my dearest,
thou never spokest to better purpose.
- Never?
- Never, but once.
What! Have I twice said well?
When was't before?
I prithee tell me,
cram's with praise
and make's as fat as tame things:
one good deed, dying tongueless,
slaughters a thousand waiting upon that.
Our praises are our wages:
you may ride's with one soft kiss
a thousand furlongs ere
with spur we beat an acre.
But to the goal.
My last good deed was to entreat his stay.
What was my first?
It has an elder sister...
You used my dad for a PR stunt.
That was not me, Selma.
No. He'd never let you take that picture.
I swear on my mother's grave.
That had to be somebody
from the old-folks' staff.
You know they're underpaid, they see
the opportunity to make a few bucks.
That's the only explanation I can find.
I mean, I'm just
as pissed off as you, trust me.
You took advantage of him. It wasn't?
Is that your wife?
- We can sue them if you want.
- No.
I don't want any more publicity.
Uh...
Listen, I swear I had nothing to do
with it, and if you wanna sue them,
I will call my lawyer immediately.
To you.
Mom's putting on a pathetic show,
pretending everything is all right.
That your husband is boning whores
and you act like you don't know.
As if all that isn't enough,
everyone at school knows.
They all laugh at me and...
Logan doesn't even know me and...
now you're like this.
I just wanna leave this town and...
You can't get upset at that, please.
But Dad wants us to go to Florida.
Why? Why would you go to Florida?
- To stay?
- Grandpa...
Are you understanding me?
Huh?
Grandpa, do you, like,
go in and out of Alzheimer's?
I don't have Alzheimer's, babe.
I faked my way into this place.
I've never had it
and I'm not gonna have it.
And I'm fine.
What?
Why would you do that?
Because there's someone
who needs me very much.
- Who?
- She was my first love.
And now she's here.
Here.
And she has Alzheimer's.
I don't know what to say. I mean...
So it was before Grandma?
Yes, way before Grandma.
Oh, God!
I need you to do us both a big favor.
What?
You have to keep this a secret.
Only if you promise
not to tell Mom and Dad
that I was trying to run away.
Deal?
Deal.
I'm so happy you have fake Alzheimer's.
I mean, it's incredibly weird
and possibly illegal, but... still.
A theater company comes
to put on a play for the residents.
- Really?
- Yeah.
And I'm making sure it's a specific one.
This one.
Ah.
The Winter's Tale.
That was
Lillian's greatest performance ever.
And there's my plan.
Your plan? For what?
To make her try and remember me.
"My dearest Claude.
"I am writing to you
"more hastily than I would like
and you deserve,
"as the little time I have
between rehearsals
"is filled with interviews
"for radio stations and the press.
"And this only adds to my frustration
"for not having you here with me
"because everything,
"absolutely everything reminds me of you.
"You know what?
"I've come to the cafe
where we always meet
"when you come to Paris."
Paris!
Hmm.
"Apart from my Earl Grey,
"I've ordered the cognac...
"...you usually have after your coffee.
"So when I put my lips on the glass,
"I try to feel
that I'm putting them to yours,
"the only place where my lips
really feel alive,
"capable of igniting my whole body.
"So, you see, I look for you
"even in the most impossible places...
"...in every shadow, in my dreams,
"in every theater stall.
"And I feel like I'm glowing,
"not from the lines I recite
"or the spotlights all around me,
"but from the strength I get
"from knowing that you are thinking of me,
"reading me,
"listening to me, feeling me.
"Please, come very soon.
"All my love, Lily."
This letter is for you, isn't it?
- Yes.
- You are Claude.
And her name is Lillian.
Lily.
Hmm.
Is that why you spend
so much time with me?
Because I remind you of her?
That's exactly why.
Ah.
And why can't you be with her?
She was married.
I don't think she ever...
ever wanted to get a divorce.
She chickened out.
I hate people who chicken out.
Oh!
Lily, come on. Let's go. It's raining.
Let's go inside.
Claude, come on! It's raining!
- Come inside!
- I like the rain.
Come on. Let's go inside.
Hey, why don't you ask Logan
and his gang of theater geeks?
- I don't wanna interrupt his clique.
- Oh, why not?
They all seem so lovely.
What is she wearing now?
Like, what is that?
She is so lame! Like her dad.
Oh, my God. Don't turn around.
I said don't turn around!
He's coming over here.
- Hey.
Yeah, hey.
I just wanted
to apologize about my friends.
They can be idiots.
Oh, we didn't even notice anything.
Sorry to interrupt.
Hey.
You do acting, right?
I've been in a couple of plays, yeah.
Yeah, we saw you in Our Town
and you were amazing.
Thank you.
Anyway, Tania wanted
to ask you something.
Yes?
What's going on with Florida?
I don't know.
Dad's still campaigning for us to go.
And Mom isn't putting up
much of a fight, so...
She never even mentioned it to me.
That's because she thinks
you have Alzheimer's, Grandpa.
Oh.
I found a theater company.
Everything's taken care of.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Which one?
- Oh, well, a very special one.
- You'll see.
- Spare no expense.
Props, costumes, lighting.
The whole proscenium.
Their Winter's Tale
will give you goosebumps.
All right. Bye.
Sorry, guys. The gig's off.
I just got a call
from Longwood Nursing Home
and they're cancelling due
to general illness of the audience.
Food poisoning, apparently.
We'll have to reschedule.
"She's a bed-swerver,
"even as bad as those
that give bold'st titles."
"Ay, and privy to this their late escape."
"No, by my life, privy to none of this."
What do you think?
- Better. That was better.
- You like it?
We're the theater company
here for the play.
- That way.
- Thank you.
"I know it too well.
"Give me the boy.
"I'm glad you did not nurse him,
"though he does bear some signs of me."
"What is this? Sport?"
"Bear the boy hence.
He shall not come about her.
"Away with him and let her sport
herself with that she's big with,
"for 'tis Polixenes
has made thee swell thus.
"She is an adulteress!"
She's not an adulteress! She's a spy!
Don't think you can fool me.
- Can't you ever shut up, madam?
- I'm so sorry.
- It's important.
- You think everybody's a spy.
And stop wearing that tacky green shirt!
Out!
Donahue. Scarborough Fair.
Now, please.
Is he a part of the show?
Well, he is now.
Um...
"For calumny will sear virtue itself,
"that mercy does...
Um...
"You can say 'she's goodly'
"come between ere
you can say 'she's honest, '
"but be it known from him that has
most cause to grieve it should be,
"she's an adulteress!"
"Should a villain say so?
"The most replenished villain in the...
"Should a villain say so,
"the most replenished villain in the world
"he were as much more villain:
"you, my lord, do but mistake."
"You have mistook, my lady...
Polixenes for Leontes.
"Polixenes...
"Polixenes for Leontes.
"Oh, thou thing
"which I'll not call a creature
of thy place, lest barbarism,
"making me the precedent,
should a like language use
"to all degrees and mannerly
distinguishment leave out
"betwixt the prince and beggar!
"I have said she's an adulteress.
"I have said with whom.
"More?
"She's a traitor."
"No! By my life!
"Privy to none of this!
"How will this grieve you
"when you shall come to clearer knowledge
"that you thus have publish'd me?
"I must be patient
"till heavens look
with an aspect more favorable.
"I'm not prone to weeping,
"as our sex commonly are.
"The want of which vain dew
"perchance shall dry your pities.
"But I have that honorable grief
"lodged here,
which burns worse than tears drown.
"The king's will be perform'd!"
"Shall I be heard?"
"Who is't that goes with me?
"Beseech your highness,
"my women may be with me
for you see my plight requires it!
"This action I now go on
"is for my better grace.
"Adieu, my lord.
"I never wished to see you sorry.
"Now I trust I shall.
"My women, come.
"You have leave."
Claude.
I've missed you so much.
Oh, my Claude.
You are so beautiful.
Hmm.
- Whoo! Yeah!
- Whoa!
Oh, my God!
- Where is she?
- Who?
My sweet embraceable you
Embrace me
You irreplaceable you
Just one look at you
My heart grew tipsy in me
You and you alone
Bring out the gypsy in me
I love all the many charms about you
Above all I want my arms about you
Don't be a naughty baby
Come to pappa, come to pappa do
My sweet embraceable you
Mr. Berenson? Mrs. Blanche?
Lily?
Hi, baby.
The new tests show
no sign of Alzheimer's or dementia.
In fact, your mental faculties
are impeccable.
I'm well. I'm not ill.
Does that make you happy?
Yeah, I'm happy.
So am I, Claude,
but Alzheimer's is nothing to joke about.
When did you hear me
joke about Alzheimer's? Never.
I just said
I didn't wanna wear a diaper. I hate it.
Now, I don't know what plans
you and your family have,
but I'm afraid you won't be permitted
to stay here any longer.
Well, but what about Lillian?
I love her and she loves me.
She has a loving husband,
who probably won't like
romantic overtures.
But we would be playing with fire
if we let you stay.
I hope you understand.
That's all I have to say.
Thanks, Ms. Marcos, for everything.
I don't want you to go.
Thank you.
And you and I both know
you're a lot smarter than people think.
You know.
Come on.
Oh.
My most fond memory here
is the fact that you could
flat-out play the guitar.
Know how special you are.
Okay?
- Well, sir.
- Sir.
My guardian angel.
Where are you going?
My daughter and my granddaughter
need to spend time with me.
You have a daughter?
That's good.
I will love you
as long as I live.
"Doubt thou the stars are fire."
"Doubt that
"the sun does move."
Mom's not gonna say it, so...
I was wondering
if we could stay here for a while.
- Please.
- Book it.
- Book it?
- Yes, ma'am.
- I'll talk to your receptionist.
- Any day you want. 24/7, 365.
Whatever it is.
I got the spare bedroom, two beds.
They're all made up and they're
just waiting for a mom and daughter!
How about that?
Good. You said you were gonna cook?
Uh...
- I love this hotel!
- It's on you, Grandpa.
This is the best hotel ever.
You mean I have to cook all the meals?
I almost lost her once.
Did everything I could to make her stay.
You got the best out of me.
I was surprised that she did stay.
But this time,
there's nothing I can do.
This time, I just couldn't stand aside.
I know.
And I'm grateful to you
for brightening up her days.
This time and back then.
You can come and visit her
any time you want.
What you just did for me
is the nicest thing
anyone will ever do for me in my life.
I wanna thank you.
Thank you so much.
Okay, who have we got next?
Daniel. Danny. Okay.
You ready, Danny?
You're not nervous?
Too bad my grandpa's girlfriend
isn't here to feed me lines.
You don't need her.
You're a natural.
I wish I could have seen her
on stage in her heyday.
She was beautiful.
- Wanna read lines?
- Yeah.
"Doubt thou the stars are fire,
"doubt that the sun doth move,
"doubt truth to be a liar,
but never doubt I love."
- Do you want to read lines again?
- Yeah.
Oh, my God.
Look at you. You look fabulous.
As do you.
- Fosamax?
- Nope!
- Diclofenac?
- You dirty bastard.
- Hmm.
Jesus! Let's have a toast to that.
- Oh, here. Thank you, ma'am.
- Thank you.
- Coffee.
- Some coffee.
Mmm.
So, how are you doing?
Sliding by.
Sliding? You, sliding is good.
- Sliding works.
- Hm-hm. Seems to.
- Eighty years.
- Uh-huh.
- Still sliding.
- Yeah.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org